<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="futureredefined.blogspot.com">
	<documents count="25">
		<document id="8244b49fbe5dc3b15cfd45a4a95779dc" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/4T66uN_gGi0/branch-is-deadlong-live-branch.html"><![CDATA[<p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 11.0px 'Lucida Grande'; color: #a79e62"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0); font-size: 9px; ">I was having dinner with an entrepreneur in the Indian payments space earlier today. The emerging business models and evolving consumer adoption trends in banking &amp; financial services, soon overshadowed the culinary delights that had adorned the table!</span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">A silent revolution is unfolding on the ground, which otherwise appear frequently on business plans and venture capital pitches. Retail outlets, appointed by Business Correspondents (BCs) are now permitted to open bank accounts, accept deposits, facilitate withdrawals, take bill payments and enable fund transfers. This bodes well for retailers as they find discover new revenue streams but also have a great proposition to drive walk ins into their outlets. Now, this is rather well known and has been the norm for several countries that have successfully adopted the BC model and driven the financial inclusion agenda effectively.</span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">An interesting development is however, that non-banking customers can now walk into a BC appointed retailer and deposit cash into third party bank accounts, and see their funds get transferred in real time! Hence a labourer toiling on the roads of New Delhi can ensure that his wife, thousands of miles away, in a village in Tamil Nadu can receive funds into her account in a couple of seconds. This effectively bridges the banked with the unbanked, converts cash into an electronic format and provides an instant transfer experience. All critical aspects for building confidence and driving usage of formal banking, payment and transfer mechanisms and eventually leading to the belief in the need for a bank account and financial inclusion.</span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">The key point to be noted is that the neighbourhood retailer has earned the ‘Trust’ of the consumers accessing this suite of services. Banks have invested billions of dollars in building their brands and providing assurance to customers that their money is safe with them. Now, the retailer with his social equity, appears to have cracked the code!</span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">Now, for most people reading this post, the process and experience of banking, having the comfort of a branch nearby (which may never be visited) is well ingrained and considered the only method of storing and accessing funds. However for billions of people worldwide, their circle of trust extends to their immediate social circle of neighbours and retailers, whom they can see and meet, at their convenience. A bank can be an ‘alien’ institution, an inanimate object that they cannot relate to as easily. MFIs with self-help groups have amply demonstrated this!</span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">Which takes us to the second inflection point. Banking services have been rolled out by some companies, wherein the retailer requires just a mobile phone to accept deposits, enable withdrawals and fund transfers! No POS machines. No ATM machines. No Internet Banking terminals! No technology intensive kioks! No card plastic! No card readers! And a ton of other no’s as well, which would give shudders to most professionals who have grown enamored (and possibly addicted) to these devices and technologies.</span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">Hence the question that is quite clearly staring us in the face today. Where do we go from here? How does one increase financial inclusion, banking access penetration and electronic payments usage.</span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">The current access metrics in India are at predictably low levels of 66.3 branches per 1 million persons* and 16.3 ATMs per million persons (Source : Report on Trends and Progress of Banking in India 2009-10, RBI). For North America those ratios stand at 260 branches per 1 million persons and 1340 ATMs per million persons. Taking into consideration the income distribution and growth levels, the geographic spread and infrastructure challenges, traditional expansion models would still target a 3x growth in number of branches and 20x growth for ATMs to achieve reasonable levels of financial access. And with over 300,000 POS terminals, the growth factor opportunity for this segment can only be exponential.</span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">This would of course incur capital investments, exceeding the GDP of several countries. But the question remains. </span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">Which would be a more economical and successful method of banking and electronic payments growth?</span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">There could be three approaches</span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">Leverage new to banking &amp; payments channels: The business correspondent and retail networks, appearing to be the primary choice.</span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">Leverage new to payments devices : Enable payment processing via devices such as the mobile phone. Square could be a good point of reference on this dimension. I have in my earlier report, outlined the recommendations of the Inter Ministerial Panel, which has outlined a framework for mobile based acceptance network development. It has set out norms for a different approach to ATMs as well. Hence the thought is in place and the initial designs as well.</span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">Follow the traditional branch + ATM expansion model</span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 36.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'; min-height: 11.0px"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px"></span><br /></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px"><b>The Shifting Point!</b></span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">The question that one ponders on now. The business correspondent / retailer models referred above have been primarily designed with a perspective of addressing the requirements of clients at the bottom of the pyramid, in both the urban rural markets. </span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">Can these models be similarly applied to address the needs of the mass affluent and affluent audiences as well, in both urban and rural markets?</span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">It’s been ages since I’ve visited my bank branch. Net banking and ATMs address my needs sufficiently. Hence the only leg that remains is that served by the ATM for dispensing cash. </span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">Then, why do we need two models of expansion? The first catering to the affluent, and the second catering to the not too affluent. </span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">A high end supermarket chain is just as hungry for business and walk-ins as your local neighbourhood grocer, a fundamental premise that drives retailers to participate in transaction processing. </span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">Would I mind walking across to the cashier at the supermarket till to withdraw cash as I pick up groceries? Possibly not! </span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">Would I mind depositing cash at a computer peripherals store as I purchase anti-virus software? Possibly not, again. </span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">Would I mind if my pizza delivery guy swipes my card on a device like square instead of a fancy high end POS device? Nope!</span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">Would I prefer a smiling attendant behind the cash till to an automated voice urging me to take my cash quickly? Yes! And she doesn’t have to be in a bank costume.</span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">What would influence banks, regulators and processors to evaluate this radical shift in thinking? Isn’t there a sufficient economic value migration opportunity, for shifting the savings in capital and operating expenditure incurred in managing branches &amp; ATM channels to the retail channel partner? </span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">Would then, banks still need to invest in branches? Can a virtual bank complemented by a payment networks brand operating on a retailing layer operate in a scalable and efficient manner? Or, would in fact, retailers actually be willing to pass back value to banks for leading customers to them? Or would this perhaps lead to drastic reduction in costs across the value chain resulting in higher earnings for customers on their savings and lower lending rates possibly?</span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">Can a model be evolved, where a ‘bank’ branch may be primarly designed for customer enrolment and loan disbursals, with currency disbursement, fund transfers and other services be completely migrated to their retailing partners? With new customer acquisition mostly occurring at third party locations, the branch could even play a administrative supervisory and customer support role in a hub and spoke model, wherein a single branch oversees the operations of hundreds of retailers and ATMs in its hinterland! </span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">With mobile devices having achieved over 100% penetration levels in the mass affluent segments, the mobile could effectively act as the access and authentication device. This in turn could restrict the need for POS or ATM devices as we know them today. This makes it even easier for retailers to participate in the payments processing domain.</span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.0px">This potentially ‘outrageous’ approach is open for debate and would welcome your views. </span></p> <p style="margin: 0.0px 0.0px 10.0px 0.0px; text-align: justify; font: 9.0px 'Lucida Grande'"><br /></p><div><span class="Apple-style-span"    style="font-family:'Lucida Grande', serif;font-size:78%;color:#009ECE;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size: 8px; text-decoration: underline;"><br /></span></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="aafe3649bb938057ef2a5782ab2f83e1" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/5t0P0NUfxbQ/recession-is-deadlong-live-recession.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;"><a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/Sg3DYwUb-rI/AAAAAAAAAP0/Ru7TokKQcJU/s1600-h/recession.jpg"><img style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer; width: 69px; height: 91px;" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/Sg3DYwUb-rI/AAAAAAAAAP0/Ru7TokKQcJU/s320/recession.jpg" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5336135963558804146" border="0" /></a><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">There has been a virtual tsunami of content lashing every medium known to mankind elucidating on why we got here in retrospective magnificence. Nobel laureates, industrialists and even social workers are in the company of laid off millionaire junk bond dealers elucidating on black swans and the death of capitalism (and banking) as we know it. There is also the trickle of hope that creeps its way through the swamp of pessimism in the shadow of the recent global enthusiasm in the stock markets.<br /><br />The irony  of the situation lies in the fact that yet again optimism breeds on the same speculative phenomenon of  clearly irrational stock markets which have wiped off trillions within 18 months, but have displayed an irrational exuberance over the last 90 days. This rather feels like the case of the battered wife that files a complaint and then returns to the husband to seek emotional support.<br /><br />The Internet boom (&amp;bust), the dizzying reality valuation explosion and stock market benevolence have bred a generation of global professionals that have set very high growth rate benchmarks for wealth creation in their professional and personal realms. With decades of personal savings having been wiped off, most retail investors find themselves out in the cold.<br /><br />With corporates facing liquidation or bankcruptcy, nations on the brink of insolvency and banks witnessing capital and reputation inadequacy, the notions and vanguards of trust are seeking true champions.<br /><br />Entrepreneurial zest, intellectual brilliance, ingenious rural &amp; urban economic ecosystems would find it difficult to navigate in the current sea of mistrust. Derivatives, junk bonds, swaps, market linked insurance products have been sold to hapless corporates and consumers alike. In this backdrop, the largest and most pertinent need that arises is for a suite of services that can provide unbiased advise on capital/wealth protection and growth.<br /><br />A stimulating dialogue with a young organization earlier today has further reinforced my belief in the need for financial advisory services that are driven only by the client interests and not by the commission and incentive structure of the manufacturers (of bonds, mutual funds, insurance companies etc.). The future lies in independent, trained and certified advisors that would  recommend a savings mix to retail individuals which truly address the individuals' risk appetite and hygiene wealth requirements.</span> <br /></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1fbe46bc3220c9a8ae23235cd3f472d" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/7PHPBoBi7rI/banking-20.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;"><a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SDxgM828ZkI/AAAAAAAAAGs/I-hy6PN7W08/s1600-h/revolution.jpeg"><img style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer;" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SDxgM828ZkI/AAAAAAAAAGs/I-hy6PN7W08/s320/revolution.jpeg" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5205141044944725570" border="0" /></a><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family:verdana;">A recent BCG publication on Financial Inclusion in India deconstructed the financial services value chain into six fundamental pieces : product development, customer acquisition, risk management, funding, administration and collection. Now this got me thinking. ......Are banks as we know today at an existential risk? Is there a disaggregated approach to banking that is emerging wherein banks do not necessarily participate directly in the complete value chain but participate in some of the pieces and not all. Is it also possible that banks may even get dislodged from their core areas of receiving deposit and enabling funding by new players.</span>  </span><br /><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family:verdana;">With over 135 million households that are financially “excluded” several banks have been pushing the envelope or in several cases been pushed out of the core areas of microfinance. Players such as BASIX and SKS have been leading forays into micro lending to retail entrepreneurs, whereas banks in most cases have been involved in providing finance to MFIs and in some cases administrative and technical support.</span>  <span style="font-family:verdana;"><br /><br />Over 500 million footfalls annually expected in India in organised retail environments including malls, and supermarkets, in the next couple of years, retail finance is not viewed as a nice to have but a critical ingredient to fuel retail purchases. Most large retailers are either building or taking financial stake in the creation and set up of retail financial services to fuel purchases within their storefronts. Spurred on by the successful financial services models of  Casa Baha in Brazil or Tesco Finance, which have multi billion dollar asset bases, the newly established retail retail financial services arms of Reliance Retail and the Future Group view the delivery of financial services as an invaluable element in fueling demand and purchase.</span>  <span style="font-family:verdana;"><br /><br />The Safaricom venture of Vodafone has already acquired over one million customers participating in the fund transfer process and no bank in sight. Models in Philippines and other parts of africa too have emerged, wherein banks are being marginalisd from the transfer process. The increasing penetration and significance of the mobile phone has clearly provided telecom players the right foundation to construct a financial services model that can quite clearly address the aspect of secure payments and transfer. Whether they choose to play more enhanced roles in the areas of acquisition, collections and risk management is yet to be seen. Hence can we imagine a Bharti tying up with ICICI Bank to sign up millions of customers each month for mobile connections and bank accounts for the financially excluded? Why not!</span>  <span style="font-family:verdana;">With the market getting competitive and retail finance having clearly become a critical ingredient for urban and retail households, the quest for low rates is on the rise.<br /><br />Hence the growing phenomenon of peer to peer lending that is emerging in Europe and North America by Zopa, Prosper, Virgin Money and a host of other players. Yet again this model technically marginalises or even excludes conventional retail banking institutions in the consumer lending process. The concept of peer to peer lending has existed since time immemorial but has also presented to the fore a new point of discussion and debate in the aspect of social scoring / equity that an individual brings to the lending process. Zopa has recently published its results on the effect of social , wherein borrowers received lower rates when endorsed by family, friends and borrowers who had lent and received their money back in the past. Would banks be able to supplement their financial credit rating score with the  the aspect of social “score” Increasingly social scores would play a greater role in enabling lending decisions and processes as noticed in the case of microlending, wherein the fear of social ostracization and associated stigma associated with non payment has typically resulted in lower default rates.<br /><br />In the case of retailers such as Casa Baha, their direct connect with the customer and their ability to mesh successfully with the social fabric of their target audience has successfully resulted in the creation and adoption of new risk models. </span>  <span style="font-family:verdana;">Recent rise in delinquencies has put banks and financial institutions under the scanner for their collection practices. Without delving deep into the “blame” game, there is an increasing need for disemmination of education. With the subprime and related consumer credit crises affecting banks and retail borrowers alike, there have emerged over the last couple of years of sites such as Wesabe, which are essentially online communities that allow retail borrowers to share tips as to how they could reduce their financing costs and best practices to be adopted to reduce their default and overspending patterns. Quite clearly a need for banks to enhance their “dialogue” and truly engage their current and prospective customers, </span>  <span style="font-family:verdana;"><br /><br />Even in the traditional transactional space, wherein banks have been quite often bogged down by legacy systems and huge transition barriers. With an increasing need for security and retailers seeking lower transactional costs, the Revolution Card was launched a couple of months back in North America by Steve Case of AOL fame, which offers credit cards issued instantly at kiosks and have no numbers embossed on them! Furthermore with the transaction rates almost halved vis a vis existing rates charged by Visa &amp; MasterCard, maybe a new David has emerged in the world of Goliaths.</span> <span style="font-family:verdana;"> </span> <span style="font-family:verdana;">Quite clearly banks need to question and take a new perspective on their strength areas in the value chain. The performance and adaptability of retail finance will have an increasing bearing on the performance of other key industries including retailing, telecom, insurance, consumer goods etc. Hence it would be quite natural to expect that these industry verticals may in the near future play a larger or even different role in the banking vertical. Going forward growth models for banks would emerge more from alliances and partnerships across the value chain with other industry verticals, and in some cases questioning or redefining the perceived core competencies of their organizational charters.</span><br /><br /></span><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family:verdana;">Banks should also be open to adopting multiple standards and methods, which has typically been a barrier in experimenting and participating in new payment mechanisms. Inconsistecny and non uniformity is the only reality that banks would face in the coming years in these new domains, hence an ever increasing need to experiment and faulter even more ( the sub-prime crisis apart). Adoption and implementation of subjects such as mobile technologies and new systems needs to move from board room poster boy status to serious business imperative status. </span>  <span style="font-family:verdana;">Banks have been relying on the trust factor that customers associate with the custodians of their money as their  fundamental lifeline and often protected by regulatory frameworks.<br /><br />With rapid evolution of technologies including the Internet, and the regulator’s evolving views on the scope of financial institutions,the trust factor would be better enhanced by engaging in a dialogue with its customers, and this would be a science worth cracking and perhaps the true differentiator in the coming years. This is perhaps the time for banks to define the new playground for Banking 2.0</span></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="24b99aaeeed806928863e1575d123205" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/7W_clZLlpkk/pyramid-of-consumption.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;"><a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://bp0.blogger.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SG0w_gZbogI/AAAAAAAAAIk/r3alBExq7gs/s1600-h/bottomofpyramid.jpg"><img style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer;" src="http://bp0.blogger.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SG0w_gZbogI/AAAAAAAAAIk/r3alBExq7gs/s320/bottomofpyramid.jpg" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5218881410778767874" border="0" /></a><span style="font-family: verdana;font-size:85%;" >A recently published report by the folks at Citibank " The Pyramid of Consumption - Who Gains Now?" makes for rather interesting reading on an evolving passion ...The Bottom of the Pyramid!</span><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family:verdana;"><br />The report represents the world population into three layers with the bottom of the pyramid classified as earning < USD 3,000 p.a., is estimated to be a USD 5 trillion market!<br /><br />The need for a radical reduction in transaction costs and lowering costs of business models in the financial services space for the BOP is quite apparent. However with all the recent momentum and interest in this space, the report estimates that under 30% of this population will have access to microfinance by 2015.<br /><br />Obviously a long way to go!<br /><br />To download the report click <a href="d%20of%20Consumption%20-%20Who%20Gains%20Now%20-%20Citigroup%20report%20ToC.pdf">here</a><br /></span></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8e7a03c93a959c32ad94377e4c93796d" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/BHBW_c_5Osw/david-goliath.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">I am a huge fan of "David &amp; Goliath" business stories. Came across this one in the economist recently, and believed I must share this with you.<br /><br />"Dabba" is a South African wireless start up which has pioneered the "village telco", making phone calls more affordable. Using reprogrammed wi-fi routers as base stations with open source software weaving them into a network and cheap wi-fi handsets, the folk at Orange Farm, near Johannesburg can make calls at cheap rates.<br /><br />They have brilliantly connected with the mainline telecom networks and actually buy airtime which is then resold to their customers! Revenues arise from call termination charges, sale of air time to retail customers and in the future selling this model and set of garage technologies to other prospective villages. And all this at an astronomical investment of USD 5,000!<br /><br />Dabba intends to present an aggregated front to the mainline telcos for the village telcos as and when the model proliferates.<br /><br />Yet again, illustrating the sheer drive and innovation that is fueled by the opportunity presented in markets where most large organizations falter.<br /></span></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c132ae2211baeb409b813a41827e80c6" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/cl5QGXBCdRs/slumdog-millionaire-and-global-risk.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family: verdana;font-size:85%;" >Was fortunate enough to see Slumdog Millionaire last week. Am a die hard romantic and as a Bombaite (or should I say Mumbaikar) at heart, there is a deep bond with the spirit of that city. The city has been witness to millions of stories of determination and grit in the face of adversity. </span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: verdana;font-size:85%;" >The concept of a child swimming through human faeces and yet coming out all charged up, may feel revolting, but such is the state of the global economy right now!....Well ,that's the feeling one gets as you browse through the Global Risk '09 report published by the World Economic Forum. F<br /><br />inding the glimmer of hope through the maze of risks portrayed across slowdowns in developed and developing economies, deceleration or even drop in infrastructure investments etc., is going to be quite a task!<br /><br />A concise and well written report, makes for a rather decent read....<br /><br />To access the report <a href="http://www.weforum.org/pdf/globalrisk/globalrisks09/">Click Here</a><br /></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="653a03c375a3af1ecabdd15f178c23ac" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/dMW0NG_j4VI/collections-redefined.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;"><span style=";font-family:GE Inspira;font-size:85%;"  >  <p  style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; font-family: verdana;font-family:verdana;"><span style="font-size:100%;">With  an increasing trend of customers playing truant on their monthly credit card and  other loan repayments, believe the collections teams require to perhaps think out  of the box!<br /></span></p><p  style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; font-family: verdana;font-family:verdana;"><span style="font-size:100%;"><br /></span></p><p  style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; font-family: verdana;font-family:verdana;"><span style="font-size:100%;">Being a Friday evening, thought I might contribute to some approaches that they could adopt to contact these mischevious customers!</span></p><p  style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt; font-family: verdana;font-family:verdana;"><span style="font-size:100%;"><br /></span></p> <p  style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt;font-family:verdana;"><span style="font-size:10;"> </span></p><span style="font-size:10;"><span style="font-family:verdana;"><span style=";font-family:verdana;font-size:85%;"  >a.  Call them for an Interview : With the employment market in a lean phase, you may be able to lure these chaps with this bait quite effectively<br /><br />b. We Goofed Up : Yup, just tell them your back end operations cell goofed up on the interest calculations and their outstandings have dropped drastically!<br /><br />c. Matrimonial Matches and Dating Services : You'd be surprised how appealing a blind date might be to a bachelor facing a liquidity crunch ( to lift his spirits of course!)<br /><br />d. GPS Transmitters : Induce their doctors to inject those neat little gps transmitters into them, and that might help you track them down a bit easier!<br /><br />Now to the serious stuff......With an increasing delinquency trend across retail customers globally, the need for innovation is dire! Though customer education and sane lending practices would perhaps address some of these issues as we go forward, a couple of approaches that are perhaps worth a shot for the chaps under repayment strife:<br /><br />a. Seek Collateral : Convert unsecured to secured. Some high value outstandings could be restructured if the customer were to submit collateral - Gold, Stocks, Bonds etc.....anything to get the EMIs down and get the customer to commence repayment. May require a skill set outside your competency or "defined process", but this is the time to think out of the box.....<br /><br />b. Counselling : Yup....may sound radical....I've come across senior professionals who get into personal economic crisis situations, and display irrational behavior. May just serve your while to get them into a counselling session " Defaulters Anonymous!"<br />The other end of counselling would involve undertaking a financial planning and budgeting exercise with the client and showing possible routes.<br /><br />c. Reduce your rate / Restructure: Critical to understand the line between an intentional and accidental defaulter, and drop your rate. Much better to see the inflows than writeoffs!<br /><br />d. Promissory Note : Yup, before you write off the loan, take a promissory note from the customer indicating promise to pay 12 months hence. You may just have a few grateful chaps who will reappear and pay.<br /><br />e. Advertise the good deeds : If your organisation has been able to work with some defaulting customers in getting them back on track, you may just like to publicize the same. Could have a positive rub off.<br /><br />Look forward to hearing your views!</span><br /></span></span></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d3937ffb3fa0a292aac096d246233be5" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/DylNnL57tyE/mobile-payments-redefined.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Purchasing an airline ticket with Rs. 30 in the wallet at 2 am in the midst of a trekking expedition, considered nigh impossible till a few years back is now a distinct reality made possible by mobile phones. Is cash on the brink of extinction, well not yet!</span></span><br /><div style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">With the explosion in mobile telephony, it was often considered that mobile payments would overtake cash and card based transactions in a similar wave. With large customer and retail footprints, customer acquisition and account management expertise, competence in managing large transaction volumes, having redefined global norms of running expensive and complex networks profitably at phenomenally low billing rates and ARPUs, the mobile ecosystem appears to have the ingredients for redefining the payments space in India.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">From a customer’s perspective, the omnipresence of the mobile device in her daily life coupled with her increasing familiarity and disposition towards accessing a wide bouquet of service offerings via the mobile, has made the argument even more tenable.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">In the context of transactions, mobile phones have been used in a wide variety of end uses including mobile banking, fund transfers and retail payments. Several service offerings have been initiated leveraging the portability and convenience factor, spanning financial inclusion to purchasing coffee. But, very few of these initiatives have evolved scale or universal acceptance.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The reasons have been attributed to economic viability, regulatory restrictions, technology limitations and consumer apprehensions or even the absence of relevant value propositions. However, the success of mobile transactions is closely linked with a mix of factors that also determine the long-term viability of any retail electronic payment system.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Retail electronic payments refer to those transactions made by individuals for retail payments, in which there is no physical exchange of cash. Hence, payments made via debit, prepaid and credit cards or electronic fund transfers such as NEFT and RTGS would qualify. Mobile transactions would hence refer to those transactions routed via the mobile channel with funds originating from credit, debit, prepaid and bank accounts.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The 180 million debit and credit card base in India today with an estimated Rs. 80,000 crores of retail spends, is nascent yet significant in its scope and opportunity. Payment cards, largely issued by banks and financial institutions today, enable both face to face and remote transactions, having fueled the over Rs. 10,000 e-commerce market in India today.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="color: rgb(51, 51, 255);font-size:100%;" ><span style="font-family: verdana;">Impact of Retail Electronic Payments</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Electronic payment allow accessibility, portability, safe storage and “ownership”, providing clear audit trails, which are distinct lacunae in cash based payments. They have also provided mechanisms for recourse in case of disputes and made remote transactions a reality. In effect, they have provided a cost efficient means for transactions.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The broader impact of electronic payments lies in its influence on triggering economic growth, reducing the costs of cash management and in deterring the large grey economy (that is rumored to equal the Indian GDP).</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Global studies have established that electronic payments have stimulated GDP growth in excess of over 200 basis points. Combined with the actual cost of cash management (including printing, disbursal, collection, reporting and theft), estimated to be as high as 5%, a need for a clearer and broader policy and framework to stimulate electronic payments clearly emerges in India today.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">As India enters the next decade, it is faced with the challenge of sustaining and further accelerating its GDP growth. Key growth drivers include initiatives in infrastructure development, financial inclusion, micro lending to stimulate commerce and healthy retail spending within the banked and un-banked populations. The viability of initiatives as disparate as financial inclusion to transit payments hinges on efficient payment mechanisms. </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The economic viability of business correspondents (BCs), driving financial inclusion today lies in their efficiencies in managing cash transactions and in stimulating usage post account opening. The NREGS, perhaps the primary stimulus today for opening bank accounts amongst the unbanked, has facilitated electronic credits to bank accounts accessible via mobile phones &amp; smart cards, thereby reducing transmission losses. However as consumers continue to withdraw cash from BCs, the larger cost and risk of cash management prevails.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The availability of a wide-spread retail electronic payment infrastructure to these consumers would allow them to purchase goods and services with the funds credited to their bank accounts thereby reducing the need for managing cash in the system.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">In the arena of infrastructure and public transport, there are already millions of prepaid instruments that have been issued to commuters to make payments on metro rail, bus services and toll roads. With a quantum growth outlined in new and modernized transport services, the volume of transactions within these operators itself is projected to exceed Rs. 100,000 crores in the next decade. With costs of cash management constantly increasing, the viability of these projects would be significantly influenced by the methods adopted for payment acceptance.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The impact of card payments on enhancing average ticket sizes, purchase of big-ticket items and catalyzing segment level spends including travel, has also been established. As banks and issuers aggressively promote card usage, consumers also see increasing value in using their card accounts. However the benefits of electronic / card payments is yet to penetrate the larger segments of retail and consumer population in India.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="color: rgb(51, 102, 255);font-size:100%;" ><br /></span><span style="color: rgb(51, 102, 255);font-size:100%;" ><span style="font-family: verdana;">Dimensions &amp; Challenges</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The six key dimensions and respective challenges for a retail electronic payment system as follows:</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">1. Transaction Sizes : Traditional card based payment systems cater to transaction sizes in excess of Rs. 250. With over 98% of retail transactions in India being below Rs. 250, any payment system seeking to expand penetration would need to cater to this segment.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">2. Banked &amp; Unbanked : Payment cards have been primarily available to the banked population in India. The unbanked have over the last couple of years been accessing prepaid cards, though in relatively smaller proportion, to make transit payments, Internet based purchases and store level purchases. The opportunity lies in enhancing the banked penetration and in bridging transactions between the formally banked and unbanked.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">3. Face to Face &amp; Remote Payments: Card based payments have made both possible, and with the debit card base also being gradually opened for remote payments, the opportunity basket would expand multifold. But face to face payments would remain crucial. The existing card &amp; POS based design approach would be prohibitive for low transaction sizes and volume throughputs per customer and retail outlet respectively</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">4. Standards &amp; Customer Convenience: As an example, with millions of prepaid cards being issued by transit operators today, following multiple technology standards, customers would soon require to load several cards in their wallet, only to make transit related payments! Hence the need for a common set of standards to be adopted early is crucial to achieve scale and consumer usage across a wide basket of services.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">5. Interoperability : If it is mandatory that both buyer and seller need to have a relationship with one bank or operator, it would typically restrict both scope and scale.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">6. Transaction Costs : The key challenge for globally adopted electronic payment systems have been in the high costs of issuing plastic, transaction cost management and managing these payment acceptance networks. Coupled with settlement costs and fraud risks, these have typically been expensive and complex businesses to operate and restricted to transaction sizes only in excess of Rs. 200.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The viability of payment networks are dependent on achieving transaction volume scale. This is one of the primary reasons for the relatively low POS acceptance infrastructure in India today and hence acceptance of electronic payments.</span></span><br /><br /><br /><span style="color: rgb(51, 102, 255);font-size:100%;" ><span style="font-family: verdana;">The Road Ahead for Mobile Transactions</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">There have been several mobile based payment systems that have emerged across the globe over the last five years. Mpesa, in Kenya, managed by a leading mobile operator, has revolutionalized the payments and transfers market. It has however developed in an economy, where the formal banking system had marginal penetration and controls in place. Other models in the Far East and South Africa have focused on the remittances &amp; transfers market and targeted the unbanked populations. South Korea, with a high penetration of banked and mobile populations has evolved into levels which most nations would aspire to reach in this decade. </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Much has been written on the elaborate opportunity and proven impact of mobile telephony on the Indian economy, stimulating entrepreneurship and trade. However, coupled with payments and fund transfers, the mobile phone could perhaps address these challenges and provide an exponential impetus to the Indian economy in the next decade.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="color: rgb(51, 102, 255);font-size:100%;" ><br /></span><span style="color: rgb(51, 102, 255);font-size:100%;" ><span style="font-family: verdana;">What Next</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Growth of electronic transactions in India can follow the conventional linear path of installing POS machines and issuing cards to consumers. Alternatively there is a confluence of forces and actions that could possibly emerge to catapult electronic payments into a trajectory similar to that achieved by mobile telephony in the decade gone by.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The existing card and cheque based payment systems were designed and established in an era when the first Internet or mobile connections had not even been issued to customers. These systems had also been designed to cater to high-ticket urban purchases and related transactional costs. A lot has changed since then.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The challenge for banks, financial institutions, mobile operators and payment processors would lie in evolving a new approach to payments. The key would lie in creating an ecosystem that offers a foundation of high frequency payments including grocery, bill payments etc. with a blend of high impact transaction opportunities such as fund transfers and P2P payments. The mobile ecosystem possibly holds the key.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="color: rgb(102, 102, 204);font-size:100%;" ><span style="font-family: verdana;">Potential Business Models &amp; Their Evolution</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The business models and economic value chain that could emerge for a mobile payment ecosystems would be defined by the following factors:</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">    1.    Who holds the funds?</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">    2.    Who would own the customer relationship?</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">    3.    Who would service the merchant?</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">    4.    Who would acquire the customer?</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">    5.    Who would own the brand?</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">    6.    Who would manage the core transaction system?</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Reference a report published by The Mobey Forum, two broad categories of models would emerge, the first would morph from the existing bank centric business models and the second would be more “transformational” in nature.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">In the bank centric models, the mobile channel would possibly play the role of carrier and user inferface as in the case of mobile banking today.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">In the transformational category, there are three models that have emerged till date:</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">1. Partnership Model : The bank and mobile operator jointly manage the business</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">2.  Independent Service Provider Model : wherein a non-banking or telecom entity would set up a mobile payments ecosystem &amp;</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">3.  Operator Centric: Wherein the mobile operator takes the lead, with the banking entity servicing evolving regulatory requirements w.r.t fund storage, clearing &amp; settlement.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="color: rgb(102, 51, 255);font-size:100%;" ><span style="font-family: verdana;">The Tipping Points for Mobile Payment System Evolution</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">1. Source of Funds :</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The recent circulars by the RBI on prepaid cards, allowing non bank entities to create prepaid payment accounts, is a critical step in expanding the funnel of customers who can be brought into the electronic payments fold, and potentially redefining the traditional role served by banks in India.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Hence virtual mobile wallets, Internet payment accounts, potentially issued by mobile operators, manufacturers and service providers along with banks, would allow both banked and non banked customers to have a prepaid payment account. The loading via cash could be undertaken at 3rd party agent networks or the banked may choose to transfer funds from their existing banking accounts.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">As open-ended prepaid cards still remain under the ambit of banks, partnerships could emerge for the creation of co-branded offerings between banks, operators and service providers.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">2. Segmented Product Offerings &amp; Value Propositions</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Students, migrant workers, housewives, micro-entrepreneurs, marginal farmers and a host of other customer segments, could be targeted with well defined and positioned “packages” bundling content and services linked with mobile payment products. </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Eg : For migrant workers, with limited access to the formal banking channel but high mobile penetration a suite of remittance related offerings clubbed with “safe storage” for cash is an arena that is likely to be exploited quickly</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">3. Use of funds :</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">  </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">a. Remittances &amp; P2P Payments</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">As operators and other retail players seek to leverage their retail and consumer reach, they would go straight for the jugular in the estimated Rs. 20,000 crores domestic remittances market.  This would be an ideal entry strategy for acquiring new and retaining large and existing customers, offering sufficient economic value propositions for the customer and retailer communities.</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The first set of services have already rolled out, and several more poised to enter shortly in 2010.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The next layers of use would emerge from the balance two categories, but would take much longer to evolve.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">b. Remote (Non Face to Face) Payments :</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The challenge here lies more on the supply side of the equatiion. Ecommerce, conducted via pcs / laptops using browsers, has been dominated by high ticket, complex selection, high involvement items such as airline &amp; railway ticket purchases followed by books, music, flowers etc. Hence the need to build a basket of products and services that could be seen and purchased via the mobile is crucial.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The turning point would be in making payments towards utilities, government levies and taxes in a user-friendly manner. These offer wide appeal, relevance and frequency. But the incentive to adopt a new mode would need to be substantial to move away from the confidence and habit of making cash payments. The agent would possibly hold the key here, as noticed globally as well.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">c. Face to Face Payments : </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The holy grail of electronic payments, would require speed, ease of use and security to converge profitably.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The battlefield is currently strewn with a myriad of acronyms and pilots. The challenge has remained in finding a solution with limited adoption or entry barriers for consumers matched with an inexpensive payment acceptance model.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">A pure mobile phone transaction play, used by both consumers and merchants, as in the case of Mobipay using USSD possibly still offers a ray of hope.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The other options include NFC or issuing new contactless payment cards stuck to the mobile phone instrument, both of which would require significant investments for large roll outs.</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The inflection point in this space would possibly arrive with the ability to make transit payments with your existing mobile!</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">4. Usability : Asking customers to remember short-codes and key words to access information and enable payments would always hinder scale. The key lies in offering a user interface with extremely low adoption barriers ( no downloads etc.), ease of use and good user experience.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Web interfaces will improve the user experience exponentially. The 3G rollout may hold the key to truly creating a payment experience that matches the classical card based payment process in time and security.</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Also, access to the Internet will enable providers to offer solutions that do not depend on the security environment offered by the SIM, the heart of the mobile relationship today.</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">5.Payment Convergence, Standards &amp; Interoperability : The 2007 payments bill by the RBI permitted third parties to perform clearing &amp; settlement, opening up the field for different models to evolve.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">It may take several years or decades for dominant universal standards to emerge as in the case of card  and cheque payments, unless banks and operators can quickly converge organically and create a new payment association for these “new” or “alternate” payments.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">This might also be a market with several closed group service offerings that co-exist and link with the existing payment franchises, bridging the banked with the unbanked, and the low ticket size with the high ticket size transaction sets.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">A key turning point however could be if a third party or even the regulator were to recognize the opportunity and define a set of standards, as in the case of cheque clearing, which is then followed by all. </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">6. The Regulatory Opportunity</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Though the government and regulator may not be in a position to directly participate in the establishment of an electronic payments infrastructure, it can play a more influential role in catalyzing and spurring innovation in new payment mechanisms including mobile-based payments.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Governments and financial regulators across the world have influenced the usage and acceptance of electronic payments with positive impact on their economies. The most influential and noteworthy has been the initiative of the South Korean government. With the primary objective of curbing the large flow of cash in the underground economy and huge losses in tax collections, consumers were incentivized with tax rebates to make purchases using cards along-with threatening retailers not accepting card payments with tax audits.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">This has resulted in electronic payments in excess of over USD 250 billion (compared to around USD 18 billion in India), comprising over half of all private consumption related payments, being settled via credit card payments in South Korea.  Similar incentive approaches also adopted in Argentina, Uruguay and Colombia where rebates are offered against VAT for card payments.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Hence the potential avenues for the regulator:</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">a. Extend the purview of electronic payments to include non bank issued accounts</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Electronic payments are currently dominated by payments emerging from bank issued credit &amp; debit cards, where the source of funds include the funds held in the bank account or credit lines extended by issuers.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">With an explosion in mass transport projects spanning toll, metro, taxi and bus services, and the RBI circular of August ’09 having laid the foundation for widening the scope for issuance of prepaid instruments by non-banking entities including transit operators, service providers or even mobile operators, requires the expansion of the term electronic payments</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Considering their vital role played in converting cash to an electronic mode, related cost savings and audit trails, the case for their inclusion is sound. Hence payments via multiple modes issued by non-banking entities such as transit or mobile operators should be considered for inclusion within the ambit of electronic payments.</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">b. Extend Tax rebates to consumers for all payments made via electronic modes</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">A tax rebate may be extended to consumers, proportionate to the value of electronic payments made on an annual basis. This would create a compelling and universal incentive to for migration from cash.</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">c. Identify focus sectors for electronic payment acceptance</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Payments towards utilities, government taxes and tourism could be three sectors in which additional focus and incentives may be explored</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">d. Incentives to retailers and service providers accepting electronic payments</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Though the South Korean and other International models have focused only on incentivizing consumers, the coupling effect of extending benefits to retailers as well would only be exponential. Tax rebates via VAT or GST could be options that could be examined.</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">e. Expand The Payments Ecosystem</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The Reserve Bank of India has made significant strides in expanding the stakeholders that can participate in the payments ecosystem, beyond traditional banking institutions.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"> </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The regulators initiatives in opening out critical elements of the payments value chain over the last couple of years is encouraging and affirmative.</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The foundation has been set for a new wave of payment systems to emerge and grow in India. As India enters the new decade, the 180 million cards and 500 + mobile phone connections offers a unique opportunity to mould the payments landscape and stimulate growth. A greater focus and stimulus at this juncture would only provide a stronger platform to fuel growth in the formal economy in the next decade.</span></span><br /></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a0e6104423e411d9a0aa49a39948eda5" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/E8CT92pJTC0/hunger-redefined.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size:85%;"><br /></span><ol style="font-family: verdana;"><li><span style="font-size:85%;"><strong>25,000 lives are lost every day </strong>from hunger and poverty; even a bad case of diarrhea can lead to death because of weakness caused by hunger<br /></span></li><li><span style="font-size:85%;"><strong>More than 800 million people know what it feels like to go to bed hungry</strong>; most of them women and children<br /></span></li><li><span style="font-size:85%;"><strong>Malnutrition causes more than half of all child deaths.</strong><br /></span></li><li><span style="font-size:85%;"><strong>Poor families     spend over 70% of their income on food.</strong><br /></span></li><li><span style="font-size:85%;"><strong>More than 100 million     children are stunted physically and mentally from malnutrition</strong>,     wrecking their chances for a good education and productive future</span></li></ol><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">On this bright Sunday, as you set out for a sumptuous lunch and an afternoon siesta, may I request you to kindly put your grey cells together and think once again how the banking and finance communities can re-engineer and make a difference...</span></span>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f020e90751512d4cc20f2cd295a03494" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/FVvsvdE4JpE/american-express-labs.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;"><a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SOOptUSOGAI/AAAAAAAAANQ/dbGarhZRz-I/s1600-h/US_en_H_AmexLabs.gif"><img style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer;" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SOOptUSOGAI/AAAAAAAAANQ/dbGarhZRz-I/s320/US_en_H_AmexLabs.gif" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5252228186448467970" border="0" /></a><span style="font-family: verdana;font-size:85%;" >I am simply in awe of American Express Labs. Its been around for a while now, but for several reasons believed that this was perhaps time to present and analyse the same.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: verdana;font-size:85%;" >For those who are new to the concept...</span><span style="font-family: verdana;font-size:85%;" ><span style="font-style: italic;">"Our mission is to highlight the important ways that innovative new products and services from American Express continue to improve the Cardmember experience. By showcasing innovative pilot programs and highlighting opportunities for Cardmembers to receive access to emerging technologies and innovative applications before they are made available to the public, we are providing a framework for understanding the trends and developments impacting the future of innovation."</span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: verdana;font-size:85%;" > They've tried out some rather neat stuff including Virtual agents that guide you through the website or the very cool "Entertainment Access spotlight" which has posts on updates in the entertainment scene and even an introduction to their mobile access application.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: verdana;font-size:85%;" >Customers are invited into the beta versions and participate in the trials and usage of the various service offerings. This is quite distinctive as they have pulled it off quite well and its heartening to see that there is a clear pipeline of innovations that they have committed to.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: verdana;font-size:85%;" >Equally amazing is the fact that they have veered from the beaten path and have attempted to blend into the lifestyles of their customer segments, rather than approaching the conventional "hardsell" route. Also believe that they have created a platform that is fairly credible and consistent with the brand experience. They've also not adopted the classical "I'm there on facebook / myspace" 2.0 approach, which lacks the punch, and the brands look rather out of place.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: verdana;font-size:85%;" >Looking forward to more exciting stuff from the folks at American Express... </span><br /></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9ca1fb8c78c0a9cfd6ba4d7dbecd5867" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/IPJn1r3bELM/electronic-payments-in-india-looking.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-family: verdana;font-size:85%;" >Have </span><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">authored a document on Electronic Payments in India recently.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: verdana;">The document is available on pymnts.com at the following link</span><br /><br /><a style="font-family: verdana;" href="http://www.pymnts.com/electronic-payments-in-india-looking-back-and-surging-forward/%3Fhpb">http://www.pymnts.com/electronic-payments-in-india-looking-back-and-surging-forward/%3Fhpb</a><br /><br /><span style="font-family: verdana;">Look forward to hearing your views and feedback</span></span>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a30c8a0bc88e78fe3166483584d1fda8" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/jYroebo7naE/its-crunch-time-for-mobile-banking-in.html"><![CDATA[<div  style="text-align: justify;font-family:verdana;"><span style="font-size:85%;">The Reserve Bank of India has updated the <a href="http://www.rbi.org.in/Scripts/bs_viewcontent.aspx?Id=1660">Mobile Banking Guidelines</a>. You would recollect that the draft had been published a few months back, and most decisions had come to a standstill as solution providers and banks awaited the final version.<br /><br />A transaction cap of Rs. 2.500 per txn and Rs. 5,000 per customer per day is one of the highlights. It would also be interesting to see the guidelines issued by some other central banks inc</span><span style="font-size:85%;">luding the S<a href="http://www.sbp.org.pk/search/results.asp?cx=002167901857236840991:v55i2sdnxfs&amp;cof=FORID:11&amp;q=%20mobile%20banking#1174">tate Bank of Pakistan.<br /></a><br />This is a significant milestone offering banks and solution providers a broad framework to move forward. We should see several initiatives being launched over the course of the year, now that this release is out.<br /><br />However, as I've stated several times earlier as well, mobile banking applications and standards in itself would not be able to serve the larger objectives of inclusion if aspects of interoperability and financial inclusion regulations are not addressed quickly. The Mobile Payments Forum of India, triggered by IRDBT is a move in that direction</span><span style="font-size:85%;">, but perhaps a more authoritative and direct participation by the RBI and the government would provide the necessary boost to make this a reality.<br /><br />A <a href="http://wordle.net/gallery/wrdl/201303/mobile_banking_guidelines">wordle</a> depiction of this article for your humour below...<br /><br /></span><a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SNZl5Q3pCuI/AAAAAAAAAMw/TQaIxCcfzQg/s1600-h/Picture+6.png"><img style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer; width: 393px; height: 251px;" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SNZl5Q3pCuI/AAAAAAAAAMw/TQaIxCcfzQg/s320/Picture+6.png" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5248494450202184418" border="0" /></a><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><br /></span> </div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="277819274c891db31cdfa163e1d752d3" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/KRrE97fgB-I/conscience-lives.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;"><a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://bp3.blogger.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SHeouD5-B-I/AAAAAAAAAI0/o_6OaY1z29U/s1600-h/teachindia.gif"><img style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer; width: 162px; height: 41px;" src="http://bp3.blogger.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SHeouD5-B-I/AAAAAAAAAI0/o_6OaY1z29U/s320/teachindia.gif" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5221827802235275234" border="0" /></a><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family:verdana;">Over 10,000 volunteer registrations in 72 hours, offering their time, skills and energies in teaching the underprivileged children of India. An initiative launched recently by the Times of India, one of India's leading media houses, inviting volunteers to teach!</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family:verdana;"><br />In these days of inflation, work stress, challenging careers and chronic blood pressure amongst professionals, it was heartening to note the enthusiasm with which men and women from all walks of life have taken that first step towards giving back to society.<br /><br />It quite obviously displays the need for a credible "brand" in giving that crucial spark to the inertia that lies within all of us! And yes, I have finally taken that plunge, and urge you do the same. Its never too late!<br /><br />I also await the day when wallets and purses shall be opened to offer money as micro-loans to small economic enterprises that await to flourish. The conscience is alive, but awaits a "brand" to start the fire!<br /></span></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f69073fa8b82f4399b1b81940171c1e8" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/lQslXnV8KiQ/for-love-of-apple.html"><![CDATA[<a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/S2msVa27dAI/AAAAAAAAAR0/U7II9Nlbunk/s1600-h/ipad.jpg"><img style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer; width: 95px; height: 70px;" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/S2msVa27dAI/AAAAAAAAAR0/U7II9Nlbunk/s200/ipad.jpg" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5434063909386155010" border="0" /></a><br /><div style="text-align: justify; font-family: verdana;"><span style="font-size:85%;">Have been an Apple convert for over three years now. It's possibly one of the leading consumer marketing organisations of the decade, if not the century.<br /><br />Came across an article on pymnts.com " <a href="http://pymnts.com/apple-and-the-dawn-of-i-commerce-2//?tsc">Apple &amp; the Dawn of I-Commerce</a>", and the author's predictions ...<br /></span><ul><li><a href="http://pymnts.com/search/amazon" target="_blank">A<span style="font-size:85%;">mazon</span></a><span style="font-size:85%;"> will be selling the iPad before Christmas regardless of the future of the <a href="http://pymnts.com/search/Kindle" target="_blank">Kindle</a>.</span></li><li><span style="font-size:85%;"><a href="http://pymnts.com/search/Google+Wave">Google Wave</a> will find its real footing not on Nexus One but on the iPad</span></li><li><span style="font-size:85%;">Independent multi-media producers will distribute their content outside of studio control, directly on a "iMarketplace" within three years</span></li><li><span style="font-size:85%;">Netbooks will disappear from the retail shelves by 2011 and be replaced by a variety of slate devices running Windows 7.</span></li><li><span style="font-size:85%;">The iPad will become a video calling mobile device by the time 4G networks are reliably deployed</span></li><li><span style="font-size:85%;">The next iteration of the AppleTV (let's call it iTV), rumored for 2011, will interact with the iPads, iPods and iPhones to extend the viewer's experience across multiple screens simultaneously.</span></li></ul><span style="font-size:85%;">Further quoting the author... <span style="font-style: italic;">"For all we know a year from now </span><a style="font-style: italic;" href="http://pymnts.com/twitter-vet-jack-dorsey-on-why-square-is-what-s-next-in-payments?art" target="_blank">Square</a><span style="font-style: italic;"> will introduce an enhanced version of its service and card reader for the iPad (let's call it "Cube") to provide low end merchants with POS functionality up to now reserved for systems integrated with a cash register.</span></span><span style="font-style: italic;">"</span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><br />Time will tell if the above predictions indeed do materialise, but would be keen to see if Apple can actually revolutionalise the alternative and core payments space....<br /></span><br /></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="db2454b56068680ff6ea2045ddacf1d0" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/mJbXdC-fOvY/speeding-time-to-market.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Hey...I've been out of action for a while...working on some new blogs and other initiatives...anyways...back in action..</span></span><br /><br /><div style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Came across a Cap Gemini Report on...</span></span><br /><ul><li><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Speeding Time to Market..</span></span></li><li><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Increasing Time in Market...&amp;</span></span></li><li><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Maintaining Market Velocity...</span></span></li></ul><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Its not an outstanding report, but quite often makes sense to revisit the basics. The strategic imperative of reducing product development cycles and accelerating time to market has been much written. The paper attempts to quantify the revenue impact of achieving the above strategic goalsa<br /><br />Do browse through it and perhaps revisit some of your businesses and product initiatives....<br /><br />To read the report click <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/redirect?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww%2Ecapgemini%2Ecom%2Fresources%2Fthought_leadership%2F%3Fd%3DC81FAA6A-A300-301A-8693-5C41190B62DA&amp;urlhash=nx0l">here</a>...<br /><br /><br /></span></span></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c281c743b7ee0b479f09a633289f2b72" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/NRzPEGZYZqs/payments-alone-may-not-pay-bills.html"><![CDATA[<span xmlns=""> <br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;"><span style="font-size:85%;">I came across an enterprising man who worked as a driver and doubled up as the neighborhood</span> <span style="font-size:85%;">milkman. In the initial months,</span><span style="font-size:85%;">he found himself collecting and carrying large amounts of money on a daily basis, which became quite unwieldy with his day job. To make matters worse, with outstanding dues, leakages in collections and a host of challenges posed with managing currency, he often wondered if in fact he was making any profits in this enterprise. </span></span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">A benevolent aunt stepped in and helped him open a bank account in a new age bank. Now armed with a debit cum ATM card, he ventured into this mysterious world of electronic banking and soon adopted a device called the 'ATM'. Though 24 hour access was the dominant benefit, the ATM allowed him to experiment and learn with his banking relationship without the risk of 'social embarrassment' in a branch. </span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;"><span style="font-size:85%;">The ATM was soon his new business ally, allowing him to make currency deposits, print mini statements, place requests for cheque books and a host of other essential features that helped run his business. It was his business ledger and he would brave it into the branch once a month to take a detailed printout for the month, tallying the</span> <span style="font-size:85%;">deposits and withdrawals! </span></span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">I'm not particularly sure if the founders and generations of bankers thereafter had conceived of such benefits, but this enterprising entrepreneur did indeed create some for his use. In an interesting twist however, in this journey, he still hasn't ventured out to use his debit cum ATM card for making over the counter purchases at retail stores! He just doesn't get it! </span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;"><em>"Why should I use a card, when I have cash in my wallet?" </em></span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;"><em>"Why should I use a card, when I know I may spend more than I should?" </em></span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">His bank, in the meanwhile, has been pounding him with offers of reward points for using his debit card for POS purchases! </span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">With a debit card population crossing the 200 million mark in India, the industry continues to be challenged with low levels of usage at POS. Furthermore, with a host of new age mobile based banking, payments &amp; transfers services available &amp; being introduced by leading players, it makes one think! </span></p><br /><ol><br /><li><br /><div style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;color:#948a54;">Should more be done to increase the adoption of these new age payment systems? </span></div></li><br /><li><br /><div style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;color:#948a54;">What is the role of banks &amp; Financial Institutions in the payments space in driving adoption of electronic payments? </span></div></li></ol><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">This appears to be a challenge spanning socio-economic segments. PhD yielding professors and rickshaw pullers seem to resonate similar questions! </span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">Hence, though the challenge is universal, is the solution necessarily singular? </span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">The conventional methods of driving adoption of electronic payments, may be broadly classified into the following three categories : </span></p><br /><ol><br /><li><br /><div style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="color:#948a54;">Legislation &amp; Financial Incentive </span>: The South Korean model wherein card based payments are mandatory for tax breaks </span></span></div></li><br /><li><br /><div style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="color:#948a54;">Convenience &amp; Safety </span>: The classical advantage of using plastic. No need to carry cash (and spend money you don't' have!) </span></span></div></li><br /><li><br /><div style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="color:#948a54;">Scarcity</span> : MPesa, launched in a financial environment that didn't offer a semblance of a reliable transfers network. </span></span></div></li></ol><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">When one operates in an environment of 'Scarcity', then the need for safety and trust are sufficient! </span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">But how would it work when alternatives are available? Here…cash is good! It's worked for centuries, and no reason that it won't for the ones coming up as well. </span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">As a significant proportion of future growth would emerge from populations that lie below the affluent &amp; mass affluent segments, there is a need to understand and define solutions that address their need states and socio economic environment. Furthermore, one needs to bring in a wave of fresh thought even for those customer segments that we have been addressing in the past. </span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;"><span style="font-size:85%;">The challenge that lies ahead for those in the payments industry is to </span><span style="font-size:85%;">think beyond</span> <span style="font-size:85%;">transaction processing and move towards designing solutions in a segmented manner. Why should financial institutions even consider this approach in a more aggressive manner. Well, let's do a reality check!</span></span> </p><br /><ol><br /><li><br /><div style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="color:#948a54;">Margins are dropping</span> : We've all seen what's going on with Interchange in North America. The wave should sweep the globe in mature markets soon </span></span></div></li><br /><li><br /><div style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="color:#948a54;">Who's grabbing the value in the value chain?</span> : Non Banking institutions appear to be raking in the revenues in what was conventionally deemed to be the domain of banks &amp; FIs, as in the case of MPesa </span></span></div></li><br /><li><br /><div style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="color:#948a54;">Dropping ticket sizes</span> : It makes immense sense to make 1.1 % on a USD 50 transaction, but not as much on a 50 cents transaction. </span></span></div></li><br /><li><br /><div style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="color:#948a54;">Brands v/s commodities</span> : We all know that brands command a greater premium vis a vis commodities. Would intermediate value added service providers come in and rule the roost? </span></span></div></li><br /><li><br /><div style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="color:#948a54;">We don't need Reward Points!</span> : The new consumer lying near the bottom of the pyramid may not find the tried and tested approaches of reward points sufficient enough to switch behavior. </span></span></div></li></ol><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;"><span style="font-size:85%;">There appears to be a tenable economic argument or justification for banks to consider going down the path of value</span> <span style="font-size:85%;">creation. </span></span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">What next? Well, banks &amp; FIs may do well in investing greater resources in enhancing both the experience and value generated in the payment process, often the last leg in the buying process. Some brands have however made some interesting forays that should inspire others. </span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">Visa had launched 'Rightcliq' in 2010, allowing consumers to shortlist products online and seek feedback from their social networks. This, as a service was made available for non-customers of Visa products as well. Subscribers could also use non – Visa cards to make purchases! </span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">American Express labs had set out on that journey, potentially reaching out to customers and going further back in the purchasing and selection behavior prior to the end payment state. </span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">The fundamental shift lies in the fact that both these brands and a few others have realized the need to develop segmented solutions that address aspects in the buying process, that venture further up the value chain, much beyond the actual act of making payments. </span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">Now, let's head back to the milkman. What would be a sufficient stimulus or trigger point for him to use debit cards for over the counter purchases. Reward Points? May be..or perhaps: </span></p><br /><ol><br /><li><br /><div style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">A discount coupon sent via an SMS with every swipe? Hence demonstrating the economic impact of using a debit card vis a vis cash? </span></div></li><br /><li><br /><div style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">An alert informing him how much he could have earned on bank interest if only he had not withdrawn a large amount of funds at the beginning of the month and used his debit card prudently for purchases through the month. Also, how much he could have saved by availing discounts from bank issued offers. </span></div></li><br /><li><br /><div style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">Offer him additional airtime if he were to purchase talk-time with his debit card </span></div></li><br /><li><br /><div style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">Escrow systems &amp; Micro-credit: Establish a promise to pay between a trader and a buyer via the mobile for a pre-defined period. On maturity, the seller receives the due amount. The buyer however continues earning interest on the balance till the date of debit! This could also be an interesting take on EMI payments </span></div></li><br /><li><br /><div style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">Group Buying &amp; Pooling : Groups often purchase items in a collective format to avail discounts, or even pool in together for gifting purposes. Could a pooling system be enabled, allowing each of the group members to make payments to the local retailer, allowing the retailer to track the payments received and the customers in availing the benefits. </span></div></li></ol><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">Though there is clearly no scarcity in creativity, a significant nudge is required in the fundamental shift required for payment service providers. </span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">Could these be services that could be charged? Why not? If the bank can establish a comprehendible and coherent value proposition, why not? </span></p><br /><p style="TEXT-ALIGN: justify"><span style="font-family:Century Gothic;font-size:85%;">The migration to electronic payments would surely need to offer solutions to daily problems and needs of the larger populace. We really need to move past reward points! </span></p></span>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="df0cbc3bac4f6e74a6877e8fce3e4a65" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/q1CELsizYCU/operative-guidelines-for-mobile-banking.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">This is a landmark event in India. The regulatory body has taken the first step in outlining guidelines for mobile banking in India. Targeted at banks and financial institutions that fall within its ambit, the draft document is simplistic at times, but does reinforce the intent.<br /><br />The need and objectives are fairly obvious, and would have preferred some finer details. I'm perhaps left asking more questions than answers being questioned.<br /><br />But, to be fair to them, this domain is a fairly complex confluence of multiple industries and technologies, and they would do well in defining the ground rules in what I call the "banking &amp; finance" layer.<br /><br />If you'd like to read the report click <a href="http://www.rbi.org.in/scripts/BS_PressReleaseDisplay.aspx?prid=18432">here</a><br /></span></span>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="939f92b7b904bac654e27f7ff946843d" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/rgh-QqrMR4w/silver-lining.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;"><a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://bp3.blogger.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SGqB1C2rh5I/AAAAAAAAAIc/c6-bvVGAa68/s1600-h/silverlining.jpg"><img style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer;" src="http://bp3.blogger.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SGqB1C2rh5I/AAAAAAAAAIc/c6-bvVGAa68/s320/silverlining.jpg" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5218125866561406866" border="0" /></a><span style="font-family: verdana;font-size:85%;" >Recession, hyperinflation, stagflation, economic downturn, liquidity crunch, rate hikes, budget optimization, cost cutting, increment minimization, stock market crash, loan defaults, frozen assets, price corrections, declining demand, over supply, margin pressure, rising oil prices, climbing delinquencies, accelerating rentals, sub prime crash, declining valuations, price corrections, dropping sales.................</span><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family:verdana;"><br />It's been a fairly eventful ninety days for the global economy. In these stimulating times, I posted a question on Linkedin enquiring " <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/answers/management/change-management/MGM_CMG/259270-6680756?browseIdx=0&amp;sik=1214936913613&amp;goback=%2Esrp_1_1214618058911_in%2Evpf_25989667_0_5JGjMtIQYVZN0ByG1vMVtF8gR91hldvhkR1jz4QdA4Ocjh6cQoVczsSdzAUejkO_NAME*4SEARCH_1214618058911_Arvind_Mediratta%2Eamq">Is there ever a recession period for innovation?</a>" It was a fairly unanimous response as would be expected. </span></span><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family:verdana;">The underlying theme was in the need for organizations to constantly inculcate and catalyze an innovation culture. </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family:verdana;"><br />However the key challenge remains in how an organization can allocate resources and investments in non-proven "innovations" when the chips are down. A few thoughts that I have on the same when the chips are down ....<br /><br />a. Get out of the Board Room : Often notice that more meetings are called during the downturn. It may help to spend some time with your customers. An unexpected dialogue can often result in a new economic value equation<br /><br />b. Back to Basics : It's not very surprising that a large portion of your customers have forgotten some key benefits or propositions of your offerings. A little repackaging, new medium or an alternate channel might just do the trick!<br /><br />c. The Core : Review and be open to redefining your core competencies, re-evaluate your core strengths and recognizing the latent value of your assets.<br /><br />d. Partnerships &amp; Speed :   Leverage shared services platforms and white labeling options for introduction of new services. Evolve performance based cost models, if required to protect your outflows and ensure incremental margins.<br /><br />These models would enable you to minimize your cost outflows and investments, yet allowing you to generate incremental value!<br /><br />e. Change Currency : Barter can be your new currency, give it a thought.....<br /><br />Will leave the rest for the innovation experts............<br /><br /></span></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a458b94cd6b1c87597dc5c9a801163a" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/rp3LGAM2l60/of-icons-defaults.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;"><a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SMVb_4bu3wI/AAAAAAAAAKA/zwXaa3zM_dI/s1600-h/jamesdean.gif"><img style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer; width: 105px; height: 106px;" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SMVb_4bu3wI/AAAAAAAAAKA/zwXaa3zM_dI/s320/jamesdean.gif" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5243698494181400322" border="0" /></a><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">An iconic brand is a legacy that most marketers would like to bequeath to the world. A brand that builds a strong relationship over the customer life-cycle and consistently delivers value at various life stages, yet retaining its charm and appeal allowing customers to clearly express their personality in a distinctive manner!<br /><br />The last decade has been an excitingly turbulent one for financial services brands, driving a roller coaster of emotions for consumers alike. These brands have expanded the market, taking risks of market expansion in their stride and expanding the customer base. Having providing a financial identity to several customers and enhancing the expenditure appetites, the players have successfully fueled the growth of a wide array of industries including the housing, travel and retail fashion sectors.<br /><br />These brands were viewed as the "dream merchants" that not only showed you the dreams, but actually financed them. Instant loan approvals, cashbacks, rock bottom rates and flexible pricing structures were the darlings of every consumer from New York to New Delhi!<br /><br />With the collapse of the housing markets across the globe, the meltdown in the financial services space has commenced with rising defaults across all formats of secured and unsecured lending. With the nationalization of Freddie and Fannie, the mortgage majors that fueled the palatial dreams of millions, the market has really turned a corner.<br /><br />The dream merchants are now perceived as the vultures, as banks and financial institutions are calling in the loans, raising rates or pushing the envelope on the collection engines to curb delinquencies and quell defaults. </span></span><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The monthly statements carrying special offers and treats have now proven to be the messengers of evil debits. </span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"><br />In these trying times, wherein economic survival is in itself the prerogative, how should financial services brands' retain their vigour and connect with their customers? For customers facing challenges in loan repayments, these brands may find it increasingly tough in retaining their emotional connect and relevance.<br /><br />So, is it really possible to retain the inconic "dream merchant" status even during and post recessionary trends for customers. And moving to an even more pertinent question, do we have brands in the financial services space that are truly iconic! Where lie the Cokes and Apples of the financial services world?<br /><br />It is often viewed that lending is a "serious" business and meeting consumers financial needs is the stuff of "serious" brands. American Express, Wells Fargo, ABN AMRO, RBS have hit the list of the worlds 100 top brands, but yet again "iconic" fervour is not something that comes to mind too often in their association.<br /><br />Where arst thou James Dean?<br /></span></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="15bd363687360a91911be81f42fcb0c4" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/SnS2STblIXw/next-big-thing.html"><![CDATA[<a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SGXwpQ0K6YI/AAAAAAAAAIM/XLECAj8q4ao/s1600-h/wave.jpg"><img style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer; width: 125px; height: 93px;" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SGXwpQ0K6YI/AAAAAAAAAIM/XLECAj8q4ao/s320/wave.jpg" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5216840335057676674" border="0" /></a><span style=";font-family:verdana;font-size:85%;"  >Over the last couple of weeks have been catching up on innovations and trends in mobile telephony, entertainment, gaming and a few others...</span><br /><div style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-family:verdana;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><br />One gets the impression that we are perhaps noticing an "innovation deceleration" in the banking and financial services space!<br /><br />With the introduction of and advances in </span></span><span style="font-family:verdana;"><span style="font-size:85%;">Internet banking, ATMs, mobile payments, electronic fund transfers, smart cards, real time gross settlement systems etc., in the recent decades, you may believe the above remark is over critical! innovation in the banking and financial services space is hindered by :<br /></span></span><span style="font-family:verdana;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><br />a. Legacy Systems : Infrastructure and standards developed decades back may not easily permit the introduction of new generation financial products and payment services. Large migration costs make the business case for large spread introduction of new services challenging if not impossible.<br /><br />The introduction of EMV in the UK recently requiring retailers and financial institutions alike to incur millions of dollars in costs would be a recent example<br /><br />b. Adddressing New Customer Segments : One of the key challenges faced in enhancing the spread and penetration of banking and financial services to the bottom of the pyramid includes the account management and transaction costs in existing systems made unviable for low ticket sizes. Grameen has developed a new system ground up, but action awaited from global vendors on this front<br /><br />c. Regulators : The central banks and other regulatory bodies are faced with the onerous challenge of advancing the use and penetration of "non cash" based services with the overbearing need to protect customer interest and finances. This often leads to large time spans for the introduction of new regulations on subjects including mobile payments.<br />Reliance Industries can construct a petrochemical complex in 30 months!.... whereas governing bodies can take a similar period in publishing a draft paper<br /><br />Moore's law does not obviously apply in this space, and nor should we expect it. But quite clearly a need and an opportunity for the grey cells to kick in and business leaders to converge on the above.<br /><br />The Revolution card is a recent example which questions the way in which we do business and puts forth a new paradigm. The need for new open platforms and standards that can support interoperability and rapid introduction of new products and services is even greater.<br /><br />Which leads me to the question of the hour...which is the next ala "iphone" or "facebook" waiting to happen in this space? Would welcome your views....</span></span><span style="font-family:verdana;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><br /></span></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e82ec97f94671ee3da02d667cb793f9b" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/uxlfgXHF-_o/carbon-redefined.html"><![CDATA[<a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SE_8aLviOeI/AAAAAAAAAH8/E2hkZmZf50o/s1600-h/carbon_logo.gif"><img style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer; width: 147px; height: 69px;" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SE_8aLviOeI/AAAAAAAAAH8/E2hkZmZf50o/s320/carbon_logo.gif" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5210660820649916898" border="0" /></a><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">I had written a <a href="http://futureredefined.blogspot.com/2008/05/green-redefined.html">post</a> recently on how banks can go Green. Subsequently came across  a great site where you can estimate the carbon emissions in your daily life.<br />Interestingly Nectar has offered its infrastructure in a pilot project wherein customers' carbon credits would be deducted with every fuel purchase at British Petroleum. This of course is a pilot, but a critical step in enabling all of us to measure and and contribute back to the environment.<br /><br />Given a few years of evolution, banks can perhaps permit individuals to trade in carbon credits once the metrics set in<br /></span></span>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f741b10e89e294751a8564c0b997c499" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/Z5HdznyAlY4/innovations-trends-in-payments-gazing.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;"><a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/S1xvYcROrgI/AAAAAAAAARE/YH2GYliIpzc/s1600-h/crystalballgazing.jpg"><img style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer; width: 80px; height: 100px;" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/S1xvYcROrgI/AAAAAAAAARE/YH2GYliIpzc/s200/crystalballgazing.jpg" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5430337716397977090" border="0" /></a><span style="font-size:85%;">The decade gone by has been a fairly exciting &amp; tumultous for the world in the realms of retail finance. Banking penetration has exploded, card payments continue to flourish in the developed and developing economies, the mobile remains the talk of the town, Internet as a significant enabler for access and transaction transmission is becoming a reality.</span><br /></div><span style="font-size:85%;"><br />The impact of electronic payments on economic growth has been proven repeatedly. Coupled with explosion in new frontier financing including microfinance, the onus on retail payments to grab the opportunity and leap frog remains.<br /><br />However, giant unconventional leaps has not been the hallmark of the banking industry, which has typically believed in incremental and linear innovation and adoption. Regulation, economics, trust and sunk investments have stymied innovation and rebellious outbreaks from the non banking sector. However, as we gaze into the crystal ball, what lies ahead in the next decade might just surprise us<br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold;">1. Micropayments Go Electronic </span>: Paypal laid the path and led the charge in the last decade. The Internet made switching costs for micro-payments an economically viable reality, ensuring no compromise on the transactional trust in the process. Mobile, transit, prepaid, contactless, biometric and a host of other applications and approaches is going to make this the decade of "Electronic Micropayments"<br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold;">2. Microfinance Goes Into Course Correction </span>: The excitement over microfinance is palpable and understandable. A few institutions in this space have reached large scale and even gone public. Repayment rates appear to remain stable across Asia, Africa and Americas, with low delinquencies.<br /><br />The challenge for microfinance is going to be in processes, talent, scaling profitably and increasing regulation. MFIs need to brace for regulators &amp; governments placing caps on interest rates &amp; charges, covering the potential customer delinquency risk caused by droughts, famines and other natural disasters. New portfolio and risk management techniques would need to emerge quickly to enable MFIs to steer clear from a significant market correction.<br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold;">3. Debit &amp; Prepaid Card Payments Explode</span> : Asia will lead the charge on debit usage. As debit card platforms open out for remote payments, an increasing number of customers will benefit from the convenience of using card payments and differentiate from the credit extension facilities offered by credit based instruments. Coupled with an increasing familiarity with prepaid payment concepts and exploding acceptance channels, both formats would soon overtake credit. <span style="font-style: italic;">( Am sure this one is open for much debate!)</span><br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold;">4. Card Acceptance Gets Cheaper </span>:  POS &amp; ATM devices have almost bottomed out on their price curve, and card acceptance services leveraging </span><span style="font-size:85%;">the mobile or its connectivity would make card acceptance drastically cheaper. Card issuance across mag stripe and chip would continue to dominate the payments landscape, hence reliance and need for card acceptance infrastructure and devices would remain.<br /></span><span style="font-size:85%;"><br /><span style="font-weight: bold;">5. Credit Scores Go Global</span> : As the global workforce moving across geographies gains scale, sharing of credit scores across boundaries will become a reality. So dont be surprised if your FICO follows you to your next assignment in Venezuela!<br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold;">6. Domestic Payment Networks Proliferate</span> : Global economies will establish and adopt domestic payment networks along the lines of NETS &amp; China Union Pay, to create  a more cost effective &amp; flexible payments DNA.<br /><br /><span style="font-weight: bold;">7. Payments Get Tax Rebates</span> : Increasing number of nations will incentivise electronic payment usage to counter parallel grey economies and money laundering activities<br /><br />Lets connect in 2020 and see where we stand.<br /></span>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ab1e40ccf6e5f790fa109ffd06691043" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/zfPDqcbOQ9o/decades-12-greatest-developments-in.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">Pymnts.com recently published a listing of the Top 12 developments &amp; trends in the Payments Industry over the last decade.<br />(There's been a deluge of lists published over the last couple of months, but this one is quite a decent analysis)<br /><br />Key Excerpts below:<br /><br /></span></span><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><strong>#12 AmEx Goes Global</strong></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><a href="http://pymnts.com/search/american+express?blg" target="_blank">American Express</a> transformed itself from a largely American go-it-alone card company into a global network with 128 bank partners in 127 countries (based on its 2008 10-k) including the United States. <a href="http://www.pymnts.com/the-decade-s-12-greatest-developments-in-payments-12-amex-goes-global/?art" target="_blank"><strong>Read the full post here</strong></a></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><strong>#11 How the World War on Interchange Fees Transformed the Card Industry</strong></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;">A global war on <a href="http://www.pymnts.com/how-regulation-impacts-the-payments-industry/?blg" target="_blank">interchange fees</a> raged during most of the decade and will continue into the next. We'll have to wait until next decade to find out who wins the war. But the war itself has already led to massive ramifications for the card business around the globe. <a href="http://www.pymnts.com/how-the-world-war-on-interchange-fees-transformed-the-card-industry/?art" target="_blank"><strong></strong></a></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><strong>#10 Collateral Damage from the Financial Crisis: Consolidation and Regulation</strong></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;">The CARD Act has transformed the card business in the United States and that's why it is number 10 on my list of the great developments in the card industry in the last decade along with the further consolidation that resulted from the crisis. <a href="http://www.pymnts.com/the-decade-s-12-greatest-developments-in-payments-10-collateral-damage-from-the-financial-crisis-consolidation-and-regulation/?art" target="_blank"><strong></strong></a></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><strong>#9 Shanghai Surprise</strong></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;">The fact that in a decade China has achieved such rapid growth of the card business and expanded globally is remarkable. As always, China has both opened up a vast new market and unleashed new competitors onto the global scene. <a href="http://www.pymnts.com/9-shanghai-surprise/?art" target="_blank"><strong></strong></a></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><strong>#8 The Mag Stripe Lives On</strong></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;">Some of the greatest developments in the last decade were the failure of massive efforts to displace the humble magstripe card. It is also serves as a reminder that innovations in payments have to make people and merchants significantly better off to gain traction. <a href="http://www.pymnts.com/8-the-mag-stripe-lives-on/?art" target="_blank"><strong></strong></a></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><strong>#7 How the ACH System in the U.S. is Encouraging Electronic Payments Innovation</strong></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;">A major factor in what you might call the greening of the payments industry has been the growth of the Automated Clearing House (ACH) system for directly debiting and crediting depository accounts. <a href="http://www.pymnts.com/how-the-ach-system-in-the-us-is-encouraging-electronic-payments-innovation/?art" target="_blank"><strong></strong></a></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><strong>#6 What Has a Bigger Head and Longer Tail? Card Issuing</strong></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;">Its head has gotten bigger and the tail longer and skinner. I'm not talking about a scary monster but about the distribution of purchasing volume for the credit and debit card issuers in the United States. <a href="http://www.pymnts.com/what-has-a-bigger-head-and-longer-tail-card-issuing/?art" target="_blank"><strong></strong></a></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><strong>#5 Innovation Driven by Prepaid Cards</strong></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;">The use of prepaid cards has exploded during the first decade of this century and they have enabled many types of payment innovation from whipping through transit lines to helping disaster victims to transferring money to mom in Mumbai. <a href="http://www.pymnts.com/innovation-driven-by-prepaid-cards/?art" target="_blank"><strong></strong></a></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><strong>#4 The New Kid on the Block: PayPal</strong></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;">Starting a new payment system is incredibly difficult. Many try, few succeed. MasterCard and Visa did it in the 1960s. No one did it in the 1970s at least in the US. Sears brilliantly did it with Discover in the 1980s. The 1990s was a miss. For this decade the only company that entered the exclusive club of major payment systems was PayPal. <a href="http://www.pymnts.com/the-new-kid-on-the-block-paypal/?art" target="_blank"><strong><br /></strong></a></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><strong>#3 Debit Takes the Plastic Throne in the U.S.</strong></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;">Debit cards helped make prepaid card possible and may lead to significant changes in banking relationships if decoupled debit cards take off. Debit cards have led to an enormous change over the decade in how Americans use plastic. <a href="http://www.pymnts.com/debit-takes-the-plastic-throne-in-the-u-s/?art" target="_blank"><strong><br /></strong></a></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><strong>#2 The Marriage of Mobile and Payments Make the World a Better Place</strong></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;">Mobile illustrates just how this industry can drive progress and really make the world a better place. I also think that it is a harbinger of a revolution that will take place over the next decade. <a href="http://www.pymnts.com/the-marriage-of-mobile-and-payments-make-the-world-a-better-place/?art" target="_blank"><strong><br /></strong></a></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;"><strong>#1 MasterCard and Visa Go Public</strong></span></p><div style="text-align: justify;"> </div><p style="font-family: verdana; text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size:85%;">MasterCard and Visa emerged as publicly traded financial powerhouses after four decades of working for associations of banks. Their transformation marks a radical shift from the past and will most likely define the shape of the payment ecosystem for decades to come. </span><a href="http://www.pymnts.com/the-decade-s-12-greatest-developments-in-payments-1-mastercard-and-visa-go-public/?art" target="_blank"><strong><br /></strong></a></p></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1744b6cfb04cdf67f25fb97ede1a233b" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/_ErUKvBJUBw/future-is-brightthe-future-is-here.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;"><a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SXH8McyZ-7I/AAAAAAAAAOs/gJxLwYPvLts/s1600-h/barclays"><img style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer; width: 160px; height: 106px;" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SXH8McyZ-7I/AAAAAAAAAOs/gJxLwYPvLts/s320/barclays" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5292288327953284018" border="0" /></a><span style="font-family: verdana;font-size:85%;" >My first blog post in over 3 months had to be something remarkably refreshing...which perhaps kept me out of action this long.<br /><br />Barclays has launched a 8,000 sq ft state of the art bank branch in Piccadilly, London, quite recently. Serving their high net worth as well as local business clients, the truly high tech branch breaks new ground as it</span><span style="font-size:85%;"> is sprinkled with a host of high tech gadgetry including Microsoft surface.<br /><br />Click <a href="http://www.newsroom.barclays.com/content/detail.asp?ReleaseID=1483&amp;NewsAreaID=2">here</a> to read more about it....<br /><br />In these times of recession and gloom, truly great brands and organisations would seek to innovate and revitalise their customer relationships. Touche to Barclays!<br /></span></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /><br /><div style="text-align: justify;"><a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SXH75NypKmI/AAAAAAAAAOk/5m8nEahT5RM/s1600-h/barclays2"><img style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer; width: 67px; height: 102px;" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SXH75NypKmI/AAAAAAAAAOk/5m8nEahT5RM/s320/barclays2" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5292287997510232674" border="0" /></a> </div></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="de42a22e4202beecc5586f0c66537e0f" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/FutureRedefined/~3/_ozso8CxJ8M/resilience.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;"><a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://bp0.blogger.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SItgTn4lzXI/AAAAAAAAAI8/EmmTWDL68tg/s1600-h/resilience.jpg"><img style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer; width: 139px; height: 96px;" src="http://bp0.blogger.com/_d7vFnDp3GZM/SItgTn4lzXI/AAAAAAAAAI8/EmmTWDL68tg/s320/resilience.jpg" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5227377682733714802" border="0" /></a><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">This blog has been set up with clearly defined objectives, but must make an exception today.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"></span></span><br /><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;">The city of Ahmedabad has been rocked by over 16 bomb blasts today, and this just a day after serial blasts rocked Bangalore. India was also witness to the gruesome bombing in the cities of Jaipur and Hyderabad earlier this year. I happened to be in Mumbai when several bomb blasts crippled the city several years earlier.<br /><br />However there is one common thread across the social fabric that  I've noticed across these mega metro cities - Resilience!<br /><br />Inspite of the most gruesome attacks and the fear that lurks post such terrorist strikes, the citizens have always prevailed and proceed with life as usual. The dedication to work, inherent belief in the democratic values and faith that normalcy shall prevail, has always resulted in these cities rolling into full swing immediately.<br /><br />There are two schools of thought. The first believes that we've become insensitive and cynical and hence we go on. The other school of thought believes that people shall not bow and staying back home results in a recognition of victory for the terrorists. I'm a member of the latter.<br /><br />May god bless the families of those who have lost their loved ones!<br /></span></span><span style="font-size:85%;"><span style="font-family: verdana;"></span></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>