<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="www.richwriting.com/blog">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="e95a9a6c790ecb95e46cf15bee517651" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RichWriting/~3/0qYJF9th_jA/"><![CDATA[It had to end. Just like we&#8217;ve all experienced that heart-thumping moment of Oh! You&#8217;re the ONE! &#8212; We&#8217;ve also shared the emotional let-down of, Ooooh, I guess not. So, tell us about it in this week&#8217;s writing prompt: I knew it was over when&#8230; Just post your love-gone-south story in the Comments section after [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bc360cfbafc39970587547215162f0db" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RichWriting/~3/2SylCI9ftC4/"><![CDATA[How do you meet people? Believe&#8230;Feast&#8230;Thank. 1.  Chatter: Social media is not going away. Now’s the time to figure out how to make it work for you. Don’t have a lot of “friends” or “connections” yet? Don’t worry. Finding special interest groups is one way to build your network. You’ll expand your connections more quickly [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="19e71144c50a8b9160b3f0955e906fce" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RichWriting/~3/53ov1am7x3o/"><![CDATA[It&#8217;s true: Marketing your book is hard work. With more than 3 million titles published in 2010 (including self-published and mainstream), there&#8217;s a lot of competition. It&#8217;s hard to get noticed by the media, and just as challenging to engage new readers. But it can be done, and Shel Horowitz hung out with Susan Rich [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="21d4af9021a174f61b884606c74d9e42" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RichWriting/~3/7D689_iIf6E/"><![CDATA[This is mine. One of the challenges most reluctant writers face is describing their business – what they do, how they help – to their target market. They know – you know – that you can explain it live. So how come you can’t transfer talk into words? If this sounds like you, you need [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="28a45eb2460899763d709ca00ddbb665" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RichWriting/~3/8asQWA5Astw/"><![CDATA[But first, let&#8217;s talk about your vision board. You do have one, right?Mine is tucked away on a shelf in my closet, but after chatting with Steve Gamlin, I think it&#8217;s time I created a new one. Steve uses his vision board as a daily reminder of all the dreams he wants to achieve. So [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a0c0712a6a351f85d9f5757e9fff8946" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RichWriting/~3/8HxquqEbHqw/"><![CDATA[FEM Factor!Weekdays, on Susan Rich Talks Join internet radio show host Susan Rich, the get-you-noticed-now marketing pro 8 am PT / 11 am ET every weekday morning for your daily dose of the FEM factor: Fascinate. Educate. Motivate. For the week of January 30:  Monday: Living the Writing Life – Our guest is guerrilla marketing [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="626726ba8d34d15d02b6d043c55fe691" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RichWriting/~3/R1gXg2Yrd78/"><![CDATA[It could be your version of Puss &#8216;n Boots. Or how you were adopted by a half-starved stray who marched into the house like she owned the place. (That&#8217;d be my story! And that&#8217;s &#8220;Butterscotch&#8221; in the picture.) Maybe you want to write about the first time you laid eyes on a lion at the [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2cb473e0f102e2e4a40aa3006e412ae4" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RichWriting/~3/wnaI_T4GpRM/"><![CDATA[Your first love. &#160; It doesn&#8217;t matter if we&#8217;re 6 or 60, that heart-rush comes to us all. Sometimes it lasts&#8230;and sometimes it&#8217;s yesterday&#8217;s news before the paper is even printed. That&#8217;s what this week&#8217;s writing prompt is: Give us 100 words about your first love &#8211; that boy or girl who carried your heart [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="29be1d18806a098a487d9ab229692f7a" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RichWriting/~3/YCgL8rzx5bI/"><![CDATA[5 days, 5 shows, pure fun Susan Rich, the get-you-noticed-now marketing pro and journalist-blogger, talks daily on internet radio station w4wn.com. Join her 8 am PT / 11 am ET every weekday morning for your daily dose of the FEM factor: Fascinate. Educate. Motivate. For the week of February 6, 2012: Monday: Living the Writing [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="111e17b8fdad0d0a280bf89c36fa4fcc" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/RichWriting/~3/ZDQkq-hUqEc/"><![CDATA[Write 100 words, maybe win a prize. Aren&#8217;t dogs amazing? That&#8217;s what we talked about this morning on Susan Rich Talks&#8230;Living the Writing Life. Our guest today was Charmaine Hammond, author of On Toby&#8217;s Terms. And in honor of her remarkable best friend, we&#8217;ve got the perfect prompt for dog lovers (or haters) everywhere: Write [...]
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>