<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="blog.cleantech.com">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="60b818a61955f9a13b7733011c2ba0ae" url="http://blog.cleantech.com/cleantech-investments/data-center-innovation-clean-cost-effective-reliable/"><![CDATA[<p>We are currently seeing a wave of new ideas in data centers, throwing the traditional model of data center management in the air. The ever accelerating demand for processing and data storage capacity globally, is coming together with environmental demands to create an area ripe for innovation.</p>
<p>This led to lively discussion last week at our <b><i>Data Centers Power Breakfast</i></b>, in partnership with Silicon Valley Bank and Wilson Sonsini Goodrich &#38; Rosati. Participants &#8211; including tech companies, start-ups and investors &#8211; proved data centers can reposition themselves as sustainability leaders and pointed to opportunities for even greater innovation through energy efficiency and greening the energy supply.</p>
<p>We were particularly interested in what was driving innovation in the data center sector. There was a simple mantra from the panelists throughout the conversation: solutions needed to be <b>clean, cost-effective and reliable</b> to gain market traction.</p>
<p>We know that over the last decade or so, environmental stewardship has become a C-Suite goal, leading companies to set challenging but attainable <b>clean</b> goals. Even for companies for whom sustainability is not a central characteristic of the product or service, customers, particularly Millennials, are holding them more accountable on environmental metrics.</p>
<p>To attain these goals, &#8230;</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="67f5059e797ed156fd4c3f4ab20d081d" url="http://blog.cleantech.com/cleantech-investments/obama-executive-order-triple-renewable-energy-usage/"><![CDATA[<p><em>[originally posted on <a href="https://joinmosaic.com/blog" target="_blank">Mosaic's blog</a>]</em></p>
<p>President Obama used to campaign on his theme of hope and change.  Despite numerous political hurdles and geopolitical events that have diverted his attention since his 2008 election, it can proudly be said that the president has taken another step towards bringing about positive change. In his second State of the Union address, President Obama lifted the hearts of environmentally-conscious people everywhere with his bold statement “For the sake of our children and our future, we must do more.  But if Congress won’t act soon to protect future generations, I will. I will direct my Cabinet to come up with executive actions we can take, now and in the future, to reduce pollution, prepare our communities for the consequences of climate change, and <a href="http://joinmosaic.com/future-of-clean-energy" target="_blank">speed the transition</a> to more sustainable sources of energy.”  Though the rhetoric was there, actual change was certainly slower in coming to fruition.</p>
<p>Today, President Obama issued an <a href="http://assets.nationaljournal.com/pdf/131205_EOenergymanagement.pdf" target="_blank">executive order</a> (bypassing the inefficiency of Congress) to mandate that the federal government (including the military) triple its use of renewable energy by 2020, at which point renewable power would provide 20 percent of the government’s energy.</p>
<p><strong>Setting a good example</strong></p>
<p>According to &#8230;</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5912fce6b90939566fbe0677dd6a8b7b" url="http://blog.cleantech.com/cleantech-investments/one-bed-one-dream-some-learnings-from-the-2013-china-cleantech-tour/"><![CDATA[<p>November 3-8 I had the honor and pleasure of leading Cleantech Group’s 3<sup>rd</sup> <a href="http://www.cleantech.com/china-tour-2013/" target="_blank">annual Cleantech Tour of China</a>, an intense week of activities to help 13 companies and investors meet key players in China, to learn about the market and to think through potential entry strategies and partners. Over the week we met with over 100 organizations. Had I written a summary letter to the group, summarizing the experience and the learnings, this is what it might have looked like.</p>
<p>Dear 2013 Tour Party Members, (representatives of <a href="http://www.advenira.com/" target="_blank">Advenira</a>, <a href="http://www.bowmanpower.com/" target="_blank">Bowman Power</a>, <a href="http://www.electranovacapital.com/" target="_blank">Electranova Capital</a>, <a href="http://enlightedinc.com/" target="_blank">Enlighted</a>, <a href="http://www.eon.com/en/about-us/innovation/strategic-co-investments.html">E.ON (Strategic Co-investments)</a>, <a href="http://www.generationim.com/" target="_blank">Generation Investment Management</a>, <a href="http://www.idinvest.com/en/" target="_blank">Idinvest Partners</a>, <a href="http://www.nexsteppe.com/" target="_blank">NexSteppe</a>, <a href="http://www.svb.com/" target="_blank">Silicon Valley Bank</a>, <a href="http://www.solvoltaics.com/" target="_blank">Sol Voltaics</a>, <a href="http://www.solexant.com/" target="_blank">Solexant</a>, <a href="http://www.sunfire.de/en/kreislauf/power-to-liquids" target="_blank">sunfire </a>and <a href="http://vandynesuperturbo.com/index.html" target="_blank">van Dyne Superturbo</a>)</p>
<p>I think you just learned why it is imperative to always approach China with as open a mind as possible. Each time I take a group like you, of companies and investors, on our <a href="http://www.cleantech.com/china-tour-2013/" target="_blank">annual Cleantech Tour of China</a>, I am always struck how pre-conceptions get challenged during the week, and how much, during the week, people begin to see and appreciate how fast the market dynamics change and how different the &#8230;</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a082a01ebb3f560f774cd6cf0a46ed67" url="http://blog.cleantech.com/cleantech-investments/techbuild-buildingsusers-getting-smarter-gridium/"><![CDATA[<p><i>On January 21-22, Cleantech Group is hosting &#8212; in San Francisco &#8212; the “</i><a href="http://events.cleantech.com/buildings/"><i>Buildings Get a Brain</i></a><i>” senior executive summit on the future of intelligent commercial buildings. In the lead up to the summit, Cleantech Group is chatting with leaders across the commercial real estate space to learn more about what the rise of building innovation means for start-ups, corporates, investors, buildings, and tenants. </i><a href="http://events.cleantech.com/buildings/"><i>Click here to learn more about Buildings Get a Brain and request an invite</i></a><i>.</i></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://events.cleantech.com/buildings/buildings-get-brain-conversation-starters" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-5773" alt="newsletter_content4_122013" src="http://blog.cleantech.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/newsletter_content4_122013.png" width="186" height="233" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Tom Arnold, CEO, Gridium</em></p>
<p><b>In just a few words, can you talk a little bit more about what problem your company is solving?</b></p>
<p>We have two sides to our business. We have the buildings business and the utilities business. In both cases, we are deploying cloud-based energy analytics software. On the buildings side, there’s this explosion of data coming from smart meters and, simultaneously, big changes in tariffs and pricing programs that make your energy bill really complex. Building managers don’t know how to analyze either the data or the tariff changes. What our software does is basically derive new sets of diagnostics and analytics from that data. Its data they already have but it’s trapped in a messy &#8230;</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="153fbfa95f21bf2f228a3c1c214da25" url="http://blog.cleantech.com/cleantech-investments/the-power-of-wind-energy/"><![CDATA[<p>Compared to conventional wind farms, high altitude wind technology can harness kinetic energy with 5x greater capacity factors, allowing for highly scalable electricity production (thanks to the cube of velocity at high altitudes). While first imagined as a source of useful energy back in the 19<sup>th</sup> century, airborne wind technologies such as floating wind turbines, aerostats, sailplanes and kites are still imagined as nascent discoveries. Yet we are seeing high altitude wind manufacturers achieving more traction in the US as well as Europe and especially in Germany, the Netherlands and Italy. Moreover, corporate and strategic players across the globe seem keen to invest in and be engaged with high altitude wind companies.</p>
<p>In Germany, for example, <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/skysails-gmbh-co-kg"><b>Skysails</b></a><b> </b>received<b> </b>€15 million from <b>DSM Venturing</b> in 2010 and has since implemented both a towing kite technology for the shipping industry and an offshore-based kite power generation system. Additionally, Kite wind innovator <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/nts-energie-und-transportsysteme"><b>Nature Technology Systems (NTS)</b></a><b> </b>received $1 million in 2012 from the multinational technology corporate, <b>3M</b>, and the German bank, Kreditanstalt für Wiederaufbau(KfW).<b> </b></p>
<p>Dutch producer of autonomously controlled glider planes tethered to ground-based generators, <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/ampyx-power"><b>Ampyx Power</b></a><b>, </b>has received capital from several international institutions and the large corporate <b>KLM Royal Dutch </b>&#8230;</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c3133486637e98d5fff2c22d50be0009" url="http://blog.cleantech.com/cleantech-investments/this-deal-matters-commercialization-of-wireless-charging-technology-for-electric-vehicles/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/witricity">W</a><img class="size-full wp-image-5742 alignleft" alt="277-1_logo_v1" src="http://blog.cleantech.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/WiTricity.jpeg" width="125" height="32" /><a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/witricity">i</a><a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/witricity">Tricity</a>, the Massachusetts-based developer of wireless energy transmission and charging technology, <a href="http://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20131205005161/en/Toyota-Licenses-WiTricity-Patent-Portfolio-Wireless-Power">announced</a> last week that it had licensed certain patents to Toyota for the development of wireless battery charging technology for the auto major’s electric vehicles. Prior to this licensing agreement, Toyota had also made an equity investment to WiTricity in 2011, to accelerate the development of such technology. This licensing agreement marks a major commercialization milestone towards the wide-spread adoption of WiTricity’s wireless charging systems. Within the same timeframe, a BMW product development executive also <a href="http://evworld.com/news.cfm?newsid=31874">announced</a> that “electrification will be a central thread” in BMW’s future product development. In addition, Audi has unveiled its electric crossover concept vehicle at the 2014 Detroit Auto Show.</p>
<p>Electric vehicle application isn&#8217;t the only market focus for WiTricity. The company’s business strategy aims to license its wireless-power technology to as many partners as possible, including sectors such as transportation, consumer electronics and industrial applications. Consequently, WiTricity also has other corporate investors that have their eyes set on this promising technology. In October of 2013, WiTricity had closed a Growth Equity round from <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/investor/intel-capital">Intel Capital</a> and <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/investor/foxconn-technology-group">Foxconn Technology Group</a>, one of China’s largest electronics manufacturers. In addition, <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/investor/general-electric">General Electric</a> was &#8230;</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d0bc095c79842f7b9d2f039f7f967ded" url="http://blog.cleantech.com/cleantech-investments/this-deal-matters-evogene-files-for-ipo/"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/evogene"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://www.anytext.co.il/image/users/118116/ftp/my_files/evogene.jpg?id=9053240" width="157" height="105" /></a> Evogene, an Israeli developer of biotechnologies geared toward developing improved plants for agriculture and biofuel industries through use of plant genomics, filed for an IPO on the NYSE on November 11. The company plans to raised $86 million and would have a market value of $412 million at the midpoint of its proposed range. Evogene has established collaborative relationships with <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/monsanto">Monsanto</a>, <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/dupont">DuPont</a>, <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/syngenta">Syngenta</a>, and <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/bayer-cropscience">Bayer CropScience</a>, showing real traction with the top players in the industry.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">While the public markets have opened up a bit, with <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/bioamber">BioAmber</a>, <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/control4">Control4</a>, and <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/silver-spring-networks">Silver Spring Networks</a> recently listing, it is still tough for companies in the areas of energy, materials, water, and agriculture to go public. However, Evogene is not the only agriculture company approaching the public markets. <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/marrone-bio-innovations">Marrone Bio Innovation</a>, a US developer of natural weed, pest and disease management products, raised $57 million on NASDAQ in its August 2013 offering.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">With Evogene&#8217;s filing, we could see even deeper interest in companies working on geed genomics for both agriculture and biofuels. To see which companies may be on the road to a public offering or could attract large venture rounds, we rounded up some of the most &#8230;</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="415975527a79b91aa56fb49d9d2aa037" url="http://blog.cleantech.com/cleantech-investments/this-deal-matters-khosla-places-big-bet-on-thin-film-solar/"><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-5734" alt="Stion" src="http://blog.cleantech.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/Stion.png" width="121" height="82" /></p>
<p>Last week, Greentech Media<a href="http://www.greentechmedia.com/articles/read/Khosla-Ventures-Takes-Controlling-Interest-in-CIGS-Thin-Film-Solar-Startup?utm_source=feedburner&#38;utm_medium=feed&#38;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+greentechmedia%2Fnews+%28Greentech+Media%3A+News%29"> reported</a> on a deal that took place quietly back in October. In a letter to creditors and shareholders, a financial services firm representing <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/stion">Stion</a>, one of the many struggling producers of Copper-Indium-Gallium-(di)Selenide (CIGS) thin film solar PV cells, disclosed that existing shareholder <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/investor/khosla-ventures">Khosla Ventures</a> had taken a controlling stake in the company and provided for &#8220;an assignment for the benefit of creditors&#8221;.</p>
<p>After conventional silicon PV markets experienced a dramatic oversupply and subsequent price crash in the past few years, thin film solar producers, which haven&#8217;t yet matched the conversion efficiency of silicon PV and so had been competing primarily on cost, found themselves unable to compete &#8212; resulting in several bankruptcies and fire sales. Khosla Ventures&#8217; investment in Stion, which had raised nearly $250 million from investors including Khosla, <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/investor/braemar-energy-ventures">Braemar Energy Ventures</a>, <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/investor/general-catalyst-partners">General Catalyst Partners</a>, <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/investor/lightspeed-venture-partners">Lightspeed Venture Partners</a>, <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/investor/avaco">AVACO</a>, and others, is a significant bet that thin film solar can still work. Time will tell, as they say, whether this bet turns out to have been a wise one.&#8230;</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bb4b35dbf3a50b7701addfae278901f3" url="http://blog.cleantech.com/cleantech-investments/this-deal-matters-sapphire-energy-partners-with-phillips-66-to-commercialize-algae-biofuels/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://blog.cleantech.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/Sapphire-Energy.jpeg"><img class="size-full wp-image-5753 alignleft" alt="Sapphire Energy" src="http://blog.cleantech.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/Sapphire-Energy.jpeg" width="200" height="49" /></a><a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/sapphire-energy">Sapphire Energy</a>, the California-based developer of algae-based biocrude oil production technology, has formed a strategic joint development agreement with Phillips 66 towards the commercialization of algae crude oil. Specifically, the two companies will work together to analyze Sapphire Energy’s renewable crude oil, with the goal of completing fuel certifications for wide scale oil refining. Given the recent resistances from opposing interest groups, including the Oil &#38; Gas sector, this collaboration between a biofuels company and an oil &#38; gas major marks another exciting milestone on the development of renewable fuels.</p>
<p>The deal is also significant in its timing, as the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) is actively proposing to lower the volumetric requirements for renewable fuels under the Renewable Fuel Standard (RFS) for 2014. Furthermore, it is also promising to see an oil major taking an active role in the commercialization efforts of renewable oils, especially given the oil industry groups’ recent petition to waive the RFS mandate. Despite the overall market opposition, Sapphire Energy has made several significant progresses in 2013, including the signing of a new commercial offtake agreement with <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/tesoro">Tesoro</a>, in addition to paying off the $54.5 million government <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/sapphire-energy/transactions">loan guarantee</a> awarded by the U.S. &#8230;</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="286d25815cd395d06b24c8c42e24380a" url="http://blog.cleantech.com/cleantech-investments/this-deal-matters-solarcity-leads-market-into-new-world-of-solar-securitization/"><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-5290" alt="SolarCity" src="http://blog.cleantech.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/SolarCity.jpg" width="131" height="45" />Despite its stock getting battered late in the week due to a bigger-than-expected third quarter loss, we believe hindsight will judge last week a good one for <a href="http://research.cleantech.com/company/solar-city/">SolarCity</a>. For us, the short-term whims of speculative day traders and hedge funds do not outweigh the significance of the company&#8217;s announcement a week ago that it was planning a private placement, worth $54 million, of debt securities backed by the cash flows of its solar projects.</p>
<p>The deal is significant as it is the first of its kind and an important step in the direction of securitization of solar generation facilities. If all goes well, it will be yet another proof point for the bank-ability of solar. Thus far, in the United States, solar project developers have raised project finance funds based on pass-through arrangements that promise the delivery of tax subsidies accrued to the solar facility, to institutional investors (typically big banks) with large tax liabilities. SolarCity&#8217;s new private placement may open the door to a plethora of private-sector pooled-asset financing vehicles including real estate investment trusts (REITs) and master limited partnerships (MLPs), that are attractive for their future cash flows, not just subsidies.</p>
<p>Across the pond in July, a &#8230;</p>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>