<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="adam-markus.blogspot.com">
	<documents count="25">
		<document id="5e1c1de5637c361e471c2866a1c164ba" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/-p7pW4jMAhE/imd-mba-admissions-essays-for-january.html"><![CDATA[IMD (The Institute for Management Development), consistently ranked among the best MBA programs in the world, is a small intensive one-year program that starts in January.  IMD, along with Columbia January Term and INSEAD (INSEAD has both September and January start dates) are three of the best options for those who want to start in January 2015 at a top MBA program.
To learn about IMD, visit the<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/-p7pW4jMAhE" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1205ec3ab41f159b1023d2c341ef24a3" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/0XhQy3cO1LY/wharton-mba-essay-questions-for-class.html"><![CDATA[
In this post, I analyze the essay questions for Wharton for Fall 2014 admission. You can find testimonials from my clients admitted to Wharton in 2009, 2010, 2011, 2012, and 2013 here.






For my most recent post on Wharton interviews, please see Preparing for Wharton Interviews for the Class of 2016.






Wharton’s essay questions have again changed.  This year’s questions are greatly <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/0XhQy3cO1LY" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a726a63202d21d104a625850cf3913b6" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/4GRI50g3-is/q-with-member-of-hbs-class-of-2014.html"><![CDATA[My former client, HBS 2014, provides great insight and strong opinions to this Q&amp;A.  HBS2014 says about himself:  "I am an international student in the HBS Class of 2014. After spending two years in Asia to finish my studies as an engineer, I started working as a consultant in Europe. I decided to apply for an MBA in the United States to bring a new perspective to my career."

———————————————————<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/4GRI50g3-is" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="73f82c03acff2b755ea8cf0bad66994" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/AQZWDchmgwE/mit-sloan-mba-essays-for-fall-2014.html"><![CDATA[In this post I will discuss the Class of 2016 MBA application admissions essays for MIT Sloan. I have taken the essay topics from the online application for 2013 admission.  You can read testimonials from some of my clients admitted to MIT Sloan for the Classes of 2011, 2012, 2013, 2014, and 2015 here.   Before analyzing MIT Sloan School of Management MBA Essays for Fall 2014, I think it is <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/AQZWDchmgwE" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d2fb8e63f45796195275fb8f8a4e9c7e" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/AzmBmzYUzEc/mock-imd-case-interview-preparation.html"><![CDATA[
While I frequently prepare clients for interviews, I don’t do case preparation interview training myself. This becomes an issue for IMD interviewees, so I am pleased to be able to refer my clients and blog readers to a Mock IMD Case Interview Preparation Course.  This service is provided by an MBA holder with extensive international business experience.  If you are interested in these courses, <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/AzmBmzYUzEc" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8abb4439f485b87b58301385b0a5bac5" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/cDWmxJegmrg/stanford-gsb-mba-essay-3-for-class-of.html"><![CDATA[This is the forth of five posts analyzing the Stanford GSB MBA Essay Questions for Class of 2016 Admission. The five posts are overall comments, Essay 1, Essay 2, Essay 3, and additional information/resume/employment history/activities. My analysis of Stanford GSB interviews can be found here. In addition to the C   lass of 2016 posts, I also recommend reading and/or listening to my presentation,<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/cDWmxJegmrg" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5f501604da7c4a792260d9258e342edd" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/Cepho1Gt-DA/london-business-school-fall-2014-mba.html"><![CDATA[
In this post I analyze the London Business School’s MBA admissions essay questions for the Class of 2016. Thinking about London Business School reminds me of the strength of the alumni network, the quality of its academic research, its core competencies in finance and international business, the intensity of its campus community, and the emphasis that LBS puts on active student involvement <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/Cepho1Gt-DA" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ff6a59f18e23cd5160d8ed7b7ac830ad" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/dLe8BcAo0yM/preparing-for-wharton-interviews-for.html"><![CDATA[In this post, I discuss how to prepare for Wharton Interviews for fall 2014 entry. My post on Wharton's essays for the Class of 2016, can be found here. 

There are two parts to the Wharton interview, the team-based interview and one-to-one interview.  Each part can be prepared for. I am assuming anyone who is reading this post has actually been invited for a Wharton interview and has reviewed <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/dLe8BcAo0yM" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="735c1d4023f2d8671a7810fb523f5443" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/eDJNt2TsMW4/new-mba-scholarship-at-stern-for.html"><![CDATA[During my visit today with Alison Goggin, Senior Director of MBA Admissions at Stern, she mentioned that Stern has just launched a full-ride scholarship program for undergraduate applicants to the MBA program. This looks like an amazing opportunity for exceptional candidates. If you are a senior in college with an exceptional background, I think the William R. Berkley Scholarship Program is <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/eDJNt2TsMW4" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b3ce2a8ef909a61153db8a3e3c8805a2" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/EDp7Zai145c/kellogg-mba-essays-for-class-of-2016.html"><![CDATA[In the post, I analyze Northwestern University’s Kellogg School of Business 2014 Application Essay Questions for the MBA and MMM programs. I have taken the questions from Kellogg’s website.

By the way, I had five clients admitted to Kellogg’s MBA Class of 2015.  You find can my Kellogg results and client testimonials here.

Kellogg’s 2014 Essay Questions for the Class of 2016 are specifically <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/EDp7Zai145c" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5d1c6d397bdf83241328943bd32032ea" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/HD1ZqvqkMz0/waitlisted-now-what.html"><![CDATA[This is an updated and expanded version of a previous post on what do if you are waitlisted at an MBA program.

As MBA results roll in with  all their joy, pain, and annoyance have more or less emerged, some people will find themselves  admitted, others outright rejected, and others in that netherworld known as waitlist. For some, the wait will actually end relatively quickly, but for others, the<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/HD1ZqvqkMz0" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f83da5fde315e10755ee32bf2898e27d" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/iw9TpTsw0Ug/ucla-anderson-mba-essays-for-fall-2014.html"><![CDATA[In what follows, I will analyze the UCLA Anderson School of Management’s MBA Essay(s) for Fall 2014 Admission. If you want to enter the Class of 2016, you will encounter only one required essay and it is most basic of all questions.

 ACTUALLY IF YOU ARE AT ALL INTERESTED IN UCLA, APPLY!


Assuming you are working on other schools, this one should not take particularly long. A few years ago, UCLA<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/iw9TpTsw0Ug" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4688fd4f8cf2764ea713f4c361b2edd2" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/JX5d0kwqC0U/chicago-booth-2013-2014-mba-application.html"><![CDATA[This post is on the University of Chicago Booth’s MBA application essays for 2013-2014 admission to the Class of 2016. The University of Chicago is a very intellectually serious place.  Booth reflects that culture. Not everyone who goes there is an intellectual, but most are quite smart.  Your objective is to show you understand yourself, understand what you want to do in the future, and <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/JX5d0kwqC0U" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6cfb0d14373a5e1571330b82d4e90ef6" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/KtJjLB_poEM/class-of-2016-stanford-gsb-essay-2-what.html"><![CDATA[This is the third of five posts analyzing the Stanford GSB MBA Essay Questions for Class of 2016 Admission. The five posts are overall comments, Essay 1, Essay 2, Essay 3, and additional information/resume/employment history/activities. My analysis of Stanford GSB interviews can be found here. In addition to the Class of 2016 posts, I also recommend reading and/or listening to my presentation, “<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/KtJjLB_poEM" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5be0976f0a9d734d82902e868a04f624" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/lIoftX7-swQ/mit-sloan-on-road-presentations.html"><![CDATA[If you are planning to apply to MIT Sloan and can’t visit the campus,  I do recommend attending one of the their Sloan-on-the-Road Presentations.  These tend to be popular (I know Tokyo maxes out each year), so I do recommend registering early. See the complete events schedule here.



-Adam Markus

  I am a graduate admissions consultant who works with clients worldwide. If you would like to <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/lIoftX7-swQ" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f42525c228bd0ac57f5ebd5a2f6ace10" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/MUeno4DqKx8/harvard-law-school-llm-program.html"><![CDATA[Harvard Law School has announced the LL.M. Program deadlines:
“For the LL.M. class beginning in September 2014, the application deadline is December 1, 2013. (We strongly encourage all application materials be submitted by November 15, 2013.)”

The application form has not been updated yet, but based on the deadline and materials page, it appears that nothing will likely change from last year. <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/MUeno4DqKx8" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f76f3934c1ac4d80d504c666ddc75745" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/R2HWOjc-IzA/haas-mba-class-of-2016-admissions.html"><![CDATA[This is how I started my Haas essay analysis last year: “Haas always asks weird questions. Years ago, they asked who the applicant would invite to dinner and why. Last year, it was “What brings you the greatest joy? How does this make you distinctive? ” Each year brings some new weirdness. Hence their song remains the same.”
Indeed, I am right, but this time the song really remains the same <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/R2HWOjc-IzA" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="dbdf739fe891655ad5db07008072b5e9" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/r2so01EkTj4/q-with-member-of-ross-mba-class-of-2013.html"><![CDATA[My former client, Ross2013, is a Japanese American. After working in Tokyo at a global software company for 6 years as an engineer, he joined the Full Time MBA program at the University of Michigan Ross School of Business. Post-graduation, he will be joining a top consulting firm at its Chicago office. You can find his first-year Q&amp;A here.

—————————————————————————————————————————————


Adam: <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/r2so01EkTj4" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="136ebf5999addf019524c997b6e2e086" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/trU4NIX0FBQ/q-with-member-of-london-business-school.html"><![CDATA[My former client, MBA2014 is Japanese. He worked in Tokyo in Investment Banking for four years as a credit trader He received MBA sponsorship from his company and joined the MBA program at London Business School in August 2012.

—————————————————————————————————————————————

Adam: What parts of the London Business School program have you liked the most? The least?


MBA2014: Flexibility is the <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/trU4NIX0FBQ" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5b60bca8d123200c725a80ce06488933" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/w55ksW87HV4/new-york-university-stern-mba-essays.html"><![CDATA[
In this post I analyze NYU Stern MBA program’s essay questions for fall 2014 Admission. Those applying for the Class of 2016 will find that they only have to write two essays this year. NYU has cut the essay down from 3 to 2 essays, but the essays themselves are unchanged from last year.

New York University Stern School of Business MBA essay questions’ web page also includes great tips which <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/w55ksW87HV4" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d8aacbd396b4fbeb4a0be17aa1f3c771" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/Wz_EtauCwvE/mit-mba-class-of-2016-deadlines-earlier.html"><![CDATA[As part of the trend of ever earlier admissions deadlines, MIT Sloan, which always had a later MBA Round One  admission deadline than its rival institutions, has joined the trend. Here are the deadlines:
  
  
MBA Program Deadlines – For August 2014 Entry
  
  
    MBA Round I  MBA Round II  
  Applications must be submitted by 3:00 p.m. ET  Tue, September 24, 2013  Tue, January 7, 2014  
  The <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/Wz_EtauCwvE" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bb7b18bd9d29fc6eaf07e1b0b682cbda" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/xd3xw_yn18o/stanford-gsb-additional-info-resume.html"><![CDATA[This is the fifth of five posts analyzing the Stanford GSB MBA Essay Questions for Class of 2016 Admission. The five posts are overall comments, Essay 1, Essay 2, Essay 3, and additional information/resume/employment history/activities. My analysis of Stanford GSB interviews can be found here. In addition to the Class of 2016 posts, I al   so recommend reading and/or listening to my presentation,<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/xd3xw_yn18o" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6893a82d2975d9a55470a563a9bb2997" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/ysiPxSyxN2M/the-hbs-class-of-2016-mba-application.html"><![CDATA[
Dee Leopold just announced (30 May 2013)  the full application deadlines and key application components on the From the Admissions Director blog. I will post my full analysis of the entire application after its release, but I wanted to provide an immediate reaction to what is a dramatic change:

This is the only "essay" question:



"You're applying to Harvard Business School.  We can see your <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/ysiPxSyxN2M" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5f44589917b0dad6c0e48e4e72ba3296" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/ytkk_S8Gkfw/q-with-member-of-insead-class-of-july.html"><![CDATA[My former client, Singy 2013, is a management consultant with 8 years experience, joining straight after graduating from a national university in Tokyo.  He had no experience working/living outside Japan before INSEAD. Singy 2013 provides some really great advice below. 
—————————————————————————————————————————————

Adam: What parts of the INSEAD program have you liked the most? The least?

<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/ytkk_S8Gkfw" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="520eb4d6410af21bae089c7481d05106" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~3/yVNJ3UYBSww/dartmouth-tuck-mba-essay-questions-for.html"><![CDATA[In this post I analyze the Tuck School of Business at Dartmouth MBA Application Essay Questions for Academic Year 2013–14 (Class of 2016). Tuck is great school in a small town. This is both its strength in terms of forming a close knit community and weakness in terms of being a location that some find unattractive. Sometimes when I talk to clients and mention Tuck, I know immediately that I made <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AdamMarkus/~4/yVNJ3UYBSww" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>