<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="theeducatedsociety.com">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="295fd72572d3f4cc9d8d1ecbbff842d2" url="http://theeducatedsociety.com/a-divided-public-2012-pdk-poll-on-public-education/"><![CDATA[Uncertainty and disagreement characterized a large portion of the general public&#8217;s attitudes toward education issues, according to the recent 2012 Phi Delta Kappan&#8217;s annual Gallup poll. Among the major highlights, the public is divided about whether: Teachers should be evaluated based on student standardized test scores (52% favor; 47% opposed) Parents should receive vouchers to [...]<div align="right"><div class="sharexyWidgetNoindexUniqueClassName"><div id="shr_28558754"></div></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9f9aa55ee4f17d1cc388768ab4fe12e9" url="http://theeducatedsociety.com/a-socially-conscious-orientation-in-education/"><![CDATA[No matter our ideology, education will always be closely linked with a nation&#8217;s economy. We saw a ramping up of science and math education during the Sputnik era in the 1950s-1960s, another call for rigorous standards when fears emerged about international competition from Japan (and Germany) in the 1980s. Of course, the past decade has [...]<div align="right"><div class="sharexyWidgetNoindexUniqueClassName"><div id="shr_24943896"></div></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="cf735b504d4bb2e69cd85b36e98001e2" url="http://theeducatedsociety.com/book-review-the-new-political-economy-of-urban-education/"><![CDATA[&#160; This article was originally published in Education and Urban Society (Jan. 2013, Vol 45, Number 1, pp. 163-165).  Who owns public goods? Conventional wisdom supposes that tax-paying citizens do, via the stewardship of elected officials. Education, housing, and transportation all fall into this category and are thus considered nonexcludable (no one can be effectively [...]<div align="right"><div class="sharexyWidgetNoindexUniqueClassName"><div id="shr_46267408"></div></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3be61f7441b7a0a31ca7db56c648312b" url="http://theeducatedsociety.com/edu-philanthropists-dangerous-zero-sum-game/"><![CDATA[I don&#8217;t think education philanthropies like the Gates Foundation are conspiring to &#8220;buy schools,&#8221; as some critics think. Nor am I against school choice. For that matter, I don&#8217;t care for bloated teachers unions, either. But, as an education researcher, I am wary of their increasing interest in K-12 education over the past ten years. Frederick [...]<div align="right"><div class="sharexyWidgetNoindexUniqueClassName"><div id="shr_5947052"></div></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8c0f02f08a9369c30b2bf48f79c0f7f5" url="http://theeducatedsociety.com/new-yorks-teacher-evaluation-system/"><![CDATA[New York State education officials and the local teachers&#8217; union reached a deal on a new teacher evaluation system on Thursday February 16, just before Gov. Andrew Cuomo&#8217;s deadline for imposing his own measures for teacher quality. Essentially, 40 percent of teachers&#8217; evaluations will be measured by students&#8217; performance on standardized test scores, half of [...]<div align="right"><div class="sharexyWidgetNoindexUniqueClassName"><div id="shr_96385565"></div></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="197a7f0fa114e6197d807176e1acce41" url="http://theeducatedsociety.com/richard-rothstein-how-to-fix-our-schools/"><![CDATA[Richard Rothstein, research associate at the Economic Policy Institute (EPI), has written a lucid article on How to Fix Our Schools, which I have reprinted in its entirety below. Essentially, he asserts that education reform is more complicated than the accountability reformers would have you believe, and he happens to be right on point. Enjoy. [...]<div align="right"><div class="sharexyWidgetNoindexUniqueClassName"><div id="shr_95021837"></div></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4d9b84a793213ee6ec043a11bdcee1dd" url="http://theeducatedsociety.com/the-impact-of-demographics-on-21st-century-education/"><![CDATA[This article was originally published in Society (May/June 2013, Vol. 50, Issue 3). The final publication is available at link.springer.com The National Academy of Sciences’ (2007) report, Rising Above the Gathering Storm, called for more scientific and technical innovation to maintain America’s economic growth and vitality. Countless other reports over the past few decades have all [...]<div align="right"><div class="sharexyWidgetNoindexUniqueClassName"><div id="shr_57186552"></div></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fc0130dcce9ccd7016cb1d4e51458ceb" url="http://theeducatedsociety.com/the-long-term-impact-of-early-childhood-education-on-student-outcomes/"><![CDATA[Does going to a high-quality early education program help young disadvantaged children do significantly better at the age of 28? That is the question Reynolds, Temple, Ou, Arteaga, &#38; White sought to answer in their comprehensive 2011 study of the Child Parent Center (CPC), an early childhood-based intervention program in the heart of Chicago&#8217;s high [...]<div align="right"><div class="sharexyWidgetNoindexUniqueClassName"><div id="shr_34199532"></div></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="22a1455c74ca79c9ad3f005dbdaeafc9" url="http://theeducatedsociety.com/the-most-valid-and-reliable-teacher-assessment/"><![CDATA[What&#8217;s the point of performance-based teacher evaluations? A few years ago, one of my former graduate professors casually suggested, &#8220;Let the children grade the teachers. It&#8217;s just as reliable as any out there now if not more.&#8221; Intellectually, it made no sense: students, especially young ones, can&#8217;t possibly know what makes an effective teacher. Their [...]<div align="right"><div class="sharexyWidgetNoindexUniqueClassName"><div id="shr_24546156"></div></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="54e66b48447cf3c9372f249c1183a8" url="http://theeducatedsociety.com/what-can-we-learn-from-the-one-percent/"><![CDATA[Instead of deriding the one percent as being out of touch with the rest of us, maybe we can learn something from them&#8211;like how to improve our children&#8217;s educational success. Dr. Sean Reardon, a Stanford professor of education and sociology, believes that high-income parents are enriching their children&#8217;s educational opportunities, from the day they are [...]<div align="right"><div class="sharexyWidgetNoindexUniqueClassName"><div id="shr_75690129"></div></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>