<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="65-XX" url="feeds.feedburner.com/Animal-World">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="93e6756e72963e46b0f426b7884b1263" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Animal-World/~3/9R7cuslj2xY/"><![CDATA[<p>A true clownfish and a Percula clownfish at that!</p><p>The post <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed/true-percula-clownfish-sunny-newcommer-animal-world/">True Percula Clownfish A Sunny Newcomer on Animal-World</a> appeared first on <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed">Dr. Jungles Pets and Animal Speak</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="34aa9c33d66269a43436f1853e296372" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Animal-World/~3/B-jTPxjcvx4/"><![CDATA[<p>Cool Pets! Reptiles&#8230; the Fascinating World of Lizards, Snakes, and Turtles The sighting of a reptile captures everyone&#8217;s attention! These are the most bizarre and curious of all the land dwelling creatures, and also some of the most adorable of the aquatic creatures. Like other terrestrial animals they evolved from creatures of the sea, but [&#8230;]</p><p>The post <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed/cool-pets-reptiles-lizards-snakes-turtles-tortoises/">Cool Pets! Reptiles&#8230; lizards, snakes, turtles and tortoises</a> appeared first on <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed">Dr. Jungles Pets and Animal Speak</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="793a15d9de6f67c8d76df8f5e2240809" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Animal-World/~3/c7Enm9Vp2iM/"><![CDATA[<p>The top 3 guard dogs!</p><p>The post <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed/top-3-guard-dogs/">The Top 3 Guard Dogs</a> appeared first on <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed">Dr. Jungles Pets and Animal Speak</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="22d7164334165ad45d37edf58dd416b" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Animal-World/~3/cRECy4BIlis/"><![CDATA[<p>Coral Spawning! I bet this is something new to you!</p><p>The post <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed/making-babies-year-coral-spawn-event/">Making Babies! Once a Year Coral Spawn Event</a> appeared first on <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed">Dr. Jungles Pets and Animal Speak</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="20129cc6e48ede615fdba2dc3b06315b" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Animal-World/~3/K6oKnl0-qIQ/"><![CDATA[<p>Here is a little information on some good small pets for apartments.</p><p>The post <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed/5-best-pets-small-spaces/">5 Best Pets for Small Spaces</a> appeared first on <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed">Dr. Jungles Pets and Animal Speak</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ed2db631e797b80135136fd3f2ca1f3" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Animal-World/~3/LdlXPXgampc/"><![CDATA[<p>Are you looking for new ways to contain your dog or give your dog more freedom? Here's some ideas!</p><p>The post <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed/fenced-keep-dog-safe-free/">Fenced In: How to Keep Your Dog Safe and Free</a> appeared first on <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed">Dr. Jungles Pets and Animal Speak</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3502fd45d95f39db8d80bc8577611d08" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Animal-World/~3/vUfcOzwdBPQ/"><![CDATA[<p>Today is Animal World Day! Take time to celebrate!</p><p>The post <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed/celebrate-world-animal-day-2014/">Celebrate World Animal Day 2014</a> appeared first on <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed">Dr. Jungles Pets and Animal Speak</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="cf752cac543c0e43a6cf5f8bdad16070" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Animal-World/~3/VZsY_reJe7k/"><![CDATA[<p>The Chinchilla is one of my all-time favorite pets! I had several of them over the years.</p><p>The post <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed/chinchilla/">The Chinchilla</a> appeared first on <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed">Dr. Jungles Pets and Animal Speak</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d6707a5c913dcdd36ee9bb73f6d6529e" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Animal-World/~3/WOEMU51dZj4/"><![CDATA[<p>Happy Holidays! Wishing you a festive holiday season and a very happy new year! Our world is filled with so many fascinating creatures &#8211; pets, animals and people! Each one has a different path in life, but no matter where we go we find a little of each other. Peace, love, acceptance and joy are [&#8230;]</p><p>The post <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed/happy-holidays-seasons-greetings-2013/">Happy Holidays, Season&#8217;s Greetings 2013</a> appeared first on <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed">Dr. Jungles Pets and Animal Speak</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2de07f6317d486cf07b3fd4bc86727f" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Animal-World/~3/_dnWtc6l_m8/"><![CDATA[<p>My Quick LinksAfrican Grey CongoAfrican Pygmy HedgehogAfrican Side-necked TurtleAlbino CoryAltum AngelfishAmerican CurlAmerican Pit Bull TerrierAppaloosaArapaimaArizona Desert KingsnakeBlack Moor GoldfishBlack Wood TurtleBorder CollieChevron TangColor Bred CanaryComet GoldfishDiscus FishEastern Gray SquirrelEastern RosellaElectric Blue Jack DempseyEmperor ScorpionFour-Eyed FishFrench BulldogGiant Clams - Hippopus and Tridacna ClamsGouldian Finch Harlequin MacawHimalayan RabbitLeather Coral FactsMalabar PufferMalayan Aqua FernMarine - Saltwater FishMetalic Blue [&#8230;]</p><p>The post <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed/whos-hungry-human-smorgasbord-flesh-eating-piranha/">Who’s hungry? A Human Smorgasbord for Flesh-eating Piranha!</a> appeared first on <a href="http://animal-world.com/newsfeed">Dr. Jungles Pets and Animal Speak</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>