<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="therealshelli.com/blog">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="8fe670ecceeea40a26520f77a13f4584" url="http://therealshelli.com/2011/11/29/how-to-create-your-own-influencer-outreach-campaign/"><![CDATA[Do you know how to reach your Influencers? A one-to-one social media marketing campaign (sometimes called an influencer outreach campaign) enables brands toconnect with influencers, promotes authentic conversations about a brand or product and empowers influencers to use their social media standing to tell their audience about goods/services they love/hate or feel indifferent about. Influencer [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=therealshelli.com&#038;blog=32495796&#038;post=1857&#038;subd=simplyshelli&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bbe9ffe13f54c8610aec8cbb5e9446e4" url="http://therealshelli.com/2012/03/05/tactics-for-pages-switching-to-the-new-facebook-timeline/"><![CDATA[As you no doubt already know, Facebook has enabled Timeline for Pages. While tactics should never be substituted for stratgy, I&#8217;d like to provide you with a list of changes that you will need to address during the big switch and things you can do to make your transition a success. Choose Your Cover Photo [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=therealshelli.com&#038;blog=32495796&#038;post=2079&#038;subd=simplyshelli&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="150564891ba055ece848d618fccd0c7a" url="http://therealshelli.com/2012/04/19/tweetchats-are-fun-even-for-the-luddites/"><![CDATA[Last night I had the opportunity to participate in #TGTaste &#8211; a tweetchat with Thirsty Girl and Chateau Ste Michelle. It was a blast! I love Tweet Chats when they&#8217;re done well. They have the power to connect brands, bloggers, influencers and potential fans. This was definitly a successful chat. The best part? I rarely [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=therealshelli.com&#038;blog=32495796&#038;post=2081&#038;subd=simplyshelli&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b7922891683a1f5238797b6d924195d8" url="http://therealshelli.com/2012/08/02/social-media-marketer-youre-doing-it-wrong/"><![CDATA[Social media marketers of the world I have one request. Please, stop to think about whatever it is you&#8217;re doing and ask yourself how your actions will be interpreted by those you are marketing to. Remember, just because you CAN do something doesn&#8217;t mean you should. For example, when I made a public Facebook post [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=therealshelli.com&#038;blog=32495796&#038;post=2166&#038;subd=simplyshelli&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="22e215567edb152d04ff19ded08f754e" url="http://therealshelli.com/2013/01/10/16-image-creation-tools-to-improve-your-content/"><![CDATA[For many brands and businesses photo albums and photos on Facebook can get up to 180% more engagement and social networking sites like Tumblr and Pinterest drive incredible amounts of traffic back to blogs and websites via images. To put it bluntly, images are more important than ever when it comes to online marketing. Unfortunately, [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=therealshelli.com&#038;blog=32495796&#038;post=2197&#038;subd=simplyshelli&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="58f93990911a06622f2a4bbfb64ba841" url="http://therealshelli.com/2013/01/16/working-with-socialpup-by-my-feet-happyplace/"><![CDATA[<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=therealshelli.com&#038;blog=32495796&#038;post=2210&#038;subd=simplyshelli&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c8f30f64cccc6946710061174ec8c475" url="http://therealshelli.com/2013/01/17/8-free-tools-for-listening-to-conversations-in-social-media/"><![CDATA[Imagine the last party you went to. Think about who you were with, how you presented yourself, who you spoke with and what you talked about. Now imagine a complete stranger walking up to you, opening his coat, and shouting, “Hey! Wanna buy some of our COOL watches? They’re buy one get one free if [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=therealshelli.com&#038;blog=32495796&#038;post=2215&#038;subd=simplyshelli&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="75948d5358ad4b1b6b8d10cf3c893f50" url="http://therealshelli.com/2013/01/25/social-media-measurement-whats-your-focus/"><![CDATA[One of the most commonly asked questions I hear about social media is, “How do you measure it?” I have a love/hate relationship with this question, because if I answer “incorrectly” I could potentially alienate myself from someone I’m trying to help: If I say that measurement is important, but should only be used as [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=therealshelli.com&#038;blog=32495796&#038;post=2286&#038;subd=simplyshelli&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="52e2ee34f3a2a6919f5842bcfd60b0f7" url="http://therealshelli.com/2013/03/25/20-easy-to-use-free-and-reliable-tools-for-social-media-management/"><![CDATA[One of the questions I get asked most is, “What tools do you use for social media?” and I often have to say something like, “it depends.” There are lots of social media tools out there each with it&#8217;s own purpose, strengths, and limitations. I like to tell people I’m tool agnostic. It’s a term that [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=therealshelli.com&#038;blog=32495796&#038;post=2300&#038;subd=simplyshelli&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ebd60e3c5e26f98c9ae6ce5bf877dd8d" url="http://therealshelli.com/2013/05/07/so-youre-making-a-facebook-profile-for-work-no-just-no/"><![CDATA[So lately it seems like I’ve been getting a ton of friend requests on Facebook from people I’m already friends with and every time this happens it causes this awkward moment: “Wait, wasn’t I already friends with Susie?” After a few of these odd requests I finally decided to investigate and it turns out that the reason [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=therealshelli.com&#038;blog=32495796&#038;post=2312&#038;subd=simplyshelli&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>