<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="www.colorbreathes.blogspot.com">
	<documents count="13">
		<document id="5a4c02498783356f1a2a2bbdd626276c" url="http://colorbreathes.blogspot.com/2006/03/finding-my-way.html"><![CDATA[This painitng sort of just emerged.  There was no plan, it just kind of happened.<br /><a href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/1600/PDR_237.jpg"><img style="float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/320/PDR_237.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></a><br />By this point in my process of painting again after my 15 year hiatus, I began to wonder if I would ever develop my own style.<br /><br />Even my use of colors in this painting is different from the others.  These aren't as vibrant, but there is something interesting about the work.  My eye is drawn to different parts of this painting everytime I see it.   I titled it "Close Range."  I'm not sure now why, but that's what it is.  The piece was painted in June 2002.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1d2412b64bb09c71a69eaa9a56e98049" url="http://colorbreathes.blogspot.com/2006/03/flowers-eternal-spring.html"><![CDATA[I just love flowers.  Unfortunately, because of my allergies, they don't love me.  But I always feel better when I see flowers.  The really cool thing is that they're all different ... no two are exactly the same.<br /><br />I painted these flowers for my bedroom.  The paintings are untitled. <br /><br /><a href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/1600/PDR_0247.jpg"><img style="float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/320/PDR_0247.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></a><br /><a href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/1600/PDR_0249.jpg"><img style="float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/320/PDR_0249.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></a><br /><br />There's not a whole heck of a lot more to say about these.  They are what they are.  I kind of like the fact that they bleed off the canvas.  Makes them look like there's more than there is.  To me, flowers in a painting is like having eternal spring.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b57979260c9d21ca5806ce56aad01a80" url="http://colorbreathes.blogspot.com/2006/03/going-in-circles.html"><![CDATA[After completing my first painting -Bursting- I was ready to keep on painting.  I had a ton of emotions swirling around inside of me.  I really couldn't name tham at the time.  In fact, I didn't even know they were there until this next painting came to be.  Entitled "Circles of Confusion," it represents the many facets of my being, and all seemed to be swirling about.  This piece was painted in July 2001.<br /><br /><a href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/1600/PDR_0254.jpg"><img style="float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/320/PDR_0254.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></a><br /><br />Apparently, circles would be a bit of a theme in many of my paintings yet to emerge on the canvas.  If you can believe it, I never even really noticed the circular motion in this painting until it was pointed out to me.  At the time, for me, it was all about the use of color and the energy on the canvas.    <br /><br />Now, of course, I see the circles, and I really understand what they mean based on what was happening in my life at the time.    What's notable is that with the exception of the color orange, the colors on the canvas represent the Chakras.  I didn't know that at the time.  In fact, I just looked up Chakra colors as I'm writing this, and made this discovery.<br /><br />Painting provides me the freedom to express myself.  And, because I was one of a very few number of people who actually saw my paintings, I got to express myself without any judgement.  It's the judgement of my work that makes me want to hide the paintings away.  So, this blog is an extraordinary step for me.  I'm proceeding cautiously.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="46967f5b0d9296aa1dd9042d57611fa" url="http://colorbreathes.blogspot.com/2006/03/little-bit-of-whimsy.html"><![CDATA[I painted this picture for my friend Carol and her partner Reed.  It's titled "Two Girls."  I wasn't nuts about how it turned out because I thought that the canvas positioning of the two girls just wasn't quite right.  So, this painting has sat in my basement for almost 4 years.  Yep ... just sitting there hanging out on the floor leaning against a wall.  Bummer.  I'm kind of liking the painting much better now. <br /><a href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/1600/PDR_244.jpg"><img style="float:right; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/320/PDR_244.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></a><br /><br />The painting was intended to be a housewarming gift for them.  So, I gave up in frustration and left the idea alone for quite a few months.  I knew I wanted to paint two girls in an atypical kind of way -- maybe with a little bit of whimsy.  I think with the first painting, whimsy was around the painting.  <br /><br />I just sat on the idea for a while.  I had lots of ideas kicking around in my head, but nothing was a clear answer ... no truly clear vision.  I didn't want the same old, same old.  I wanted something that would represent these two women.  Ah, the pressure of it all.<br /><br /><a href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/1600/PDR_0367.jpg"><img style="float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/320/PDR_0367.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></a> And then one day, an idea came to me to imbed the image in a bunch of shapes -- triangles, and the circles would be their heads.  This painting was the result.  It's titled "Just Two Girls."  I'm happy to say that it actually hangs in Carol and Reed's home.  That's far better than occupying space in my basement!  I really like this painting.  It's fun, bright, colorful, bold, intriguing -- I just get a feel-good vibe from it.  It's much smaller in size from "Two Girls," but it's just right.  It feels right, it looks right ... it's just what it was suppose to be.  The lines aren't perfect.  I didn't want perfectly straight lines and perfectly sized shapes.  I wanted it to look like it was done free hand without a straight edge or tape.  It's not sterile.  It's alive.  It has movement.  It says, "Look at me!  -- Okay.  Now, look closer!"<br /><br />Ok, that's what this painting says to ME.  What does it say to you?
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3677293b66009735a507ae272f3b1131" url="http://colorbreathes.blogspot.com/2006/03/march-19-beginning.html"><![CDATA[My paintings are a very personal form of expression for me.  In my paintings, I have been able to express sadness, anger, joy, fear, exhilliration, love and myriad other emotions.  I love to use color in different combinations to represent my feelings.  <br /><br />For 15 years, I took a break from painting.  I had so many dark emotions during this period that I was terrified of how they might be reflected in my work.  Greeting the canvass again after such a long period of time was a little intimidating.  My work was very different from how I left it.  When I stopped painting, my work had primarily consisted of realism.  Now, it's a little off the charts.<br /><br /><a href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/1600/PDR_239.jpg"><img style="float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/320/PDR_239.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></a> "Bursting" -- This was my first painting after 15 years.  I was so excited to smell the paint and mix the colors. It was awesome.  This painting reflects that excitement along with the intense emotions that were living inside me.<br /><br />This is my first post.  But, through this web site, I'll introduce you to my work and try to explain some of the pieces.  <br /><br />Through this blog, my paintings won't just sit on the floor in my basement studio.  While I don't yet have the courage to show  them publicly, I can do it here.  <br /><br />Enjoy.  Be kind.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a04df078240bf7833356b1b42603d3fc" url="http://colorbreathes.blogspot.com/2006/03/my-favorite-painting.html"><![CDATA[Interestingly, my favorite of my paintings has no title.  I painted it in August of 2001.  I didn't know I didn't title it until I pulled it away from the wall two nights ago.  <br /><br />I guess if I had to title it today, it would be called "Layers."  I love this painting because it has depth and dimension.  I like the colors and the transparency of the colors.  In August of 2001, I was just getting ready to have a hysterectomy.  Maybe that explains this painting a little.<br /><br /><a href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/1600/PDR_0250.jpg"><img style="float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/320/PDR_0250.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></a><br /><br />At the time, I was a little scared and extremely sad that I would never be able to have a child.  I hadn't really faced my sadness until the day of my surgery.  I think that the complexity of this piece speaks to what I was feelilng.<br /><br />Painting from my soul is so different from what I was accustomed to doing.  This style of painting is extremely liberating.  It's like a soul cleansing.  When I'm painting, I lose all sense of time.  I become completely immersed in the work.  I feel like I AM the paint.  I am unaware of what the painting even looks like.  I just go with my gut when mixing colors.  It's kind of like painting in a trance.  I'm not at all aware of even thinking about what colors to mix and apply next.  It all just kind of happens.  And when I "feel" done, I clean my brushes and pallete and the step away to look at the piece.  Almost always, I feel like I'm seeing it for the first time.  I'm always surprised.  It's really a weird sensation to express, but it's so totally cool at the same time.<br /><br />Maybe this painting is untitled because that period of my life was untitled, too.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="26bb72587c3c6bb45c1fcc3d21890079" url="http://colorbreathes.blogspot.com/2006/03/thing-with-angels.html"><![CDATA[I love angels.  And, I believe in them.  There is something really calming and mystical about the thought of angels being around you.  In 2002, I painted this picture, "Angel at 20,000 Feet."<br /><br /><a href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/1600/PDR_235.jpg"><img style="display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/320/PDR_235.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></a><br /><br />This particular angel is pretty cool.  She's just hanging out in the midst of a lot of other stuff.  Yes, "she" is a she.  <br /><br />I like the colors and how fun and light this painitng is.  The star and moon add a few celestial elements.  This is one of those feel-good paintings for me.  It's hard to remember 4 years ago and what I was thinking when I was painting this one.  I can only guess that I was in an ok place.  I think that this angel is representative of the good that sits in the middle of chaos.<br /><br />I think angels keep us all in an ok place.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="776dbaa902e4bc6c948d0d6b886c4ec9" url="http://colorbreathes.blogspot.com/2006/04/fuzzy-butts.html"><![CDATA[You know, I always thought that people who wove their lives around their pets ... especially their dogs were whacked.  I mean, they're JUST dogs.  Yeah, that's what I thought until Reilly.  He's my friend Lynn's dog.  He comes to the office everyday.  <br /><br />Reaily is a Tibetan Terrier.  He's 4.  He is the most adorable dog ever.  He has a quirky personality and loves to have his fuzzy butt rubbed.<br /><br />Lynn got Reilly right after she had undergone major surgery.  I was staying with Lynn at the time to help her through her recovery.  So, I got to love and nurture this tiny and most adorable puppy, too.  He was 8 weeks old when she got him, and he was the sweetest thing.<br /><br />Anyway, Reilly and I got to do some major bonding early in his life, and so we're loyal and trusting friends today.  When Lynn got Reilly, her sister, Pat, got his sister, Hayley.  So, Reilly and Hayley are ... needless to say ... really good buds.<br /><br />For Christmas 2003, I wanted to do something special, so I painted Reilly for Lynn,<br /><br /><a href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/1600/Reilly.jpg"><img style="float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/320/Reilly.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></a><br />Reilly<br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br />And, I painted Hayley for Pat.<br /><br /><a href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/1600/Hayley.jpg"><img style="float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/320/Hayley.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></a><br />Hayley<br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br />These paintings were a throw back to realism work for me.  While they weren't nearly as liberating to paint, it was still a cool feeling to know that I COULD do realilsm if I wanted to.  When painting free expression, you so quickly lose yourself in the work.  But, in the process, I did begin to wonder if I had any serious artistic talent..  Like, I didn't want people to look at my work and think something like, "my 5 year old could do that."  So, through the Reilly and Hayley paintings, I kind of debunk that thought .... at least for myself.<br /><br />Hayley turned out better than Reilly.  But, what heck ... after not doing realism for 15+ years, I think they didn't turn out half bad.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7d48b5d2e26f9cedadd6b83906b277e9" url="http://colorbreathes.blogspot.com/2006/04/giving-is-better-than-receiving.html"><![CDATA[Here in Pittsburgh, we have an organization that provides support and services to individuals who are gay, lesbian, transgendered, etc. called Persad.  Each year Persad has an event called Art For AIDS, Art For Change.  It's an awesome event that calls for primarily local artists to submit pieces of work that are then auctioned either live or through a silent auction.  Well, I decided after attending the event a few times that it would be really cool to submit a painting to the auction.<br /><br />I was a nervous wreck throughout the process.  I worried that the painting wouldn't sell or that I would overhear people criticizing the piece or dissing it.  And, I didn't think I could take the criticism or that I would do well if it had been shunned in any way.  But, I sucked it up and submitted a painting anyway.<br /><br />My first painting submitted to Art For AIDS was called "Glorious."<br /><br /><a href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/1600/Glorious.jpg"><img style="display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/320/Glorious.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></a><br /><br />My first order of business when I went to the event was to immediately find out where my painting was hanging so that I could avoid the area for the entire night ... and I did.  When I saw it hanging there, I wanted to run up to it and take it down and run away with it.  I was so nervous.  Well, I didn't need to worry about avoiding it for the entire night, because I ended up gulping down a glass of wine and than bailing out of there.  I didn't have a clue for 2 days whether or not the painting sold.  My friend David called me to tell me that there were a lot of bids on it.  But, I seriously thought that he was just trying to make me feel good.  I did find out officially that the painting DID sell ... for $180.  I was so happy.<br /><br />So, having had a successful first venture, I decided to submit another painting the following year.  When I painted "Glorious" I stayed pretty conservative.  It wasn't a bit of a risk-taking painitng.  I didn't pour my soul into it.  But the painting that I did for the 2005 auction is a different story.  "Patchwork of Hope Emerging" is a painting that has a piece of my soul in it.  It was very, very hard to part with it.  But, I really wanted to do it.  I wanted to take a risk.  I was still really scared - particularly when I brought it to Persad and the woman who collected it for the auction said, "Wow, this one is SO different from last year's."  And that was all she said.  So, I walked away thinking, "She hates it.  it sucks."  But then I didn't care.  This painting had ME in it.  It is a good painting ... at least I think so.  It evokes feeling, and that's the purpose of art.<br /><br /><a href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/1600/Patchwork.jpg"><img style="display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/320/Patchwork.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></a><br /><br />Some may judge it harshly, but I don't care.  It is powerful and it speaks to the value of life in all of its intricacies.  I don't exactly remember, but I think this one sold for $215.  I know it was over $200, but I'm not exactly sure of the amount.  I was so thrilled that it sold and that it raised funds for Persad.<br /><br />Ok, so this brings me to my 2006 submission.  The auction is coming up on May15th.  I think it's a totally safe painting.  It was inspired by a painting that I did for my therapist when she moved away. I don't have a photo of that one, but when I get it I'll post it here for you to see.  <br /><br />This painting is kind of fun and elegant.  I call it "Ruby Red."  It was painted with an irredescent gold paint, and I used red glitter for the lips.  It's so much more alive in person than in the photo, but I hope your enjoy it.<br /><br /><a href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/1600/RubyRed.jpg"><img style="display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/320/RubyRed.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></a><br /><br />I hope it sells and does well for Persad ... and if it does, it then does well for me.<br /><br />So, in many, many ways, through these paintings I have expereienced that there is much more meaning to the phrase, "Giving is better than receiving."
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="74738060d48995b58aa95ea134278a19" url="http://colorbreathes.blogspot.com/2006/04/more-from-soul.html"><![CDATA[Painting emotions is like painting from the soul.  Most of these emotions are buried so deep that you don't even know they're there.  You can't name them, feel them or see them.  And, yet, I can paint them.  It's the most phenomenal thing to paint your emotions.  <br /><br />I have no idea what the painting will be.  I just paint.  I put colors together without full cognition of what those colors are until the painting is finished.  I'm not really sure how this happens.  It's like going into a trance of sorts.  <br /><br />I become the paint.  I am each stroke, each splat, each swirl, each color.  This painting was completed in July 2002.  It's titled "Release."  <br /><br /><a href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/1600/PDR_0331.jpg"><img style="display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/320/PDR_0331.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></a><br />This was painted during a period when I was getting in touch with a ton of things from my past.  Lots and lots of buried emotions were swirling around inside me.  In many ways, there still are a lot.  But, in this painting I begin to see and feel those emotions.<br /><br />Interestingly, I always thought that if I painted feelings, the paint would be black ... total darkness.  <br /><br />When I stepped away from this canvas ... and so many other paintings ... I was surprised to see what I had created.  You might think, "How can you be surprised?  You painted it!"  But, it's a completely surreal feeling.  Even though I painted the piece, I don't really know what's on the canvas.  I can't SEE the painting ... I can only feel it.  I don't actually see it it until I step away when the painting is finished.<br /><br />I wish everyone could feel that feeling of being one with the canvas and the paint.  It's a complete removal from the present.  You lose track of time, and just get lost in the canvas.  It's a feeling that I really love.  It's such a release.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b20316cb40fdabd26d769e1b7448e0a0" url="http://colorbreathes.blogspot.com/2006/04/past-catching-up.html"><![CDATA[Our past is our history, it's our roadmap to where we are today.  Sometimes that map runs a pretty direct, normal course.  Other times, it's filled with road blocks and hazards.  And then there's childhood ... our distant past.   For me, childhood is not something that I remember vividly.  I get flashes of a few highlights here and there.  Most of my memories center around my grandmother who died when I was 9.  She was an extraordinary woman and a huge influence on the person I am today.<br /><br />My parents separated when I was 2 and then divorcced.  So, life wasn't all that easy ... for many reasons.<br /><br />This painting, "Whispers of the Past," is a piece of time captured on canvass.  I can't explain it exactly ... it just is.  I think it has something to do with the stick figure image.  <br /><br /><a href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/1600/WhispersOfThePast.%20jpg.jpg"><img style="display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/320/WhispersOfThePast.%20jpg.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></a><br /><br />This painting is a little haunting and also filled with a little whimsy.  It definitely has whispers of the past.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="eb5e3da016c0b06148f66d8457712a3d" url="http://colorbreathes.blogspot.com/2006/04/tough-one.html"><![CDATA[This painting was a tough one for me.  It's not like it's anything great.  In fact, it's not a great painting at all.  Yet, it moves me more than any other painitng I've done.  It's disturbing.  But, it needed to be done.<br /><br />This painting is titled "Suicide."  I painted it in July 2002.  My father committed suicide on January 7, 2000.  You might say that I wasn't dealing with it.  Of course, there was a lot of pre-suicide baggage between my father and me.  The suicide was a real kicker and just added to a lot of psychological angst for me.<br /><br /><a href="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/1600/PDR_0245.jpg"><img style="display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;" src="http://photos1.blogger.com/blogger/1463/2524/320/PDR_0245.jpg" border="0" alt="" /></a><br /><br />Anyway, this is a painting that will probably never hang on a wall in my home.  It just sits.  And, it should just sit.  <br /><br />It causes a visceral reaction for me everytime I look at it.  That flipping stomach feeling.  Agghh.<br /><br />So, this painting got done 18 months after my father's death.  There are still days when his suicide freaks me out.  Although I have to admit that there is a lot about my father that freaks me out.  There is a ton more I could say, but I don't want to drone on here.  So, the painting stands as a constant reminder that people are not always what they appear to be.  Things don't always happen as you plan.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7276d2b1299f206c0e73497cddb5d69e" url="http://colorbreathes.blogspot.com/2009/08/back-to-blog.html"><![CDATA[I started my blog so that I'd have an outlet for sharing my paintings and the stories behind them.  <br /><br />I'm returning to blogging because life is moving faster than we blink, and this is one way I can share news about me and about the things I think.<br /><br />Now, I'm just hoping that I can keep up and keep blogging.  It seems that I just never have enough hours in the day to do all the things that I hope to do.<br /><br />Holy crap - can you believe that it's already August 6th?!!  I seriously think that the days fly by as we get older.  How does that even happen?  I remember those long lazy days of summer when it seemed like the days were always sunny and friends were plentiful, so even when you were bored you could hang out with a friend to pass the time.  Now, days are so short, and so much responsibility occupies our minds and our lives.  <br /><br />Oh to be 16 again ... wait, did I just SAY that?  Who in the world would want to actually be 16 again.  I'd settle for being 30 again ... lol.<br /><br />Ok, gotta run.  See what I mean ... I sure hope I'm gonna have time for this blog.
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>