<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="reviews.bargainbriana.com">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="767d6900354b5d5f5a99c4e5829bf8c9" url="http://reviews.bargainbriana.com/bungalow-cool-storage-options-for-your-child/"><![CDATA[Get your child&#8217;s room organized with these cool storage options from Bungalow. They are on sale at The Mini Social right now.  Includes bins, under the bed storage, trunks, and more including reusable beverage totes that look like they would fit a wine bottle for just $3 &#8211; perfect to give along with a bottle [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6bce8ec47a39f91256a1e5b680078567" url="http://reviews.bargainbriana.com/cool-mickey-band-aids-for-adults/"><![CDATA[I had a Christmas accident! The first one of the holiday season when I dropped a pair of scissors smack on my big toe&#8230;which in turn ripped off part of the toenail. Lucky for me, I have these really cool retro Mickey Mouse Band-Aids to cover the nasty toe! You should be able to find [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6774642bfe483c0d9777b9ea6e7a5a95" url="http://reviews.bargainbriana.com/gain-sniff-sniff-hurray/"><![CDATA[When I think of Gain, I think of laundry detergent. However, Gain also has dishwashing liquid that is available in three refreshing scents. No more boring dishwashing! While, the new Gain scents don&#8217;t make dishwashing do themselves, it is does  make it more pleasant with the wonderful aromas.  Gain Dishwashing liquid comes in Original, Lavender, Citrus [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="86624cab45d9c44d56339932cc1d16d0" url="http://reviews.bargainbriana.com/moon-dough-fun-that-is-easy-to-clean-up/"><![CDATA[Sofia was giddy with the new Moon Dough. I&#8217;ve read about it but we&#8217;ve never tried it. I&#8217;m sold on it now. For one, it is much easier to clean up that other types of dough. It is dry so you can vacuum right up when your child is done playing with it. Secondly, it [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ebcc4ab5c92f7590a1eae05f31fc061a" url="http://reviews.bargainbriana.com/nutrasea-vitamin/"><![CDATA[Research has shown that essential fatty acids play a vital role in our children&#8217;s development. Getting children or even adults to eat fish the recommended amount per week can be quite a chore. Most children can&#8217;t swallow pills or tablets so an alternative is needed. Ascenta has created a new NutraSea Kids supplement so now [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="249e93e76a0ad68aeedd1aa2f953d701" url="http://reviews.bargainbriana.com/pook-a-looz-collect-clip-and-play/"><![CDATA[Pook-a-Looz has taken Classic Disney characters and gave them a stylish new twist like the modernize Minnie pictured above. These will appeal to kids of all ages from tweens to preschoolers! For a perfect gift filler, stocking stuffer, or just a little something for your child, you can choose from Pook-a-Looz Wobblers, Yip Yappers, Spinners, [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fe64206222df575c029d28e49e8707ad" url="http://reviews.bargainbriana.com/scientific-explorer-heavenly-hair/"><![CDATA[Scientific Explorer has several new Spa Kits which incorporates science, exploration, and FUN!  These are hands on kits that explore science in a new and fun way that children especially little girls will love! We were sent the Heavenly Hair kit. With the Heavenly Hair kit you can make your own shampoo and conditioner. You [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="17b14a534bc1b9d15248f971f6e3d16d" url="http://reviews.bargainbriana.com/sports-illustrated-kids-all-access/"><![CDATA[Sports Illustrated Kids: All Access is a must give book if you have a child who is a sports fan! This book gives you an inside look to sports stars, locker rooms, and more. It is a book that could keep a child&#8217;s interest with the pictures and get behind the scenes information. Even as [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="12d8ed87b4e8ff083a623c02dda2ea48" url="http://reviews.bargainbriana.com/suave-red-carpet-style/"><![CDATA[Last year, when I hosted my Suave Red Carpet style party, the guests were disappointed only because they had these fabulous hair dos and no place to go! This year, a few of us were attending a Gala for our local Boys &#38; Girls Club, which was a perfect excuse to get our best &#8220;Suave [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b7b2da71e7b9914eb9bd5cfcb3fcede7" url="http://reviews.bargainbriana.com/webkinz-jr-online-world-perfect-for-ages-3-6/"><![CDATA[The people who brought you Webkinz are now bringing the Webkinz Jr. world to children ages 3-6. Kids will love the lovable plush animals such as a bunny, puppy, kitty, giraffe, and more! Each animal comes with a unique Pet Code, which will allow your child to access the online world of Webkinz Jr. Your [...]
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>