<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="www.onviolence.com">
	<documents count="8">
		<document id="37d5e1fdf8bc60207db7b111c18a0144" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/OnViolence/~3/6iUB2KU8Wfw/"><![CDATA[<p id="docs-internal-guid-01a7dd8b-46f3-1016-bfc0-45077645999b" dir="ltr"><em><span id="docs-internal-guid-7ef8b20f-6dd8-6fd1-3448-340a5d44bdef">(To read all of our </span></em>Lone Survivor<em> posts,<a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=230"> please click here</a>. The most important post is "<a href="http://www.onviolence.com/?e=762">A List of the Mistakes and Differences Between Lone Survivor (Film), Lone Survivor (Book) and Reality</a>" so read that first if you are new to the blog or this topic.)</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">I (Eric C) saw the film <em>Lone Survivor</em> a few weeks ago at a special screening hosted by &ldquo;<a href="http://www.theqandapodcast.com/" target="_blank">The Q&amp;A with Jeff Goldsmith</a>&rdquo;. (Goldsmith, who also publishes an e-magazine on screenwriting called <em><a href="http://backstory.net/" target="_blank">Backstory</a></em>, regularly hosts screenings for upcoming films with screenwriters panels afterward. If you want to work in the film industry, this is a must-listen podcast. If you live in Los Angeles, you should be on the email list.)</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.theqandapodcast.com/2013/12/lone-survivor-q.html" target="_blank">Near the end of the question and answer session</a> (also available on iTunes), Peter Berg told the audience:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m sure there are murmurs...There are people who hated the book in the SEAL community, in the military community. There&rsquo;s people who hate Marcus Luttrell. Not a lot of them. But go online, it&rsquo;s all there. The beautiful internet. Everybody gets keyboard courage, and says all kinds of things.&rdquo;</em> (minute 1:22:00 on the podcast)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Which is funny, because Peter Berg followed those keyboard-courage-endowed haters&rsquo; advice almost to a T.</p>
<p dir="ltr">By haters, I&rsquo;m referring, of course, to Michael C and myself, who, along with Ed Darack, have led the effort to correct the historical record on Operation Red Wings. I doubt that Peter Berg expected one of those haters to be in the audience...or to take a picture with him after the screening.</p>
<div class="pivotx-wrapper"><img src="http://www.onviolence.com/images/2013-12/p1060526.jpg" title=""  alt="" class="pivotx-image"  /></div>

<p dir="ltr">Mostly, I don&rsquo;t get why Peter Berg mocked us when he agreed with everything we wrote. The <em>Lone Survivor</em> film is good for all the reasons that the <em>Lone Survivor</em> memoir is bad. Peter Berg is a good filmmaker, so he avoided all the mistakes Luttrell and Robinson made when they wrote the memoir. Frankly, I hope they watch the film to realize how they should have written the book.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So what does the <em>Lone Survivor</em> film not do?</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>1. Politics. </strong>Our biggest problem with<em> Lone Survivor</em> (memoir) wasn&rsquo;t its inaccuracies; <a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=238" target="_blank">it was with its politics</a>. The book is endlessly political, and explicitly and repeatedly blames liberals and the media for the deaths of every Navy SEAL that day. What does Peter Berg think of politics?</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<em>There was an active decision to not politicize it...I did not want to make a film that created political discussion over a discussion about who these men were</em>.&rdquo; (minute 1:11:00)</p>
<p>Unlike the book, in <em>Lone Survivor </em>(film) there are no WMDs or al Qaeda training camps in Iraq, no mentions of George W. Bush, no politics, either liberal or conservative. And it&rsquo;s a better film for it.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>2. Rules of Engagement.</strong> Yes, in a crucial scene in the middle of <em>Lone Survivor</em> (film), the SEALs debate the Rules of Engagement, but those ROEs aren&rsquo;t vilified the way Luttrell vilifies them in his memoir. The discussion is balanced and even-handed, with two characters debating their options. Good art asks questions instead of giving answers.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) asks questions; <em>Lone Survivor</em> (book) gives answers.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>3. The Vote.</strong> A few weeks ago, Roberto commented on the site:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;Further, some of the things you claim to be false are highly speculative such as the &ldquo;vote&rdquo; contraversy. [sic] Im aware that its not customary for battlefield decisions to be subject to democracy but this isnt your everyday military unit and to suggest you have insight into their methodology based off of, well frankly nothing, makes you seem a little pretentious. Im [sic] aware other SEALs have also criticized this claim but again, exigent circumstances can lead to breaking SOPs and the main point is: no one but those 4 men were there.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Fair enough, Roberto, but what about that fact that in the book Marcus Luttrell clearly writes, &ldquo;The deciding vote was mine and it will haunt me till they rest me in an east Texas grave. Mikey nodded, &lsquo;I guess that&rsquo;s two votes to one...&rsquo;&rdquo; (pg. 207) and in the film no vote takes place? As Peter Berg said in the Q&amp;A, &ldquo;Mike Murphy made that decision. There wasn&rsquo;t a vote.&rdquo; (minute 00:54:00)</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>4. The Writing. </strong>The writing in <em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir) is terrible. And I mean terrible. We did <a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=231" target="_blank">post after</a> post <a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=237" target="_blank">after post</a> on it. It&rsquo;s uninteresting and cliched.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Peter Berg let the actors improvise their dialogue until they found something good. I&rsquo;m not going to pretend like it&rsquo;s perfect, (One character's wife wants a horse. Awww!) but it&rsquo;s a million times more competent than the writing in the book. Most importantly, <a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=233">no characters memorize crosswords in their head</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>5. Pacing.</strong> In the memoir, way too much time is spent away from the action, discussing Iraq, training, the home front, political rants. <em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) pares all this down into one tight, brutal story. It&rsquo;s about the mission and only the mission...just like the book should have been.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>5. The Inaccuracies.</strong> According to the question and answer session after the screening, Peter Berg believes that Luttrell choose him to tell his story was because of the meticulous amount of research he does before every film. And in doing that research, Berg (must have) learned a few things, like...<a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=234" target="_blank">the actual name of the mission, the actual size of the group attacking the SEALs, who Ahmad Shah actually was, etc</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Peter Berg cut those inaccuracies from the film. (I mean, <a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=758" target="_blank">not the Ahmad Shah thing</a>, but still, he cut a lot of the inaccuracies out.) We&rsquo;ll dive into the other changes from the film to the memoir later this week.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So yes, some people on the internet may have keyboard courage. But as <em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) proves, sometimes they&rsquo;re right.</p>
<p dir="ltr">You&rsquo;re welcome.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/OnViolence/~4/6iUB2KU8Wfw" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e6e9ca0c9f9b118f77f83bc970a37a79" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/OnViolence/~3/I7WpSP87kzc/"><![CDATA[<p id="docs-internal-guid-160a50a5-728d-127f-9dc7-9efd17d61d7d" dir="ltr"><em>(Normally, we start the year with our &ldquo;Most Intriguing Event of the Year&rdquo;. But since </em>Lone Survivor <em>hits theaters across the country on January 10th, we&rsquo;re devoting this week to that topic.</em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><em>To read all of our</em> Lone Survivor<em> posts, <a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=230" target="_blank">please click here</a>. The most important post is "<a href="http://www.onviolence.com/?e=762" target="_blank">A List of the Mistakes and Differences Between </a></em><a href="http://www.onviolence.com/?e=762" target="_blank">Lone Survivor</a><em><a href="http://www.onviolence.com/?e=762" target="_blank"> (Film), </a></em><a href="http://www.onviolence.com/?e=762" target="_blank">Lone Survivor</a><em><a href="http://www.onviolence.com/?e=762" target="_blank"> (Book) and Reality</a>" so read that first if you are new to the blog or this topic.)</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Last month, we received this comment from Roberto in &ldquo;<a href="http://www.onviolence.com/?e=759" target="_blank">Luttrell No Longer Stands By his Mistakes</a>&rdquo;:&nbsp;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;...but I implore you to decide if the difference between &ldquo;redwing&rdquo; and &ldquo;Red Wings&rdquo; is as significant as you make it out to be when compared to the sacrifices that were made June 28th 2005.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">This weekend, commenter Jay wrote:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;What is to be gained by spending time and effort pointing out the difference between Lutrell&rsquo;s account and the film?&rdquo; </em></p>
<p dir="ltr">In short, Roberto and Jay are summarizing a comment we frequently receive by email, &ldquo;Why spend so much time on this topic, especially being critical, when we could just say, &lsquo;These men are heroes,&rsquo; and be done with it?&rdquo;</p>
<p dir="ltr">Frankly, Operation Red Wings is too important to simply let one account define the narrative. If Operation Red Wings is important--and we believe it is--then we want to help set the record straight.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>First, Operation Red Wings was historically important.</strong> Until that point, the previous high in US combat casualties occurred during Operation Anaconda, shortly after the initial invasion of Afghanistan. (Although, a non-combat helicopter crash in Ghazni did claim 17 lives earlier in 2005.) Partially, due to Operation Red Wings, US commanders decided to replace the marines in the Pech River Valley with a brigade from the 10th Mountain Division, which increased the total number of boots on the ground in both Kunar and the Pech River specifically. This eventually led to the 173rd Airborne Brigade deploying to Afghanistan with even more soldiers.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Both the marines, the 10th Mountain brigade and the 173rd took significant casualties in Kunar province and its surroundings. These casualties, in part, led to a surge in news coverage, including a Nightline special on the Korengal Valley and Sebastian Junger&rsquo;s embed with Battle Company, which led to the book <em>War</em> and the Academy Award nominated documentary <em>Restrepo</em>. This surge in news coverage, coupled with the Iraq War winding down, helped lead to the &ldquo;Afghan surge&rdquo;.</p>
<p dir="ltr">If Operation Red Wings hadn&rsquo;t happened (or had turned out differently), you could make a case those events wouldn&rsquo;t have happened. (From a personal perspective, I also ended up deploying to Kunar with the 173rd.)</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Secondly, Operations Red Wings was important tactically to the military. </strong>The U.S. military learned quite a few lessons from the battle, if not explicitly than implicitly; small &ldquo;strategic recon&rdquo; units all but disappeared. Generals put specific size limits on coalition patrols, which affected my deployment to Afghanistan on a daily basis (I had a lot of crazy ideas that violated a lot of policies). Aviation units also put a lot more restrictions on where and when they could fly, which restricted offensive operations.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Operation Red Wings is also now wildly popular in military circles as a case study, primarily used as an ethical dilemma which begins and ends with the goatherders compromising the SEALs. Most of the other tactical issues--like proper insertion methods, the role of small patrols, the need for redundant comms, the larger counter-insurgency operations in Kunar, and the role of terrain in hidesights (which are/were extremely important to most units deploying to Afghanistan)--were largely overlooked.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Of course, Operation Red Wings&rsquo; success as a case study is partly due to the success of Luttrell&rsquo;s Lone Survivor memoir. </strong>As we&rsquo;ve written before, <em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir) is probably the single most read book about Afghanistan. Now, with the movie possibly earning an Oscar nomination and box office success, more Americans will see this film more than any other piece of media about the war in Afghanistan. We believe this will influence how Americans think about the war in Afghanistan (and even how they feel about counter-insurgency) more than any other form of media.</p>
<p dir="ltr">It doesn&rsquo;t seem right that one account by one former SEAL--who has incredibly strong political views--should dominate the entire discussion around this important event, especially if he got many of the core facts wrong. This battle raised important issues, and <em>Lone Survivor</em> (both film and memoir) have consistently emphasized the heroism and honor of the troops involved instead of tackling those tough issues.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Meanwhile, the larger discussion of <em>Lone Survivor</em> has started and ended with the decision to let the goat herders go, and not the operational decision-making before, during and after the mission. We keep coming back to Lone Survivor to tell those other stories, make those other connections and provide other viewpoints.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>If Operation Red Wings is important--and it is--then getting the facts right is important </strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">(This is also why we keep recommending that readers who want to learn a lot more about Operation Red Wings and the Pech River Valley in 2005 should read <em>Victory Point</em> by Ed Darack.)</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/OnViolence/~4/I7WpSP87kzc" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7db4d0ec1ab2e5c02994aa2aec065df9" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/OnViolence/~3/IwZp4NCgz9w/"><![CDATA[<p id="docs-internal-guid-0-58a6dc-fe54-2efe-4db8-2c5b80e73205" dir="ltr"><em><span id="docs-internal-guid-7ef8b20f-6dd8-6fd1-3448-340a5d44bdef">(To read all of our </span></em>Lone Survivor<em> posts,<a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=230"> please click here</a>. The most important post is "<a href="http://www.onviolence.com/?e=762">A List of the Mistakes and Differences Between Lone Survivor (Film), Lone Survivor (Book) and Reality</a>" so read that first if you are new to the blog or this topic.)</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Last week, friend of the blog Ed Darack pointed out a mistake in <em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) that we had previously missed <a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=733" target="_blank">when we reviewed the trailer</a>. That mistake is...</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Ahmad Shah killed 20 marines the week before Operation Red Wings.</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Lone Survivor inaccuracies fall into roughly three categories: 1. Those we can prove definitively. (Like the name of the operation.) 2. Those we can say have no evidence to support them. (Luttrell&rsquo;s past claims about the number of attackers.) 3. Theoretical mistakes. (The SEAL team had more than 2 options on the hill side.)</p>
<p dir="ltr">This mistake falls firmly in the first category.</p>
<p dir="ltr">In the new film, during the briefing before the operation, someone claims that Shah killed &ldquo;20 marines&rdquo; the week before. In full disclosure, Eric C didn&rsquo;t notice this during his first viewing of the film. Though we haven&rsquo;t had a chance to see the movie again, there&rsquo;s good evidence this line made it into the final cut. First, Emanuel Levy <a href="http://emanuellevy.com/comment/lone-survivor-tough-factual-actioner/" target="_blank">writes in his review</a>, &ldquo;Shah killed 20 marines the previous week.&rdquo; Further, the screenplay of <em>Lone Survivor</em> on UniversalPictureAwards.com has <a href="http://www.universalpicturesawards.com/media/7/pdfs/screenplay7_586140.pdf%20" target="_blank">Lt. Commander Erik Kristensen saying</a>, &ldquo;We know Shah killed fourteen Marines last Tuesday in Kandahar.&rdquo;</p>
<p dir="ltr">Oh, and <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WGexkC-lvh4" target="_blank">it&rsquo;s in the trailer</a>. (At the 40 second mark.)</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/news/survivor-60-minutes/" target="_blank">In his interview with <em>60 Minutes</em> last Sunday</a>, Marcus Luttrell echoed this theme, telling Scott Pelley, &ldquo;[Ahmad Shah] was...killing Marines, Army, I mean, you name it.&rdquo;</p>
<p dir="ltr">Of course, Luttrell amplified Ahmad Shah&rsquo;s role even further in <em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir) (page 179):</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;...suffice it to say [Ahmad Shah] was a serious Taliban force, a sinister mountain man known to make forays into cities and known to have been directly responsible for several lethal attacks on U.S. Marines, always with bombs...had already murdered many of my colleagues in the U.S. Marines.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">The truth is much less sexy. And fact-checkable, thanks to <a href="http://icasualties.org/OEF/Fatalities.aspx%20" target="_blank">the work of iCasualties.org</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">As Ed Darack <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Victory-Point-Operations-Whalers-Afghanistan/dp/B0043RTAOS%20" target="_blank">writes in <em>Victory Point</em></a>, intelligence only linked Ahmad Shah to eleven attacks. Even if he had been responsible for all the deaths in that part of Afghanistan--when I deployed to Afghanistan/the Korengal valley, we called it N2KL: Nuristan, Nangahar, Kunar and Laghman--only three U.S. service-members died in all of 2005 because of hostile action. Two marines died in Laghman by enemy fire. (Which Shah could possibly have assisted, but most likely didn&rsquo;t.) One soldier died in an IED blast near Asadabad in Kunar province. One marine drowned in the Pech River, also in Kunar. (I ended up living in both of the bases named after the casualties in Kunar of 2005, Camp Wright and Camp Joyce.)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Four is much less than 14 or 20, which is what makes this mistake so glaring. Worse, in all of Afghanistan in 2005, <em>only 99 U.S. soldiers and marines died in total</em>. In the week before Operation Red Wings, no soldiers or marines died in Kandahar province the week before, much less 14. Only one soldier died from a bomb in 2005 in Kunar up to that point. The worst loss of U.S. life in 2005 took place in Ghazni province in a non-hostile helicopter crash. Further, the majority of the fighting in Afghanistan was taking place in provinces far removed from Kunar and its environs. Specifically, many more casualties took place in Paktika, Paktia, Logar and other provinces.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So why did this new mistake come to pass? Like the initial <em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir) mistakes, it makes for a much better story. The <a href="http://www.universalpicturesawards.com/main/title/loneSurvivor%20" target="_blank">Universal Pictures&rsquo; Oscar website</a> describe Ahmad Shah as a &ldquo;high level al Qaeda&rdquo; operative, when he was no such thing. The movie describes him killing 20 marines in one week, when he hadn&rsquo;t killed that many people in the war period. The initial screenplay describes him as a national figure--Kandahar is hundreds of miles from Kunar--when he was at best a regional player. Turning Shah into a national, al Qaeda leader who is killing marines by the dozens makes him a much better villain, but it wasn&rsquo;t true.</p>
<p>It turns out, the truth doesn&rsquo;t sell very well.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/OnViolence/~4/IwZp4NCgz9w" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a1019817cde4789b27f2e700496f86fd" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/OnViolence/~3/J_ljYJdRGhU/"><![CDATA[<p><em><span id="docs-internal-guid-7ef8b20f-6dd8-6fd1-3448-340a5d44bdef">(To read all of our </span></em>Lone Survivor<em> posts,<a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=230"> please click here</a>. The most important post is "<a href="http://www.onviolence.com/?e=762">A List of the Mistakes and Differences Between Lone Survivor (Film), Lone Survivor (Book) and Reality</a>" so read that first if you are new to the blog or this topic.)</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">When we first wrote about <em>Lone Survivor</em>, we identified <a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=234" target="_blank">several clear mistakes</a>:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">1. The number of fighters involved (Luttrell put the number of enemies in interviews at over 100 when military documents kept it at 30-40.)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">2. Ahmad Shah/&rdquo;Ben Sharmak&rdquo; (Luttrell claims he was a top al Qaeda commander and Osama bin Laden lieutenant when he wasn&rsquo;t even in the Taliban, but allied with it.)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">3. The name of the mission (Red Wing versus Redwings)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">4. The fact that a vote took place. (Though we can&rsquo;t prove that it didn&rsquo;t, the military is not a democracy.)</p>
<p dir="ltr">In addition to those mistakes, we also took issue with the idea that Luttrell <a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=232" target="_blank">only had a choice between killing the goatherders, or letting them go free</a>. We believe the SEALS also had the options to take the goatherders captive or evacuate after they let them go, which they chose not to do.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Later, we pointed out in &ldquo;<a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=514" target="_blank">Marcus Luttrell Stands by His Mistakes</a>&rdquo; that Luttrell repeats these inaccuracies ad nauseum, in interviews, speeches before the NRA and other political groups, and campaign ads.</p>
<p dir="ltr">All the mistakes above have been corrected by Marcus Luttrell in his most recent <em>60 Minutes</em> interview. (We should also mention that Peter Berg also took out the mistakes in the <em>Lone Survivor</em> movie.) Below, we&rsquo;ve cut paragraphs from the transcript of the <em>60 Minutes</em> interview, to point out where Marcus Luttrell has changed his story.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Did they take a vote?</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;Luttrell told us the unit discussed what to do and were divided. &nbsp;In the past he&rsquo;s been criticized for saying they took a vote&hellip; something that&rsquo;s not supposed to happen in SEAL teams because it&rsquo;s up to the team leader to make a decision.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Anderson Cooper: What did Mike finally decide to do?</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Marcus Luttrell: Oh, we cut 'em loose.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>How many people attacked?</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;The first guy I saw had an RPG over each shoulder and an AK-47 and then there was about 30 or 40 guys in line with him.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Ahmad Shah, al Qaeda or Taliban?</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;Their job was to locate this man whom the four SEALs had only seen in grainy photographs. He was an elusive militia leader aligned with the Taliban named Ahmad Shah.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Anderson Cooper: Who was Ahmad Shah?</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Marcus Luttrell: He had a group that he ran called the Mountain Tigers. He was creating all kinds of havoc out there in that particular region that he was in, killing Marines, Army, I mean, you name it.</em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Kill the Goatherders?</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Actually, this one isn&rsquo;t from Luttrell, it&rsquo;s from a retired officer in the Navy.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;Retired Vice Admiral Joe Maguire says the only options the SEALs really had were to take the goat herders captive and try to get evacuated by helicopter or let them go.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Oh, and the name of the mission?</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;They were part of a larger mission called Operation Red Wings.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Appropriately enough, we didn&rsquo;t actually buy a copy of <em>Lone Survivor</em>, the book, until two weeks ago. Eric C, after he saw <em>Lone Survivor</em>, the movie, bought a copy of the memoir to see if the ending of the film is completely made up. (Spoiler alert: it is.) And in that copy of<em> Lone Survivor</em> all of the mistakes remain. The inaccurate number of attackers, the al Qaeda affiliation for Ahmad Shah, and the vote.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Hell, the title still reads &ldquo;Operation Redwing&rdquo;.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So everyone who rushes out to buy a copy of this book will remain woefully misinformed.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/OnViolence/~4/J_ljYJdRGhU" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9873e02233b422a56191eb4e6e1ede8b" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/OnViolence/~3/Pr7FgJlFayY/"><![CDATA[<p id="docs-internal-guid-168f6e27-5699-9550-62f9-25650baceb79" dir="ltr"><em><span id="docs-internal-guid-7ef8b20f-6dd4-d914-30d6-db64194af27b">(To read all of our </span>Lone Survivor posts,<a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=230"> please click here</a>. The most important post is "<a href="http://www.onviolence.com/?e=762">A List of the Mistakes and Differences Between Lone Survivor (Film), Lone Survivor (Book) and Reality</a>"--the article below--so read that first.)</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Since <em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) gets released in theaters next week, Michael C and I have been doing a lot of writing on it over the past few days. After a certain point, we decided that the best thing to do would be to write one, giant article listing off the differences between the memoir, the film and the actual history of Operation Red Wings.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>If anyone finds a mistake or difference we missed, please let us know. Also, if you find a mistake in this article (and you can write a polite/respectful email), please let us know.</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Some notes first:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">- We&rsquo;ll begin with the differences between the book and movie. Then, since we&rsquo;ve covered some of this material before, we&rsquo;ll list the mistakes in the book and movie versus reality (with lots of links). At the end, we&rsquo;ll provide a references section to the major works on Operation Red Wings. We hope this can be a resource and easy link for anyone on the internet to learn about <em>Lone Survivor</em>.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">- This is not a full and complete list, but it is our best attempt to make one. We also do not have a screener of <em>Lone Survivor</em> (film), so we may change or add to the list after we see the film again.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">- Discrepancies between the memoir and film could have one of two explanations: Peter Berg changed the film to make it more exciting or Luttrell&rsquo;s memoir is even more inaccurate than we thought.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">- Page numbers come from the paperback version of <em>Lone Survivor</em>. Page numbers for the screenplay come from the version hosted online by Universal Pictures.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">- We did make some judgement calls, deciding what&rsquo;s important versus what isn&rsquo;t. Small dialogue changes are unimportant to us; changing events are. For example, in the memoir, an Afghan doctor pulls the shrapnel from Luttrell&rsquo;s leg; in the film, Marcus does it himself. For <a href="http://www.avclub.com/review/lone-survivor-comes-dangerously-close-to-glorifyin-200700">critics who think the film</a> <a href="http://www.ocweekly.com/2013-12-26/film/lone-survivor-peter-berg-mark-wahlberg/">turned soldiers into super heroes</a>, this change would be exhibit A.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Without further ado, the differences between <em>Lone Survivor</em> (film), <em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir) and reality:</p>
<p dir="ltr">&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#0"><strong>The Differences Between the Lone Survivor Memoir and Film</strong></a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=762#1">Marcus Luttrell Nearly Dies in the Opening and Closing of the Film</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#2">Which Local Afghan Found Luttrell?</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#3">Marcus Luttrell is Almost Beheaded by Ahmad Shah&rsquo;s Soldiers</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#4">Marcus Luttrell Pulls A Bullet From His Leg</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#5">How the Afghans Alerted the Military</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#6">The Final Battle from <em>Lone Survivor</em> (Film)</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#7">Did Luttrell Stab Someone with a Knife at the End of Operation Red Wings?</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#8">Luttrell is Rescued by U.S. Military</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#9">Gulab Doesn&rsquo;t Stay Behind in Salar Ban</a></p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#10"><strong>The Mistakes or Exaggerations</strong></a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#11">Number of Afghan Fighters Who Attacked the SEALs?</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#12">Estimated Size of Ahmad Shah&rsquo;s Enemy Force Before Operation Red Wings?</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#13">Ahmad Shah: Major al Qaeda Leader or Osama bin Laden lieutenant?</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#14">The Number of Marines Killed by Ahmad Shah before Operation Red Wings?</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#15">Did the SEALs Take a Vote on What to Do with the Goatherders?</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#16">Who Planned and Led Operation Red Wings?</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#17">What was the Name of the Operation?</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#18">The Name of the Village</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#19">Ahmad Shah, Member of the Taliban?</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#20">How many Insurgents Died during Operation Red Wings?</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#21">Cellular phone or satellite phone?</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#22">Ahmad Shah versus Ben Sharmak</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#25">Billy Shelton Was Not a Green Beret</a></p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#24"><strong>Updates</strong></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.onviolence.com#23"><strong>References</strong></a></p>
<h3 dir="ltr"><strong><a name="0"></a>The Differences Between the <em>Lone Survivor</em> Memoir and Film</strong></h3>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="1"></a>Marcus Luttrell Nearly Dies in the Opening and Closing of the Film</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) opens with voice over as a dying Marcus Luttrell is airlifted back to a military base. As the plane lands, <a href="http://www.universalpicturesawards.com/media/7/pdfs/screenplay7_586140.pdf">Marcus Luttrell literally dies</a>:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;Surgical pack working franticly [sic] to save Luttrell.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;Tight on HEART MONITOR: FLATLINE&hellip;</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;Pushing in on the flatline. Alarm screaming. Tight on Luttrell&rsquo;s eyes starting to glaze over. Dying.&rdquo; </em>(Pages 1 - 2 of script.)</p>
<p dir="ltr">In the book, Luttrell is not in mortal danger. After the Army Rangers rescue Luttrell, he writes &ldquo;First [the Army Rangers] radioed into base that I had been found, that I was stable and unlikely to die.&rdquo; (page 352) They also, literally, stop and have tea with the locals, which you wouldn&rsquo;t do with a dying man. Finally, when Luttrell makes it back to the base, instead of flatlining...</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;.<em>..I tried to stand unassisted. I turned to the doc and looked him in the eye, and I told him, &lsquo;I walked on here, and I&rsquo;m walking off, by myself. I&rsquo;m hurt, but I&rsquo;m still a SEAL, and they haven&rsquo;t finished me. I&rsquo;m walking.</em>&rdquo; (page 357)</p>
<p><strong><a name="2"></a>Which Local Afghan Found Luttrell?</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">After the battle, according to the book, Luttrell is found by a local man named Sarawa, who also tends to his wounds. &ldquo;I saw the leader walk up to me. He smiled and said his name was Sarawa.&rdquo; (page 282)</p>
<p dir="ltr">According to the film, a local man named Gulab rescues him:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<em>A 30 year old male GULAB, the leader, strong rugged handsome, steps forward. Hands up in peace.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>GULAB: Not Taliban.</em>&rdquo; (page 110)</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/news/survivor-60-minutes/" target="_blank">According to Luttrell&rsquo;s 60 Minutes interview</a>, &ldquo;That&rsquo;s when an Afghan man appeared. Luttrell later learned his name was Mohammad Gulab.&rdquo; Luttrell might have changed this detail to protect Gulab from retribution, but Gulab is mentioned by name later in the memoir.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="3"></a>Marcus Luttrell is Almost Beheaded by Ahmad Shah&rsquo;s Soldiers</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">In the film, Ahmad Shah (or his lieutenant Taraq) comes to the village, grabs Luttrell, and drags him out to a log to behead him, literally raising a machete in the air. Luttrell is saved at the last minute by the local villagers, who fire off their AK-47s to threaten the attackers.</p>
<p dir="ltr">This doesn&rsquo;t occur in the film&rsquo;s screenplay. On page 115, Taraq, one of Ahmad Shah&rsquo;s lieutenants, puts a knife to Luttrell&rsquo;s throat in the room where he is staying, then the villagers stop him.</p>
<p dir="ltr">In reality, none of this happened. The Taliban does enter Luttrell&rsquo;s room and begins beating him. (As Luttrell describes it, &ldquo;I didn&rsquo;t give that much of a shit. I can suck this kind of crap up, like I&rsquo;ve been trained. Anyway, they didn&rsquo;t have a decent punch among them.&rdquo; page 294) The village elder then enters the room, and commands the Taliban to leave. The whole ordeal takes about six hours. As Luttrell explains, his life was never in danger:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<em>I found out later [the village elder] was forbidding [the Taliban] from taking me away. I think they knew that before they came, otherwise I&rsquo;d probably have been gone by then...They hardly said a word while this powerful little figure laid down the law. Tribal law, I guess&hellip;</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;Upon the departure of the village elder, six hours after they&rsquo;d arrived...the Taliban suddenly decided to leave</em>.&rdquo; (page 297)</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="4"></a>Marcus Luttrell Pulls A Bullet From His Leg</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">In the film, Luttrell removes a bullet from his leg. According to my recollection of seeing the film, Luttrell does this himself after a young boy gets him a knife. According to the script, Gulab helps:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<em>Gruesome bullet removing sequence. Blood. Screaming digging scraping out bullets and shrapnel from Luttrell&rsquo;s back and legs. Gulab digs with a knife. Pours water on the wounds. The little boy holds Luttrell&rsquo;s hands and whispers to him.</em>&rdquo; (page 119)</p>
<p dir="ltr">According to the book, none of this happens. As soon as they reach the village, the locals give him medical aid. And there&rsquo;s no bullet to be found:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;.<em>..watching as Sarawa went to work. He carefully cleaned the wounds to my leg, confirming what I had suspected, that there was no bullet lodged in my left thigh. Indeed, he located the bullet&rsquo;s exit&hellip;</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;Then he took out a small surgical instrument and began pulling metal shrapnel out of my leg. He spent a long time getting rid of every shard from that RPG he could find.</em>&rdquo; (page 290)</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="5"></a>How the Afghans Alerted the Military</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">In the film, an old man heads over a mountain to alert the military to Luttrell&rsquo;s location. In the script:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<em>MARINE: We&rsquo;ve got a report of a letter asking for assistance.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;COMMANDER: From who?</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;MARINE: Marcus Luttrell. Sir, they did a hand writing comparison and its [sic] does appear to be Luttrell.</em>&rdquo; (page 119)</p>
<p dir="ltr">In the book, the village elder walks to Asadabad to alert the military to Luttrell&rsquo;s presence, but that&rsquo;s ultimately not how the military found fim. Instead, Luttrell uses a radio air-dropped by the military:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<em>Before we left, I asked them how the hell they&rsquo;d found me. And it turned out to be my emergency beacon in the window of the little rock house in the mountain.</em>&rdquo; (page 351)</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em>60 Minutes</em> tells a similar story. &ldquo;He was finally rescued by U.S. forces who had been scouring the mountains.&rdquo;</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="6"></a>The Final Battle from <em>Lone Survivor</em> (Film)</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) ends with the village of Kandish fending off a Taliban attack in a gigantic firefight. From the script:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<em>The two men staring at each other as an incoming RPG slams into the house. Huge explosion.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;Frantic screaming from outside...Luttrell grabbing his vest and gun moving out just as a 2nd RPG detonates destroying the rest of Gulab&rsquo;s house&hellip;</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;Taraq attacks with his men.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em> &ldquo;Brutal fight. Hand to hand, gun to gun. Gulab shot, Marcus shot again</em>.&rdquo; (page 121)</p>
<p dir="ltr">This fight continues, with a Marcus Luttrell sequence we&rsquo;ll get to in the next section, until American planes and helicopters comes to the rescue.</p>
<p dir="ltr">In <em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir) or reality, none of this happened. Gulab&rsquo;s house isn&rsquo;t destroyed, nor do the Taliban ever fire shots into the village. Gulab isn&rsquo;t shot and Marcus isn&rsquo;t shot again.</p>
<p dir="ltr">On page 336, it seems like the Taliban is going to attack, and Luttrell prepares for a firefight. But instead of attacking, they shoot bullets into the air, to scare the villagers. The most important reason is why they don&rsquo;t attack: the Taliban can&rsquo;t afford to lose the support of the villagers. Luttrell makes this very clear in the memoir:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<em>And then we both heard the opening bursts of gunfire, high up in the village.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;There was a lot of it. Too much. The sheer volume of fire was ridiculous, unless the Taliban were planning to wipe out the entire population of Sabray. And I knew they would not consider that because such a slaughter would surely end all support from these tribal villages up here in the mountains.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;No, they would not do that. They wanted me, but they would never kill another hundred Afghan people...in order to get me&hellip;</em>(page 339)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<em>...[the Taliban] would not risk causing major disruption to the day-to-day lives of the people. I&rsquo;d been [in Sabray] for five nights now and...and the Taliban had crossed the boundaries of Sabray only twice&hellip;</em>&rdquo; (page 341)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Later, Ahmad Shah and his men actually find Luttrell and Gulab on a flat field on the edge of the village. Do they attack? No. Why?</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<em>The presence of Gulab made it a complete standoff, and [Shah] was not about to call in his guys to shoot the oldest son of Sabray&rsquo;s village elder.</em>&rdquo; (page 345)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Gulab and Ahmad Shah actually have a discussion at this point, then Shah leaves.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="7"></a>Did Luttrell Stab Someone with a Knife at the End of Operation Red Wings?</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">In the film, as a battle rages on in the village, Marcus Luttrell stabs an attacker with a knife:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<em>The Taliban is on top of Luttrell, choking him, killing him. Luttrell&rsquo;s hands claw at the man, digging into earth, grasping for wood, a stone, anything&hellip;.when...a KNIFE, is slapped into Luttrell&rsquo;s hand&hellip;</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>&ldquo;Marcus buries the knife into the neck of the fighter.</em>&rdquo; (page 122)</p>
<p dir="ltr">In <em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir), Luttrell never writes about attacking an enemy combatant while he&rsquo;s being rescued. I can&rsquo;t even find a relevant page from <em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir) to dispute it because it diverges so radically from the book.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="8"></a>Luttrell is Rescued by U.S. Military</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">In the film, the military comes to the rescue of Luttrell in a roar of gunships and men descending from helicopters:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<em>We see gunners targeting. The 40mm firing with extreme precision...Air Force Search and Rescue Helicopter airmen charge out of the chopper toward Luttrell.</em>&rdquo; (page 122)</p>
<p dir="ltr">In the book, the Rangers find Luttrell in the forest as he and Gulab walk back to the village after Gulab spoke with Ahmad Shah.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<em>But right behind him, bursting through the undergrowth, came two U.S. Army Rangers in combat uniform, rifles raised...Behind me, with unbelievable presence of mind, Gulab was roaring out my BUD/S class numbers he&rsquo;d seen on my Trident voodoo tattoo: &ldquo;Two-two-eight! It&rsquo;s Two-two-eight!&rdquo;...</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;By this time there was chaos on the mountain. Army guys were coming out of the forest from all over the place...</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;They moved into action immediately. An army captain ordered a team to get me up out of the forest, onto higher ground&hellip;</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;The atmosphere was unavoidably cheerful, because all the guys felt their mission was accomplished&hellip;</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;The army threw up a security perimeter all the way around Sabray.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;The guys rustled up some tea and we settled down for a detailed debriefing.</em>&rdquo; (page 348-352)</p>
<p dir="ltr">I included all of these quotes above to clarify how safe Luttrell was once he was rescued. Again, they had time for tea.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="9"></a>Gulab Doesn&rsquo;t Stay Behind in Salar Ban</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">In the film <em>Lone Survivor</em>, Gulab stays behind after Luttrell leaves. From page 123 of the script, &ldquo;The US Airmen separate Marcus from Gulab, Marcus is too weak to resist...Gulab steps back as the helicopter takes off.&rdquo; (page 123)</p>
<p>In the book, he joins Luttrell on the helicopter ride. &ldquo;The guys helped me into the [helicopter] cabin, and Gulab joined me.&rdquo;</p>
<h3 dir="ltr"><a name="10"></a>The Mistakes or Exaggerations</h3>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="11"></a>Number of Afghan Fighters Who Attacked the SEALs?</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Simply put, the SEALs on the hill that day were overwhelmed by an enemy force with superior numbers and superior fire power that held the high ground. However, there is a huge difference between an 8-10 men squad-sized enemy force and a 200 man infantry company-sized enemy force. Frankly, the Korengal and Shuryak valleys--the geographic region of Operation Red Wings--are very sparsely populated and could not support an enemy force of 200 people. This discrepancy is what first piqued our curiosity in <em>Lone Survivor</em>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Increasing the size of the enemy that day makes for a much, much better story though. Numbers sell, and as <em>Lone Survivor</em> became more popular, the size of the enemy force that day increased with each telling. (Interestingly, the Lieutenant Murphy&rsquo;s Medal of Honor Citation and Summary of Action contradict each other.) Here are the various descriptions of the number of enemy that attacked:</p>
<p dir="ltr">Accurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Ed Darack in Victory Point: 8-10 enemy with a machine gun</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Luttrell After Action Report: 20-30 enemy</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Lt. Murphy Medal of Honor Citation: 30-40 enemy</p>
<p dir="ltr">Inaccurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Lt. Murphy Medal of Honor Summary of Action: over 50 enemy</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Marcus Luttrell on Today Show: 80-100 members of the Taliban</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir): 140-200 enemy</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Marcus Luttrell speeches after <em>Lone Survivor</em>: 200 enemy</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (screenplay): 50 enemy. &ldquo;A solid line of at least fifty Taliban in firing positions on top of the hill above them.&rdquo; (page 80)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Other various media outlets</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="12"></a>Estimated Size of Ahmad Shah&rsquo;s Enemy Force Before Operation Red Wings? </strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">While any intelligence efforts in Afghanistan are fraught with confusion, before Operation Red Wings, the marines in Kunar believed Ahmad Shah led up to 20 people, according to Ed Darack. In <em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir), this balloons to 200 people, an unreasonably large size. Here the various descriptions which exaggerate the size of Ahmad Shah&rsquo;s &ldquo;army&rdquo;.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Accurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Ed Darack in Marine Corps Gazette: up to 20 enemy combatants</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) screenplay: &ldquo;we are estimating ten men&rdquo; (page 18)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Inaccurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir): Shah led 80-200 enemy combatants</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) trailer: &ldquo;that&rsquo;s a lot more than ten guys. That&rsquo;s an army.&rdquo;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) screenplay: &ldquo;Quick shots of the Taliban army. Feels like 150 men.&rdquo; (page 74)</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="13"></a>Ahmad Shah: Major al Qaeda Leader or Osama bin Laden Lieutenant?</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Ahmad Shah was an insurgent leader in Afghanistan, which is why the marines in the Pech launched Operation Red Wings. However, there is a huge difference between a local, Afghan insurgent leader and an al Qaeda operative. Prior to Operation Red Wings, Ahmad Shah was not a member of al Qaeda and had never met Osama bin Laden.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Accurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Lt. Murphy Medal of Honor citation: &ldquo;a high-level, anti-coalition militia leader&rdquo;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Lt. Murphy Medal of Honor Summary of Action: &ldquo;Shah led a guerrilla group known to locals as the "Mountain Tigers" that had aligned with the Taliban and other militant groups close to the Pakistani border.&rdquo;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> trailer: &ldquo;senior Taliban commander&rdquo;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px;" dir="ltr">* See below for discussion of term &ldquo;Taliban&rdquo;</p>
<p dir="ltr">Inaccurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir): &ldquo;a leader of a serious Taliban force&rdquo; (page 178); &ldquo;He was also known to be one of Osama bin Laden&rsquo;s closest associates.&rdquo; (page 179)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) award website: &ldquo;a high-level al Qaeda operative&rdquo;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em><span id="docs-internal-guid-168f6e27-56af-1e45-076e-03a7d222e8d9">Lone Survivor</span></em> (film) Production Notes, Site and Universal Award website: &ldquo;a high-level al Qaeda operative&rdquo;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Other various media outlets</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="14"></a>The Number of Marines Killed by Ahmad Shah Before Operation Red Wings? </strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">This is a mistake we didn&rsquo;t identify in our initial post on the <em>Lone Survivor</em> memoir because Luttrell didn&rsquo;t make a specific claim on how many people Shah had killed in the time before Operation Red Wings. The film <em>Lone Survivor</em> does make the claim in multiple places that Shah killed 20 marines in the week before Operation Red Wings. As iCasualties.org clearly shows--and have no doubt that US military casualties are meticulously recorded--the U.S. had not lost 20 marines in the week before Operation Red Wings.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Further, as mentioned above and in Darack&rsquo;s reporting, Shah was a local player, not a regional leader. Kandahar is hundreds of miles from Kunar, and well outside Shah&rsquo;s area of operations.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Accurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">iCasualty.org: No marines died in Kandahar in the week before Operation Red Wings. Only 3 U.S. soldiers or marines died in 2005 before Operation Red Wings.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Ed Darack in Victory Point: Shah was linked to 11 attacks.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Inaccurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir): : &ldquo;...suffice it to say [Ahmad Shah] was a serious Taliban force, a sinister mountain man known to make forays into cities and known to have been directly responsible for several lethal attacks on U.S. Marines, always with bombs...had already murdered many of my colleagues in the U.S. Marines.&rdquo; (page 179)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">60 Minutes interview with Marcus Luttrell: &ldquo;He was killing Marines, Army, I mean, you name it.&rdquo;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> trailer 1: &ldquo;Shah killed twenty marines last week. Twenty.&rdquo;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> trailer 2: &ldquo;Shah killed twenty marines last week. We let him go, 40 more will die next week.&rdquo;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) screenplay: &ldquo;Shah just killed twenty marines last week&hellip;&rdquo; (page 51)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="15"></a>Did the SEALs Take a Vote on What to Do with the Goatherders? </strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">This is the most publicized mistake in the memoir <em>Lone Survivor</em>. Lieutenant Michael Murphy&rsquo;s family specifically and publicly refuted Luttrell&rsquo;s account that the SEALs took a vote and that Luttrell cast the deciding vote on what to do. In his 60 Minutes interview, Luttrell appears to retract his account, without admitting the error in his book.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Accurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Peter Berg in The Q&amp;A Podcast: &ldquo;Mike Murphy made that decision. There wasn&rsquo;t a vote.&rdquo; (minute 00:54:00)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> screenplay: No vote takes place.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> trailer: &ldquo;This is not a vote.&rdquo;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (film): No vote takes place.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">60 Minutes: &ldquo;Luttrell told us the unit discussed what to do and were divided. &nbsp;In the past he&rsquo;s been criticized for saying they took a vote&hellip; something that&rsquo;s not supposed to happen in SEAL teams because it&rsquo;s up to the team leader to make a decision.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;Anderson Cooper: What did Mike finally decide to do?</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;Marcus Luttrell: Oh, we cut 'em loose.&rdquo;</p>
<p dir="ltr">Inaccurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir): &ldquo;The deciding vote was mine and it will haunt me till they rest me in an east Texas grave. Mikey nodded, &lsquo;I guess that&rsquo;s two votes to one...&rsquo;&rdquo; (page 207)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Marcus Luttrell on the Today Show: Agrees with Matt Lauer when he says, &ldquo;You took a vote.&rdquo;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Marcus Luttrell&rsquo;s personal website: &ldquo;After taking a vote and basing their decision on ROE, Michael Murphy made the final decision to let them go.&rdquo;</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="16"></a>Who Planned and Led Operation Red Wings?</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">This mistake is primarily a gigantic sin of omission in the <em>Lone Survivor</em> film and a sin of misdirection in the <em>Lone Survivor</em> memoir, which almost entirely ignores the role of marines in conceiving, planning and leading Operation Red Wings. The marines brought in SEALs to gain access to aviation support.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Accurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Ed Darack in Marine Corps Gazette: &ldquo;but 2/3 sought the integration of only a SOF aviation support element, not ground forces. The SOTF...responded that 2/3 could be granted 160th support, but only if SOF ground personnel undertook the opening two phases of RED WINGS and were tasked as the lead, supported elements with full OPCON (inclusive of 2/3) for these phases. With no alternatives, battalion staff agreed...The NAVSOF element planned the specifics of these first two phases of RED WINGS with 2/3&rsquo;s staff providing input...&rdquo;</p>
<p dir="ltr">Inaccurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir): &ldquo;Almost every morning Chief Healy would run the main list of potential targets past Mikey, our team officer, and me. He usually gave us papers with a list of maybe twenty names and possible locations, and we made a short list of the guys we considered we should go after.&rdquo; (page 179)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (film): No mention of larger Marine mission. No mention of SEALs finding their own targets.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="17"></a>What was the Name of the Operation? </strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">This is the most corrected mistake from Luttrell&rsquo;s <em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir). The name of the mission was &ldquo;Operation Red Wings&rdquo;, a fact supported by the Medal of Honor citation, Summary of Action, the U.S. Navy and every other source that didn&rsquo;t rely on Marcus Luttrell&rsquo;s original memoir for information. This fact was corrected by Peter Berg in his film. [Update 4 Jan 2014: Marcus Luttrell, in a documentary released on HBO this week, once again referred to "Operation Red Wing".]</p>
<p dir="ltr">Accurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Lt. Murphy Medal of Honor Citation and Summary of Action, Victory Point, <em>Lone Survivor</em> (film), and <a href="http://marcusluttrell.com/bio/">Marcus Luttrell&rsquo;s personal website</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Inaccurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir) (from a copy purchased in December): &ldquo;The Eyewitness Account of Operation Redwing&rdquo;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Will of the Warrior</em> documentary (released 4 Jan 2014): <span id="docs-internal-guid-602ee0ff-5e40-b066-ba0d-9dea4ff5d331">&rdquo;The book is the debrief...If you have any questions about what happened in Operations Red Wing, there it is right there.&rdquo;</span></p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="18"></a>The Name of the Village</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Probably for security reasons, Luttrell changed the name of the village to from Kandish to Sabray. According to Ed Darack&rsquo;s <em>Victory Point</em>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operation_Red_Wings#Afghans_who_aided_Luttrell">the name of Gulab&rsquo;s village is Salar Ban</a>.<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operation_Red_Wings#Afghans_who_aided_Luttrell"></a></p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="19"></a>Ahmad Shah, Member of the Taliban? </strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">The media and advertisements for <em>Lone Survivor</em> repeatedly refers to Ahmad Shah as a Taliban leader. In reality, the truth comes closest to the U.S. Navy&rsquo;s Medal of Honor Summary of Action that Shah was &ldquo;aligned&rdquo; with the Taliban and other militant groups. (This same citation goes on to use Taliban interchangeably with &ldquo;insurgent&rdquo;.) As Ed Darack has written about extensively, Shah was much more closely aligned with Hezb il Gulbuddin, another insurgent group in Afghanistan. The best description is therefore &ldquo;insurgent leader&rdquo;, not Taliban leader.</p>
<p dir="ltr">In fairness to the media, Luttrell and <em>Lone Survivor</em> (film), the difference between insurgent groups in Afghanistan is a nuance the vast most do not understand. In fact, many if not most soldiers, don&rsquo;t understand the difference. For instance, even I made this mistake as a young platoon leader in Afghanistan, describing all insurgents as &ldquo;Taliban&rdquo; when most in my area of operations were not.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="20"></a>How many Insurgents Died During Operation Red Wings? </strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Multiple accounts--including the U.S. Navy--have put forward extremely high enemy casualty accounts during the battle between the SEALs and Shah&rsquo;s men. The key here is that both the U.S. Navy and Luttrell claim the SEALs killed 35 enemy, not created 35 casualties (which includes dead and wounded).</p>
<p dir="ltr">The reality is that we will probably never know exactly how many insurgents died on the Sawtalo Sar that day. That said, the number of casualties sustained by the enemy, at the least, could not have exceeded the number of enemy involved in the fight. Further, if 50 insurgents attacked, then 35 dead insurgents means the SEALs killed 70% of the opposing force, which is virtually unheard of in warfare.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Inaccurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Washington Post article about Marcus Luttrell: 35 bodies on the ground</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">U.S. Navy Summary of Action: &ldquo;An estimated 35 Taliban were also dead.&rdquo;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir): &ldquo;We must have killed fifty or more of them&rdquo; (page 221)</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (film): At least 23 enemy are killed (from The Q&amp;A with Jeff Goldsmith)</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="21"></a>Cellular phone or satellite phone?</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">The SEAL team inserted into the ridge line with a radio and a back up satellite phone as an emergency. Marcus Luttrell&rsquo;s memoir refers to this phone as a &ldquo;cell phone&rdquo; throughout the book. This mistake has been corrected in the upcoming film.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Accurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) screenplay, trailer and film</p>
<p dir="ltr">Inaccurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir)</p>
<p><strong><a name="22"></a>Ahmad Shah versus Ben Sharmak </strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">As we&rsquo;ve covered before, Luttrell changed the name of the operation&rsquo;s target from Ahmad Shah to Ben Sharmak for security purposes. The name &ldquo;Ben Sharmak&rdquo; only appears in <em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir).</p>
<p id="docs-internal-guid-168f6e27-646d-e5ba-fef7-ab3da04e8a8b" dir="ltr"><strong><a name="25"></a>Billy Shelton Was Not a Green Beret</strong></p>
<p>Lone Survivor (memoir) spends much more time than the film describing Luttrell&rsquo;s childhood and training in the lead up to Operation Red Wings. One of the men who figures prominently in his early life is a local man named Billy Shelton, who helped prepare the Luttrell boys for SEAL training. Luttrell and Robinson describe him as a former Special Forces soldier who served in Vietnam. This was not the case. (We believe that this mistake was not Luttrell&rsquo;s fault, but his editor should have fact checked the account.)</p>
<p id="docs-internal-guid-168f6e27-646e-0d1b-84ab-3641642097fe" dir="ltr">Accurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em><a href="http://thisainthell.us/blog/?p=18988">This Ain&rsquo;t Hell</a></em>: &ldquo;Well, it adds a nice dimension to the story, but unfortunately, Billy Shelton had been lying to the Luttrell brothers &ndash; he&rsquo;d never been in the Special Forces. According to records, Specialist Five Shelton was a truck driver and a general&rsquo;s chauffeur at Fort Eustis, Virginia....</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;No Special Operations training, no jump school, not even a CIB.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Inaccurate accounts:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (memoir): &ldquo;...a former Green Beret sergeant who lived close by. His name was Billy Shelton&hellip;Billy had a glittering army career in combat with the Green Berets in Vietnam and, later, serving on a government SWAT team.&rdquo; (page 55)</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="24"></a>Updates</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr"><em>[Update, 4 Jan. 2014: We've updated the post to add a quote from the documentary </em>Will of the Warrior<em> to the section, "<a href="http://www.onviolence.com#17">What was the Name of the Operation?</a>".</em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><em>Update 5 Jan 2014: We've updated the post to add the section, "<a href="http://www.onviolence.com#25">Billy Shelton Was Not a Green Beret</a>".]</em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><a name="23"></a>References:</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><span id="docs-internal-guid-168f6e27-56c2-1419-1141-2fd67aac9c75">&ldquo;</span><a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=234" target="_blank">He Got the Title Wrong? And Six More Mistakes from Luttrell&rsquo;s Lone Survivor</a>&rdquo;, OnViolence.com</p>
<p id="docs-internal-guid-168f6e27-56c2-3689-812c-3258eca87069" style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=758%20" target="_blank">Bad, Bad Ahmad Shah...the Baddest Shah in the Whole Damn Village</a>&rdquo;, OnViolence.com&nbsp;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=514" target="_blank">Marcus Luttrell Stands By His Mistakes: An Update to Our Lone Survivor Week</a>&rdquo;, OnViolence.com</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=759" target="_blank">Luttrell No Longer Stands by His Mistakes: Lone Survivor vs. the 60 Minutes Interview</a>&rdquo;, OnViolence.com</p>
<p id="docs-internal-guid-168f6e27-56c2-8cf9-653b-a5d66868c18b" style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<a href="http://www.darack.com/sawtalosar/ED-DARACK-RED-WINGS-MISINFORMATION.pdf" target="_blank">OPERATION RED WINGS &ndash; What Really Happened?</a>&rdquo; by Ed Darack, Marine Corps Gazette, January 2011</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<a href="http://www.darack.com/sawtalosar/misinformation.php" target="_blank">Misinformation page</a>&rdquo;, Darack.com</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<a href="http://www.darack.com/sawtalosar/%20" target="_blank">Sawtalo Sar</a> page&rdquo;, Darack.com</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.navy.mil/moh/mpmurphy/oc.html" target="_blank">Lieutenant Mike Murphy Medal of Honor Official Citation</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.navy.mil/moh/mpmurphy/soa.html%20" target="_blank">Lieutenant Mike Murphy Medal of Honor Summary of Action</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.lonesurvivorfilm.com/site" target="_blank"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) website</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/universal/lonesurvivor/" target="_blank"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) Trailers</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.universalpicturesawards.com/main/title/loneSurvivor%20"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) Universal Award Site</a> including synopsis and screenplay&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.lonesurvivorfilm.com/assets/img/LONESURVIVOR_productionnotes.pdf"><em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) Production Notes</a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.theqandapodcast.com/2013/12/lone-survivor-q.html" target="_blank">The Q&amp;A Podcast</a> featuring Lone Survivor (film) and Peter Berg</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">Today Show appearance by Marcus Luttrell on June 12th, 2007. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=irC4K7Q4JCo" target="_blank">Accessed via this Youtube video</a>.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">&ldquo;<a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2007/06/10/AR2007061001492_2.html" target="_blank">The Sole Survivor</a>&rdquo;, WashingtonPost.com, June 10th, 2007</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://marcusluttrell.com/bio/" target="_blank" id="docs-internal-guid-168f6e27-56c2-ab4f-825b-0f09c6e900df">MarcusLuttrell.com</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/OnViolence/~4/Pr7FgJlFayY" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="694c7368acf59ac32e4bc1b2b3a9274b" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/OnViolence/~3/VW9yrHU1HrQ/"><![CDATA[<p id="docs-internal-guid-608abf9c-0dcc-79d0-304a-5602cf434daf" dir="ltr"><em>(To read all of our </em>Lone Survivor <em>posts,<a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=230"> please click here</a>.)</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Before I start my review of <em>Lone Survivor</em> (film), I have some caveats:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">- First, the one, lingering problem with the Lone Survivor film is that it will lead people to read the Lone Survivor book. <a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=238">You know how we feel about that</a>.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">- Second, the movie is about Navy SEALs, the &ldquo;quiet professionals&rdquo; who have way too much publicity. Expect more posts on this next year.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">- Third, Michael C hasn&rsquo;t seen the film, so their could be glaring military inaccuracies I would miss.</p>
<p dir="ltr">That said, I&rsquo;ll get straight my thesis: I loved <em>Lone Survivor</em> until the ending. I think <em>Lone Survivor</em> is one of the greatest war films ever made, with brutal, excruciating action sequences and great acting. But the ending is so egregiously wrong and over-the-top, I almost can&rsquo;t recommend it.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Some specifics. Peter Berg shot the action very realistically, with the SEALs sighting their enemies through their rifles and taking them down systematically and professionally. I&rsquo;ve never seen this type of directing before, and it absolutely works. It&rsquo;s the type of war film that will make past war films--even the great ones--look dated.</p>
<p dir="ltr">As the battle gets more intense, so does the pain you feel. To escape their attackers, the SEALs literally jump off a cliff. Their falls are some of the best, most-realistic and brutal sequences I&rsquo;ve ever seen on film. Literally, the audience I watched it with cringed with each fall. It makes you physically move in your chair. On the basis of these sequences alone, I would recommend the film.</p>
<p dir="ltr">What else can I write? The film looks gorgeous, shot with small, handheld cameras but not in a way that brings attention to itself. The acting is tremendous, particularly Ben Foster and Emile Hirsch, who just nail their scenes. I&rsquo;m not a huge Mark Wahlberg fan, but he&rsquo;s good in this role.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Technically, the film is a masterpiece.</p>
<p dir="ltr">But.</p>
<p dir="ltr">But the ending is horrendous, for reasons I&rsquo;ll describe later in a much longer post. Peter Berg essentially made up the ending. He took an already inaccurate book, corrected most of those mistakes, then got to the end and was like, &ldquo;Screw it, I&rsquo;m making something up.&rdquo; And the changes are cliched and ridiculous.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;d recommend seeing <em>Lone Survivor</em> when it airs on cable. But when Marcus Luttrell gets rescued after the firefight, you can press stop, and watch something else. As Michael C pointed out to me, it&rsquo;s like the inverse <em>Zero Dark Thirty</em>. (<a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=751" target="_blank">We recommend skipping the first hour of that film</a>.)</p>
<p>So yes, <em>Lone Survivor</em> is an incredible, but flawed, piece of filmmaking.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/OnViolence/~4/VW9yrHU1HrQ" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5e3320e34f77eb5bb6963fdc9b14c35" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/OnViolence/~3/xGlguuIKVM8/"><![CDATA[<p id="docs-internal-guid-7560ab3b-bd8f-d01b-2ed0-532c950e49b9" dir="ltr"><em>(To check out other &ldquo;On V Updates to Old Ideas&rdquo;, <a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=482%20" target="_blank">please click here</a>.)</em></p>
<p>Before last month&rsquo;s &ldquo;On V Update to Old Ideas&rdquo; post, we hadn&rsquo;t run one in months, but we&rsquo;ve been collecting links the whole time. Prepare for a bunch of updates, sorted by theme. Today&rsquo;s theme? Money.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>We Don&rsquo;t Need a Sequester to Waste Money</strong></p>
<p>Secretary of Defense Chuck Hagel warned that if the sequester went through, it would force the military to implement blunt budget cuts, which would waste money and (hypothetically) harm our soldiers in the future. (The go-to argument for anyone defending the military.) He neglected to mention that the Pentagon routinely makes terrible financial decisions. For instance...</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">...the Army is now <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/worldviews/wp/2013/06/20/the-u-s-military-is-scrapping-up-to-2000-of-its-mine-resistant-vehicles-which-cost-1-million-each/" target="_blank">literally junking the mine resistant vehicles</a> that it spent billions shipping to Afghanistan instead of shipping them home.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/worldviews/wp/2013/06/20/the-u-s-military-is-scrapping-up-to-2000-of-its-mine-resistant-vehicles-which-cost-1-million-each/"></a></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">...the Army is <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/a-brand-new-us-military-headquarters-in-afghanistan-and-nobody-to-use-it/2013/07/09/2bb73728-e8cd-11e2-a301-ea5a8116d211_print.html" target="_blank">constructing a headquarters building in Afghanistan</a>, costing millions per month, which it plans to leave vacant.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">...as it prepares to leave Afghanistan, an Inspector General report <a href="http://www.wired.com/dangerroom/2013/07/afghanistan-audits-reveal-billions-in-u-s-taxpayer-waste/%20" target="_blank">found billions of dollars in waste</a> in only three months.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr">...Air Force officer Dan Ward writes that military contracting is so poorly managed, <a href="https://medium.com/war-is-boring/d90703424873" target="_blank">we don&rsquo;t even know how bad we are at it</a>.</p>
<p>When the military does contracting this bad, no one wins. Oh, except for defense contractors. They make lots of money. To fix the system, one assumes we need strong civilian leadership to rein in Generals and Admirals. Unfortunately, President Obama <a href="http://www.wired.com/dangerroom/2013/08/obama-nominates-defense-contractor-executive-as-air-force-secretary/" target="_blank">nominated military industry executive</a> Deborah Lee James as Secretary of the Air Force. The revolving door between government and contractors continues to spin.</p>
<p dir="ltr">It also turns out that defense spending doesn&rsquo;t provide the economic benefits many claim. Blogger, professor and <a href="http://drezner.foreignpolicy.com/category/wordpress_tag/zombies">zombie aficionado</a> Dan Drezner has a new paper that <a href="http://drezner.foreignpolicy.com/not_enough_bang_for_the_bucks" target="_blank">debunks the idea that American military spending provides economic benefits</a> to the world or America.</p>
<p dir="ltr">And that go-to-defense of military spending, &ldquo;that it will hurt our men and women in uniform&rdquo;? Friend of the blog <a href="http://defense-and-freedom.blogspot.com/2013/07/military-spending-and-lifesaving.html%20" target="_blank">Sven Ortmann delivers a marvelous pieces combining economics and military budgeting</a> which debunks that notion completely. He asks, "How much should the U.S. spend to keep its soldiers safe?" and comes up with a number. For all the economists out there (or conservatives who claim to follow economics), you have to read this.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Contracting Money Influences the Debate</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Since the NSA debate has triggered a lot of journalist-on-journalist attacks, we have avoided taking sides or commenting. (If our readers want to know our takes, wait until January...) However, we absolutely agree with <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2013/aug/12/michael-hayden-nsa-media-reverence" target="_blank">Glenn Greenwald when he nailed the press</a>--particularly <em>Face the Nation</em>--for not disclosing the financial self-interest of many pro-NSA commentators to its viewers, like General Michael Hayden, former director of the NSA under President Bush. From Greenwald:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;But worse than the omission of Hayden's NSA history is his current - and almost always unmentioned - financial stake in the very policies he is being invited to defend. Hayden is a partner in the Chertoff Group, a private entity that makes more and more money by increasing the fear levels of the US public and engineering massive government security contracts for their clients. Founded by former Homeland Security secretary Michael Chertoff, it's filled with former national security state officials who exploit their connections in and knowledge of Washington to secure hugely profitable government contracts for their clients."</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">As we wrote in <a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=744%20" target="_blank">our coverage of <em>Zero Dark Thirty</em></a> and <em><a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=743" target="_blank">Argo</a></em>, many government officials exaggerate the threat of terrorism. While they sincerely believe in their work, they also have financial interests to do so.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>An Update to Doing Aid Right</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://matadornetwork.com/change/7-worst-international-aid-ideas/" target="_blank">While this article on &ldquo;The Matador Network&rdquo; seems like a Reddit link bait scam</a>, it accurately explains why dropping bombs of free t-shirts and shoes (as TOMS does) is terrible aid policy. The best part about the TOMS story is that I swear my entire business school loves TOMS. Literally, business school students take economics in one class, then give a presentation during communications advocating the TOMS model.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I, (Michael C), say this criticism as a solid moderate. I just think <a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=241" target="_blank">we should do aid/government/business</a> <a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=239" target="_blank">efficiently and effectively</a>. While business has built-in mechanisms for that, aid and government don't. The podcast <em><a href="http://www.tinyspark.org/" target="_blank">Tiny Spark</a></em> had done great work critiquing foreign aid, with a recent episode on <a href="http://www.tinyspark.org/podcasts/tracking-sachs/" target="_blank">Jeffrey Sachs&rsquo; Millenium Villages</a>. I&rsquo;ve advocated before for renewed U.S. foreign aid spending. I still want that, but our government must do it right, using controlled experiments, analyzing data and spreading it liberally.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Why Does the U.S. Keeps Sending Weapons to Egypt?</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Because of <a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=111" target="_blank">defense contractors</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Before Syria replaced Egypt in the news, there was a lot of discussion about U.S. aid to that specific country. For a primer and explanation on why that aid doesn&rsquo;t make a lot of sense--because most of the money spent on Egypt goes to American defense contractors--<a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2013/08/23/214928040/episode-482-why-the-u-s-keeps-sending-weapons-to-egypt%20">listen to this excellent <em>Planet Money</em> episode</a>, then shake your head.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/OnViolence/~4/xGlguuIKVM8" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="44e47b6b35748b5ae80a7709ed8bc57" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/OnViolence/~3/y8M3Zsz6A5Q/"><![CDATA[<p id="docs-internal-guid-4eecf32b-6dbf-c331-b2f8-bcfc043a66b8" dir="ltr"><em>(Normally, we start the year with our &ldquo;Most Intriguing Event of the Year&rdquo;. But since Lone Survivor hits theaters across the country on January 10th, we&rsquo;re devoting this week to that topic.</em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><em>To read all of our </em>Lone Survivor<em> posts, <a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=230" target="_blank">please click here</a>. The most important post is "<a href="http://www.onviolence.com/?e=762">A List of the Mistakes and Differences Between Lone Survivor (Film), Lone Survivor (Book) and Reality</a>" so read that first if you are new to the blog or this topic.)</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Michael C and I have actually been kind of surprised (and pleased) at the overwhelmingly positive response to last Thursday&rsquo;s post, &ldquo;<a href="http://www.onviolence.com/?e=762" target="_blank">A List of the Differences Between <em>Lone Survivor</em> (Film), <em>Lone Survivor</em> (Book) and Reality</a>&rdquo;. Like any widely-shared post, we&rsquo;ve also received some criticism. Mostly the two criticisms are, first, &ldquo;Does this matter?&rdquo; (We&rsquo;ll address that criticism tomorrow.) The second most common criticism we&rsquo;ve received is:</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Everyone knows movies aren&rsquo;t real!</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">For example, from Jay, &ldquo;It&rsquo;s a movie made for entertainment. No one should walk away and think &lsquo;now I know what it was like on the ground.&rsquo;&rdquo; Or from Juan on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/DoctrineMan" target="_blank">Doctrine Man&rsquo;s Facebook page</a>, &ldquo;Just a simple thought. If you go to the movies to learn history lessons, then you might want to consider going back to school...&rdquo; Or from Rick, also on Doctrine Man&rsquo;s Facebook page, &ldquo;anyone who looks to Hollywood for truth has other problems&rdquo;.</p>
<p dir="ltr">To this criticism, I have five rebuttals:</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>1. Lone Survivor is being marketed as a film that captures &ldquo;the essential experience&rdquo; of those SEALs.</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.lonesurvivorfilm.com/assets/img/LONESURVIVOR_productionnotes.pdf" target="_blank">From the &ldquo;Production Notes&rdquo; distributed to all major film reviewers</a>:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><em>&ldquo;Although </em>Lone Survivor<em> takes the creative liberties necessary to make a movie, it is committed to preserving the essential experience of what these men endured on their mission. It is a realistic, timeless and isolated portrait of the sacrifices that one small band of warriors made...and how one survived to tell their tale.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Peter Berg has explicitly stated that he wanted to make the most accurate film possible. "I've never felt more pressure to get a film right," <a href="http://www.mensjournal.com/magazine/inside-the-making-of-lone-survivor-20131223#ixzz2pOOKTQkp" target="_blank">Berg told <em>Men&rsquo;s Journal</em></a>. Speaking with Jeff Goldsmith for the Q&amp;A, <a href="http://www.theqandapodcast.com/2013/12/lone-survivor-q.html" target="_blank">Berg brought up research multiple times</a>, &ldquo;For me, everything good that I think I&rsquo;ve ever done has come from research...For both films, research was the key.&rdquo; (Min 16:00) Berg goes on to talk, at minute 18:00, about how Luttrell choose him to turn Lone Survivor into a movie because of this attention to detail. <a href="http://www.grantland.com/blog/hollywood-prospectus/post/_/id/96079/b-s-report-peter-berg-2">Berg mentioned this research on <em>The BS Report</em> as well</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">That makes the mistakes in this film more important, not less.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>2. Film critics and the media are promoting the film as an accurate, realistic portrayal.</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Many critics and reporters have praised <em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) for its accuracy:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://bigstory.ap.org/article/review-superb-action-scenes-anchor-survivor" target="_blank">Jocelyn Noveck for the AP</a>: <em>&ldquo;...expertly rendered account of a disastrous 2005 military operation in Afghanistan...And he's executed that approach with admirable skill, down to using autopsy reports to get the number of wounds a soldier suffered exactly right.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/tv-movies/lone-survivor-peter-berg-stuck-strategy-article-1.1558204" target="_blank">Ethan Sacks for the <em>NY Daily News</em></a>: <em>&ldquo;&lsquo;Lone Survivor&rsquo; features some of the most realistic military combat scenes ever filmed.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.latimes.com/entertainment/movies/moviesnow/la-et-mn-lone-survivor-review-20131225,0,6791422.story#axzz2pYcFuyaV" target="_blank">Betsy Sharkey for the <em>Los Angeles Times</em></a><em>: &ldquo;...with a gruesome energy and a remarkable reality...The production and costume designers have paid a great deal of attention to the details, from the uniforms and tribal robes, to the bullet wounds and blood. It certainly adds to the film's verisimilitude.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;" dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.avclub.com/review/lone-survivor-comes-dangerously-close-to-glorifyin-200700" target="_blank">A.A. Dowd for <em>The AV Club</em></a><em>: &ldquo;...gruelingly committed to realism...unrelenting, hyper-real way&rdquo;</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">These reviewers--aka the experts--believed in <em>Lone Survivor</em>&rsquo;s authenticity.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>3. Most viewers who see <em>Lone Survivor</em> will accept what they see on screen as true.</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">I know this thanks to science. A study by Duke researchers shows that <a href="http://m.today.duke.edu/2012/03/movieerrors%20" target="_blank">students who watch historical films learn the inaccuracies in those films</a>, even when they&rsquo;re told to research the inaccuracies later. They still remember the mistakes, and repeat them on tests.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>4. I was fooled.</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">One of the things I <a href="http://onviolence.com/?e=760" target="_blank">initially praised about <em>Lone Survivor</em></a> was the battle scene, which was expertly done. Except, <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/scottmendelson/2013/12/18/review-lone-survivor-is-war-porn/" target="_blank">as some critics have pointed out</a>, much of that battle scene is unrealistic, or at least one-sided. Mainly, our troops--the SEALs--<a href="http://www.onviolence.com/?e=762#20" target="_blank">take down 23 enemy fighters</a>, usually with just one or two expertly placed bullets. The SEALs, on the other hand, take bullet after bullet without stopping.</p>
<p dir="ltr">As Michael C had to point out to me, this just isn&rsquo;t how war really works. A rugged Afghan mountain man will take roughly the same amount of punishment as a rugged American soldier/SEAL. In our opinion, our better trained SEALs likely shot a lot of the insurgents. But that doesn&rsquo;t mean they killed those insurgents that easily, which the movie repeatedly shows.</p>
<p dir="ltr">But I didn&rsquo;t know that when I saw the film. I thought it was perfectly accurate. As probably the most skeptical viewer of <em>Lone Survivor</em> in the country, if I got fooled, anyone could.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>5. <em>Lone Survivor</em> (film) is not accurate.</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">If a film has <a href="http://www.onviolence.com/?e=762" target="_blank">a 4,300 word blog post rebutting its inaccuracies</a>, that film didn&rsquo;t capture the &ldquo;essential experience&rdquo; of the operation. From Ahmad Shah &ldquo;killing 20 marines&rdquo; the week before Operation Red Wings to the fictionalized third act, the film gets a lot of things wrong. And viewers will remember those mistakes even though they shouldn&rsquo;t. And despite beliefs to the contrary, <em>most Americans will believe these events actually happened</em>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Most viewers will not know that Marcus Luttrell never survived a final firefight in the village that rescued him, unless they stumble upon our blog.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So feel free to shrug off the mistakes as no big deal. Or as simply, &ldquo;Hollywood&rdquo;. But know that these films will permanently misinform many, many people.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/OnViolence/~4/y8M3Zsz6A5Q" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>