<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="dish.andrewsullivan.com">
	<documents count="40">
		<document id="c22ae2c1abd3a76df29612b43d0a5dd8" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/07/a-room-more-than-his-own-npr-12-28-dont-think-video-works-moving-to-sullydish-jr/"><![CDATA[James Baldwin&#8217;s second novel, Giovanni&#8217;s Room, follows the tragic love affair of a gay American in Paris. When Chris Abani encountered the book as a bullied, unhappy adolescent, it made him feel less lonely: As the youngest of four boys, I often found it hard to come to terms with the expectations of masculinity around [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213051&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5e91eb583a93dfff0f9a100663c32ba3" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/07/another-war-we-cant-win/"><![CDATA[Derek Thompson marks the 50th anniversary of Lyndon Johnson&#8217;s war on poverty, partly blaming the problem&#8217;s stickiness on the rise of the single-parent household: The poverty rate among married couples is quite low: 6 percent. The poverty rate among single-dads/moms is quite high: 25/31 percent. Since the share of single-parent households doubled since 1950, we should expect [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213434&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e361f250447c55e5bccdd701d7b5d838" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/07/do-humans-pass-the-smell-test/"><![CDATA[It&#8217;s no surprise that dogs can identify their owners by smell, but can people sniff out their pets? Researchers at The Queen’s University of Belfast put the question to the test: In the study, dog owners smelled two blankets — one that had been infused with the individual odor of their dog, and one that [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=212883&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="399c4ff32fffbcb1a13d2bfdb3485cf6" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/07/face-of-the-day-373/"><![CDATA[Images of Jesus Christ are paraded by Catholic devotees during the start of the Feast of the Black Nazarene on January 7, 2014 in Quiapo district, Manila, Philippines. The Feast of the Black Nazarene culminates in a day-long procession on January 9 as barefoot devotees march to see and touch the image of the Black [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213573&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e3eb717e2832b66d0a9befb6a808c37e" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/07/how-to-repel-tourism-ctd-2/"><![CDATA[Another reader marvels at the visa bureaucracy of the US: I just read your post about how hard the US makes it for tourists. What struck me is that it’s a lot harder than going to China. When a friend and I decided in 2012 to go on a tour there, I was apprehensive about getting a [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213223&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="cd0027dff7ec767502b943eb0a46cf90" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/07/is-the-worlds-newest-country-falling-apart-ctd/"><![CDATA[Fisher passes along the above map showing refugee displacement caused by the unrest in South Sudan, noting that “people are getting displaced across huge swathes of the country, suggesting that fighting and instability are spreading wide and fast across the Texas-sized country.” Another ominous observation: [A]t least a few thousand people have fled into Sudan, the country [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213459&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b3abd2db149efffa5c82331e6711a2da" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/07/mental-health-break-402/"><![CDATA[A second-a-day diary of a dog&#8217;s life: It was created by this cool app: One Second Everyday.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213557&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="39e330760d68580605736f85d7d66d35" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/07/quote-for-the-day-300/"><![CDATA[&#8220;Many of the most successful new content sites –Buzzfeed, Huffington Post, Gawker, Business Insider, and Glam Media, among them – are such an amalgam of aggregated content, partnership sharing agreements, pay per click modules, user generated contributions, and, as well, the blitherings of novice journalists (sometimes heralded as a return to long form), that it&#8217;s [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213476&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="dd81a72377b9306895922d1454ca487f" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/07/quote-for-the-day-ii-89/"><![CDATA[&#8220;My advice would be for people not to climb into appliances,&#8221; &#8211; a police officer tasked with removing a man from a top-loading washing machine, with the help of copious amounts of olive oil. The dude was playing hide-and-seek.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213528&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="16b226c0aa3c9a286da51504b13e823e" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/07/snls-black-woman-problem/"><![CDATA[Sasheer Zamata, the 27-year-old comedian seen above, has been tapped to join the cast of Saturday Night Live, becoming the first black woman on the show since Maya Rudolph&#8217;s departure in 2007. Drew Grant comments: It’s an uneasy victory: While it’s definitely a good thing to have more diversity in the cast, the fact is that Ms. [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213471&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bb9e01fea34fa6d8d761ad78ad85868e" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/07/the-math-on-the-medicaid-expansion/"><![CDATA[Ezra unpacks the ACA enrollment numbers: The exchange numbers are solid. You can trust those. &#8230; But the Medicaid numbers are more complex. Each state runs its own count, and the data includes people who enrolled in Obamacare&#8217;s Medicaid expansion as well as people who were eligible under prior law. To the Obama administration&#8217;s annoyance, some states are [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213511&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1d06828d4176599a64e22b25eadf9d70" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/07/the-view-from-your-window-413/"><![CDATA[Shomal, Iran, 12 pm<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213322&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="36fba3f9ade03ea5350f74b347b2f3d" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/07/where-they-really-really-want-gay-marriage/"><![CDATA[Las Vegas: The rapid increase in the number of states permitting gay marriages has crushed demand for commitment ceremonies, a legally meaningless alternative many of the resorts and chapels have offered. DeCar and Flint, who has owned the Chapel of the Bells in Reno for 51 years, said such bookings have plummeted since California resumed [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213501&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ae60948e51dd8d0f01862d3c17939026" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/a-metronome-for-your-day-to-day-life/"><![CDATA[Kyle VanHemert talks about a new tool for keeping time: Durr [seen above] is a watch designed to draw attention to that slippery disconnect between time as it passes and how we perceive it passing. Instead of hands or numbers, it’s just a solid, colorful disk. Every five minutes, it vibrates. &#8230; [Designer Theo] Tveterås says it adds [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=212805&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="333d75a747be1eb6fbc2197f794b76ea" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/a-power-of-prayer-that-even-atheists-can-appreciate/"><![CDATA[A new study premised on the idea that &#8220;cognitive resources, like our physical resources, are limited&#8221; has found that prayer helps block some of the effects of cognitive depletion. First, researchers asked participants to watch funny videos while stifling &#8220;all emotional responses, verbal and non-verbal, to the content &#8230; [which] requires a good amount of [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=212862&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ee3d8de020364b199967ba91c745d578" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/anticipating-the-strain/"><![CDATA[Scientists are studying the brains of athletes in search of &#8220;brain-training techniques that will enable the rest of us to develop elite-level mental agility&#8221;: In a series of studies starting in 2009, [researcher Martin] Paulus and his colleagues put hardened Marines, elite adventure racers, and regular Joes through various cognitive tasks while monitoring their brain [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=212880&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="43f94a191a697ce953a4aa26fe614ba" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/freezing-as-the-world-warms/"><![CDATA[Greg Laden insists that this week’s frigid temperatures don’t mean global warming isn’t real: What is happening instead is the cold air mass that usually sits up on the Arctic during the northern Winter has moved, drooped, shifted, gone off center, to engulf part of the temperate region. Here in the Twin Cities, it is about 8 below zero [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213326&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f0fadd67c5e3eac3aff667e6507ad125" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/gates-bombshell-is-a-dud/"><![CDATA[I have very little but extreme admiration for Bob Gates, as a human being and as a defense secretary. He has always seemed to me a very level-headed, pragmatic and sane realist &#8211; the kind of conservative that would bring me back to the GOP if there were more like him. So why is his [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213610&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="99a51df74dea6469d9ece574a220d0b3" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/having-their-steak-and-eating-it-too/"><![CDATA[Siddhartha Mahanta exposes how your tax dollars are funding the National Cattlemen’s Beef Association, the lobbying arm of Big Beef: Imagine if the federal government mandated that a portion of all federal gas taxes go directly to the oil industry’s trade association, the American Petroleum Institute. Imagine further that API used this public money to finance ad [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213219&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9deee77eccb5069c34dd79eff599b3c1" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/is-success-always-deserved/"><![CDATA[The rich certainly seem to believe so: [Researchers Michel] Kraus and [Dacher] Keltner found that the higher people perceived their social class to be, the more strongly they endorsed just-world beliefs, and that this difference explained their increased social class essentialism: Apparently if you feel that you’re doing well, you want to believe success comes to those [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213253&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e29c98a44f49ae03ec22905de5ec9fc7" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/mental-health-break-403/"><![CDATA[Cats serving their masters: Update from a reader, who sees it differently: Those cats are not massaging the dogs; they are tenderizing them in case they have to eat them later if their human is late coming home.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213734&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="24407ead1aa0a43007e74e4c86136d05" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/not-because-we-are-evil-because-we-are-stupid/"><![CDATA[Ashutosh Jogalekar explains that the high price of drugs isn&#8217;t all because of corporate greed: Often you will hear people talking about why drugs are expensive: it’s the greedy pharmaceutical companies, the patent system, the government, capitalism itself. All these factors contribute to increasing the price of a drug, but one very important factor often [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213663&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7b0a08dfba228001d200906131d5ea45" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/our-outrageous-media/"><![CDATA[Jeffrey M. Berry and Sarah Sobieraj ask whether Americans are addicted to outrage: On cable news networks, talk radio and in the political blogosphere there is a constant stream of name-calling, belittling, character assassination and falsehoods. Americans tell pollsters they dislike this kind of talk and believe it degrades our political system. But the audience data [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213204&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="41d7bd4d9989508a0673f246580ab74e" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/playing-political-football-with-the-unemployed/"><![CDATA[Josh Green makes the &#8220;case for extending jobless benefits in seven charts.&#8221; One of the most striking: How Republicans are approaching the unemployment insurance fight: [M]ultiple Republicans are going all in on the suggestion that they would support extending benefits if only it were paid for. Republicans want to reframe this as a battle over how to pay for extending benefits, [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213608&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="530828ea91bcd3a5aa1f0f848e04521d" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/quote-for-the-day-301/"><![CDATA[&#8220;Gates 1996 and Gates 2014 are rather like America 1996 and America 2014. The first, ebullient, a tad triumphal, serenely confident that U.S. policymaking will be driven by countervailing democratic pressures both to express the will of the people and to secure order in the world as well as national security. The second, embittered, exhausted, [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213638&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="eb0dc720342028ccd0096477d0258402" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/quote-for-the-day-ii-90/"><![CDATA[&#8220;I was offended by [Obama's] suspicion that any of us would ever write about such sensitive matters,&#8221; - Robert Gates, in his tell-all book, Duty: Memoirs of a Secretary at War.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213679&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b0bc2a52a3ac981cf142c094b361a41b" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/the-big-picture-on-iran/"><![CDATA[Beinart focuses on it: One day, I suspect, the people obsessing about the details of an Iranian nuclear deal will look a bit like the people who obsessed about the details of the Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces treaty between the U.S. and U.S.S.R. in 1987. In retrospect, what mattered wasn’t the number of ballistic and cruise missiles each side dismantled. [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213423&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7d14fd4d0711b379af04a6ce10b0448c" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/the-character-of-chris-christie/"><![CDATA[Perhaps it is no big surprise to discover that governor Chris Christie is a vindictive, petty egomaniac contemptuous of the people he serves. But it&#8217;s hard to avoid that conclusion when you&#8217;ve pored over the new tranche of emails that show how he and his staff made life miserable for a large number of New [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213643&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b7cd963b8a7f97b217dd975b99777428" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/the-gops-talking-points-on-poverty/"><![CDATA[Philip Rucker and Robert Costa report that &#8221;there is deep disagreement among Republican leaders and strategists over whether to embrace an economic-mobility agenda in the 2014 midterm campaigns.&#8221; But some prominent Republicans are beginning to address the issue: Sen. Marco Rubio (R-Fla.) will give a speech Wednesday that aides said will lay out changes to federal programs to help people [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213625&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2ccb8cdea36294d1d5050e01fc71867e" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/the-nyt-follows-buzzfeed/"><![CDATA[The pinnacle of American journalism is now hiring a Dell employee to write its &#8220;articles&#8221;: &#8220;We wanted to start with someone who we thought really understood how to be a great storyteller,&#8221; said Meredith Kopit Levien, evp of advertising for the Times. &#8220;And [Dell global communications managing editor] Stephanie Losee was [a writer] at Fortune. [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213691&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c5c68637aa7496bae4ce5142f4123f96" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/the-technology-gimmick-show/"><![CDATA[Victoria Turk yawns at the hype of the Consumer Electronics Show (CES), singling out one of this year’s buzzy gadgets, an app-enabled toothbrush: CES always seems to bring out these sort of “wow look, a random everyday object—but connected!” kind of products, and they inevitably get a disproportionate amount of hype. Remember the HAPIfork from last year? The “smart [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213500&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="46e8d4edfd51d71bfd52610a7232932c" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/the-unschool/"><![CDATA[Mark Oppenheimer visits the Sudbury Valley School in Framingham, Mass., where there are no required classes and students make their own rules: In a 2004 study of 119 alumni who had attended the school for at least three years, over 80 percent had gone to college or university. Others became entrepreneurs, chefs, carpenters, artists, etc. The school [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213513&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="685edb82342b04a841926156e93199a1" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/the-view-from-your-window-414/"><![CDATA[Mumbai, India, 7.18 am<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213592&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ca57c533794cacef69a1dc4979b5f48" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/traffic-stop-and-frisk/"><![CDATA[Black drivers who obey all traffic laws get pulled over three times as often as whites do: In traffic safety stops, being black has no influence: African Americans are not significantly more likely than whites to be stopped for clear traffic safety law violations. But in investigatory stops, a black man age 25 or younger has a [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213039&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4100e01c4a8ab7125db0f8fb3a81489c" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/uplift-in-a-jar/"><![CDATA[Megan Mayhew Bergman wrestles with the ethics of her makeup use: I know my beauty products are largely unnecessary. Furthermore, they’re often made from toxic or unsustainable materials like palm oil. The wrappers, jars, and tubes pile up in landfills and plastify the ocean. The micro-plastic exfoliation beads in soaps and scrubs wind up in otter stomachs. [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213284&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="39db84b5fbd838d0ffc75e0e6810dc6" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/we-arent-going-to-reinvade-iraq/"><![CDATA[Michael Crowley lays out how Obama will and won&#8217;t respond to a resurgent al Qaeda in Iraq. He says &#8220;the White House’s game plan involves better arming Maliki to repel al-Qaeda forces from his country&#8221;: With America out of Iraq, disillusioned with Afghanistan, and clearly opposed to intervening in Syria, the opposition to a direct re-engagement in [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213609&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="305149648488efc0cccef38afe1706a7" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/when-unvaccinated-kids-grow-up/"><![CDATA[They write essays like this one: I am the ’70s child of a health nut. I wasn’t vaccinated. I was brought up on an incredibly healthy diet: no sugar till I was one, breastfed for over a year, organic homegrown vegetables, raw milk, no MSG, no additives, no aspartame. My mother used homeopathy, aromatherapy, osteopathy, we took daily [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213305&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e94437f84c287fb53fe97b2aa91fbd80" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/when-weird-is-synonym-for-black/"><![CDATA[Freddie deBoer discusses how kids with characteristically black names become objects of derision: Being born in 1981 and attending an elementary school that was about a third black, I grew up around many peers who had African or African-inspired names, names like Qualisha and Kamika and Kareem. The mid-80s was a period of racial optimism, in [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213228&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7baaf20d5c69b9c1ede0239f11566f0c" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/will-legalization-hurt-poor-minorities/"><![CDATA[Frum and I debate the question: Reihan opposes full commercial legalization because he fears it will harm the poor and black: To say that we ought to legalize marijuana because marijuana doesn’t hurt anyone is to discount the fact that legalization will cause a collapse in the price of marijuana and that this price collapse will lead [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=213257&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="15fd8fcb8737b391561bc51acd642b57" url="http://dish.andrewsullivan.com/2014/01/08/would-you-gamble-10-on-a-coin-toss/"><![CDATA[Adam Alter explains why only 1 in 20 people would take him up on the offer: Until recently, it was difficult to measure how painfully losses stung and for how long, but a recent paper suggests that the gamblers and teachers were wise to be cautious. Five European economists and psychologists measured how 50,000 German and British [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=dish.andrewsullivan.com&#038;blog=45219523&#038;post=212782&#038;subd=sullydish&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>