<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="justingroc.com">
	<documents count="20">
		<document id="8a0487216f7cbb248009e5db4fc6f2f2" url="http://justingroc.com/post/70953168704"><![CDATA[<p>Right-handed reliever Jamey Wright returns to SoCal on a one-year deal for act two with the Los Angeles Dodgers, per Dylan Hernandez of the Los Angeles Times. The amount is undisclosed at this moment.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Source: The <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23Dodgers&amp;src=hash" target="_blank">#Dodgers</a> have signed Jamey Wright to a one-year deal.</p>
— Dylan Hernandez (@dylanohernandez) <a href="https://twitter.com/dylanohernandez/statuses/415249761412083713" target="_blank">December 23, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>
<script charset="utf-8" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" type="text/javascript"></script></p>
<p>Wright was with the Tampa Bay Rays during the 2013 season when he posted a 3.09 earned run average after 70 innings of work. He only gave up four home runs and recorded an 8.4&#160;K/BB ratio. Back in 2012, with the Dodgers, he had a pedestrian 3.72 ERA. This moves comes after the Dodgers have made waves in an effort to bolster their bullpen behind closer Kenley Jansen – re-signing Brian Wilson and signing Chris Perez, both pitchers who have closing experience themselves.</p>
<p>The right-hander had his choice between returning to the Rays or the Dodgers – ultimately choosing Los Angeles as his 2014 destination. Signing with the Dodgers for 2014 ends an eight-season streak where he made a major league club via a non-roster invitee (Eric Stephen, True Blue L.A.)</p>
<p>Wright has had experience as a long-man out of the bullpen. Dodgers general manager Ned Colletti has let it be known that the role was one the club wanted to address during this offseason.</p>
<p>“We’ve also had conversations with somebody who could be a genuine long man,” Colletti said. “We really didn’t have that this past year. We mixed and matched a few guys in that role” (Stephen).</p>
<p>The Dodgers get an arm that previously had experience in Dodgers-blue – adding to the abundance of arms out of the club’s bullpen. The move provides Los Angeles with further bullpen depth. In addition to the starting pitching, the club is loaded with talented arms.</p>
<p>- <a href="http://www.themlbnation.com/news/2013/12/23/mlb-news-dodgers-bring-back-jamey-wright-on-one-year-deal/" target="_blank">MLB Nation</a></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bf3b5a9ade8729b964000383107a2842" url="http://justingroc.com/post/70961644223"><![CDATA[<img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/f6d345270be22bb4af6c47a58a3befc1/tumblr_myahjkA5SE1rqyqnzo1_500.jpg"/><br/><br/><p>The New York Giants have an ugly sweater party. Someone’s got to win, right? (I kid, I kid.)</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="518f02d6f8575dddc8d383654f431888" url="http://justingroc.com/post/70962620940"><![CDATA[“"Knowing about Big Ten football, that’s bring your big-boy pads, run the ball. It’s a nasty brand of football. That’s how the New Jersey kids are growing up to be nasty, fast, strong football players. Going into the Big Ten, I think, is very appealing to recruits. The Big Ten is a great conference. That conference demands having big linemen like New Jersey has and aggressive running backs like they have."”<br/><br/> - <em>Notre Dame senior defensive tackle Tyler Stockton, a New Jersey-native, speaking about how Rutgers going to the Big Ten can help in the school’s recruiting. Stockton, with all due respect from him, was not all fond of the Big East conference as a football one.</em>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4d3404bca655067f3c537f19d60cbb57" url="http://justingroc.com/post/70976165576"><![CDATA[<img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/39ab9e4108857ddbf7f5c6c9dde4ebc3/tumblr_myaoxl0T051rqyqnzo1_500.jpg"/><br/><br/><p>The Carolina Panthers are playoff-bound. Ice up, son.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5d47bc9782085438c8304bf53ec914c2" url="http://justingroc.com/post/71348064314"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Stephon Tuitt, DE, Notre Dame, Junior<br/>Height / Weight (lbs) – 6’5” / 303<br/>Projected Round – 1<br/>Rutgers vs. Notre Dame – 12/28, Saturday 12:00pm ET – ESPN</strong></p>
<p>Regarded as arguably the best defensive end in the nation, Stephon Tuitt might be the best player on Notre Dame’s 2013 team – one that is following up from a season ago as a national championship contender. He leads all defensive lineman in the nation with 45 tackles, whoie also posting 7.5 tackles for loss and six sacks. Per CBS Sports back in early December, Tuitt is currently weighing his options regarding whether to forgo his senior season with the Fighting Irish. He is waiting for his evaluation regarding where he may be drafted. Fellow defensive lineman Louis Nix III has already decided to forgo his senior season and is likely to be a first or second-round draft pick.</p>
<p>Rutgers has given up the eighth-fewest sacks in the country with 11 in 12 games. Notre Dame has only 16 sacks all season after the same amount of games. While looking at it from a statistical standpoint, Rutgers may be the assumed favorite in this battle of the trenches – the Scarlet Knights may not have been truly tested yet. The Fighting Irish had more of a bruising schedule than the Knights. Depending on how Tuitt plays, this game should help swing his judgment regarding whether or not to leave school early.<br/>—–<br/><strong>Seantrel Henderson, OT, Miami (Fl.), Senior<br/>Height / Weight (lbs) – 6’7” / 345<br/>Projected Round – 4-5<br/>Miami vs. Louisville – 12/28, Saturday 6:45pm ET – ESPN</strong></p>
<p>Miami gave up 13 sacks in 12 games this season – the fewest in the ACC conference. After agreeing to enroll as USC, Seantrel Henderson changed his mind and went to South Beach after the Trojans were slapped with a two-year postseason ban way back years ago. He saw a lot of playing-time early in his college career – starting nine games while as a freshman.</p>
<p>Henderson will likely play right tackle at the next level given his size to maul defenders in the running game. Despite his massive size, he can still play better for a man of his stature. He still earned All-ACC honorable mentions last season after seven starts during last season – which came after when he was recovering from offseason back surgery.<br/>—–<br/><strong>Donte Moncrief, WR, Ole Miss, Junior<br/>Height / Weight (lbs) – 6’2” / 226<br/>Projected Round – 2<br/>Ole Miss vs. Georgia Tech – 12/30, Monday 3:15pm ET – ESPN</strong></p>
<p>Donte Moncrief leads Ole Miss in receiving with 825 yards on 53 catches. He also recorded five receiving touchdowns this season. The emergence of fellow wide receivers Laquon Treadwell and Ja-Mes Logan has allowed Moncrief to see a lot more one-on-one coverage this season. His best season may end up being his sophomore season when he put 979 receiving yards on 66 catches along with 10 receiving touchdowns.</p>
<p>Georgia Tech is 84th in passing yards allowed so Moncrief may have the opportunity to have a big game here. The soft-spoken junior is still mulling his option to commit to the 2014 NFL Draft. Rob Rang of NFLDraftScout.com says that Moncrief might have a good chance of being a better pro-receiver than USC’s Marqise Lee and Clemson’s Sammy Watkins.<br/>—–<br/><strong>Ifo Ekpre-olomu, CB, Oregon, Junior<br/>Height / Weight (lbs) – 5’10” / 190<br/>Projected Round – 1-2<br/>Oregon vs. Texas – 12/30, Monday 6:45pm ET – ESPN</strong></p>
<p>The Walter Camp All-American team is regarded as the most prestigious in terms of recognition by head coaches and sports information directors across the country – and Ifo Ekpre-olomu was named to the second team. It was the fourth straight-season in which a Duck was named to the team. Ekpre-olomu is second on the Oregon Ducks in tackles with 78 and interceptions with three. In the season finale against Oregon State, Ekpre-olomu posted 12 solo tackles along with an interception which helped the Ducks go on to win 36-35.</p>
<p>Texas has struggled this season, according to their standards, by going 8-4 overall. They are fortunate to draw a marquee opponent in Oregon in their bowl game – although I believe it has more to do with the Texas brand rather than the actual team itself. I expect Oregon to wallop Texas, and Ekpre-olomu should have a good chance to give Longhorns quarterback Case McCoy headaches.<br/>—–<br/><strong>Andre Williams, RB, Boston College, Senior<br/>Height / Weight (lbs) – 6’0” / 227<br/>Projected Round – 3<br/>Arizona vs. Boston College – 12/31, Tuesday 12:30pm ET – ESPN</strong></p>
<p>Andre Williams currently leads the nation in rushing yards with 2,102 yards. He has recorded this production after 329 carries, which equates to a 6.4 yard-per-carry average. Williams has been the Eagles’ workhorse by far, with the next leading rusher having only 55 carries. He also has rushed for 17 touchdowns.</p>
<p>Boston College will need to have a strong rushing attack as their passing game ranks 113th in the nation with only 150.5 yard-per-game. NFL scouts have taken notice to Williams’s workload. At 227 pounds, he can definitely look the part as a bruiser in an NFL backfield-by-committee.</p>
<p>- <a href="http://www.bigblueunited.com/2013/12/big-blue-united-college-football-bowl-season-part-ii-nfl-hopefuls-watch.html" target="_blank">Big Blue United</a></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="29b307091e38ef6ca5d89ea5341d5ff4" url="http://justingroc.com/post/71376241656"><![CDATA[<img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/5d1c77a8678b4913bae788f8fc1f5d8f/tumblr_myi09wjC8P1rqyqnzo1_500.jpg"/><br/><br/><p>New York Giants safety Antrel Rolle on not making the Pro Bowl.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fd29e0b23a291f17ea2ee882a2dc6daf" url="http://justingroc.com/post/71455880928"><![CDATA[<p>The New York Yankees are the assumed favorite in the effort to acquire the services of Masohiro Tanaka. The Yankees’ rotation as of now consists of CC Sabathia, Hiroki Kuroda, and Ivan Nova – the assumed front-three. After that, things get a little murky. Does David Phelps finally get his spot in the rotation? Will Michael Pineda finally produce a return on the investment that general manager Brian Cashman made when he traded then-prospect Jesus Montero?</p>
<p>Per the NY Daily News, the Yankees will “make a very strong offer” possibly next week at the earliest. It is no secret that New York wants Tanaka badly. Also reported, Tanaka may demand a minimum deal of $100 million across five years.</p>
<p>Last time Cashman won the rights to a Japanese import, it ended badly as left-hander Kei Igawa has not seen major league action since 2008. Igawa started 13 of 16 games and posted a career earned run average of 6.66. However, Tanaka is only 25 years old and is coming off a season with the Rakuten Golden Eagles where he posted a 24-0 record along with a 1.27 ERA. Igawa, who was 27 when he signed with the Yankees, was nowhere near as dominating as Tanaka was while in Japan. Of course, playing in the MLB will expose every player to the cream of the crop so time will tell whether if Tanaka, or any Japanese import, was worth the bidding dollars that was posted.</p>
<p>Acquiring Tanaka will also keep the Yankees in touch with Japanese media relations to keep on the exposition of the Yankees’ brand overseas (as if it needs to be exposed any further). Ichiromay likely be in his last year as Bronx Bomber and acquiring Tanaka will keep the international relations going (just saying). Hideki Matsui was a huge success for the Yankees as well (despite not delivering the amount of pop that was expected from Matsui’s bat, he did go on to earn 2009 World Series MVP honors).</p>
<p>With the declination of Sabathia, and the overall lack of starting pitching depth, the Yankees are in serious need of starting pitching. Sabathia should earn Opening Day starting honors, as he should, but Tanaka is a guy that New York is hoping to rise to the top of their rotation if he is indeed Bronx-bound. The success of Yu Darvish with the Texas Rangers certainly has many teams salivating at the thoughts of Tanaka and his potential. Acquiring Tanaka would be a big win for the Yankees at the moment but there is still more work to be done to bolster the rotation.</p>
<p>- <a href="http://www.themlbnation.com/news/2013/12/28/mlb-rumors-yankees-reach-out-to-masohiro-tanaka-and-co/" target="_blank">MLB Nation</a></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f83a05a543c6c9bf7f3cc95206043aa3" url="http://justingroc.com/post/71474518496"><![CDATA[<p>Los Angeles Dodgers outfielder Yasiel Puig has been arrested earlier today for suspicion of reckless driving. He was caught going 110 miles-per-hour in a 70 MPH-zone. Puig was pulled over at 9:30 a.m. Eastern time while on Interstate-75 in Florida, taken from his 2013 Mercedes, and put in handcuffs on his way to Collier County Jail in Naples, Florida.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Arrest mug shot of Los Angeles Dodger All-Star Yasiel <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23Puig&amp;src=hash" target="_blank">#Puig</a>. Read full story at <a href="http://t.co/bIvMfQFn5v" target="_blank"><a href="http://t.co/bIvMfQFn5v" target="_blank">http://t.co/bIvMfQFn5v</a></a>. <a href="http://t.co/i1wZeXIwPx" target="_blank">pic.twitter.com/i1wZeXIwPx</a></p>
— Dave Osborn (@NDN_dosborn) <a href="https://twitter.com/NDN_dosborn/statuses/417077570648424452" target="_blank">December 28, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>
<script charset="utf-8" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" type="text/javascript"></script></p>
<p>Florida Highway patrol spokesman Lieutenant Greg Bueno said that Puig cooperated with the authorities. The Dodgers have yet to comment on this situation. It should be noted that this is the second incident where Puig has been arrested for suspicion of reckless driving within the last eight months – when back in April of this year, Puig had charges dropped while in Chattanooga, Tennessee.</p>
<p>Per USA Today, Puig was released on a $500 bond around 1:30 p.m. Eastern time this afternoon. There is currently no court date scheduled, at least one that is known.</p>
<p>The fact that Puig is repeating some of this minor offenses is starting to be troubling. A speeding ticket is one thing, while reckless driving is another – WHILE two incidents of reckless driving within not even a year is troubling. Puig is a budding superstar at his pace for not just the Dodgers but for the MLB as a whole. The young man can perhaps use a mentor to keep himself in check. I cannot blame the guy for wanting to have a little fun given his talent, age, money, and media exposure – but there is a difference between fun and stupid. Puig should perhaps settle down and wait for the new season to arrive so he can focus on baseball.</p>
<p>- <a href="http://www.themlbnation.com/news/2013/12/28/mlb-news-yasiel-puig-arrested-for-suspicion-of-reckless-driving/" target="_blank">MLB Nation</a></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="470ad3926d8c022856d2cc54540d74bb" url="http://justingroc.com/post/71667409319"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Xavier Su’a Filo, OG, UCLA, Junior<br/>Height / Weight (lbs) – 6’3” / 305<br/>Projected Round – 3-4<br/>Virginia Tech vs. UCLA – 12/31, Tuesday 2:00pm ET – CBS</strong></p>
<p>Xavier Su’a Filo has been selected to the 2013 All-Pac-12 First Team by the conference’s coaches. He is the most pro-ready and experienced offensive lineman that UCLA features. Filo has helped UCLA be 36th in the nation in terms of rushing yards forced.</p>
<p>Virginia Tech is seventh in the nation in rushing yards allowed with 103.8 per-game and is tied for fifth in the nation with 37 sacks forced on defense. Although Filo plays along the interior now, he saw time at left tackle during his freshman season with 13 starts. He currently slots in at left guard under head coach Jim Mora Jr.<br/>—–<br/><strong>Cedric Ogbuehi, OT, Texas A&amp;M, Junior<br/>Height / Weight (lbs) – 6’5” / 300<br/>Projected Round – 2<br/>Duke vs. Texas A&amp;M – 12/31, Tuesday 8:00pm ET – ESPN</strong></p>
<p>While fellow offensive tackle Jake Matthews is likely to be the top offensive lineman off the board come the 2014 NFL Draft, Cedric Ogbuehi is a stellar prospect himself as he has seen time along the interior of the line when Matthews was the right tackle last season while left tackle Luke Joeckel was still with the Aggies. Ogbuehi could potentially go in the first round as well if he were to declare early entry in this upcoming draft class. Texas A&amp;M could have three offensive tackles go in the first round within two drafts.</p>
<p>Duke has forced 23 sacks in 13 games so far this year. Ogbuehi should not have much of an issue protecting against a Duke team that has not played against a physical team like the Aggies (other than Florida State) all season. Aggies quarterback Johnny Manziel is also one of the more elusive QBs in college football so I cannot see a Duke pass rush being a big issue here.<br/>—–<br/><strong>Craig Loston, S, LSU, Senior<br/>Height / Weight (lbs) – 6’1” / 209<br/>Projected Round – 3-4<br/>Iowa vs. LSU – 1/1, Wednesday 1:00pm ET – ESPN</strong></p>
<p>Craig Loston has posted 51 tackles, two pass breakups and two interceptions on this season so far. He began starting for the Tigers during this season as well, while previously making only two starts during prior. He is often compared to former LSU safety Eric Reid, although he is not considered as athletic. Loston still possesses hard-hitting ability which is probably his best trait.</p>
<p>With not having much starting experience, it could make for an interesting take regarding where Loston should be drafted. Year-after-year LSU is usually loaded with defensive talent and with Reid now with the San Francisco 49ers, Loston had his one chance at starting a full season and used it to enhance his draft stock. I would not get too down on his lack of experience because LSU usually features plenty of defensive depth.<br/>—–<br/><strong>Jacob Pedersen, TE, Wisconsin, Senior<br/>Height / Weight (lbs) – 6’4” / 240<br/>Projected Round – 6-7<br/>Wisconsin vs. South Carolina – 1/1, Wednesday 1:00pm ET – ABC</strong></p>
<p>Per Wisconsin Football, Jacob Pedersen has been selected as an All-Big Ten Honorable Mention. Make no mistake, the bread-and-butter of Badgers football is the run game. But maybe for those moments where they need to run play-action within the redzone they look for Pedersen to haul in the touchdown grab. Pedersen is not an exciting prospect but his experience in the run-blocking game can make NFL scouts feel that he has a solid foundation in coming in the NFL as a number-two tight end.</p>
<p>Blocking defensive end and potential number-one overall pick Jadeveon Clowney just cannot be done one-on-one. Pedersen will see moments when he is going to need to chip Clowney before Pedersen releases off the line.<br/>—–<br/><strong>Bradley Roby, CB, Ohio State, Junior<br/>Height / Weight (lbs) – 5’11” / 193<br/>Projected Round – 1<br/>Clemson vs. Ohio State – 1/3, Friday 8:30pm ET – ESPN</strong></p>
<p>Clemson will be boasting what looks to be the last game featuring quarterback Tajh Boyd hooking up with wide receiver Sammy Watkins in a game. Bradley Roby has three interceptions on the season, which is tied for the team-lead. He also has 63 tackles on the season which is third-most on the team. Roby was named to the All-Big Ten First Team.</p>
<p>Roby has already declared that he will enter the 2014 NFL Draft. Per NFLDraftScout.com, he is rated as the number-three corner in this upcoming draft. For his career as a Buckeye he has eight interceptions and 32 pass deflections.</p>
<p>- <a href="http://www.bigblueunited.com/2013/12/big-blue-united-college-football-bowl-season-part-iii-nfl-hopefuls-watch.html" target="_blank">Big Blue United</a></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fc7cacd3d6559898de25c4dfb115b2a4" url="http://justingroc.com/post/71813192571"><![CDATA[<img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/998011df4541bfc6041e251ce4d47183/tumblr_mypfmaCeXL1rqyqnzo1_500.jpg"/><br/><br/><p>San Francisco 49ers head coach Jim Harbaugh mistakes Arizona Cardinals head coach Bruce Arians for Indianapolis Colts head coach Chuck Pagano (still following?)</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f6f045d53aab9f29c5371f982c775ad0" url="http://justingroc.com/post/72103613559"><![CDATA[<img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/fe02673adf7ed4afed659aa818c23e47/tumblr_myu7oaWFgy1rqyqnzo1_500.jpg"/><br/><br/><p>New York Rangers goalie Henrik Lundqvist paying tribute to some Yankees history.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="cf052d0bb0ead5c4f08522b0762fd4f9" url="http://justingroc.com/post/72155132063"><![CDATA[<p>The Philadelphia Phillies and Comcast SportsNet have agreed on a new television deal that will span through 25 years. The current deal was set to expire after the 2015 regular season. The new deal is reportedly going to be worth over $2.5 billion and will kick in after 2015. The club will also be obtaining a stake in the network’s equity.</p>
<p>The previous contract was worth $35 million per season. Per Mike Axisa of CBS Sports, “smaller” market clubs like the Houston Astros and San Diego Padres were each receiving $65 million-plus from television deals alone per-season.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We’re pleased to confirm that NBCUniversal and Comcast SportsNet have signed a new long-term deal with the Philadelphia Phillies that will expand Comcast SportsNet’s role as the Phillies’ primary TV partner. Although the terms of the comprehensive deal are confidential, details surrounding the 2014 schedule of games will be provided in the coming months”</p>
<p>(Maureen Quilter, senior director of communications of Comcast).</p>
</blockquote>
<p>NBC10 will broadcast a portion of the Phillies’ Sunday games but the remaining will mostly be with Comcast.</p>
<p>With a new television deal, the Phillies should continue their spending ways. They currently have one of the highest payrolls in the MLB (had a 2013 Opening Day Payroll just under $160 million, per <a href="http://deadspin.com/2013-payrolls-and-salaries-for-every-mlb-team-462765594" target="_blank">Deadspin</a>). This new deal will provide them with some more financial relief, if anything, if they decide not to increase their spending. They currently have an ailing team with former stars on the decline, so they can possibly throw even more money at their problems (or hopeful solutions).</p>
<p>- <a href="http://www.themlbnation.com/news/2014/01/03/mlb-news-phillies-agree-to-new-television-deal-with-comcast-sportsnet/" target="_blank">MLB Nation</a></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3798083767a9158f500e677dc840aa5c" url="http://justingroc.com/post/72173863949"><![CDATA[<img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/e0ed71cff670ac9e8b2200f563c5ab36/tumblr_myv4cxf4aK1rqyqnzo1_500.jpg"/><br/><br/><p>The white board in the Ohio State locker room after the 2014 Orange Bowl loss to Clemson.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="230ff21d3918b1e8e67340acfd73b527" url="http://justingroc.com/post/72238975672"><![CDATA[<img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/cadc511a3c26f9f432577fcaee9fc37a/tumblr_mywayjzDeC1rqyqnzo1_500.jpg"/><br/><br/><p>Some epic photobombing.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1ed38a220f31f7d59f362f7c82bd33fa" url="http://justingroc.com/post/72266186217"><![CDATA[<img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/f8cb89a153d0650885a7e33e91e40ec6/tumblr_mywnpoQPa91rqyqnzo1_500.jpg"/><br/><br/><p>The New Orleans Saints placed a target sign on their team bus for when they rolled into Philadelphia.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="440c19792629ff54bd3118fd5c6f15c7" url="http://justingroc.com/post/72272560300"><![CDATA[<p>During this offseason, rumors have been floating around regarding the availability of New York Mets first baseman Ike Davis as a potential trade chip. <a href="http://www.baltimoresun.com/sports/orioles/blog/bal-where-does-the-orioles-offseason-go-from-here-20140103,0,7064557.story" target="_blank">Per Eduardo Encina of The Baltimore Sun</a>, the Mets have been in talks with the Baltimore Orioles in regards to Davis along with Daniel Murphy and Lucas Duda.</p>
<p>With Davis being demoted to Triple-A Las Vegas during the 2013 regular season, the Mets may be looking to move on from the one-time highly-regarded prospect. Davis played 103 games at the big-league level and hit a measly .205/.326/.334 with nine home runs and 33 runs batted in. During the season prior, he managed to bash 32 home runs and 90 RBIs after 156 games played, but only managed a .308 on-base percentage.</p>
<p>Although he has not lived up to what the Mets were hoping for him to become, he will be 27 years old come 2014 Opening Day which may be enough for some other team to still have some hope for him. If Ike Davis was sent to Baltimore, that could allow the club to have Chris Davis see more time as a designated hitter.</p>
<p>Duda has seen time at first base and outfield for the Mets. If they were to move Ike Davis, they should consider playing Duda at first with Curtis Granderson and Chris Young now manning both corner outfield spots. So I am unsure if trading Duda is a good idea.</p>
<p>I am a little surprised that the Orioles are so focused on bolstering their lineup when that was their strength in 2013 (fifth in the MLB in runs-scored with 745). The club is loaded with bats with the likes of Chris Davis, Manny Machado, J.J. Hardy, Nick Markakis, and perhaps the face of the Orioles in Adam Jones. Baltimore ranked 23rd in the MLB last season with a 4.20 team-earned run average. The Orioles do have top-pitching prospect Eduardo Rodriguez waiting in the wings – a potential trade piece that the Mets have asked for but have been unsuccessful in getting included in deal.</p>
<p>- <a href="http://www.themlbnation.com/news/2014/01/04/mlb-rumors-mets-talking-with-orioles-in-latest-league-trade-talks/" target="_blank">MLB Nation</a></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7a4969a832e55b08c71d8b3869b2ca39" url="http://justingroc.com/post/72424619583"><![CDATA[<iframe src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F128130642&liking=false&sharing=false&origin=tumblr" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" class="soundcloud_audio_player" width="500" height="116"></iframe><br/><br/><p><em><span>01-03 - “Al And Eddie Share A Hotel Room” *All rights go to WFAN 600AM/101.9FM*</span></em></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7ccde3b03c80e7d05d40b8600fd72fc2" url="http://justingroc.com/post/72564258978"><![CDATA[<iframe width="400" height="225" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/35AFrS1sQVA?wmode=transparent&autohide=1&egm=0&hd=1&iv_load_policy=3&modestbranding=1&rel=0&showinfo=0&showsearch=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe><br/><br/><p>Zip lining in an NFL Stadium.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="93c72fd84a068c0087b4d203f22e3ff0" url="http://justingroc.com/post/72602402119"><![CDATA[<img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/a148d632815648bfc025c1d10d5bd68c/tumblr_mz22pdnAnp1rqyqnzo1_500.jpg"/><br/><br/><p>Apparently I work with Terry Tate.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="899e1cc4b4752766a13509ba343a8bf3" url="http://justingroc.com/post/72685964137"><![CDATA[<p>After seeing his last action with the Los Angeles Angels and Los Angeles Dodgers back in 2012, outfielder Bobby Abreu is attempting a comeback at once-again playing in the MLB. The Cleveland Indians have been keeping tabs on Abreu while he has been playing ball down in Venezuela during this winter, and have been “talking” with him about a potential deal – per Tony Lastoria of IndiansBaseballInsider.com.</p>
<div>
<blockquote>Indians are very interested in signing OF Bobby Abreu. They have been monitoring him in winter ball and talking about deal with him. — Tony Lastoria (@TonyIBI) <a href="https://twitter.com/TonyIBI/statuses/420355199526400000" target="_blank">January 7, 2014</a></blockquote>
</div>
<p>I would assume for the potential deal to be of the minor-league variety. In 2012, he hit .242/.350/.342 with three home runs and 19 runs batted in after 100 games of action. During winter ball, he has hit .322/.416/.461. The one thing that Abreu still retains from his previous form is his ability to still get on-base (he has a career .396 on-base percentage in the MLB). Signing with the Indians could have him see time at designated hitter if he were to make it back to The Show. There would be very little risk here for the Indians if they were to sign Abreu for going into the 2014 season.</p>
<p>- <a href="http://www.themlbnation.com/news/2014/01/08/mlb-rumors-indians-contemplating-about-signing-bobby-abreu/" target="_blank">MLB Nation</a></p>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>