<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="www.mooneyelabs.com/song-of-the-nutria">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="b405cdd9b864e0ee56c41f5e89c1e390" url="http://www.mooneyelabs.com/2012/03/wind-map/"><![CDATA[I saw this really nifty real-time Wind Map today. I have nothing more to add to this other than to say it is utterly mesmerizing.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="28ede673a6a3b15b429fe08414e1858b" url="http://www.mooneyelabs.com/2012/03/world-water-day/"><![CDATA[Going way back to the first job I ever had I&#8217;ve been aware of the role that water has played in the relationship humanity has with his environment.  In that first job I had the fascinating pleasure of being exposed to aerial photography for (essentially) the first time. When you see water in the landscape [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="47643ceeeb1a9bb7a398325c91e0f287" url="http://www.mooneyelabs.com/2012/04/america-revealed-pbs/"><![CDATA[I just happened upon this series on PBS tonight &#8211; it is about all the stuff I am very much interested in. Patterns, nature &#8211; and tonight it happens to be about America&#8217;s &#8220;Food Factory&#8221;. Well, well! You can&#8217;t talk about that without showing those center pivot irrigation fields. America produces so much more food [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9e50f1276e7d0966caea60085af78f39" url="http://www.mooneyelabs.com/2012/04/lidar-in-archaeology/"><![CDATA[Years ago I went to a sales partner meeting at EROS in Sioux Falls SD. During a cool meeting there I got to see some applications of LiDAR in combination with aerial and satellite imagery. Well &#8211; boy have things improved! Pretty awesome quality! Just think of all the new old data we now could [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="367e6b6ad2596586d60ef6354da97121" url="http://www.mooneyelabs.com/2012/04/scientific-illustration-secretary-bird-sagittarius-serpentarius-by/"><![CDATA[Scientific Illustration &#124; Secretary Bird Sagittarius serpentarius by&#8230;. I can&#8217;t believe it! I got blogged! Groovy&#8230; &#160; &#160;
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bcdab6c157a7c7e5aa1f14f67ce947a8" url="http://www.mooneyelabs.com/2012/05/entry-in-laracs-2012-members-show/"><![CDATA[Today I trekked up to Glens Falls to drop off a watercolor at the Lower Adirondack Regional Arts Council. I&#8217;m hoping it will sell &#8211; while I have a long career making art, I don&#8217;t have a long gallery career! It is located in a pretty little building in the center of town, the same [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="878f2b4528e120b85773818c53611419" url="http://www.mooneyelabs.com/2012/05/it-never-fails-to-amaze-me-when-i-find-my-photos-on-the-web/"><![CDATA[I stumbled across a photo I took in my living room back in the late 80s when I lived in downtown Albany. What a spartan interior! All I had there was a large acrylic painting of mine from college, a teeny shelflet for my TV &#38; stereo, one flat sheet (split lengthwise) for two windows, [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="34841872749c2b8955b01cf9b662db39" url="http://www.mooneyelabs.com/2012/06/restoring-photographs-with-photoshop/"><![CDATA[I like to restore old photographs using Photoshop. I know that to some people that sort of work can be really mind-numbing, but I really love to do it. I suppose it is because it results in something in which you can see immediate improvement. This example is a photo my mother had which had [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="447f68211bbebda06ea3ec051df5aade" url="http://www.mooneyelabs.com/2012/07/where-to-live-to-avoid-a-natural-disaster-map-nytimes-com/"><![CDATA[A friend of mine brought to my attention this nice little graphic from the New York Times online regarding where natural disasters tend to be, based upon historical data. Oddly, I noticed that where I live has a nice big (compared to others on this map),  juicy amber circle right over it. I can&#8217;t imagine [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="22adfc5239b602f5298f791a31c43bcd" url="http://www.mooneyelabs.com/2012/08/piedra-del-aguila-dam-reshapes-the-limay-river-image-of-the-day/"><![CDATA[The best way to see the effects of those dammed humans&#8230; Really, it&#8217;s a cool way to view something that is useful and scary at the same time. Go to the link and then click on the [VIEW BOTH IMAGES] box below the aerials. You can then use a slider to compare the 1986 image [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>