<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="meaningfulpapers.blogspot.com">
	<documents count="4">
		<document id="e520e333f85fcd37272fe876f85f7ff5" url="http://meaningfulpapers.blogspot.com/2010/01/silent-honor-by-danielle-steel.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-family: inherit;">Have you ever wondered what and how will you feel when you are left all alone in Karachi or Lahore when India and Pakistan are in war? If you like to experience the thrill of it, Danielle Steels's Silent honor is the book that you have to read rather experience. Hats off to steel for brining out such a beautiful book.</span><br /><br /><b><span style="font-family: inherit;">Sneak Preview of the book:</span></b><br /><span style="font-family: inherit;">Hiroko, a traditional brought up Japanese girl goes to US to fulfill her dads wish of studying in States for at least a period of&nbsp; 1 year. She finds herself in a land filled with people of prejudice thoughts. None are friendly to her either in her school or other places. The only place where she was herself and enjoyed the most her cousins place. Thats&nbsp; </span>where she gets to find her love, Peter. Tragedy strikes them soon after. Due to Japanese attack on the Pearl Harbour, the Japanese immigrants of US have to undergo huge turmoil. Does Hiroko manage to survive? How does she survive? Where does her fate land her? For more details read this interesting work.<br /><br /><b>My Review:</b><br /><br />Its an excellent work from the author. I basically love war and love stories. This one has a good mix of both love and the sufferings of common people during war. The best part of this story is that the humor has been inserted and right places so that the movie is all that not serious. The love that the lead pair and other pairs share has been well brought out. But at times you feel as though the author has taken a longer route to explain the love, when there was a easier way of saying it.&nbsp; All the characters in the story play an important and interesting part. The struggle that this little girl had to go through during the 2nd world war that too in the alien land where she totally hated and chased to the very corner of life has been described splendidly so that you really feel pity for her.I always loved the Japanese girls in the Jackie Chan movies i have seen&nbsp; just because they look like dolls. But the heroine of the story also impressed me a lot with her determination, love and attitude.By reading this book you also get to know some of the Japanese terms (<i>chance to learn a foreign language</i>). The climax has also been drafted well showing the after effects of war. It also reminded me of some feel good Indian movies though. Over all it was a pleasant experience reading this book.<br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://i.biblio.com/z/051/224/9780440224051.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://i.biblio.com/z/051/224/9780440224051.jpg" /></a><br /></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6c06edb0d7b941748d5a451681ee6daa" url="http://meaningfulpapers.blogspot.com/2010/02/digital-fortress-by-dan-brown.html"><![CDATA[You are assigned a task of decoding a complex code that even the Human being's best ever decoder was not able to solve. Moreover you are held hostage by a suspect in your den. Your beloved is not with you, he is in a place far off and he is also in danger because of your work. You have only your mentor to help you out in this mess? What would it feel like to be in this situation? Just read Digital Fortress By Dan Brown.<br /><br /><b>Sneak Preview of the Book</b>:<br /><br />This is a beautiful scientific fiction thriller. Susan a beautiful Cryptographer who works for the NSA is being assigned a secret task of decoding a code (sent by an ex NSA employee) that was not even broken by the greatest code breaking machine "TRANSLTR" by her mentor Trevor Strathmore. As she goes about her job more and more mystery unfolds and she is caught in a trap. Her sweet heart David Becker is also in danger. How is the code finally broken then? How does she save herself and her fiancéis forms the rest of this exciting thriller from one of the well known writers.<br /><br /><b>My Review:</b><br /><br />"Dan Brown what a author he is, chanceless dude".&nbsp; "Awesome work from Dan Brown". These are some of the words that my friends uttered when they hear the name Dan Brown. This is the first book that i have read written by this author. And yeah i have to agree with my friends for sure. I love edge of the seat thriller movies, so is this story. No wonder his works like DA VINCI CODE and ANGEL and DEMONS have been made into movies. The way that this scientific thriller has been handled speaks volume of this author. The shifting of locations from America to Europe is pcture perfect and does not bore you a single minute. All the characters have been given equal space and equal importance. There are loads of twist in the story and keeps you excited all the time. The manner in which the mystery is finally revealed is also splendid i must say. I felt like i was watching a cool movie when i read this book. A must read for anyone who loves science and thriller. <br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://rplib.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/digital-fortress.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://rplib.files.wordpress.com/2009/10/digital-fortress.jpg" width="247" /></a></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f6fd2706c5f816fe2ef58064cc9978cf" url="http://meaningfulpapers.blogspot.com/2010/04/how-to-cut-long-story-short-by-jeffrey.html"><![CDATA[The very first thing that came to my mind after reading this book was the bollywood movie "DUS KAHANIYAN" in which the director tries telling 10 different stories in a single movie. Here the author tries to tell 14 different stories in a sinlge book. I remember Rajeev Masand of CNN IBN giving the movie a big thumbs down and i seriously hope that this book did not meet with the same fate as that of the movie. I loved reading this book. This book is full of short stories and some are really short and very interesting. There is not much to speak more about the book i would say as it would be an injustice to both the author and the book to reveal the plot of all the short stories. But i would like to conclude with mentioning my favorite short story of the book. END GAME.<br /><br />I am sure Archer fans would have loved this book. This happens to the first one of his collections that i have read.<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://img1.fantasticfiction.co.uk/images/c1/c7375.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://img1.fantasticfiction.co.uk/images/c1/c7375.jpg" width="198" /></a></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="82f84fccbf102d5d0f7df5b9365b50a2" url="http://meaningfulpapers.blogspot.com/2010/09/double-image-by-david-morrell.html"><![CDATA[<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://img1.fantasticfiction.co.uk/images/n5/n26711.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><br /></a></div>You should be cautious about every step that you take. The more you want to move away from something, the more it keeps coming near you. Can your passion and curiosity to explore the hidden truths land you in a big trouble? Everyone around you are in trouble because of you. How to get out of this mess? Just read Double Image by David Morrell.<br /><br /><b>Sneak Preview of the book:</b><br /><br />Coltrane an award winning photographer whose job is to take photographs of the crimes committed by criminals in war ravaged countries. He escapes near death and some how manages to save his life. He wants to change track and start taking pictures to show beauty and not sorrow as he has been taking so far. But someone wants him dead and follows him like his shadow. Who is the killer? Does the killer succeed in his mission?<br /><br /><b>My Review about the book:</b><br /><b><br /></b><br />The crime thriller has enough stuff in it to keep you interested in reading the book. David Morrell has presented the thriller in a very interesting manner. But i don’t know why the author has to combine 2 stories into one? I felt that the book was a master piece for the first half and the second half was just dragging taking us into a totally different plot. I probably think that the author thought that the second half if written as a separate book will not sell as this piece would have sold. Has there been a movie made(adapted) from this book? But i must say Bollywood directors will be itching to take this book to silver screen for sure. I would rate this say 6 out of 10.<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://img1.fantasticfiction.co.uk/images/n5/n26711.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://img1.fantasticfiction.co.uk/images/n5/n26711.jpg" width="219" /></a></div>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>