<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="heartheather.com">
	<documents count="5">
		<document id="929bd6dea7d8db0db3a72d20b5030d37" url="http://heartheather.com/2013/11/05/diy-avocado-beauty-recipes/"><![CDATA[I try not to put anything on my skin that I wouldn&#8217;t put in my stomach (this means choosing natural, organic and/or chemical-free products where my budget allows). But as I learned at a recent beauty blogger event, in the case of avocados, my beauty rule of thumb also works in reverse. My skin is on [...]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HeartHeather/~4/tURIFLX_4jo" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6dd7afc88c99e770eddacb45a3d08733" url="http://heartheather.com/2013/11/07/if-you-dont-ask-the-answer-is-always-no-a-free-printable/"><![CDATA[I can&#8217;t remember the context or the conversation exactly, but at some point during my visit with my sister earlier this year, she said this to me. And it&#8217;s been an ear worm ever since. Asking for help makes me feel vulnerable. A little scared. Like I&#8217;ll be perceived as weak. And maybe like I&#8217;m [...]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HeartHeather/~4/NiyelPVy24w" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6179dc6c42eea2fdcaaa353ca767eb6e" url="http://heartheather.com/2013/11/12/sentimental-hoarding-50-minted-giveaway/"><![CDATA[I read recently that sentimentality is the enemy of minimalism. Well, anyone who&#8217;s ever seen my collection of craft supplies, or books, or even my desk, knows that I&#8217;m no minimalist. Which is not to say I&#8217;m a hoarder, per se, but maybe I am a sentimentalist. Each year, when we unpack our Christmas decorations (and [...]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HeartHeather/~4/fxpxv3_wiW8" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="633792642b1984947785df00958bd10" url="http://heartheather.com/2013/11/23/guelph-craft-show-listings/"><![CDATA[The thing I love most about the holiday season isn&#8217;t decorating, or baking, or eating. Nope: it&#8217;s the plethora of seasonal craft shows. I try to spend a good chunk of my gift-giving budget on handmade or local goods, and if I can wrap both of those into one gift, I generally feel pretty awesome [...]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HeartHeather/~4/ZzJg9ma4uac" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a5f00bc4ae1473d037a72aeeac60da52" url="http://heartheather.com/2013/12/06/want-need-wear-read-gift-guide-for-cyclists-win-a-bike-cap/"><![CDATA[Have you heard of this gift-giving method? We tried it last year and not only was it a simple way to keep our budget in line, but the want/need/wear/read categories provided just enough direction when shopping. Gift giving gets even easier when you apply the categories to the intended recipient&#8217;s special passion or hobby. Here [...]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HeartHeather/~4/Bc5Z_lbD4LY" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>