<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="vanillaextract.me">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="75e06189bfdc6822663eb61f35f89322" url="http://vanillaextract.me/3-ways-to-style-grown-out-bangs/"><![CDATA[I have a love/hate relationship with bangs. They were so hot in 2013 (I made the chop and loved them!), but in true girl fashion, I changed my mind. Now, the dreaded grow-out process begins and it’s an awkward one to say the least. If you’re over fringe, try out one of these super easy [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e63446c7d8cb06da008f259650b4eb98" url="http://vanillaextract.me/5-things-that-are-drying-out-your-skin-how-to-avoid-them/"><![CDATA[I love winter and all, but it seriously wreaks havoc on my skin. There&#8217;s nothing sexy about dry flakes and when you have &#8216;em, makeup application is the most frustrating process in all of the land. To avoid dry skin depression (trust me, it&#8217;s real), I like to eliminate all of the pesky little things [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ea95454effbccacf25a633a15cc488e" url="http://vanillaextract.me/back-to-basics/"><![CDATA[Hiiiii. I just did a major closet clean out before the holidays and realized a few things: 1) I should have never worn acid wash in public. 2) I have nothing to wear. 3) I don&#8217;t own enough basics: white t-shirts, beige sweaters, trousers, etc. Classics! They&#8217;re the fundamentals of the closet. When B and [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="644104f23d552d22e915334a7536e269" url="http://vanillaextract.me/beauty-gifts-for-you-me/"><![CDATA[If there&#8217;s something you want, you treat.yo.self. You work hard. You got your ish together, in the office and at home. Basically, you&#8217;re a rockstar and rockstars need a little something for the holidays too. Sometimes, the best gifts are the &#8220;to me; from me&#8217;s.&#8221; So, here&#8217;s the scoop. I&#8217;ve already purchased a couple of [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="20d3a3e0885b6118b251af42e5047022" url="http://vanillaextract.me/feeling-bossy/"><![CDATA[I was feeling particularly badass the day Elise shot these pics. There&#8217;s something about combat boots and a utility jacket that just makes you want to take over the world. The jacket was a Forever 21 steal. Gosh, I love those. They&#8217;re few and far between, but when you find one it&#8217;s like the stars [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b6c3ca4bccce3e20f8125c547bd03a14" url="http://vanillaextract.me/our-winter-wish-list/"><![CDATA[It&#8217;s hard to believe that the winter season is in full swing! Although our heads are spinning with holiday shopping, travel plans, and projects, B and I made a pact to not let the holiday craze get the best of us. Much like our fall wish list, we have one for the winter season &#8211; [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f3a2f3322e53d99090a6dc0d8dc01972" url="http://vanillaextract.me/philly-girl/"><![CDATA[Holy holidays, guys! And happy (almost) New Year! B and I just got back to California from a week long visit with my family on the east coast. It was the perfect time to decompress, reflect, and of course, be merry. Over the weekend, we made a trip to Philly to see my girlfriend Kristen, [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a7c1bd64b9307cd4707fbddcecbaa441" url="http://vanillaextract.me/the-lookbook-falling-into-winter/"><![CDATA[Guys, I&#8217;m so excited to share this! My friends Amanda and Ashley invited me to be a part of their new vision: a seasonal publication that showcases the hottest trends from a blogger&#8217;s point of view. I thought it was such a smart idea since so many of us turn to street style for inspiration [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b33d6b51683dd4d63678bcf8b2bd8867" url="http://vanillaextract.me/trend-to-try-brushed-up-brows/"><![CDATA[Guys, I could talk about brows all day long. I take mine very seriously (ahem, here and here.) Full brows have been on the scene for awhile now, but it was only a matter of time before the beauty Gods decided to introduce a new trend. Meet the new brushed up brows. They&#8217;re a little [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8e5db2854f7887f14a98c9ecb85046f7" url="http://vanillaextract.me/weekend-wear/"><![CDATA[This weekend, B and I started and finished our Christmas shopping (for both families!). It really is a Christmas miracle. We wanted to get things done early (at least it feels early compared to years past) because we are skipping town in a week. We&#8217;ll be spending Christmas with my family in Philly and I am SO [...]
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>