<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="mandsfood.tumblr.com">
	<documents count="20">
		<document id="b16e7231be080c02e59198ad33660b61" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/50173558246"><![CDATA[“The more you eat, the less flavour; 
the less you eat, the more flavour.” - Chinese...
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="62870a991c1a918bcc7d68975eff0ed6" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/50177122234"><![CDATA[<img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/54cc68cff75564a773adbf2f6db85c28/tumblr_mmn8gihkDR1s5cqb1o1_500.jpg"/><br/> M&S Fragrant White Chicken Korma<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/875484bbd8516ae4fd2561504ce38ae7/tumblr_mmn8gihkDR1s5cqb1o5_500.jpg"/><br/> Reminds me of German "Königsberger Klopse"<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/654631157d46a0bc2feeab806550b592/tumblr_mmn8gihkDR1s5cqb1o2_500.jpg"/><br/> Ingredients<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/ffeb743994a7b8aaa49a9f808c2d18a2/tumblr_mmn8gihkDR1s5cqb1o3_500.jpg"/><br/> Rahila's story<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/3ee215918f0a69319b28fccdf1dabaf1/tumblr_mmn8gihkDR1s5cqb1o4_500.jpg"/><br/> Not a very pleasant look<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/0025d5a0f95f25409e72851aed071008/tumblr_mmn8gihkDR1s5cqb1o6_500.jpg"/><br/> The flavours of the sauce makes it really yummy<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/ef99fa66438a18f1b74750ab18572bb5/tumblr_mmn8gihkDR1s5cqb1o7_500.jpg"/><br/> Seriously, how cute... how bad can it be?<br/><br/> <img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/a03b829601259e74c01c7aa58d7a6133/tumblr_mmn8gihkDR1s5cqb1o8_500.jpg"/><br/> Let's see...<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/05973eff59dae2babdaab311bfd0b6f2/tumblr_mmn8gihkDR1s5cqb1o9_500.jpg"/><br/> Really BAD!<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/1908757857813a59d15a083283cb0b9e/tumblr_mmn8gihkDR1s5cqb1o10_500.jpg"/><br/> Don't forget tissues on the table!<br/><br/> <p><em><strong>M&S Fragrant White Chicken Korma</strong></em><br/>-spice up your day! </p>
<p>I love spicy food. However, it must not take away the flavour. Flavour might well be the most important element of a dish.</p>
<p>The <em>M&S Fragrant White Chicken Korma </em>is the winner dish of the first season of the itv show “Food Glorious Food” that tours throughout the whole country to find the nation’s best dish. The winner is called Rahila Hussain, who was born in Yorkshire and who could never forget her mother’s tasty chicken korma.</p>
<p>At first glance the dish simply looks disgusting. Even though the packaging is designed quite nicely the content doesn’t look very tempting. In fact, I feel like I already regret paying 4 Pounds for it. On the other hand, after watching parts of the show and ‘getting to know’ Rahila’s story was intriguing. Thus, I just have to try it.</p>
<p>I’m not really a fan of meaty dishes. However, the flavour of this dish is amazing. There is no dominant taste neither of the meat nor of any of the spices.</p>
<p>I had a slice of toast with it -actually three as the sauce was delicious- which turned out to be really useful when I had the insane idea of eating the green chili.</p>
<p>IT BURNT MY TONGUE.</p>
<p>Honestly, I have loads of spicy dishes, I even had a plain habanero (<a href="https://vimeo.com/42830636">https://vimeo.com/42830636</a> at 8:50min) but I didn’t expect this green chili to be so nasty. To be fair, the package does say “hot” at the front but I recommend not to have the chili, or at least cut it in small pieces. However, if you have the whole chili, it will really take away the nice flavours of the dish.</p>
<p><em><strong>4 out of 5 stars</strong></em></p>
<p>The <em>M&S Fragrant White Chicken Korma </em>is a really tasty dish that is great with bread (rice would be nice as well). Unfortunately, it doesn’t look very tempting and I’d prefer the meat to be pre-cooked slightly longer. Definitely watch the green chili.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="77fb70eab789865e5715b0bbcaf45e88" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/52618673399"><![CDATA[<img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/290866077eaf8ea7ea24edaebc8173b5/tumblr_mo6am5JBcg1s5cqb1o1_500.jpg"/><br/> Chocolate Brownie Mini Bites<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/42b68123da3f89abc4f26f145e7d78b6/tumblr_mo6am5JBcg1s5cqb1o2_500.jpg"/><br/> What a nice little container - reuse it ... "because there is no plan B"<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/11ceafd44b374a18c17fb0f824ff6115/tumblr_mo6am5JBcg1s5cqb1o3_500.jpg"/><br/> Ingredients: free range eggs, rapeseed oil! But sugar first?!<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/df51756fd2959d26486bfe5a0a2c882c/tumblr_mo6am5JBcg1s5cqb1o5_500.jpg"/><br/> You have never seen this...<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/138e0d58e156205f81cd26f9b3bbce8d/tumblr_mo6am5JBcg1s5cqb1o4_500.jpg"/><br/> So tempting next to your computer!<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/a1b63e82e39080fcce7b0db46f4e09bb/tumblr_mo6am5JBcg1s5cqb1o6_500.jpg"/><br/> Ok yes, I couldn't stop...<br/><br/> <p><em><strong>M&S Chocolate Brownie Mini Bites</strong></em><br/>-sweet treat</p>
<p>We all have it from time to time: this nasty craving for chocolate…<br/>Unfortunately, it usually haunts us at times when we are sitting at a desks (working/studying). Thus, we don’t get the chance to burn the calories off.</p>
<p>Therefore, we should make sure that the things we eat aren’t too bad.</p>
<p>In this regards, it might actually be a good thing that there are less brownies in the container than expected -on the downside: what a waste of plastic!<br/>But then, there are enough brownies to make you feel sick (and guilty) if you eat them all and believe me, once you have started…</p>
<p>The brownies are unexpected soft and the bite size prevents you from making the usual crumble mess. It’s great to see that M&S is using free range eggs for their products and also rapeseed oil is meant to be a healthier option that other oils/fat. However, sugar as the first and therefore main ingredient is quite naughty but then it’s a sweet treat anyway. Maybe more cocoa mass instead would be better.</p>
<p>All in all, nice little bites that will boost your sugar levels and keep your work going (at least for a while).</p>
<p><em><strong>3+ out of 5 stars</strong></em></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2ca7b711c4f5aa5762e62d1f86a56a4a" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/52802657671"><![CDATA[<img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/b5a26de9b560196b39e3d9e87fce3a8a/tumblr_moakxe8ttk1s5cqb1o5_500.jpg"/><br/> YUM!<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/55d8f70916a3aa9fd9a39560c36085af/tumblr_moakxe8ttk1s5cqb1o1_500.jpg"/><br/> M&S Espana Garlic Mushrooms<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/13b96add3048ff006e8d1ec399aa5a42/tumblr_moakxe8ttk1s5cqb1o2_500.jpg"/><br/> Ingredients<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/79cabeb3c3bf0a251947e82ab567a1e5/tumblr_moakxe8ttk1s5cqb1o3_500.jpg"/><br/> Fried in a usual pot (no need to add oil!!)<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/35a369fc31d32eb652959bc0de00ec80/tumblr_moakxe8ttk1s5cqb1o4_500.jpg"/><br/> Goes well with bread (as everything does)<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/62d7593fbe90ee7359a51eb1f6906e94/tumblr_moakxe8ttk1s5cqb1o6_500.jpg"/><br/> Enjoyable.<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/dd198811760880edc522d49f03f754fb/tumblr_moakxe8ttk1s5cqb1o7_500.jpg"/><br/> Heaps of garlic -good to fight vampires bad for kisses!<br/><br/> <p><em><strong>M&S Espana Garlic Mushrooms</strong></em><br/><em>-tasty starter full of garlic</em></p>
<p> The M&S product line “Espana” is meant to bring Spanish/Catalan flavours to your kitchen. It features loads of paella and chorizo dishes.</p>
<p>The ‘M&S Espana Garlic Mushrooms’ can be enjoyed as a starter or a side dish. They are full of flavour which you can tell by the list of ingredients: olive oil, white wine, garlic and parsley are definitely a winning mix.</p>
<p>Ever since I had my first fresh brown mushroom, I never wanted to go back to white mushrooms (occasionally I did but I always regretted it).</p>
<p>The ’M&S Espana Garlic Mushrooms’ are yummy however, less garlic and less oil would have been better on my opinion. Especially the garlic was too dominant for me. The name ‘Garlic’ mushroom does give away that the dish will have a garlic taste but even though I love garlic, this was too much.</p>
<p>Please don’t add any more fat when frying. Also be aware of the alcohol that was used as an ingredient. Personally, I would like to see a special note on the packaging.</p>
<p><em><strong>4 out of 5 stars</strong></em></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="56c556ca2dd7973f12254aad0425b0a1" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/52875262026"><![CDATA[<img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/471b648d28706a9041ba9a8e2cfa16dc/tumblr_mocb8ekO8a1s5cqb1o7_500.jpg"/><br/> Stir the yogurt in and add a slice of toast if you like ;)<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/8571cb5f849a51a206de6a7e4f87bc15/tumblr_mocb8ekO8a1s5cqb1o1_500.jpg"/><br/> The M&S Maroccan Spiced Chicken and Super Fruity Tabouleh<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/f65303411ed5a6868e0ea8d168617b04/tumblr_mocb8ekO8a1s5cqb1o2_500.jpg"/><br/> All delicious and nutricious<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/48ed02d7261a2e552dcea4f5ebc2b44c/tumblr_mocb8ekO8a1s5cqb1o3_500.jpg"/><br/> Always cook the meat first - even though it says don't ;)<br/><br/> <img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/2ea8fbfa4c181f8c229283e7ccb24402/tumblr_mocb8ekO8a1s5cqb1o4_500.jpg"/><br/> All in one (pot) -looking good, smelling delish<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/38dbd075b8f0ddd85c45cf57acf39d77/tumblr_mocb8ekO8a1s5cqb1o5_500.jpg"/><br/> Nicely organized on a plate...<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/420b0d10a0fe04b010073e2414622975/tumblr_mocb8ekO8a1s5cqb1o6_500.jpg"/><br/> ...and decorated with yogurt<br/><br/> <img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/5d631ef1e8dd9b17b98efcca257e539c/tumblr_mocb8ekO8a1s5cqb1o8_500.jpg"/><br/> Play with the tenderstem broccoli or rather crunch/munch away...<br/><br/> <p><em><strong>The M&S Maroccan Spiced Chicken and Super Fruity Tabouleh</strong></em><br/><em>-‘Delicious & Nutricious’ and full of healthy flavours</em></p>
<p>So this is the new M&S ’Delicious & Nutricious’ product line. Looking good: like the package and the food looks like high and healthy quality. Unfortunately for me, that includes loads of fruit in most dishes (fructose intolerance!)<br/>Thus, I decide to have the ‘Maroccan Spiced Chicken and Super Fruity Tabouleh’ without actually knowing if I had ever had tabouleh… If I remember right, I had it before but I couldn’t remember the name.</p>
<p>All of the ingredients look very crunchy -it’s always nice to have nuts or in this case sunflower seeds added to your dish. I also fell in love with tenderstem broccoli.</p>
<p>The whole dish was really tasty. The only little downside for me was the honey that was added to the chicken as it gave my fructose levels a bit of a hard time.</p>
<p>As usual, I don not recommend to heat the dish up in the microwave but quickly fry the ingredients. Even though the instructions say that you can/should fry all ingredients at the same time, I prefer to do the chicken first.</p>
<p>Great dish, interesting product line!</p>
<p><em><strong>4+ out of 5 stars</strong></em></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b3b9f2cbc981a8948c1e3a253d759241" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/53863124931"><![CDATA[<img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/3befd0ad5c4acbdb761964fd0f5171ff/tumblr_moyrjppjP01s5cqb1o1_500.jpg"/><br/> The M&S Belgian Metropolitan Milk Chocolate Biscuits<br/><br/> <img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/fabe75b681385b111a1511360f017148/tumblr_moyrjppjP01s5cqb1o2_500.jpg"/><br/> Ingredients - desiccated coconut YAY flavourings NAY<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/60832710e32fe4d25da80786101a5ab5/tumblr_moyrjppjP01s5cqb1o3_500.jpg"/><br/> Get them out!<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/54624041de7276cf499bcbe60f82a3ed/tumblr_moyrjppjP01s5cqb1o4_500.jpg"/><br/> Work well with coffee/milk/tea and telly<br/><br/> <img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/3970dbe5e515e6d88a961a800d789414/tumblr_moyrjppjP01s5cqb1o5_500.jpg"/><br/> Dunk it or not?<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/d87202e14dcc59f10d783fd66b14ad10/tumblr_moyrjppjP01s5cqb1o6_500.jpg"/><br/> YUM -warning addictive, especially in front of the telly!<br/><br/> <p><strong><em>The M&S Belgian Metropolitan Milk Chocolate Biscuits</em></strong><br/><em>-I want my biccies</em></p>
<p>Sweets are yum. Sweets are unhealthy. We all know that. However, from time to time, we all need our little treats.<br/>The M&S Belgian Metropolitan Milk Chocolate Biscuits are made for cosy couch days in front of the telly. Equally you will love them on your office desk.</p>
<p>I’ve always been in love with biscuits that are covered by chocolate. Digestives are great but sometimes I feel like a less oaty taste and therefore these Belgian milk chocolate biscuits are fantastic. Sweet but not too sweet (especially when you have them with coffee/milk), crunchy but still soft and dunkable so you would like to.</p>
<p>Again M&S uses free range eggs and the hint of coconut rounds the flavour up but the vanilla flavourings could be replace by real vanilla if you ask me…</p>
<p>A great treat but don’t get addicted ;)</p>
<p><em><strong>4 out of 5 stars</strong></em></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f6d12833ff3519c4655c58dc9f3f38db" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/54532686146"><![CDATA[<img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/a80fb9e41945dff6aadc879a44c99547/tumblr_mpdl1m8Q741s5cqb1o1_500.jpg"/><br/> Simply M&S Pea & Cheddar Frittata<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/d2091d43218d0cc295508bac9c25f2a0/tumblr_mpdl1m8Q741s5cqb1o5_500.jpg"/><br/> Love to see petits pois in this dish as I usually have peas in my scrambled eggs<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/bd74282a49539121b0a76d372aa2e836/tumblr_mpdl1m8Q741s5cqb1o2_500.jpg"/><br/> Everything in the pan (non-sticky!!!)<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/5ec73a61211a493c002a461f657db810/tumblr_mpdl1m8Q741s5cqb1o3_500.jpg"/><br/> Give it some time, then flip it (as good as you can)<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/a9f18d7546af47185f1e67fcf4c8c87b/tumblr_mpdl1m8Q741s5cqb1o4_500.jpg"/><br/> Et voilà: The frittata plus (rocket and rye bread)<br/><br/> <p><em><strong>The “Simply M&S Pea & Cheddar Frittata”</strong></em><br/><em>-flip and munch away…</em></p>
<p>You probably know that I love <a href="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/48127379123/scrambled-omega3" title="My M&S omega3 scrambled eggs">scrambled eggs</a>… There’s almost no weekend without them. Therefore, I certainly had to try the ”Simply M&S Pea & Cheddar Frittata” recipe!</p>
<p>This is what you need:</p>
<p>- 6 Simply M&S medium free range eggs (or omega3)<br/>- 250g Simply M&S frozen petit pois, defrosted and drained<br/>- 175 g Simply M&S English Mature Cheddar, coarsely grated<br/>- 1 Simply M&S garlic clove, crushed<br/>- 3 tablespoons olive oil<br/>- Salt and freshly ground black pepper<br/>- Salad leaves and dressing to serve</p>
<p>For instructions and the M&S TV clip check the M&S <a href="http://social.marksandspencer.com/recipes/pea-and-chedder-frittata/" title="M&S Pea & Cheddar Frittata">website</a>.</p>
<p>I added some left-over rocket salad and my compulsory (rye) bread. My flipping wasn’t as successful as hoped but there was still a slight difference to the consistency of my scrambled eggs recognizable…</p>
<p>The cheddar adds a nice flavour and the whole recipe is quite easy to follow.<br/>I totally enjoyed the frittata and would always cook it again. In addition, you can add more ingredients (e.g. mushrooms or tomatoes).</p>
<p>The “Simply M&S Pea & Cheddar Frittata”</p>
<p><em><strong><strike>Simply</strike> Truly recommended.</strong></em></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="cfdb3827ff37dd77168e0605a3bc8acd" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/55506935145"><![CDATA[““There is no love sincerer than the love of food.”” - George Bernard Shaw 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fd60050df5a814afcbe87fb0dd2431fc" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/55509450105"><![CDATA[<img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/b0673d217700a2eb8be39b7c916623dd/tumblr_mpzbcelNdM1s5cqb1o1_500.jpg"/><br/> The M&S Spicy Peanut Chicken<br/><br/> <img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/88a6ed03227703c5ce73956dca393fce/tumblr_mpzbcelNdM1s5cqb1o2_500.jpg"/><br/> Getting a little sweaty in the box? Let's get it out!<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/f4dcd48e1cc6edd4aed531740db9b358/tumblr_mpzbcelNdM1s5cqb1o3_500.jpg"/><br/> All fresh now and colourful ingredients<br/><br/> <img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/751cfbec8254a96f2d7a51788df26c70/tumblr_mpzbcelNdM1s5cqb1o4_500.jpg"/><br/> Meat goes in first in my house...<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/21c4182a8b62e7ad1a22a3bf61caa497/tumblr_mpzbcelNdM1s5cqb1o5_500.jpg"/><br/> ...then the veggies...<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/16d753f9b172a081410f76c8a5e318c2/tumblr_mpzbcelNdM1s5cqb1o6_500.jpg"/><br/> and finally the peanut sauce.<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/e2e44cd5ce95540591087d7768e7defd/tumblr_mpzbcelNdM1s5cqb1o7_500.jpg"/><br/> A colourful and crunchy dish on my plate.<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/7672b333ece4c90bae490642b90a67c8/tumblr_mpzbcelNdM1s5cqb1o8_500.jpg"/><br/> Yet the lime was quite dominant and the chicken was partly gristly.<br/><br/> <img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/a5717a7ee9143026b8a75e4a84a6f96e/tumblr_mpzbcelNdM1s5cqb1o9_500.jpg"/><br/> I loved the crunchy sugar snap peas!<br/><br/> <p><em><strong>The M&S Spicy Peanut Chicken</strong></em><br/><em>Crunchy, colourful but could be better</em></p>
<p> I really love the packaging of the M&S “Modern Asia” range: Simply great.</p>
<p>The Spicy Peanut Chicken was a no brainer for me as love satay and the ingredients looked fresh and yummy.</p>
<p>As usual, I fried the meat first and then I added the veggies and finally the sauce. It all looked great, however the smell was already different then expected.<br/>I was looking forward to a sweet peanutty sauce but instead the lime and the ginger were very dominant. Also, the meat was partly gristly, however this was the first time ever a M&S chicken didn’t taste as good as expected. Thus, maybe I was just unlucky.</p>
<p>I really liked the greens and the crunchy carrots.</p>
<p>The whole dish was quite refreshing. It might be good on hot Summer days as it tasted quite light. The rice noodles might have contributed to this ‘light impression’, especially when you compare them to the thicker and heavier Udon Noodles (like in the <a href="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/44577146674/sichuan-pork-noodles" title="M&S Spicy Sichuan Pork Noodles">M&S Spicy Sichuan Pork Noodles</a>).</p>
<p>All in all, a nice crunchy dish. However, I’ll hesitate to buy it again as I’d die for a good chicken satay and this dish is just not the same…</p>
<p><em><strong>3+ out of 5 stars</strong></em></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8f8c07ca7c674c11a192659f1f27b6a" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/56253876216"><![CDATA[<img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/4a0703d60e32abbb1610bdfe70e07a27/tumblr_mqehh5xp5k1s5cqb1o1_500.jpg"/><br/> M&S Devon Scones with Raspberries and Custard / vanilla yoghurt<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/cc154448c3a993b81e752fdad3b805e7/tumblr_mqehh5xp5k1s5cqb1o2_500.jpg"/><br/> Scone buns without raisins YAY<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/3afd32a578080e4d851b49e09549075d/tumblr_mqehh5xp5k1s5cqb1o3_500.jpg"/><br/> fresh raspberries<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/7b1bf1e19aaf3ea3509756daf3629819/tumblr_mqehh5xp5k1s5cqb1o4_500.jpg"/><br/> Step one: decorate the plate with raspberries and custard / vanilla yoghurt<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/e1bed6e4b0e6b2c0ef50d993b8608045/tumblr_mqehh5xp5k1s5cqb1o5_500.jpg"/><br/> Step two: half the scone and place the bottom in the centre of the plate<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/2ff48993429b547845e3bae635d7cc81/tumblr_mqehh5xp5k1s5cqb1o6_500.jpg"/><br/> Step three: fill the scone with custard and raspberry pieces<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/ea8f7d048eedd0eb96951f4216ea25e7/tumblr_mqehh5xp5k1s5cqb1o7_500.jpg"/><br/> Step four: put the top half in position and sprinkle it with icing sugar<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/ccdcebaa819664ce063f25901df407bd/tumblr_mqehh5xp5k1s5cqb1o8_500.jpg"/><br/> Add some custard / vanilla yoghurt and a raspberry on top if you like<br/><br/> <img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/0cdbfde65c34d74a8a3731beefc89bca/tumblr_mqehh5xp5k1s5cqb1o9_500.jpg"/><br/> My flatmates Kirsten and William liked the M&S scones "Diana's version"<br/><br/> <img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/d2a940cb12aa2f7f0c41f594b5225279/tumblr_mqehh5xp5k1s5cqb1o10_500.jpg"/><br/> Do you want to have a go?<br/><br/> <p><em><strong>The M&S Devon Scones -Diana’s version</strong></em><br/><em>light fruity scones</em></p>
<p>So here I am, a German in England. I HAVE to have scones, don’t I?!<br/>I mean, I did have scones before and when I say scones, I’m talking scones (with cream tea): fresh from the oven with fluffy clotted cream.<br/>Unfortunately, I can’t have proper scones with raisins any more due to my fructose intolerance. In addition, with all that clotted cream and sugar, proper scones are quite heavy (and thus, great to share).</p>
<p>However, I wanted to make a healthier scone option and was happy to find the M&S Devon scones without raisins. To be fair, raspberries contain loads of fructose as well but still less than raisins. You can either replace the clotted cream with custard or with vanilla yoghurt. I used Rachel’s organic vanilla flavoured yoghurt which is less sweet then clotted cream and custard.</p>
<p>To add a bit of temperature, you may heat the scones up -either in the oven or in the toaster (be careful, you don’t want burnt scones).<br/>I also replaced the icing sugar with dextrose to support my digestion system with the fructose intake. </p>
<p>Personally, I really enjoyed the light and fresh version of the scones and the buns were a great base. My flatmate Kirsten however, has more of a sweet tooth and prefers the sweeter ‘proper’ scones.</p>
<p>Why not try to make up your own version today?<br/>It’s done in no time and with a bit of effort for a nice decoration, you will please your Mum or any other loved one. </p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a434626e4efeb4038719042ee7cb8a92" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/56268064917"><![CDATA[<img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/adc770bf79f0dd10c3cc9f2de2ebc558/tumblr_mqepvpNf6F1s5cqb1o1_500.jpg"/><br/> M&S Steamed Vegetable Dim Sum<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/19957499f04d1aa589b87cfb1a64e510/tumblr_mqepvpNf6F1s5cqb1o2_500.jpg"/><br/> lovely "Modern Asia" packaging<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/37aa35aa8e749177d35c93eb2266cbc4/tumblr_mqepvpNf6F1s5cqb1o3_500.jpg"/><br/> ingredients: oyster mushrooms, Chinese chive flower and yam beans -EXOTIC!<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/3bb83b2138a2c35c5cf4a84dd3bb854b/tumblr_mqepvpNf6F1s5cqb1o4_500.jpg"/><br/> Preferable frying over a medium heat<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/2215f83a148c88ae0e21575b1183ad70/tumblr_mqepvpNf6F1s5cqb1o5_500.jpg"/><br/> decorated on a glass plate<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/94436b23087a4870a27ce911cd3713ff/tumblr_mqepvpNf6F1s5cqb1o6_500.jpg"/><br/> Use chopsticks -or fingers ;)<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/c2898477dbc99b13d3d7d55750fdd467/tumblr_mqepvpNf6F1s5cqb1o7_500.jpg"/><br/> Add a little soy sauce...<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/abcbb53065af6faf74e718c30a6b243c/tumblr_mqepvpNf6F1s5cqb1o8_500.jpg"/><br/> ...or sweet chilli...<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/1016da6eac8e83b073c005a50498c723/tumblr_mqepvpNf6F1s5cqb1o9_500.jpg"/><br/> ...or M&S soy chilli dressing :)<br/><br/> <p><em><strong>The M&S Steamed Vegetable Dim Sum</strong></em><br/><em>an exotic starter/snack full of flavour and spices</em></p>
<p>The Asian kitchen is great! I really love it. On my trip to China last year, I tried both divine and disgusting dishes but in general, I really enjoy Asian food and I love the M&S ‘Modern Asia’ range (see the <a href="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/44577146674/sichuan-pork-noodles" title="The M&S Spicy Sichuan Pork Noodles">'Spicy Sichuan Pork Noodles'</a>, the <a href="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/46868694660/teriyakisalmon" title="The M&S Teriyaki Salmon">'Teriyaki Salmon'</a> and the <a href="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/55509450105/the-m-s-spicy-peanut-chicken-crunchy-colourful" title="The M&S Spicy Peanut Chicken">'Spicy Peanut Chicken'</a>).</p>
<p>Now, I was very excited about the M&S Dim Sum. As usual, I ignored the “For best results microwave” advice and fry the Dim Sum. To be fair, for the real Dim Sum experience, you should steam it but I was lacking the equipment.<br/>If you fry it, make sure you only use a medium heat so you don’t burn it.</p>
<p>The M&S Steamed Dim Sum was incredibly full of flavours. I think I can say I have barely tasted anything similar. I was really amazed since I’ve had many different spring rolls and they all taste very similar. When you look at the ingredients, you will find oyster mushrooms, Chinese chive flower and yam beans -an unusual taste guaranteed.</p>
<p>I added some soy sauce and the M&S Soy, Chilli and Coriander Dressing to round the taste up. However, the plain Dim Sum are tasty enough so if you feel like adding sauce, don’t overdo it.</p>
<p>What a fantastic taste! Always again.</p>
<p>5 out of 5 stars</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="47a44b9ef78c51d6d6c579b6faad550" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/57709902974"><![CDATA[<img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/4fe0841a9d3b779032aedbf7b0bf62c4/tumblr_mr7zr9yFZp1s5cqb1o5_500.jpg"/><br/> Perfect snack-bite portions, decorated delightly<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/6427459c29a887a88c03c8968725d57c/tumblr_mr7zr9yFZp1s5cqb1o2_500.jpg"/><br/> Even on a hot day they did not melt -amazing!<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/e132865724c0170cb02dac038db0b44f/tumblr_mr7zr9yFZp1s5cqb1o3_500.jpg"/><br/> No eggs! Actually a bit of E503 as a rising agent...<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/8c99f5a264107f2216e62e1740e2bbc4/tumblr_mr7zr9yFZp1s5cqb1o4_500.jpg"/><br/> naked on a plate... sooo tempting!<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/01dad739637284183215be71f1db2563/tumblr_mr7zr9yFZp1s5cqb1o1_500.jpg"/><br/> The M&S Great British Summer Tripple Chocolate Tiffins<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/8dbbfa9a12cb58a21c94f826777ff4b3/tumblr_mr7zr9yFZp1s5cqb1o6_500.jpg"/><br/> For best results/enjoyment: with a coffee -alternatively milk or tea<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/094a3e0db96f492cb7ba3eb1abeca983/tumblr_mr7zr9yFZp1s5cqb1o7_500.jpg"/><br/> Having a Great (British) Summer bite...<br/><br/> <img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/8aecdff0db0ab1dd5631cb3d9d707769/tumblr_mr7zr9yFZp1s5cqb1o8_500.jpg"/><br/> Absolutely DIVINE!<br/><br/> <p><strong><em>The M&S Great British Summer Tripple Chocolate Tiffins</em></strong><br/><em>-triple divineness</em></p>
<p>WOW - yes it was definitely one of those M&S-WOW-moments that I regularly get, when I first saw ‘The M&S Great British Summer Tripple Chocolate Tiffins’. I mean TIFFINS -I LOVE tiffins! Ever since I had my first <a href="http://londoncallingundisguised.tumblr.com/post/53957525264/coffee-love" title="My London coffee shops review" target="_blank">Costa Belgium Chocolate Tiffin</a> about four years ago, I couldn’t stop having my regularly (=weeklyish) tiffin.</p>
<p><em><strong>What is a tiffin?</strong></em></p>
<p>Tiffins are a form of cake-like confection composed of crushed biscuits (mainly digestives), sugar, syrup, raisins and cocoa powder, often covered with a layer of melted chocolate. The best thing -besides the divine taste- is that tiffins don’t require any baking! Thus, sometimes, they are called ‘fridge cakes’.</p>
<p>Even though I should not have raisins (fructose), I can’t resist a good tiffin and if you would leave out the raisins, something would be missing.</p>
<p><em><strong>What’s special about the M&S tiffins?</strong></em></p>
<p>Well, what a great move of creating a TRIPLE CHOC tiffin! A nice mix of chocolatey flavours. As the Costa tiffins sometimes slightly break in pieces (which eventually fall to the ground -what a waste!) I am happy to see that the M&S tiffins come in bite size.<br/>M&S also adds shortbread to the (digestives) biscuits mix which gives the tiffin a fuller biccy flavour.<br/>The 6% sultanas seemed to be in dices which left a little ‘processed impression’ on my and I didn’t like there rather jam than fruity flavour.</p>
<p><em><strong>Conclusion</strong></em><br/>Surely, the M&S tiffins won’t replace my regular Costa tiffin treat as Costa’s tiffin appears more ‘handmade’ and therefore have a slightly greater ‘freshly prepared’ flavour. However, I like the triple choc mix and the practical size of the M&S tiffins. They are better to share and believe me, you won’t be able to have the pack for yourself -those tiffins are far too heavy. I usually have my tiffins with coffee to neutralize the super-sweet taste. Equally works milk or tea, whatever you prefer.</p>
<p>Marks and Spencer, now, that you do my favourite treat, I love you even more!</p>
<p>Let this <em>'Great British Summer'</em> never end…</p>
<p><em><strong>5 out of 5 stars</strong></em></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9c0808ccb926b74f5419e343b7bb5ab7" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/59388825068"><![CDATA[<img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/77c776ee62352d73b9bc9e7ae9e45c65/tumblr_ms500r7o5y1s5cqb1o1_500.jpg"/><br/> Lamb pastries and onion rings<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/f135cfb17c4392df178fc8f47e524965/tumblr_ms500r7o5y1s5cqb1o2_500.jpg"/><br/> M&S DELI Moroccan Style Lamb Pastries <br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/b3b246f801b8092dce43f5941237f31e/tumblr_ms500r7o5y1s5cqb1o5_500.jpg"/><br/> ingredients - authentic Harissa<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/1f6f712caf52910c66ee562aa38b78fe/tumblr_ms500r7o5y1s5cqb1o4_500.jpg"/><br/> M&S Onion Rings<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/a79080416bdf2eebe26625d9bd7f6dce/tumblr_ms500r7o5y1s5cqb1o6_500.jpg"/><br/> ingredients<br/><br/> <img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/9d58963d2803bb9469c0477eb4dc2be1/tumblr_ms500r7o5y1s5cqb1o7_500.jpg"/><br/> mixed platter<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/f2a6e48fadc398187c04a83fb90a86db/tumblr_ms500r7o5y1s5cqb1o8_500.jpg"/><br/> add some soy chilli coriander dressing<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/b66b6ffb7777e265c1d2fc546850012e/tumblr_ms500r7o5y1s5cqb1o9_500.jpg"/><br/> great handy snack -slightly greasy: onion rings, what else?!<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/fd2131541a938d4ccd3a8e49759406e4/tumblr_ms500r7o5y1s5cqb1o10_500.jpg"/><br/> very tasty and flavourful lamb pastries<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/0a545a4818881443dccbd9d0ace36b1c/tumblr_ms500r7o5y1s5cqb1o11_500.jpg"/><br/> packed with great ingredients<br/><br/> <p><em><strong>The M&S DELI Moroccan Style Lamb Pastries with onion rings</strong></em><br/>-snack away </p>
<p>The M&S DELI range was invented in line with the Deli Counters in stores. Both are designed to bring international flavours to M&S customers.</p>
<p>Even though I don’t really like lamb (besides quality lamb from New Zealand), I thought I give the Moroccan style lamb pastries a go. As I also had some onion rings, I combined both to create a great snack.<br/>I grilled everything in the oven (instead of microwaving it). </p>
<p>The lamb pastries were really tasty. A nice but not too dominant meat flavour completed with authentic spices.</p>
<p>On the contrary, the onion rings needed a bit of an additional dip. Thus, I added some M&S low fat soy, chilli and coriander dressing.</p>
<p>Great snack -also great as finger food on parties!<br/>Just slightly (too) greasy.. </p>
<p>4 out of 5 stars</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="500d8f9fa75e0cf2d91f2870095b6d0" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/60086032718"><![CDATA[<img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/6aef3dbac152b18f4024e0687e7203db/tumblr_msiavf1Inw1s5cqb1o1_250.jpg"/><br/><br/><p><strong><em><span>Nathan Ansell - </span></em></strong><em><strong>Head of Brand and Marketing for M&S Food</strong></em><strong><em><span><br/></span></em></strong><em><span>Meet the expert</span></em></p>
<p><span><br/></span></p>
<p><span>Nathan is currently <em><strong>Head of Brand and Marketing for M&S Food</strong></em>. Nathan joined the team in November 2011 as Head of Brand and was promoted into his current role in September 2012. <br/><br/> Prior to moving to M&S he was European Marketing Manager at <strong><em>Birds Eye </em></strong></span><strong><em>iglo Group (BEiG</em></strong><span><strong><em>)</em></strong>, the market leading frozen foods business in Europe. </span><span><br/> Nathan previously held a number of marketing roles at <strong><em>Heinz</em></strong>, quickly rising through the ranks to run Heinz </span><span>Beanz</span><span> - a top ten UK grocery brand worth £200 million RSV. He was credited with leading the company’s biggest ever brand investment, launching Heinz Snap Pots, which clocked up sales of over £20m in the first year.</span></p>
<p><span><br/> Nathan had his first taste of consumer marketing at <strong><em>Red Bull</em></strong>, first whilst at University and then continuing to work for Red Bull as a Regional Brand Manager. Nathan holds a first class (</span><span>hons</span><span>) degree in Neurological Psychology from UWS.</span></p>
<p>Find the first part of the interview with Mr Ansell <a href="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/60110948771/ansell-interview1" title="Interview: Nathan Ansell -part I">here</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4a408f84e0201b5a6b0346e97708738" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/60110948771"><![CDATA[<img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/8ee4255a809ad85e4a5daa2a4b26b2c1/tumblr_msinjzG7A01s5cqb1o4_500.png"/><br/> 'Make Today Delicious' - a campaign by M&S<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/6aef3dbac152b18f4024e0687e7203db/tumblr_msinjzG7A01s5cqb1o1_250.jpg"/><br/> Nathan Ansell<br/><br/> <img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/3cce4ca87244c3ee4d2b520260e48e0a/tumblr_msinjzG7A01s5cqb1o2_500.jpg"/><br/> Mr Ansell's favourite M&S product<br/><br/> <img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/e20e527591a0dece13e67df640f20b35/tumblr_msinjzG7A01s5cqb1o3_500.jpg"/><br/> The M&S 'Great British Summer'<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/02091c26a070f7aff1bf449f74c3fc84/tumblr_msinjzG7A01s5cqb1o5_500.jpg"/><br/> Woodfired means woodfired<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/c58e35c06b26b50b29413a41c5486e59/tumblr_msinjzG7A01s5cqb1o6_500.jpg"/><br/> The mock-up LP 'M&S Food Halls ed.'<br/><br/> <p><strong><em>Nathan Ansell - </em></strong><span class="Apple-style-span"><em><strong>Head of Brand and Marketing for M&S Food</strong></em></span><br/><em>-the interview</em> part I: the serious bits</p>
<p><em><strong><br/></strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>What is your favourite M&S product?</strong> </em></p>
<p>Well, I guess it would have to be the <a href="http://www.marksandspencer.com/Marks-and-Spencer-Gastro-Shanks/dp/B005OT42WY" title="The Gastro Pub Lamb Shanks" target="blank">Gastro Pub Lamb Shanks</a>.</p>
<p><em><strong><br/></strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>What is a ‘Great British Summer’ to you?</strong></em></p>
<p>For me the absolute perfect <em>'Great British Summer'</em> is friends and family in the garden, BBQ and British Ales.</p>
<p><em><strong><br/></strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>Tell us a bit about the ‘Make Today Delicious’ campaign.</strong></em></p>
<p>The point about <em>'Make today delicious'</em> is we have this believe that any occasion can be better with really really great food. It doesn‘t really matter whether you are having a mid-week bite to eat with a partner or whether you are having a pick-nick with loads of friends. It doesn‘t even matter if it‘s raining outside - as long as you have fantastic food, you can have a good time and have a really good occasion. That‘s the thinking of that campaign.</p>
<p><em><strong><br/></strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>I‘ve been trying out your ready meals although I don‘t very much like ready meals and I was very surprised how tasty they are. How do you make them so delicious?</strong></em></p>
<p>Instead of using a smoked flavour in our Gastro Pub smoked duck for example, we use real smoked duck meat and our woodfired pizzas are actually made in a proper woodfire oven. Also, for our paella dishes, we use proper kitchen pans. That‘s why it tastes like it made self or restaurant cooked and it basically also contains the same ingredients.</p>
<p><em><strong><br/></strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>In my M&S <a href="https://vimeo.com/68312597" title="The mock-up LP M&S Food Halls ed." target="blank">‘travel guide‘ </a>I talk about the ‘special ingredient’ M&S always uses -like free range eggs, rapseed oil, halloumi cheese, Chinese chive flower- where do you get the inspiration from?</strong></em></p>
<p>We spend an enormous amount of time on travelling all around the world, eating in the most amazing restaurants, meeting fantastic chefs and also talking to several people for a better understanding of different tastes and specialities to make sure we always use proper ingredients and make dishes the traditional way. It takes huge amounts -not just desk research but basic research where we go out to all different parts of the world to understand what it really takes to replicate a dish. We‘re not cutting corners but using those real traditional ingredients.</p>

<p>Find the (cheeky) second part of the interview <a href="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/60574559942/ansell-interview2" title="Interview with Nathan Ansell -part II">here</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5de95816585d1fd58fc1a661cf08c6ec" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/60574559942"><![CDATA[<img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/6aef3dbac152b18f4024e0687e7203db/tumblr_msrwhh0SrB1s5cqb1o7_250.jpg"/><br/> Nathan Ansell - Head of Brand and Marketing, Food, Plan A, M&S Energy<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/96d63a13f0e1d718fd37cfa5e6ee3168/tumblr_msrwhh0SrB1s5cqb1o1_500.jpg"/><br/> Percy Pig<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/d6b2db6f5d2018c68b1c090159a5f88b/tumblr_msrwhh0SrB1s5cqb1o2_500.jpg"/><br/> Colin the Caterpillar -my favourite M&S character<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/119543b2736352358fa39592d923a19d/tumblr_msrwhh0SrB1s5cqb1o3_500.jpg"/><br/> 'Made without wheat' - gluten free sandwiches<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/528f75dc9981c3f16f3863f38cdad12a/tumblr_msrwhh0SrB1s5cqb1o4_500.jpg"/><br/> Marc Bolland at the store opening in Paris<br/><br/> <img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/17e9f047e094b6adac4fd3bf870a7373/tumblr_msrwhh0SrB1s5cqb1o5_500.jpg"/><br/> The M&S Vegetarian range<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/39ce2f2c615e25a27f5f920d1707c9ee/tumblr_msrwhh0SrB1s5cqb1o6_500.jpg"/><br/> The M&S Gastro Pub Scotch Eggs<br/><br/> <p><em><strong>Nathan Ansell - Head of Brand and Marketing for M&S Food </strong></em><br/><em>-the interview part II: the cheeky bits</em></p>
<p><em><br/></em></p>
<p><em><strong>On my blog I have several posts about my favourite M&S character <a href="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/47207660574/colin-easter" title="Easter hunt for Colin" target="blank">“Colin the Caterpiller“</a>, now Percy Pig just got a lot attention for his 21st birthday. Will Collin get some attention soon?</strong></em></p>
<p>Well, it was a big birthday for Percy, so we gave him a lot of attention. However, since Colin is a good friend of Percy, he was always there to celebrate. At the moment there is no such a special event for Colin planned but I’m sure he will get his chance to shine sometime in the future.</p>
<p><br/><br/></p>
<p><em><strong>While working for Red Bull, you spend quite some time in Germany, what are your impressions of the German cuisine? </strong></em></p>
<p>I don‘t know if I have tried the best of Germany as I actually only had cream spinach, potatoes and fish sticks. So, I‘m not sure if I saw the best from the German cuisine. However, I tell you something I like about the German food offering which is the variety of products for lactose and gluten intolerant customers. I think you deal with food allergies much much better. I think there is a much greater awareness.</p>
<p><em><strong><br/></strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong><br/></strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>M&S is currently expanding in France - Are there more branches on the European main land planned?</strong></em></p>
<p>Our store in Paris is a phenomenal success actually. We are really really pleased with that success: Every day people are queueing for knickers and our croissants. They are doing pretty well. We are definitely looking to make up more stores on the continent. Probably stores that are a bit closer to the UK at the moment. But we are definitely looking as the demand has been fantastic.</p>
<p><br/><br/></p>
<p><em><strong>In Germany, there is a current debate on whether there should be a veggi day at office cafeterias - what do you think about that?</strong></em></p>
<p>I definitely think that the idea of having a meat-free Monday is a really good one. We do talk a lot about the consuption of meat. You know a billion of people will go to bed tonight starving while we sometimes go to bed on a big meat meal. So we definitely want to encourage people to maybe have one day per week to have a bit less meat or don‘t eat meat at all. I don‘t think we ever stop selling meat in general of to tell them off but we might encourage them and we always make sure that we have got plenty of vegetarian options.</p>
<p><br/><br/></p>
<p><em><strong>Can you give us a little sneak preview on the next M&S food events/campaigns?</strong></em></p>
<p>Coming up in Autumn, we will talk about getting cosy when it‘s getting cold at night. We will also have the 10th anniversary of Gastro Pub this year so we will launch fantastic traditional dishes. We also want to put a focus on the high quality warming types of food. So, it‘s going to be a really awesome period.</p>
<p><br/><br/></p>
<p><em><strong>Which M&S dish can you recommend me to try next? </strong></em></p>
<p>Well, the nex thing you should try is the limited edition Gastro Pub range which will come out in a few weeks time.</p>
<p><em><strong>I have always been hesitating to try the Gastro Pub Scotch Eggs because that is something very … British.</strong></em></p>
<p>Have you not tried them? Then try that -it‘s amazing!</p>
<p><br/><br/></p>
<p>Find the first part of the interview <a href="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/60110948771/ansell-interview1" title="Interview Nathan Ansell -part I" target="blank">here</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6d2f57285350391e94543e700877dcb1" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/69522077809"><![CDATA[<img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/4fc02f92e69ef99242ece7b17b1f00a4/tumblr_mxk8b9iyuM1s5cqb1o1_500.jpg"/><br/> M&S Chicken Bites & Fries<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/868f0b1611f37f4ddd35d4a018cfd987/tumblr_mxk8b9iyuM1s5cqb1o4_500.jpg"/><br/> nice little package<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/a2147af07a76dbe74ba24ee156bbe8c3/tumblr_mxk8b9iyuM1s5cqb1o5_500.jpg"/><br/> ingredients - nice and clean, maybe rapeseed oil could replace sunflower oil and dextrose is nice for #fructoseIntolerance<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/0ab6ee5a0712369060bc1138ab47bfd5/tumblr_mxk8b9iyuM1s5cqb1o7_500.jpg"/><br/> Do more of what makes you(r kids) happy :)<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/47c999d00308a49229e328f808515a5d/tumblr_mxk8b9iyuM1s5cqb1o6_500.jpg"/><br/> clean package and great food protection but more plastic waste<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/1b1e2b8ae774dffa73f5bf87ed8f082e/tumblr_mxk8b9iyuM1s5cqb1o8_500.jpg"/><br/> for a bit of a change<br/><br/> <img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/17d209c3431009d29a81840332257f00/tumblr_mxk8b9iyuM1s5cqb1o2_500.jpg"/><br/> If I don't see what I eat, I can eat anything -even fries. And also you won't see that I eat a kids' menu<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/6b6d8ca098c0d496935b2e9ec0e144cf/tumblr_mxk8b9iyuM1s5cqb1o3_500.jpg"/><br/> The M&S Chicken Bites & Fries are a great snack for kids AND 'big kids' and you can get creative in terms of the presentation...<br/><br/> <p><em><strong>The M&S Chicken & Fries</strong></em><br/><em>-a great snack for <strike>kids</strike> everyone</em></p>
<p>The first thing that catches my eye is the different <em><strong>packaging</strong></em>: a nice little paper box with green elements and some cartoony graphics. The dish is meant to be a kids menu.<br/>Well, I’m not exactly a kid anymore but I can be a big kid and who doesn’t like chicken nuggets and chips as a snack every now and then?!</p>

<p><br/><br/></p>

<p><em><strong>Portion size</strong></em></p>
<p>For sure, it looks like a tiny (kids’) portion (215g) but that is exactly what I need for dinner after having a good lunch.</p>

<p><br/><br/></p>

<p><em><strong>Ingredients</strong></em><br/>The best bit about kids menus is that the ingredients are usually of high quality -at least they are meant to be. Indeed, the list looks like nasty additives, preservatives, flavourings and sweeteners are left out.<br/>Surprisingly, the chips contain <strong><em>dextrose</em></strong>. For me being<em> fructose intolerant</em> that is good news as dextrose helps me to deal with fructose which I will get big time from ketchup and mayo.<br/>However, bear in mind that dextrose goes fast into the blood and then the sugar boost decreases fast.</p>

<p><br/><br/></p>

<p><em><strong>Preparation</strong></em><br/>I am very happy to see that the recommended preparation method is to bake it in the oven as it keeps the best nutritions of the product alive and gives the chips a nice golden colour and a crispy taste.</p>

<p><br/><br/></p>

<p><strong><em>Taste</em></strong><br/>Both, the chicken and the chips taste really nice and far less greasy than the chicken and chips from the shop around the corner (and it’s most likely still less expensive). The chicken also tastes better than most of the chicken pieces I have tried so far from Marks and Spencer.</p>

<p><br/><br/></p>

<p><strong><em>The special extra</em></strong><br/>It’s great to see that M&S kids menus support the Great Ormond Street Hospital Charity and local farmers as the chicken comes from Great Britain.<br/>The only little <strong><em>downside</em></strong> is the caption “low in salt” as the ‘equivalent to salt’ (what is that btw?!?) is 25g and the GDA for children is only 20g! However, I would imagine that alternative products might contain far more salt.</p>

<p><br/><br/></p>

<p><em><strong>The final rating</strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>4+ out of 5 stars</strong></em><br/><em>-what a fantastic snack (every now and then)</em></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2f5a434f10ccd3a84c0d5465bcbf58d7" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/69523733655"><![CDATA[The M&S Christmas TV Advert 2013: 

"Welcome to the Marks and Spencer fairytale"
Not bad, not...
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d841326e6db9cfe86ccc63f7b21abf73" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/69595834692"><![CDATA[<img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/1ed8859748e765e3adb99631fa219d4a/tumblr_mxlmt1fEDL1s5cqb1o4_500.jpg"/><br/> #CollinTheCaterpillar got a make over for Christmas #LoveIt #SoCute<br/><br/> <img src="http://31.media.tumblr.com/ea46f1d9582e8c2e4ada68aaae49d157/tumblr_mxlmt1fEDL1s5cqb1o1_500.jpg"/><br/> The #PercyPig #adventcalendar -like the design and for once Percy gets chocolaty<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/8a3c4a760f7b7910870594dd5604cf71/tumblr_mxlmt1fEDL1s5cqb1o5_500.jpg"/><br/> #HelloKitty #really?!<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/35bd2080ea8f016f3ff5e53453769c93/tumblr_mxlmt1fEDL1s5cqb1o3_500.jpg"/><br/> Good ol' #Santa is popping in...<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/6f4e5cff3c4b71397e6900c00ca847cc/tumblr_mxlmt1fEDL1s5cqb1o2_500.jpg"/><br/> Practical #Reindeer: nice double #adventcalendar with a #3D look<br/><br/> <img src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/75fb47eaea51ee57a8893bc8e6e64889/tumblr_mxlmt1fEDL1s5cqb1o6_500.jpg"/><br/> That's #classic -I LOVE "Where's Wally"<br/><br/> <p><strong><em>Which is your favourite advent (calendar) treat?</em></strong><br/><em>M&S is counting the days</em></p>
<p>When you’re a kid, advent calendar are just great: The make the time until Christmas shorter and you get an extra treat every day.<br/>When I was a kid, I sometimes had several advent calendar: one homemade from my Mum (she’s incredibly good at art and crafts and being creative), probably a chocolate one from the supermarkets from Dad and at least one from my grandparents.<br/>With time, I realized that those homemade ones are the best. Their are made with love.<br/>However, sometimes I have a weird crave for the supermarket ones as they seem to have a special (cheap) chocolate.</p>
<p><br/><br/></p>
<p><em><strong>Where’s <strike>Wally</strike> Colin?! </strong></em><br/>I was really close to buy a Marks And Spencer advent calendar this year but then I realized that there was no Colin the Caterpillar advent calendar!!!</p>
<p><br/><br/></p>
<p><em><strong>Percy Pig</strong></em><br/>Of course, Percy got his calendar. To be fair the design is quite nice but who are those little pigs? Anyway, Percy is famous to be that pink soft gum not for his chocolate products -in contrast to his best friend Colin.</p>
<p><br/><br/></p>
<p><em><strong>Hello Kitty</strong></em><br/>Hello?!? I know <em>"Hello Kitty"</em> is popular. I don’t like it. My association is a fluffy pink kitty. Now why should M&S have a red advent calendar of a brand that isn’t its own. Lately, I have seen <em>"Monsters Inc."</em> characters and there is the<em>"Where’s Wally"</em> -both way cooler than <em>"Hello Kitty"</em>- on the shelves which I don’t really appreciate. I believe Colin and Percy are great and able to sell enough or rather I would love M&S to be able to be strong enough to avoid selling other brands/names.</p>
<p><br/><br/></p>
<p><em><strong>Santa and his reindeer</strong></em><br/>In contrast, Santa and his reindeer are global Christmas characters and more than welcome on the shelves. I specifically like the double function of the reindeer calendar and its 3D look.</p>
<p><br/><br/></p>
<p><strong><em>Where’s Wally?</em></strong><br/>Wally’s wonderful. I love that game. It’s great to practice focussing and mindfulness. Certainly, I had to find Wally and I did. As usual, it wasn’t too easy. Can you find him?</p>
<p><br/><br/></p>
<p><em><strong>Colin’s Christmas</strong></em><br/>Recently, I brought Collin to a 20th birthday party and what shall I say, he was the star -right behind the birthday girl obviously.<br/>Seeing his Christmas make over makes me happy as he finally gets some attention again and I love the little hat:</p>
<p><em>Colin goes Christmas!</em></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2a61921ff4a60b4b90b404c5e8b62471" url="http://mandsfood.tumblr.com/post/72588019502"><![CDATA[<img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/76611d94e73e51cf21d4569e3495121e/tumblr_mz1w39alU71s5cqb1o1_500.jpg"/><br/> Filled with several sweeties #YUM but what do the numbers stand for?<br/><br/> <img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/74d0af8e249b6c70b2328687ffcf2a28/tumblr_mz1w39alU71s5cqb1o2_500.jpg"/><br/> Are you ready to party? Well, I'm afraid, it's "Invite only" -nice little details.<br/><br/> <p><strong><em>Are you ready to party???</em></strong><br/><em>-jump on the M&S Party bus</em></p>
<p>The Marks and Spencer party bus is filled with sweet passengers. The shortbread collection is indeed very sweet, especially those with the triple chocolate bits. It goes down really smooth with milk, coffee or tea.</p>
<p><br/><br/></p>
<p>Yes, it does taste amazing.</p>
<p><br/><br/></p>
<p>Furthermore, the design is quite cute. Not only is the red double decker famous for London and therefore always a bestseller design, Marks and Spencer pays attention to detail: it’s most exclusive <em>"Invite only"</em> and also the final destination is <em>"Paddington Basin"</em> where the M&S head office is based.</p>

<p>I’m still trying to figure out what the numbers 159 and 129 (number plate) stand for…</p>

<p>This “party bus” is amazing as a gift -I actually used it as a Christmas gift for my parents and the tin can be reused for several purposes.</p>

<p><br/><br/></p>
<p><em><strong>5 out of 5 stars</strong></em></p>
<p>Fabulous.</p>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>