<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="accidental-greenie.blogspot.com">
	<documents count="25">
		<document id="e3157766cf605b718eba311bff8def58" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2011/11/essential-oils-for-christmas.html"><![CDATA[

Tea light candle holders made from Australian Banksia seed pods


Diffusing essentials oils in your home at Christmas will not only help with creating a lovely festive aroma, but they can encourage a calm and relaxed state of being - a special gift at this busy time of year!

Although we have a hot Christmas in Australia, we still love the warming and woody oils traditionally associated with 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bdb35c72159b81a2840556b9348439e0" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2011/12/spending-for-positive-impact.html"><![CDATA[


For all of us concerned about the earth's precious and limited resources, Christmas time really stretches and strains our conscience.  We think carefully about the purchases we are making, about whether they are necessary and whether they are responsbile.

At Biome Eco Stores, we agonise over finding the balance between encouraging consumption at Christmas and operating a viable business.  For
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="79a16fe7fe72790cb7e8789f8bce07c8" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2012/01/mind-expanding-new-year-resolutions.html"><![CDATA[We all need the injection of energy that the start of a fresh year brings.  It's hard to avoid the reminder to stop the wheel of life, re-group, tweak priorities and chart a course for exciting new destinations.  There's something about opening a fresh diary, that same feeling of writing for the first time in a crisp new exercise book back in school days. How about pencilling in those blank pages
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f91cb7798fb5ca153168dc569d6b2a66" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2012/02/how-will-you-make-difference-today.html"><![CDATA[
Here's three ideas ...




Clean up Australia Day sneaks up on us every year--and it is now only 12 days away.  The main day is on Sunday, 4 March; Business Clean Up is 28 February, and Schools on Friday, 2 March.

Why not register for Clean up Australia Day and co-ordinate a group of friends?





Does it seem like forever since you last checked a printed telephone directory?  You can cancel 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f1ba7f5ad805a3d250d5bb0d0d0fdff8" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2012/02/put-cork-in-it.html"><![CDATA[



When 80% of the 20 billion bottles of wine produced in the world each year use natural corks, why do nearly all wine bottles in Australian bottle shops seem to have screw caps?

Is it a reflection of Australian culture?  After all, we drink a lot of beer with screw tops, perhaps we expect to be able to casually screw the top off a beverage. 

Australia and New Zealand are among the leaders in
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="26bb3d0baa4b81600d89e416ca15673b" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2012/03/fighting-to-save-my-home-reefs-wwf.html"><![CDATA[

We recommend a read of this informative and engaging blog post from WWF team member, Nick Heath > Fighting to save my home reefs | WWF-Australia BLOG  Nick's connection with the Great Barrier Reef began from a young age on his father's dive boat and he writes about the decline he sees in the Great Barrier Reef today.


Among the issues, Nick explains "We’ve learned that outdated farm practices 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6f56ba284c2330fe17d756743326a4bc" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2012/03/jump-on-local-food-train-for-ride.html"><![CDATA[



Image from www.foodconnect.com.au


People are asking questions.  People want to know not only where their food comes from, but who grew their food - not just a name, but details ... What motivates the grower?  How do they look after their soil?  What does the farmer do with their spare time?  Do they have kids?  What's their favourite food?  

There is a groundswell of interest in the 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="914b6dc43ae936f91e0e4fb56aedec9d" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2012/03/mineral-makeup-foundation.html"><![CDATA[

Musq - winner of the 2012 Natural Beauty Award for best foundation




Our international Women's Day offer to receive 25% off

all our Mineral Makeup has ended

Please join our Rewards program 

to be sure you hear about our next special offer!



Millions of
women in Australia and around the world are ditching the chemicals found in
conventional cosmetics in favour of beautiful natural 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3d2c5a0e9ad82e9da59c07053b2b001d" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2012/03/take-3-initiative-single-use-plastics.html"><![CDATA[





Story by Biome's Online Manager:  Some of the Biome team recently attended a screening of the documentary BAG IT, which was promoted by Queensland Conservation and
TAKE 3.



We learned how garbage and litter flows from our
waterways out to sea and the harm it causes to water birds and sea life as well
as our fragile ocean eco systems.



Turtles, who apparently eat everything, are

]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2d57aeea43407e713a28d931e5e5345e" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2012/04/magazine-for-green-mind-thrives.html"><![CDATA[

With its beautiful photography of sustainable, serene homes, gentle nature-inspired colour scheme, and thick matte-finish paper, Australian green magazine looks and feels as great as it reads.

Each issue of green showcases the most interesting and creative 
sustainable designs from product designers, architects and landscapers around Australia and
 internationally.  The content is as much for 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a982cc09b4163af246f80e10ee4f2859" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2012/05/keeping-free-range-free.html"><![CDATA[


Thank you to the Australian Greens for the content in this post.

Buyer beware ...
Consumers are being exploited with eggs labelled “free-range” that are not
truly free-range, while the the Egg Corporation is proposing to increase
free-range stocking from 1,500 to 20,000 birds per hectare!  This is a massive
1233 per cent increase in bird densities on the range. At this stocking rate,

]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b73d828be7890e4d4ab8f2c9df8462e9" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2012/06/bob-dylan-honour-blowin-in-wind-book.html"><![CDATA[


President Barack Obama 
awards Bob Dylan the Medal of Freedom. Image from the Huffington Post.













































We're honoured to offer a small part of Bob Dylan's story at Biome (see more about the book below), so we were pleased to hear that he received the Medal of Freedom, the United States' highest civilian honor.

According to the Huffington Post, Dylan
 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b64b739ae328b5602ac15992e031e0c8" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2012/07/best-queensland-organic-gourmet-finds.html"><![CDATA[




We had a sensational time at the Biome stall as part of Regional Flavours at South Bank, Brisbane this past weekend.   What a lively and positive gathering of Queensland food and wine producers and their devotees.  Cooking demonstrations with a garden to table theme were very popular, while the creative installations of productive gardens added to the inspiring atmosphere, like these herb 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="994b0da62be036295aa96c295f273230" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2012/08/green-olympics-london-gold-medal.html"><![CDATA[

Richmond Park, London.  Green Olympic rings salute mowed by traditional horse drawn drays.
Source: http://www.globalpost.com/photo/5711169/green-olympics

 


From the world's first "recycled stadium", a food strategy that requires balance, affordability and sustainability, to water-harvesting, cycle parks, a sustainable timber Velo track, plus, the target of sending none of the 8,000 tonnes of
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e5e74d263b0ec2d7fabea27b49ca4c80" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2012/10/clove-oil-and-mould.html"><![CDATA[

Many people with seemingly unsolveable allergies are excited by the growing consensus that mould causes some allergy and asthma problems - and clove oil is the magic ingredient to help end the sneezing and wheezing.

The Victorian Department of Health states:

Mould associated with damp buildings can trigger nasal congestion, 
sneezing,   cough, wheeze, respiratory infections and worsen asthma 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b1246c3e70e1eaa043029ea8e83e351f" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2012/10/led-replacement-for-halogen.html"><![CDATA[






Would you like to replace your
energy-guzzling halogen downlights with efficient LEDs but
are confused about where to start? 



Many people think it would be too difficult or costly - but actually it's much easier than you think.  Read on...



Home lighting is one of the most significant opportunities to save energy and slow climate 
change. Currently, lighting accounts for approximately
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="76348654f2c7a7b9c5feec4f64f9fcfd" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2013/01/tried-and-true-lunch-box-packing-ideas.html"><![CDATA[

Zucchini & Sweetcorn fritters.  Lunch box ideas photo source: www.taste.com.au 





Lunch box ideas to make it easy & nutritious
Biome's eco and health-minded community recently shared a bunch of brilliant ideas to help make packing a waste free, nutritious kids lunch box easy peasy!   They entered our survey competition to win a $200 voucher from Eeni Meeni Miini Moh. 

We were overwhelmed by
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1832cf5809464ec5aaeead4572e09633" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2013/02/leaf-love-beautiful-heart-shaped-leaves.html"><![CDATA[
We love this great green earth. Love is everywhere ... see it in nature around you ... in the tallest of trees, in the tiniest of leaves. We wish everyone a happy day of love and appreciation for every living thing.





The photographer said "The tiny red heart-shaped leaf was one of the last clinging to a branch 
of this shrub, so I turned it upside down and  held it up against a 
larger, 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="108ab3b690adbaf4b4b3d421aa0b89ef" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2013/02/vulnerable-lungfish-rescue-gympie.html"><![CDATA[




Image source: The Courier Mail

It's not every day you get to save the life of a threatened species and a living fossil! 

A remarkable photograph of a Gympie resident rescuing a rare lungfish from a hotel car park in Gympie after it was washed there by the flood waters that have flowed through Gympie, Queensland for the fifth time in one year.

This ancient air breathing fish can survive 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7d479b1fbbe82d669a81ec2198367013" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2013/03/organic-coconut-oil-one-of-natures.html"><![CDATA[







--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Where can you buy certified organic coconut oil?


You can buy coconut oil
 online and in store at Biome  Brisbane.  We are impressed by the 
Niugini Organics story, which being produced in Papua New Guinea, has 
the lowest food miles for delivery to Australia.  It is extracted 

]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bad4c808a08accbf14508222ef4a29a7" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2013/05/5-rawsome-protein-ball-recipes.html"><![CDATA[Raw, real, unprocessed, containing just the ingredients you want and nothing else!  It's easier than you think to whip up these protein balls or bars at home (also known as a bliss ball, goodie ball, treat ball!).

Here's five of our favourite rawsome protein ball recipes, perfect for a pick me up any time of day.

1.  Tree Nut, Tahini and Loving Earth Cacao Protein Ball 



Protein ball recipe 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4c6bf644d843380327962e88fcce3068" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2013/05/australian-made-goodies.html"><![CDATA[


Mungalli Creek Dairies ~ North Queensland, Australia


To help support Aussie industry and encourage us all to choose locally grown and made, we recently asked our Biome blog and Facebook
 followers to share their favourite Australian-made products. Here's a compilation of their suggestions to look out for next time you are shopping.*  Please feel free to share your favourites in the comments.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d8bbfdfa24db891a9cc83909ca12413d" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2013/05/takaiya-blaney-children-are-our-future.html"><![CDATA[

Image from http://bcrainforest.com/saying-no-to-oil-sands-mining/


Young Candian, Ta‘Kaiya 
Blaney is a Sliammon First Nations singer, songwriter and 
environmental activist. Now about 12, she has campaigned more for 
environmental protection in a few years than most adults. 

This is an incredible TEDx talk she made at TEN 
years of age - she lays out the issues with oil and consumerism
 so 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="893be6fc3dfb7c7ca88d6732b6009c1e" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2013/09/tanjung-puting-orangutan-sanctuary.html"><![CDATA[




















 

In September 1996, my mother, father and I shared a truly remarkable journey to "Camp Leakey" at the heart of Tanjung Puting National Park in the south of Kalimantan, Indonesia.  This precious place is where a young Birute Galdikas arrived in 1971 under the mentorship of Prof. Louis Leakey, beginning 42 years of relentless endeavour to save the orangutans and their forests
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a8473b8232df7f103bb562052934eb15" url="http://accidental-greenie.blogspot.com/2013/10/glass-containers-for-safe-food-storage.html"><![CDATA[


 



Fabulous new larger size glass containers from Wean Green make it even easier to use glass at home for all your food preparation and storage, as well as for lunch boxes, picnics and outdoor catering.  



Wean Green by Glasslock glass containers are made from strong tempered glass with leak-proof, high quality snap lock lids made from BPA free plastic. Pictured above are the Meal Cube on 
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>