<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="www.whitecollarfraud.blogspot.com">
	<documents count="4">
		<document id="663a046ddfacf0277a42f288bd703b47" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/WhiteCollarFraud/~3/cISqpr9osA4/is-overstockcom-trying-to-cook-books.html"><![CDATA[I hoped that Overstock.com (NASDAQ: OSTK) had finally learned the error of its ways. Now it seems that the company has again resorted to accounting shenanigans to inflate its reported income.<br /><br /><b>Background</b><br /><br />From Q2 2007 to Q2 2008, Overstock.com used an improper EBITDA calculation to materially overstate its pro-forma income in violation of Securities and Exchange Commission Regulation G. From Q4 2008 to Q3 2009, the company violated Generally Accepted Accounting Principles (GAAP) and materially overstated its reported earnings. I endured <a href="http://www.stockwatch.com/newsit/newsit_newsit.aspx?bid=U-s0127742-U:OSTK-20090220">malicious personal attacks</a>, <a href="http://garyweiss.blogspot.com/2009/12/patrick-byrnes-facebook-pretexting.html">cyber-stalking</a>, <a href="http://www.ritholtz.com/blog/2010/01/why-is-patrick-byrne-the-dumbest-ceo/">pretexting</a>, and threats to my personal safety from Overstock.com’s <a href="http://www.whitecollarfraud.blogspot.com/2013/01/overstockcom-ceo-patrick-byrne-sleeps.html">gun-toting</a> CEO Patrick Byrne and his paid <a href="http://nypost.com/2007/01/02/overstock-com-lashes-out-at-critics-on-web/">thugs</a> in <a href="http://garyweiss.blogspot.com/2009/07/patrick-byrne-teaches-lesson-in-issuer.html">retaliation</a> for exposing its illegal accounting practices. In each case, I <a href="http://whitecollarfraud.blogspot.com/2009/08/open-letter-to-securities-and-exchange.html">complained</a> to the Securities and Exchange Commission. Eventually Overstock.com was forced to <a href="http://goingconcern.com/2010/2/overstock-com-to-restate-financial-statements-reassures-profitability-for-2009">stop</a> using those <a href="http://www.whitecollarfraud.com/overstock-accounting-fraud.html">illegal accounting practices</a>. It seems that Overstock.com is up to its old tricks again.<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-BL95Y29PG4g/S2FjhrWUUTI/AAAAAAAAAVE/uNKrXoQzsWo/s1600/1952759941_234826ad2f.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-BL95Y29PG4g/S2FjhrWUUTI/AAAAAAAAAVE/uNKrXoQzsWo/s320/1952759941_234826ad2f.jpg" height="320" width="213" /></a></div><b>Executive summary</b><br /><br />In the three month period (third quarter) ended September 30, 2013, Overstock.com claimed that its pretax income was $3.624 million compared to $2.824 million in the same quarter of 2012, an $800,000 increase over the previous year. However, the validity of the increase in pretax income is questionable.<br /><br />In 2013, Overstock.com quietly changed the useful life of certain fixed assets. The company did not inform investors in its 2013 financial reports that the useful life of its computer software and computer hardware costs was higher in 2013 than it was in 2012, leaving the impression that their useful lives were the same in both years. It simply changed the useful life numbers without providing an explanation. Since it was able to spread depreciation and amortization expenses over a longer period of time, it was able to report a lower depreciation and amortization expense in each quarter and inflate its reported profits.<br /><br />Furthermore, there is a $700,000 numerical discrepancy in the amount reported for capitalized internal use-software and website development costs in the third quarter. There is another $400,000 numerical discrepancy in the amount reported for amortization expense associated with internal use-software and website development in the third quarter.<br /><br />Moreover, in the third quarter of 2013, Overstock.com reduced its accrual for loss contingencies by $300,000 from the previous quarter despite a growing number of serious lawsuits against the company. If the company reversed its previous estimate of loss contingencies, it added $300,000 to its third quarter pretax income.<br /><br />At the very least it appears that a substantial part of the $800,000 increase in pretax income would have disappeared if Overstock.com had not changed the useful life of certain fixed assets. It's possible that Overstock.com could have reported a decline in pretax income. The third quarter numbers don't add up. The numbers cannot be trusted. These accounting irregularities could be a red flag for a material weakness in internal controls over financial reporting.<br /><br /><b>Depreciation and amortization accounting</b><br /><br /><a href="http://www.investopedia.com/terms/f/fixedasset.asp">Fixed assets</a> are required to be depreciated or amortized over their “estimated” useful lives. For example, a company purchases computer software for $10,000. It amortizes computer software over its 2 year useful life. Initially, the computer software is reported on the balance sheet as fixed asset. No expense is initially recognized on the income statement. Over the next two years, the company recognizes $5,000 per year of amortization expense in its income statement ($10,000 cost divided by 2 year useful life).<br /><br />If a company lengthens the useful life of a fixed asset, it spreads out <a href="http://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/06/amortizationvsdepreciation.asp">depreciation and amortization</a> expense over a longer period of time. Therefore, it can report higher profits by recognizing a lower depreciation and amortization expense in each period. For example, if a company changes its policy to amortize computer software over 4 years instead of 2 years, it can reduce its amortization expense from $5,000 per year to $2,500 per year ($10,000 cost divided by 4 year useful life). Therefore, the company can increase its profits by $2,500 per year in the first 2 years it owns the software by extending the useful life from 2 years to 4 years.<br /><br />As the amount of fixed assets increase on the balance sheet, the amount reported for depreciation and amortization expense should grow too. However, after analyzing Overstock.com's numbers, I discovered that its fixed assets <i><b>increased</b></i> year-over-year, while its depreciation and amortization expense <i><b>decreased</b></i> year-over-year. The numbers grew in opposite directions. That occurs when a company is either reporting an erroneous amount of depreciation and amortization expense or when it lengthens the useful life of its fixed assets.<br /><br /><b>Overstock.com buries changes in the useful life of fixed assets</b><br /><br />To find out how Overstock.com changed the useful life of its fixed assets, you have to compare different S.E.C. flings over two years because the company did not fess up and tell investors about the change. Buried under 72 pages of disclosures and another 9 page of footnotes in Overstock.com's 2012 <a href="http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1130713/000104746913001400/a2212820z10-k.htm">10-K</a> report, we finally learn that the useful life of computer software was <i><b>2 to 3 years</b></i> and the useful life of computer hardware was <i><b>3 years</b></i> in 2012. See below (highlights added):<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Kx4cfgyZPpw/UmyRjzH_dVI/AAAAAAAAC7Q/dwbV7j-YZfE/s1600/Overstock.com+Useful+Life+of+Fixed+Assets+2012.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Kx4cfgyZPpw/UmyRjzH_dVI/AAAAAAAAC7Q/dwbV7j-YZfE/s1600/Overstock.com+Useful+Life+of+Fixed+Assets+2012.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Overstock.com 2012 10-K report</td></tr></tbody></table><br />However, Overstock.com's 10-Q reports issued for each quarter of 2013 show a different useful life for computer software and computer hardware than was reported in 2012. Buried on page 9 of the first two quarter 10-Q reports and page 10 of the third quarter 10-Q report, Overstock.com revealed that the useful life of computer software was <b style="font-style: italic;">2 to 4 years.</b> However, the useful life of computer software was <i style="font-weight: bold;">2 to 3 years</i> in 2012. In those same 2013 10-Q reports, the useful life of computer hardware was <i><b>3 to 4 years</b></i>. However, the useful life of computer equipment was only <i><b>3 years</b></i> in 2012. (Source: <a href="http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1130713/000110465913032734/a13-8354_110q.htm">Q1 10-Q</a>, <a href="http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1130713/000110465913056690/a13-13700_110q.htm">Q2 10-Q</a>, and <a href="http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1130713/000113071313000014/ostk-20130930x10q.htm">Q3 10-Q</a> reports)<br /><br />In each of those 2013 10-Q reports, Overstock.com disclosed:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">Fixed assets<br /><br />Fixed assets, which include assets such as technology infrastructure, internal-use software, website development, furniture and fixtures and leasehold improvements, are recorded at cost and depreciated using the straight-line method over the estimated useful lives of the related assets or the term of the related capital lease, whichever is shorter, as follows: </blockquote><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-BbasCmzZeHA/UmyR6G14tWI/AAAAAAAAC7Y/_0hhOgcLduw/s1600/Overstock.com+Useful+Life+of+Fixed+Assets+2013.jpg" imageanchor="1"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-BbasCmzZeHA/UmyR6G14tWI/AAAAAAAAC7Y/_0hhOgcLduw/s1600/Overstock.com+Useful+Life+of+Fixed+Assets+2013.jpg" /></a></div><br /><b>Note:</b> Yellow highlights were added for emphasis<br /><br />Overstock.com's fixed asset disclosure leaves the impression that the useful life of its computer software and computer hardware was the same in both 2013 and 2012. The company did not inform investors that the useful life of computer software and computer hardware was higher in 2013 than it was in 2012. It simply changed the numbers without explanation. It did not provide a year-to-year comparison of the useful life of its fixed assets in its 2013 financial reports.<br /><br /><b>Third quarter 2013: Higher level of fixed assets but lower depreciation and amortization expense </b><br /><br />In the three month period (third quarter) ended September 30, 2013, Overstock.com <a href="http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1130713/000113071313000014/ostk-20130930x10q.htm">claimed</a> that its pretax income was $3.624 million compared to $2.824 million in the same quarter of 2012. Pretax income increased by $800,000 over the previous year. However, the validity of the increase in pretax income is questionable.<br /><br />In the three month period ended September 30, 2013 (third quarter) depreciation and amortization expense was $3.307 million compared to $3.839 million in the same three month period of the previous year. Depreciation and amortization expense <b><i>decreased</i></b> by $532,000 year-over-year.<br /><br />At the end of the third quarter of 2013, Overstock.com reported fixed assets of $26.892 million on its balance sheet compared to $23.034 million at the end of the same quarter of the previous year. The amount of fixed assets on its balance sheet was $3.858 million <i><b>higher</b></i> in 2013 than it was in 2012. Depreciation and amortization expense was $532,000<i><b> lower</b></i> despite a $3.858 million <i><b>higher</b></i> amount of<i style="font-weight: bold;"> </i>fixed assets.<br /><br /><b>Third quarter 2013: Numbers don't add up</b><br /><br />The amount of internal-use software and website development costs that the company claimed it capitalized for the entire nine month period (first three quarters) ended September 30, 2013 is $700,000 lower than the totals it claimed that it capitalized in each of the three quarters of the year. In the previous quarter ended June 30, 2013, the six month total equaled the total reported for the first and second quarters. Therefore, the $700,000 discrepancy appears to impact its third quarter 2013 numbers.<br /><br />Moreover, amortization expense for internal-use software and website development costs that the company claimed it reported for the entire nine month period (first three quarters) ended September 30, 2013 is $400,000 higher than the totals it claimed it amortized in each of the three quarters of the year. In the previous quarter ended June 30, 2013, the six month total equaled the total reported for the first and second quarters. Therefore, the $400,000 discrepancy appears to impact its third quarter 2013 numbers.<br /><br />According to the third quarter ended September 30, 2013 <a href="http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1130713/000113071313000014/ostk-20130930x10q.htm">10-Q</a> report:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">During the three months ended September 30, 2013 and 2012, we <i style="font-weight: bold;">capitalized $3.3 million</i> and $3.0 million, respectively, of costs associated with internal-use software and website development, both developed internally and acquired externally. Amortization of costs associated with internal-use software and website development was <i><b>$1.8 million</b></i> and $2.0 million for those respective periods. During the nine months ended September 30, 2013 and 2012,<b> we <i>capitalized $8.1</i></b> million and $6.8 million, respectively, of such costs and had <b><i>amortization of $5.9 million</i></b> and $6.3 million for those respective periods. [Emphasis added.]</blockquote><br />In <b style="font-style: italic;">three month</b> period ended September 30, 2013, Overstock.com claimed that it capitalized $3.3 million of costs associated with internal-use software and website development. In the <b style="font-style: italic;">nine month </b>period ended September 30, 2013, the company claimed that it capitalized $8.1 million of such costs.<br /><br />In the <b><i>three month</i></b> period ended September 30, 2013, Overstock.com claimed that its amortized $1.8 million of internal-use software and website development costs. In the <b style="font-style: italic;">nine month </b>period ended September 30, 2013, the company claimed that it amortized $5.9 million of such costs.<br /><br />In the second quarter ended June 30, 2013 <a href="http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1130713/000110465913056690/a13-13700_110q.htm">10-Q report</a>, Overstock.com claimed that:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">During the six months ended June 30, 2013 and 2012, we <i><b>capitalized $5.5 million</b></i> and $3.9 million, respectively, of such costs and had <i><b>amortization of $3.7 million</b></i> and $4.3 million for those respective periods. [Emphasis added.]</blockquote><br />Let's do some basic math.<br /><br />During the six month period ended June 30, 2013, Overstock.com capitalized $<b><i>5.5 million</i></b> of costs associated with internal-use software and website development. In the three month period ended September 30, 2013 it claimed that it capitalized an additional <b><i>$3.3 million</i></b> of such software costs. Therefore, Overstock.com should have reported a nine month total of <i><b>$8.8 million</b></i>. However, it reported a nine month total of <i><b>$8.1 million</b></i>, leaving a $<i><b>700,000</b></i> discrepancy in its third quarter numbers.<br /><br />During the six month period ended June 30, 2013, Overstock.com amortized <i><b>$3.7 million</b></i> of costs associated with internal-use software and website development. In the three month period ended September 30, 2013 it claimed that it amortized an additional <i><b>$1.8 million</b></i> of such software costs. Therefore, Overstock.com should have reported a nine month total of <i><b>$5.5 million</b></i>. However, it reported a nine month total of $<b><i>5.9 million</i></b>, leaving a <i><b>$400,000</b></i> discrepancy in its third quarter numbers.<br /><br /><b>Third quarter 2013: Reduction in amounts accrued for loss contingencies</b><br /><br />In the three month period (third quarter) ended September 30, 2013, Overstock.com reduced its accrual for loss contingencies by $300,000 from the previous quarter despite a growing number of serious lawsuits against the company. If the company reversed its previous estimate of loss contingencies, it added $300,000 to its third quarter pretax income.<br /><br />In the third quarter ended September 30, 2013 <a href="http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1130713/000113071313000014/ostk-20130930x10q.htm">10-Q report</a>, Overstock.com disclosed:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">We establish liabilities when a particular contingency is probable and estimable. At September 30, 2013, we have <i><b>accrued $2.6 million</b></i> in light of these probable and estimable liabilities. It is reasonably possible that the actual losses may exceed our accrued liabilities. We have other contingencies which are reasonably possible; however, the reasonably possible exposure to losses cannot currently be estimated. [Emphasis added.]</blockquote><br />In the second quarter ended June 30, 2013 <a href="http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1130713/000110465913056690/a13-13700_110q.htm">10-Q</a> report, Overtock.com reported:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">We establish liabilities when a particular contingency is probable and estimable. As of June 30, 2013, we have <i><b>accrued $2.9 million</b></i> in light of these probable and estimable liabilities. It is reasonably possible that the actual losses may exceed our accrued liabilities. We have other contingencies which are reasonably possible; however, the reasonably possible exposure to losses cannot currently be estimated. [Emphasis added.]</blockquote><br />A loss contingency reserve can be reduced two ways. Either the company paid out money it previously accrued (no effect on income) or it changed its estimate of contingent liabilities (reversed prior accruals of loss contingency expense). Such a change in estimate would increase its pretax income. Was Overstock.com trying to further tweak its third quarter numbers?<br /><br /><b>Conclusion</b><br /><br />Given Overstock.com's prior history of accounting violations and its past malicious retaliatory actions against journalists, independent whistleblowers like me, and other critics, investors should be skeptical of its accounting and financial disclosures.<br /><br />Written by,<br /><br />Sam E. Antar<br /><br /><b>Disclosure</b><br /><br />I am a convicted felon and a former CPA. As the criminal CFO of Crazy Eddie, I helped my cousin Eddie Antar and other members of his family mastermind one of the largest securities frauds uncovered during the 1980's. I committed my crimes in cold-blood for fun and profit, and simply because I could. If it weren't for the heroic efforts of the FBI, SEC, Postal Inspector's Office, US Attorney's Office, and class action plaintiff's lawyers who investigated, prosecuted, and sued me, I would still be the criminal CFO of Crazy Eddie today. I do not want or seek forgiveness for my vicious crimes from my victims. My past sins are unforgivable.<br /><br />There is a saying, "It takes one to know one." I've provided professional work for the FBI, IRS, SEC, Justice Department, and other federal and state law enforcement agencies in training them to identify fraud and catch white-collar criminals. Often, I <a href="http://www.crainsnewyork.com/assets/pdf/CN67159104.PDF" target="_blank">refer</a> cases to them as an independent whistleblower. In addition, I&nbsp;<a href="http://whitecollarfraud.blogspot.com/p/consulting.html" target="_blank">teach</a> white-collar crime classes for various government entities, professional organizations, businesses, and colleges and universities. Recently, I've helped the <a href="http://www.journalofaccountancy.com/Issues/2012/Aug/20125839.htm" target="_blank">AICPA Fraud Task Force</a> develop better methods for detecting fraud.<br /><br />I do not own any Overstock.com securities long or short.<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=cISqpr9osA4:Nj8Imiho93w:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=cISqpr9osA4:Nj8Imiho93w:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=cISqpr9osA4:Nj8Imiho93w:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=cISqpr9osA4:Nj8Imiho93w:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=cISqpr9osA4:Nj8Imiho93w:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=cISqpr9osA4:Nj8Imiho93w:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=cISqpr9osA4:Nj8Imiho93w:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=cISqpr9osA4:Nj8Imiho93w:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=cISqpr9osA4:Nj8Imiho93w:KwTdNBX3Jqk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=cISqpr9osA4:Nj8Imiho93w:KwTdNBX3Jqk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=cISqpr9osA4:Nj8Imiho93w:l6gmwiTKsz0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=l6gmwiTKsz0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=cISqpr9osA4:Nj8Imiho93w:gIN9vFwOqvQ"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=cISqpr9osA4:Nj8Imiho93w:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=cISqpr9osA4:Nj8Imiho93w:TzevzKxY174"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=TzevzKxY174" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=cISqpr9osA4:Nj8Imiho93w:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=cISqpr9osA4:Nj8Imiho93w:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=cISqpr9osA4:Nj8Imiho93w:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/WhiteCollarFraud/~4/cISqpr9osA4" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="27e2bdcac9acc879c87c2aff4507559" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/WhiteCollarFraud/~3/EBHpTVTRgA8/did-tesla-violate-sec-rules-by-failing.html"><![CDATA[<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-PHHuJPN93z4/UpHGUOF4xrI/AAAAAAAAC9o/EDXHfIaiApc/s1600/Tesla-Motors.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-PHHuJPN93z4/UpHGUOF4xrI/AAAAAAAAC9o/EDXHfIaiApc/s1600/Tesla-Motors.jpg" height="172" width="200" /></a></div>Last Thursday, <a href="http://www.siliconbeat.com/2013/11/21/exclusive-top-tesla-executive-george-blankenship-vp-of-sales-departs/" target="_blank">Silicon Beat</a> reported that George Blankenship retired from his position as Vice President, Worldwide Retail at Tesla Motors (NASDAQ: TSLA). According to Blankenship's&nbsp;<a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/george-blankenship/0/52/a2b" target="_blank">LinkedIn</a>&nbsp;profile, he had already left the company in October 2013. Tesla's most recent <a href="http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1318605/000119312513158904/d506419ddef14a.htm" target="_blank">proxy report</a> listed Blankenship as a "named executive officer." The retirement, appointment, resignation, or termination of a registrant’s "<a href="http://us.practicallaw.com/6-382-3638" target="_blank">named executive officer</a>" is required to be disclosed within four business days of such a departure on <a href="http://www.sec.gov/about/forms/form8-k.pdf" target="_blank">Form 8-K</a>. Therefore, it appears that the company should have disclosed his retirement no later than November 6, 2013. So far, Tesla has made no such disclosure.<br /><br />On November 21, 2013, Silicon Beat <a href="http://www.siliconbeat.com/2013/11/21/exclusive-top-tesla-executive-george-blankenship-vp-of-sales-departs/" target="_blank">reported</a> that:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">Blankenship is still listed as Vice President, Sales &amp; Ownership Experience on Tesla’s website. But his LinkedIn profile now says he is “Director of Smiles for the Blankenship Family” and he apparently left Tesla a few weeks ago.</blockquote><br />Shortly after Silicon Beat's exclusive report, Blankenship's name was finally removed from Tesla's list of officers on its website.<br /><br />George Blankenship's <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/george-blankenship/0/52/a2b" target="_blank">LinkedIn</a> profile says he was employed at Tesla until October 2013 and was "done at Tesla" in November 2013. See below (click on image to enlarge):<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-hMSHRFG8y7U/Uo7bs3hmJ7I/AAAAAAAAC9U/V7d6x9GB5-k/s1600/George+Blankenship+Linkedin+Profile.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-hMSHRFG8y7U/Uo7bs3hmJ7I/AAAAAAAAC9U/V7d6x9GB5-k/s1600/George+Blankenship+Linkedin+Profile.jpg" height="171" width="320" /></a></div><br />When Tesla finally gets around to filing an 8-K report, will it claim that Blankenship did not retire in October 2013 as he reported in his Linkedin profile? That seems to be the only way Tesla can claim that it did not violate S.E.C. disclosure rules governing the departure of a named executive officer.<br /><br />Written by,<br /><br />Sam E. Antar<br /><br /><b>Disclosure</b><br /><br />I am a convicted felon and a former CPA. As the criminal CFO of Crazy Eddie, I helped my cousin Eddie Antar and other members of his family mastermind one of the largest securities frauds uncovered during the 1980's. I committed my crimes in cold-blood for fun and profit, and simply because I could. If it weren't for the heroic efforts of the FBI, SEC, Postal Inspector's Office, US Attorney's Office, and class action plaintiff's lawyers who investigated, prosecuted, and sued me, I would still be the criminal CFO of Crazy Eddie today. I do not want or seek forgiveness for my vicious crimes from my victims. My past sins are unforgivable.<br /><br />There is a saying, "It takes one to know one." I've provided professional work for the FBI, IRS, SEC, Justice Department, and other federal and state law enforcement agencies in training them to identify fraud and catch white-collar criminals. Often, I <a href="http://www.crainsnewyork.com/assets/pdf/CN67159104.PDF" target="_blank">refer</a> cases to them as an independent whistleblower. In addition, I <a href="http://whitecollarfraud.blogspot.com/p/consulting.html" target="_blank">teach</a> white-collar crime classes for various government entities, professional organizations, businesses, and colleges and universities. Recently, I've helped the <a href="http://www.journalofaccountancy.com/Issues/2012/Aug/20125839.htm" target="_blank">AICPA Fraud Task Force</a> develop better methods for detecting fraud.<br /><br />I do not own any Tesla securities long or short.<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=EBHpTVTRgA8:3o_oUN88sMc:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=EBHpTVTRgA8:3o_oUN88sMc:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=EBHpTVTRgA8:3o_oUN88sMc:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=EBHpTVTRgA8:3o_oUN88sMc:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=EBHpTVTRgA8:3o_oUN88sMc:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=EBHpTVTRgA8:3o_oUN88sMc:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=EBHpTVTRgA8:3o_oUN88sMc:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=EBHpTVTRgA8:3o_oUN88sMc:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=EBHpTVTRgA8:3o_oUN88sMc:KwTdNBX3Jqk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=EBHpTVTRgA8:3o_oUN88sMc:KwTdNBX3Jqk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=EBHpTVTRgA8:3o_oUN88sMc:l6gmwiTKsz0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=l6gmwiTKsz0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=EBHpTVTRgA8:3o_oUN88sMc:gIN9vFwOqvQ"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=EBHpTVTRgA8:3o_oUN88sMc:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=EBHpTVTRgA8:3o_oUN88sMc:TzevzKxY174"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=TzevzKxY174" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=EBHpTVTRgA8:3o_oUN88sMc:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=EBHpTVTRgA8:3o_oUN88sMc:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=EBHpTVTRgA8:3o_oUN88sMc:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/WhiteCollarFraud/~4/EBHpTVTRgA8" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="56ad0a029e9e31258234e24a1d75b8f" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/WhiteCollarFraud/~3/QpHQJIqbSV4/is-medifast-cry-baby-or-corporate-bully.html"><![CDATA[This is the way corporate bullying works. Last Monday, September 30, 2013, I <a href="http://www.whitecollarfraud.blogspot.com/2013/09/was-medifast-transparent-with-investors.html" target="_blank">reported</a> that Medifast (NYSE: MED), its former CFO, and the engagement partner who supervised its audits for its former accounting firm agreed to the entry of separate Cease-and-Desist Orders by the Securities and Exchange Commission for various violations of securities laws. On Wednesday, October 2, 2013, I received a <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/173005121/2013-10-02-Ltr-to-Sam-Antar-Address-Redacted" target="_blank">letter</a> from its lawyers with the following barely veiled threat, “…The Company, is not adverse to taking decisive action to redress false accusations against its business.”<br /><br /><b>Background</b><br /><br />On September 19, 2013, Medifast (NYSE: MED) disclosed that on the previous day it consented to an entry of a <a href="https://www.sec.gov/litigation/admin/2013/34-70448.pdf" target="_blank">Cease-and Desist Order</a> and agreed to pay a $200,000 civil money penalty in connection with an "investigation" by the Securities and Exchange Commission into its improper financial reporting from 2006 to 2009. I <a href="http://www.whitecollarfraud.blogspot.com/2013/09/was-medifast-transparent-with-investors.html" target="_blank">reported</a> that Medifast's <a href="http://ir.medifastdiet.com/releasedetail.cfm?ReleaseID=791732" target="_blank">press release</a> and <a href="http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/910329/000114420413051618/v355486_8k.htm" target="_blank">8-K</a> report made no mention that <a href="http://www.sec.gov/litigation/admin/2013/34-70450.pdf" target="_blank">Brendan N. Connors</a>, its former CFO and <a href="http://www.sec.gov/litigation/admin/2013/34-70449.pdf" target="_blank">Marc G. Nochimson</a>, the engagement partner who had supervised Medifast's audits for its former accounting firm, consented to the entry of separate Cease-and-Desist Orders which alleged improper conduct. Furthermore, I wrote that "I <i><b>did not find</b></i> any specific disclosure of the above referenced investigation in <i><b>any of Medifast's previous filings</b></i> with the S.E.C. I asked the company for an explanation via email, but it did not respond my request."<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-pcHhBaA3v-s/S3464yMeKlI/AAAAAAAAAV4/QJOnr7ESYYk/s1600/medifast.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-pcHhBaA3v-s/S3464yMeKlI/AAAAAAAAAV4/QJOnr7ESYYk/s1600/medifast.jpg" /></a></div>Therefore, I <a href="http://www.whitecollarfraud.blogspot.com/2013/09/was-medifast-transparent-with-investors.html" target="_blank">asked</a> a reasonable question: "Was Medifast transparent with investors about an S.E.C. investigation?" based on underlying facts that were referenced in the S.E.C.’s three Cease-and-Desist Orders, Medifast’s S.E.C. filings and a certain press release). Medifast responded by having their lawyer <a href="http://www.lpgllp.com/rag_page.html" target="_blank">Robert A. Giacovas</a> send me a threatening legal letter. The letter cannot cite a single false or erroneous fact that it claims I published. Instead, it resorts to veiled threats, personal attacks, and innuendo in an attempt to distort the meaning of what I wrote and to bully me. [<a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/173005121/2013-10-02-Ltr-to-Sam-Antar-Address-Redacted" target="_blank">Read a copy of the letter from Robert A. Giacovas, Esq. here.</a>]<br /><br /><b>Medifast's letter and my response</b><br /><br />If I may be so bold as to summarize their lawyer’s <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/173005121/2013-10-02-Ltr-to-Sam-Antar-Address-Redacted" target="_blank">letter</a>, they are complaining that I “did not find any specific disclosure of the [SEC] investigation in any or Medifast’s previous filings with the S.E.C.” They claim “the Company cannot locate any email” from me asking them for an explanation. They requested that I forward them "the email that was <i><b>supposedly</b></i> sent to the Company and went unanswered." [Emphasis added.]<br /><br />On September 20, 2013 at approximately 3:00 AM, I filled out an online inquiry for Medifast's Investor Relations Department:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">Did Medifast make any PRIOR disclosure referenced in the 8-K report filed on 9/13/2013?<br />Here is the link:<br />http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/910329/000114420413051618/v355486_8k.htm<br />I cannot find any disclosure by the company of the referenced SEC investigation PRIOR to the filing of the 8-K.<br />Please respond via email.</blockquote><br />See the screen shot below (Click on image to enlarge it):<br /><br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ZWi5gwCrFJs/Uk0j-xjvkBI/AAAAAAAAC3s/YI3emF9GEkA/s1600/2013+09-20+Medifast++Inc.++-+Contact+Us.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ZWi5gwCrFJs/Uk0j-xjvkBI/AAAAAAAAC3s/YI3emF9GEkA/s320/2013+09-20+Medifast++Inc.++-+Contact+Us.png" width="305" /></a></div><br /><br />At about 3:01 AM ET, I received the following confirmation that my inquiry was received. See the screen shot below (Click on image to enlarge it):<br /><br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zo8LyKFhtaQ/Uk0lWlKRTVI/AAAAAAAAC34/57-kF_ENhtg/s1600/2013+09-20+Medifast++Inc.++-+Contact+Us+Confirmation.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="180" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zo8LyKFhtaQ/Uk0lWlKRTVI/AAAAAAAAC34/57-kF_ENhtg/s320/2013+09-20+Medifast++Inc.++-+Contact+Us+Confirmation.png" width="320" /></a></div><br />In addition, on September 20, 2013 at 4:41 AM ET, I sent an email to Medifast’s Investor Relations Department which made the same request: [<a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/173006234/2013-09-20-Sam-Antar-Email-to-Medifast" target="_blank">Read the full email here.</a>].<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><b>Question:</b> Did Medifast make any disclosure of the above referenced investigation into Medifast's financial reporting in its previous filings with the S.E.C.? I cannot find any reference to the above referenced investigation in any of Medifast’s filings with the S.E.C. prior to the filing of the 8-K report referenced above.</blockquote><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">I’d appreciate a prompt answer to this question via email.</blockquote><br />However, Medifast did not respond to me as of the time I published my blog 10 days later on September 30, 2013. If Medifast cannot find my online inquiry and email detailed above, I respectfully suggest that apparently either someone at the company is not being truthful to them or it has a problem with its information technology infrastructure.<br /><br />Medifast's <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/173005121/2013-10-02-Ltr-to-Sam-Antar-Address-Redacted" target="_blank">letter</a> does not deny that it failed to report the existence of an S.E.C. investigation prior to the issuance of a Cease-and-Desist Order, press release, and 8-K filing. Instead, it explains that Medifast had no specific legal obligation to disclose such an investigation:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">However, there is no statute, regulation, or rule that explicitly imposes an affirmative duty upon a public company to disclose the existence of an SEC investigation.</blockquote><br />The <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/173005121/2013-10-02-Ltr-to-Sam-Antar-Address-Redacted" target="_blank">letter</a> says:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">First, you state that you "did not find any specific disclosure of the [SEC] investigation in <i>any</i> of Medifast's previous filings with the SEC." The statement and your emphasis on the word "<i>any</i>" is clearly meant to convey that the Company has somehow not made proper disclosures to investors."</blockquote><br />Apparently, the <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/173005121/2013-10-02-Ltr-to-Sam-Antar-Address-Redacted" target="_blank">letter</a> claims that I inferred that Medifast had broken the law by not reporting the existence of an ongoing investigation prior it consenting to the entry of a Cease-and-Desist Order. I made no such claim or inference. I asked a reasonable question: “Was Medifast transparent with investors about an S.E.C. investigation?” For example, many public companies report the existence of confidential S.E.C. investigations. Whether or not public companies should disclose the existence of ongoing S.E.C. investigations has been a matter of endless public debate. Therefore, even if we accept Medifast’s contention that by the letter of the law it was not required to report the existence of the S.E.C. investigation, it is still reasonable to ask a question about whether it was transparent with investors in communicating with them.<br /><br />In addition, I <a href="http://www.whitecollarfraud.blogspot.com/2013/09/was-medifast-transparent-with-investors.html" target="_blank">reported</a> that Medifast did not disclose in its <a href="http://ir.medifastdiet.com/releasedetail.cfm?ReleaseID=791732" target="_blank">press release</a> and <a href="http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/910329/000114420413051618/v355486_8k.htm" target="_blank">8-K</a> filing that its former CFO and the former engagement partner who supervised its audits also consented to the entry of separate Cease-and-Desist Orders. Their letter claims that I inferred that Medifast “<i><b>purposely</b></i> omitted mention of these other settlements." [Emphasis added]. As I detailed above, Medifast claimed that it had no specific legal obligation to report the S.E.C. investigation prior to it accepting the entry of a Cease-and Desist Order against it. Is Medifast now claiming it would have reported the other two Cease-and-Desist orders if they had known about them prior to its press release and filing of an 8-K report? If that is so, Medifast could have issued another press release and filed an amended 8-K report with the S.E.C. if it had chosen to do so. It did not.<br /><br />The <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/173005121/2013-10-02-Ltr-to-Sam-Antar-Address-Redacted" target="_blank">letter</a> goes on to say that:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">For your information, as a matter of policy, the SEC does not disclose the status of any investigations and settlement discussions with other potential parties (and it did not in this case).</blockquote><br />The letter claims that:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">The Company learned about details of those settlements at the same time as everyone else – when they were released by the S.E.C.</blockquote><br />Those statements raise another reasonable question. Their letter is silent on whether Medifast knew that its former CFO and the engagement partner who supervised its audits were being simultaneously investigated by the S.E.C. Is Medifast inferring that it did not know that the S.E.C. was investigating its former CFO and the engagement partner who handled its audits until after it learned that they consented to the entry of Cease-and-Desist Orders? If Medifast did know that its former CFO and the engagement partner were being investigated by the S.E.C., wouldn't its lawyers be in contact with their lawyers to monitor the ongoing investigation? Again, these are reasonable questions based on the information presented.<br /><br />Furthermore, Medifast, its former CFO, and the engagement partner who supervised its audits for its former accounting firm all consented to Cease-and-Desist Orders on the same day: September 18, 2013. The respective Cease-and Desist Orders entered against all three parties contain sequential Securities Exchange Act of 1934 file numbers, sequential Accounting and Auditing Enforcement Release numbers, sequential Administrative Proceeding file numbers, and sequential URLs to access them on the internet. A day later, on September 19 at around <a href="http://finance.yahoo.com/news/medifast-inc-enters-settlement-131900671.html" target="_blank">9:19 AM</a> Medifast issued a press release which reported its Cease-and-Desist Order, but omitted reference to the other two orders. Its 8-K filing with the S.E.C., which also omitted reference to the other two Cease-and-Desist Orders, was accepted by the S.E.C. later that same day at <a href="http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/910329/000114420413051618/0001144204-13-051618-index.htm" target="_blank">4:59 PM</a>. Based on that sequence of events, it’s a reasonable question to ask why Medifast did not disclose the two Cease-and-Desist Orders in its initial press release and 8-K report. In any case, as I suggested above, Medifast could have issued a new press release or filed an amended 8-K report disclosing the other two Cease-and-Desist orders if it chose to do so. It did not. There still remains a reasonable question to ask about whether Medifast was transparent in communicating with investors even if Medifast complied with S.E.C. reporting requirements on this issue. [<a href="https://www.sec.gov/litigation/admin/2013/34-70448.pdf" target="_blank">Cease-and-Desist against Medifast</a>, <a href="https://www.sec.gov/litigation/admin/2013/34-70450.pdf" target="_blank">Cease-and-Desist against Brendan Connors</a>, and <a href="https://www.sec.gov/litigation/admin/2013/34-70449.pdf" target="_blank">Cease-and-Desist against Marc Nochimson</a>]<br /><br />What further amuses me about Medifast's bullying is their lawyer's apparent blundering. For example, the <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/173005121/2013-10-02-Ltr-to-Sam-Antar-Address-Redacted" target="_blank">lette</a>r states:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">Your post, which begins with the question – “Was Medifast transparent with investors about an S.E.C. investigation?” – then contains a<b><i> number of statements that answers the question in the affirmative</i></b>, thereby raising specter of some improper conduct by Medifast surrounding the entry of a cease and desist order with the Securities and Exchange Commission (“SEC’). [Emphasis added.]</blockquote><br />Apparently, the <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/173005121/2013-10-02-Ltr-to-Sam-Antar-Address-Redacted" target="_blank">letter</a> erroneously claims that I answered my own question “in the affirmative” which means that I implied that Medifast engaged in proper conduct while it goes on to erroneously claim that I answered the question in the negative, meaning that Medifast engaged in improper conduct. I'm confused by their language. A company can follow the letter of the law and still not be transparent as I understand the term to mean. In any case, I did not say that Medifast was transparent or that it was not transparent. I simply asked a reasonable question about whether Medifast was transparent with investors and published the underlying facts accurately to help readers reach their own conclusion.<br /><br />The <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/173005121/2013-10-02-Ltr-to-Sam-Antar-Address-Redacted" target="_blank">letter</a> references a certain defamation lawsuit Medifast brought against "...your friend and twice convicted felon Barry Minkow and (others)." I thought Minkow was a friend, but he is no longer a friend anymore and he has not been a friend for years. In any case, Medifast's defamation lawsuit against Barry Minkow was <a href="http://www.sequenceinc.com/fraudfiles/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/Medifast-Order.pdf"><span id="goog_1038129335"></span>dismissed<span id="goog_1038129336"></span></a>, although it is appealing the ruling. (<a href="http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/910329/000114420413044398/v351041_10q.htm" target="_blank">See 10-Q report - Contingencies on page 14.</a>)<br /><br />Finally, Medifast <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/173005121/2013-10-02-Ltr-to-Sam-Antar-Address-Redacted" target="_blank">requested</a> that “And if you are truly interested in full transparency, you should publish this letter for your readers.” Well, I am interested in transparency. I made an upload of their letter available in the first paragraph of this blog, provided links to it several times above, and it can be <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/173005121/2013-10-02-Ltr-to-Sam-Antar-Address-Redacted" target="_blank">uploaded here</a>, too. In the spirit of the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, I welcome the debate. Back in 2012, I <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/walterpavlo/2012/03/05/when-sam-antar-speaks-people-listen-and-speak-their-mind/" target="_blank">defended</a> a government employee's right to free speech after he was fired for saying personal insults about me:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">When Antar was asked about the critique of his talk and Mr. Kaplan’s firing his reaction was, “He has every right to voice his opinion of me. It was wrong for the City of Philadelphia to fire him for what he said about me."</blockquote><br />In my humble opinion, Medifast appears to be thin-skinned. They are acting like crybabies. However, Medifast, like me has a constitutional right to the freedom of speech. Their opinions like mine here have a right to be heard. However, I will not allow them to bully me.<br /><br />Written by:<br /><br />Sam E. Antar<br /><br /><b>Disclosure</b><br /><br />I am a convicted felon and a former CPA. As the criminal CFO of Crazy Eddie, I helped my cousin Eddie Antar and other members of his family mastermind one of the largest securities frauds uncovered during the 1980's. I committed my crimes in cold-blood for fun and profit, and simply because I could. If it weren't for the heroic efforts of the FBI, SEC, Postal Inspector's Office, US Attorney's Office, and class action plaintiff's lawyers who investigated, prosecuted, and sued me, I would still be the criminal CFO of Crazy Eddie today. I do not want or seek forgiveness for my vicious crimes from my victims. My past sins are unforgivable.<br /><br />There is a saying, "It takes one to know one." I've done professional work for the FBI, IRS, SEC, Justice Department, and other federal and state law enforcement agencies in training them to identify fraud and catch white-collar criminals. Often, I <a href="http://www.crainsnewyork.com/assets/pdf/CN67159104.PDF" target="_blank">refer</a> cases to them as an independent whistleblower. I <a href="http://whitecollarfraud.blogspot.com/p/consulting.html" target="_blank">teach</a> white-collar crime classes for various government entities, professional organizations, businesses, and colleges and universities. Recently, I've helped the <a href="http://www.journalofaccountancy.com/Issues/2012/Aug/20125839.htm" target="_blank">AICPA Fraud Task Force</a> develop better methods for detecting fraud.<br /><br />I do not own any Medifast securities long or short.<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=QpHQJIqbSV4:mrYqbF29qpo:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=QpHQJIqbSV4:mrYqbF29qpo:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=QpHQJIqbSV4:mrYqbF29qpo:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=QpHQJIqbSV4:mrYqbF29qpo:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=QpHQJIqbSV4:mrYqbF29qpo:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=QpHQJIqbSV4:mrYqbF29qpo:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=QpHQJIqbSV4:mrYqbF29qpo:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=QpHQJIqbSV4:mrYqbF29qpo:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=QpHQJIqbSV4:mrYqbF29qpo:KwTdNBX3Jqk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=QpHQJIqbSV4:mrYqbF29qpo:KwTdNBX3Jqk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=QpHQJIqbSV4:mrYqbF29qpo:l6gmwiTKsz0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=l6gmwiTKsz0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=QpHQJIqbSV4:mrYqbF29qpo:gIN9vFwOqvQ"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=QpHQJIqbSV4:mrYqbF29qpo:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=QpHQJIqbSV4:mrYqbF29qpo:TzevzKxY174"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=TzevzKxY174" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=QpHQJIqbSV4:mrYqbF29qpo:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=QpHQJIqbSV4:mrYqbF29qpo:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=QpHQJIqbSV4:mrYqbF29qpo:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/WhiteCollarFraud/~4/QpHQJIqbSV4" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8c8e6ea28f5ad06c0ef246402dc8027a" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/WhiteCollarFraud/~3/TnhcbJPrHwo/california-judge-rules-slaps.html"><![CDATA[<i><b>Updated</b></i><br /><br />It's now official: Overstock.com (NASDAQ: OSTK) defrauded consumers. Late Friday afternoon, a California Judge issued a tentative ruling in favor of district attorneys from eight California Counties who had sued Overstock.com for engaging in fraudulent comparative pricing practices. The Judge imposed a civil penalty in the amount of $6.819 million and approved issuance of an injunction to prevent Overstock.com from continuing its deceptive practices. To make matters worse, Overstock.com will have to reimburse the State of California possibly millions of dollars for legal fees, investigative costs, and other costs. [<a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/195875655/People-of-the-State-of-California-vs-Overstock-com-Tentative-Ruling-and-Proposed-Statement-of-Decision" target="_blank">Download ruling.</a>]<br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-YZE7W052qoQ/S2gFNvkywyI/AAAAAAAAC8E/H1SuCwKDH10/s1600/websWeb_ServicesAllMerchantsOverstock_com1-resized200.gif" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-YZE7W052qoQ/S2gFNvkywyI/AAAAAAAAC8E/H1SuCwKDH10/s1600/websWeb_ServicesAllMerchantsOverstock_com1-resized200.gif" /></a></div><br />Overstock.com will definitely appeal the ruling, adding to its already huge legal costs, a huge lose-lose proposition for the company. For instance, last quarter the company<a href="http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1130713/000113071313000014/ostk-20130930x10q.htm" target="_blank"> reported</a> a $2 million increase in legal fees resulting in large part from the "defense of a case brought by district attorneys in eight California counties."<br /><br /><b>Overstock.com refused to settle thinking it could get away with paying millions of dollars less in penalties</b><br /><br />Back in March 2010, the California county district attorneys <a href="http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1130713/000110465910054525/a10-17550_110q.htm" target="_blank">offered</a> to resolve its investigation for $7.5 million, but Overstock.com's <a href="http://www.whitecollarfraud.blogspot.com/2013/01/overstockcom-ceo-patrick-byrne-sleeps.html" target="_blank">gun-toting</a> CEO Patrick Byrne arrogantly refused to settle. According to Overstock.com's Q3 2010 <a href="http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1130713/000110465910054525/a10-17550_110q.htm" target="_blank">10-Q</a> report:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">In March 2010, we received correspondence from the Office of the District Attorney of the County of Monterey in which the respective offices of the various district attorneys have made a collective proposal to resolve the dispute by our payment of $7.5 million in penalties and reimbursement. We disagree with the proposal and continue to discuss this matter with the authorities involved. In October 2010, we received notification that the Alameda County District Attorney joined the investigation group.</blockquote><br />The company had accrued a loss contingency reserve totaling only $1.2 million to cover all its potential litigation risks, including but not limited to the district attorneys' investigation.<br /><br />In response to an <a href="http://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1130713/000110465910041612/filename1.htm" target="_blank">inquiry</a> by the Securities and Exchange Commission, Overstock.com revealed that the loss contingency covered potential liabilities arising from the California investigation and an unrelated tax matter:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">There are two matters for which we have established accrued liabilities, namely, the California district attorneys’ investigation and the administrative proceeding before the Ohio Tax Commissioner.</blockquote><br />Evidently, Overstock.com thought it could get away with paying the State of California far less money than it was seeking in fines and restitution.<br /><br />After the <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/113026875/2010-11-17-california-vs-overstock-com-complaint" target="_blank">lawsuit</a> was filed on November 17, 2010, Overstock.com attempted to <a href="http://whitecollarfraud.blogspot.com/2011/04/why-is-overstockcom-obstructing.html" target="_blank">obstruct</a> efforts by the <a href="http://www.whitecollarfraud.com/files/43433491.pdf" target="_blank">California District Attorneys</a> to gather evidence of wrongdoing and was later <a href="http://whitecollarfraud.blogspot.com/2011/05/california-court-compels-overstockcom.html" target="_blank">compelled</a> by the <a href="http://www.whitecollarfraud.com/files/44163002.pdf" target="_blank">Judge</a> to turn over crucial documentation. Overstock.com CEO Patrick Byrne claimed:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">It is not our job to host DA’s on a no-limits fishing trip, especially when they have not acted in good faith in the past.</blockquote><br />Now Overstock.com has been <b><i>convicted of consumer fraud</i></b> after spending several million dollars more in legal fees. In addition, it has to pay $6.819 million in fines plus possibly millions of dollars more in court costs.<br /><br />Based on the ruling, it was Overstock.com who had not acted in good faith with District Attorneys investigating its wrongdoing and with consumers who were misled into believing that they were saving money by purchasing product from the company.<br /><br /><b>Lawsuit alleges fraud</b><br /><br />On November 17, 2010, district attorneys from eight California counties filed a <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/113026875/2010-11-17-california-vs-overstock-com-complaint" target="_blank">lawsuit</a> against Overstock.com (NASDAQ: OSTK) alleging that it made up comparative prices:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">20. ...Overstock does not always offer the lowest prices available online for the products it sells. In some cases, it charges significantly higher for those products than other merchants selling the identical products.</blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq">21. ...beginning at a date unknown to Plaintiff, but no later than January 1, 2006, Overstock has routinely and systematically made untrue and misleading comparative advertising claims about the prices which other merchants charge for the identical products offered by Overstock.</blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq">22. Often Overstock has not been determining or verifying the price other merchants charge for those identical products. Rather, Overstock has been using various misleading methods to make up its own “straw-man” prices which it claims other merchants are charging for those products, and then claiming that its own prices are significantly lower than those prices.</blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq">23. Overstock has advertised comparative prices which do not exist (i.e., simply making up the prices charged by other merchants).</blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq">24. When Overstock actually examined what merchants were charging for identical products, Overstock often deliberately chose <i>the highest price</i> charged for that product by any merchant instead of the price offered by most merchants for that product. These representations were likely to mislead consumers into believing that Overstock's prices were significantly lower than prices offered by other merchants.</blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq">25. For example, in 2007, Overstock.com sold a patio set on its site for $449.00. It claimed that the "List Price" for that patio was $999.99. The consumer who ordered the item noted that it came in a box with a Wal-Mart sticker showing the sales price to be $247.00. Wal-Mart was in fact offering the same patio set at $247.00 (and later, on clearance, as low as $218.00) on its web site. Overstock's "List Price" of $999.00 for the patio set was untrue and misleading.</blockquote><br />After the lawsuit was filed, Chris Moran from the <span id="goog_685219541"></span><a href="http://consumerist.com/2010/11/18/overstockcom-sued-for-allegedly-overstating-discounts/" target="_blank">Consumerist</a><span id="goog_685219542"></span> remarked, "Apparently, the “O” in Overstock.com stands for “Overstating discounts and misleading customers,”....<br /><br /><b>Overstock.com defrauded consumers</b><br /><br /><table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="float: right; margin-left: 1em; text-align: right;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zNOzKE0iBeM/TjiaqHRu_GI/AAAAAAAAAuw/g-Wkl3F-HD8/s1600/Patrick-Byrne.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-zNOzKE0iBeM/TjiaqHRu_GI/AAAAAAAAAuw/g-Wkl3F-HD8/s1600/Patrick-Byrne.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Patrick Byrne, CEO</td></tr></tbody></table>On January 3, 2014, the Judge ruled that Overstock.com was indeed faking its comparative prices. For example, the Judge cited an internal Overstock.com email that observed:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">18. ...Oh, I think it's been established that the 'List Price' is egregiously overstated. This place has some balls.</blockquote><br />The Judge ruled that:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">112. In sum, the court finds that Overstock has continuously used ARPs [advertised referenced price] in a manner designed to overstate the amount of savings to be enjoyed by shopping on the Overstock web site.</blockquote><br />According to the tentative ruling, Overstock.com used phony formulas to set comparative prices or simply made up comparative prices:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">114. Whenever Overstock used a formula to set an ARP [advertised referenced price] and then displayed a “You save” amount or percentage, it made a <i><b>misleading statement </b></i>as to the amount (and perhaps the <i><b>existence</b></i>) of a price reduction. When the ARP nomenclature was “list price,” the statement was also false for the same reason: the representation that there was a list price was <i><b>false</b></i>. In other words, where there was <i><b>no actual list price</b></i> but only one set by formula, the statement as to the dollar and percentage amount of the savings from <i><b>the nonexistent list price was also false</b></i>. When Overstock’s ARP was based on a “similar” product and then displayed a “You save” amount or percentage, the company made a <i><b>misleading statement</b></i> as to the amount (and perhaps the <i><b>existence</b></i>) of a price reduction. Whenever Overstock set an ARP based on the highest price it could find for the product, it made a <i><b>misleading statement</b></i> as to the amount (and perhaps the existence) of a price reduction. [Emphasis added.]</blockquote><br /><b>Injunction</b><br /><br />Mindful that Overstock.com deliberately faked comparative prices, the Judge approved the issuance of the following injunction:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">128. Overstock may not post any ARP [advertised referenced price] unless it verifies the reference price and documents that verification by a screen shot of the product offerings(s) and price(s) relied upon to comply with this order. The verification documentation shall be maintained for two years from the date the ad containing the ARP is initially posted, and the People may have reasonable access to such documentation throughout the five year period during which the injunction shall be in place.</blockquote><br />The district attorneys from eight California counties will monitor Overstock.com's compliance with the injunctive order.<br /><br />Written by:<br /><br />Sam E. Antar<br /><br /><b>Additional reading</b><br /><br /><a href="http://garyweiss.blogspot.com/2014/01/judge-fines-overstockcom-68-million.html" target="_blank">Gary Weiss: Overstock.com still scamming customers despite court ruling</a><br /><br /><b>Disclosure</b><br /><br />I am a convicted felon and a former CPA. As the criminal CFO of Crazy Eddie, I helped my cousin Eddie Antar and other members of his family mastermind one of the largest securities frauds uncovered during the 1980's. I committed my crimes in cold-blood for fun and profit, and simply because I could. If it weren't for the heroic efforts of the FBI, SEC, Postal Inspector's Office, US Attorney's Office, and class action plaintiff's lawyers who investigated, prosecuted, and sued me, I would still be the criminal CFO of Crazy Eddie today. I do not want or seek forgiveness for my vicious crimes from my victims. My past sins are unforgivable.<br /><br />There is a saying, "It takes one to know one." I've provided professional work for the FBI, IRS, SEC, Justice Department, and other federal and state law enforcement agencies in training them to identify fraud and catch white-collar criminals. Often, I <a href="http://www.crainsnewyork.com/assets/pdf/CN67159104.PDF" target="_blank">refer</a> cases to them as an independent whistleblower. In addition, I <a href="http://whitecollarfraud.blogspot.com/p/consulting.html" target="_blank">teach</a> white-collar crime classes for various government entities, professional organizations, businesses, and colleges and universities. Recently, I've helped the <a href="http://www.journalofaccountancy.com/Issues/2012/Aug/20125839.htm" target="_blank">AICPA Fraud Task Force</a> develop better methods for detecting fraud.<br /><br />I do not own any Overstock.com securities long or short.<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=TnhcbJPrHwo:AR7Mxp6_5ZI:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=TnhcbJPrHwo:AR7Mxp6_5ZI:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=TnhcbJPrHwo:AR7Mxp6_5ZI:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=TnhcbJPrHwo:AR7Mxp6_5ZI:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=TnhcbJPrHwo:AR7Mxp6_5ZI:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=TnhcbJPrHwo:AR7Mxp6_5ZI:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=TnhcbJPrHwo:AR7Mxp6_5ZI:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=TnhcbJPrHwo:AR7Mxp6_5ZI:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=TnhcbJPrHwo:AR7Mxp6_5ZI:KwTdNBX3Jqk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=TnhcbJPrHwo:AR7Mxp6_5ZI:KwTdNBX3Jqk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=TnhcbJPrHwo:AR7Mxp6_5ZI:l6gmwiTKsz0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=l6gmwiTKsz0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=TnhcbJPrHwo:AR7Mxp6_5ZI:gIN9vFwOqvQ"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=TnhcbJPrHwo:AR7Mxp6_5ZI:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=TnhcbJPrHwo:AR7Mxp6_5ZI:TzevzKxY174"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=TzevzKxY174" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=TnhcbJPrHwo:AR7Mxp6_5ZI:-BTjWOF_DHI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?i=TnhcbJPrHwo:AR7Mxp6_5ZI:-BTjWOF_DHI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?a=TnhcbJPrHwo:AR7Mxp6_5ZI:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/WhiteCollarFraud?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/WhiteCollarFraud/~4/TnhcbJPrHwo" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>