<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com.es">
	<documents count="30">
		<document id="70c915fd7ca20ebb253ab8f406e7ce8a" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/05/cern-another-big-giant-that-is-going-to.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">CERN is another “big giant” that is going to use OpenStack. In fact, right now is deploying the OpenStack cloud this month, and it has already been in use by pilot testers with 250 new VMs being created each day.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">The figures are impressive: 150.000 virtual machine, running on 16.000 physical machines distributed in two DataCenters (the oldest in Genève and the new one in Budapest) that will provide IaaS to Nearly 11,000 physicists across the globe working on official CERN experiments would be eligible to use this private cloud: <em>“Scientists will be able to request whatever amount of CPU, memory, and storage space they need. They will also be able to get a virtual machine with the requested amounts within 15 minutes”.</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">This approach let media publish that:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;&nbsp;</div><div><h1 class="heading" style="text-align: center;">150,000 cloud virtual machines will help solve mysteries of the Universe</h1><h2 class="standalone-deck" style="text-align: center;">&nbsp;&nbsp;</h2><h2 class="standalone-deck" style="text-align: center;">OpenStack, Puppet used to build cloud for world's largest particle accelerator.</h2><div class="standalone-deck">&nbsp;</div><div class="standalone-deck">&nbsp;</div><div align="right" style="text-align: center;">&nbsp;</div></div>The full new and more details <a href="http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2013/05/150000-cloud-virtual-machines-will-help-solve-mysteries-of-the-universe/?utm_campaign=Tweets+Q2+2013&amp;utm_source=linkedin&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_content=42817" target="_blank" title="new about CERN and OpenStack">can be read</a> in:<br /><a href="http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2013/05/150000-cloud-virtual-machines-will-help-solve-mysteries-of-the-universe/?utm_campaign=Tweets+Q2+2013&amp;utm_source=linkedin&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_content=42817">http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2013/05/150000-cloud-virtual-machines-will-help-solve-mysteries-of-the-universe/?utm_campaign=Tweets+Q2+2013&amp;utm_source=linkedin&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_content=42817</a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d109f4dbb9db7d1ca7d1cf1855198ea3" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/05/tissat-becomes-part-of-uk-cloudstore-g.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">I am absolutely proud of announcing that TISSAT has got into the <a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-nG" target="_blank" title="post 2013-may-2">“UK CloudStore”</a>, a&nbsp;UK Government&nbsp;marketplace designed to make the process of selecting Cloud services easier, simpler and quite cheaper for Public Sector Procurement Officers.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">This success&nbsp;becomes more important because&nbsp;the UK Government has just confirmed that it has adopted a 'Cloud First' policy (similar to the&nbsp;US one), making it mandatory for buyers of IT products and services in central government to consider purchases through the cloud as their first option: Cabinet Office Minister said that the policy will drive wider adoption of cloud computing in the public sector, boosting business through the G-Cloud programme's CloudStore, and ensuring the public sector buys IT in a 'quicker, cheaper, more competitive way'.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">This is the TISSAT's press release:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><b>Tissat, 07th&nbsp;May 2013 – </b>Tissat, Spanish company specializing in the Mission-Critical Outsourcing and Cloud Computing services, has been successful as a supplier under the Governments G-Cloud framework within the United Kingdom. Thus, Tissat becomes part of the UK Cloud Store, a platform for suppliers to offer their services for Cloud computing created by the British government.</div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;">Thus, the British government intends to promote maximum transparency in procurement of such cloudservices within the public sector. These enable a channel for the acquisition of products and services, as a catalog “on line” that contains all the information from various providers and the services they offer.</div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;">Moreover, being successful suppliers &nbsp;it may be seen as a product and/or service with good value for money, quick and efficient offering quality solutions at reasonable prices.</div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><b>—————</b></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em><b>About Tissat</b></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><strong><em>&nbsp;</em></strong></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>Tissat, Spanish company leader in asset management technology and provider of Cloud Computing services, ContactCenter and Business Development, possess an excellent position in the provision of services and application development for the end client, under a model of efficiency and management energy management unique at European level. Its new CPD, Walhalla (Tier IV) represents an industrialization model of own designed CPD own ready to host cloud computing services and able to provide international hosting.</em></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="aee87ff1a8fc629be4cec8352583e366" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/06/it-evolution-boosted-by-functional.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">For everybody who understands Spanish, I recommend this 10 minute video that review the IT evolution to explain (with subtle humor sense, since the interviewer is Guillermo Fesser, a Spanish humorist, one of members of comic duo “goma-espuma”, i.e. “foam rubber” in English) how initially expensive IT devices developed for handicapped people now have become cheap and commonly used gadgets. At the end, the video claims for the <b><i>“Functional Diversity”</i></b> as a new positive concept, <span class="tgtColl" direction="target" id="ctl00_cC_ucResEM_lblTranslation" lang="1033">instead of</span> disability or handicap, and a revitalizing incentive that boosts innovation.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Note: the term <em>“divertad”</em> is an invented word, resulting of contraction of two Spanish words: “diversidad” y “libertad”, used for Javier Romañach (the interviewed human rights activist, who also is an Internet pioneer in Spain) to say goodbye.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div>Hereafter, I quote Javier’s Word:<br /><br /><br /><div style="padding-left: 30px;"><i>Un vídeo de 10 minutos para estudiantes de tecnología:</i></div><div style="padding-left: 30px;"><i>&nbsp;</i></div><div style="padding-left: 30px;"><i><a href="http://www.canaluned.com/#frontaleID=F_RC&amp;sectionID=S_TELUNE&amp;videoID=10907">http://www.canaluned.com/#frontaleID=F_RC&amp;sectionID=S_TELUNE&amp;videoID=10907</a></i><i></i></div><div style="padding-left: 30px;"><i>&nbsp;<a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/javier-romac3b1ach1.jpg"><img alt="Javier Romañach" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1576" height="335" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/javier-romac3b1ach1.jpg?w=529&amp;h=335" width="529" /></a></i></div><div style="padding-left: 30px;"><a href="http://www.canaluned.com/#frontaleID=F_RC&amp;sectionID=S_TELUNE&amp;videoID=10907"><b><i> &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; </i></b></a><i></i></div><div style="padding-left: 30px;"><i>Salud y divertad,</i></div><div style="padding-left: 30px;"><i>Javier Romañach</i></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c2d7442f404e2ddede249f4772b95272" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/06/private-cloud-vs-public-cloud-one-of.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">A few day ago <a href="http://www.opendatacenteralliance.org/newsroom/blog/blogauthors/item/bhargavi-srivathsan" title="Bhargavi Srivathsan">Bhargavi Srivathsan</a> publishes a <a href="http://www.opendatacenteralliance.org/newsroom/blog/item/the-future-of-private-cloud?category_id=1" target="_blank" title="Bhargavi's post">post</a> in the <a href="http://www.opendatacenteralliance.org/" target="_blank" title="Open Data Center Alliance website">Open Data Center Alliance </a>website fostering an interesting discussion about comparison between Private Cloud and Public Cloud. This discussion was going to be analyzed in detail in ad-hoc panel in the <a href="http://www.opendatacenteralliance.org/forecast2013/">Forecast 2013</a>, on June 18th. Unfortunately I could meet that panel (I’m based in Spain), so maybe other ideas were added to the ones stated by Bhargavi in its post (in fact, the idea of Bhargavi was to warn and prepare the discussion in Forecast 2013).</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">I disagree with some of the point that Bhargavi said in its blog. So let me first copy the main Bhargavi’s paragraphs:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><i>What is a Private Cloud? It is a complete cloud infrastructure that is dedicated to the needs of a single organization, typically implemented within the firewall of the organization employing internally available resources and controlled by the IT department. Now, how is this different from a public cloud? In a public cloud, the services are delivered over a network that is open to public access and data travels through an un-trusted network.</i></div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><em>&nbsp;</em></div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><i>So is private cloud better than public cloud? It depends. There is definitely a choice to make. While private and public clouds share several architectural similarities, there are clear differences. A private cloud solution comes with the following advantages:</i>&nbsp;</div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><blockquote class="tr_bq"><ul><li><em>Better control over data (and data security)</em></li><li><em>Ability to balance and provision resources with very little turnaround time</em></li><li><em>Better risk control&nbsp;</em></li></ul></blockquote></blockquote><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><i>Obviously, there are some disadvantages in choosing a private cloud. Private clouds generally more costs upfront – there are costs associated with maintenance, planning for redundancy to avoid data loss, involving additional personnel to handle all operations in-house.</i></div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><em>&nbsp;</em></div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><em>&nbsp;</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><strong>So let me show my opinion about:</strong></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></div><div style="text-align: justify;">First, according to <a href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-145/SP800-145.pdf" target="_blank" title="NIST Cloud Definition paper">NIST Cloud definitions</a>, Private Cloud could be operated for the same organization that uses it (as Bhargavi stated) but also for an external provider (e.g., we offer that services to our Customers).</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Second, in order to be a real and authentic Cloud it should be mutitenancy (<a href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-145/SP800-145.pdf" target="_blank" title="NIST Cloud Definition paper">NIST definition again</a>), that implies that the Private Cloud, although dedicated to the same company/organization, the infrastructures are shared between different department of that company: each one of them becomes a different tenant; evidently, usually, that implies big companies (<span style="text-decoration: underline;">see Note 1</span>). So, in general, the <i>“ability to balance and provision resources”</i> is not a difference with the Public Cloud: this issue is roughly the same in both Public and “real” Private Clouds. However, I agree with the other 2 points a Private Cloud offer both better control over data (and data security) and better risk control that Public Cloud.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Finally, I also agree with Bhargavi that one disadvantage of the Private Cloud is the price: it’ll be more expensive than the Public Cloud either you own it, or you uses the services of a provider; part of&nbsp;the facts for that are the ones Bhargavi said, but for me there’s one more important (because, in some way, it is mostly the root cause of them): in spite of a real multitenant (departments of a large company)&nbsp;the usage percentage of infrastructures of Private Cloud will be, in general, lower that the Public Cloud usage percentage, so the Public Cloud prices can be cheaper because of the better usage of infrastructures, better usage of technicians operating the cloud, and so on.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;&nbsp;</div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><b>Note (1):</b> For not large enough companies the “Community Cloud” could be the answer if “private” approach is needed; in this model, according to NIST definition, the cloud infrastructure is provisioned for exclusive use by a specific community of consumers from organizations that have shared concerns, e.g., mission, security requirements, policy, and compliance considerations; besides, as in the case of private cloud, the cloud may be owned, managed, and operated by one or more of the organizations in the community, a third party, or some combination of them, and it may exist on or off premises).</div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d186014a1244d8b63811f2d30efcf090" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/07/the-european-standard-for-innovation.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">On June, 2013, was approved the UNE-CEN/TS 16555-1:2013, the European Standard for Innovation Management, and finally on July, the 4th was finally published.</div><div class="post-entry"><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">As Oana-Maria Pop (Senior Editor of IM) <a href="http://www.innovationmanagement.se/2013/02/25/code-name-cents-16555-1-innovation-management-an-edifying-conversation-about-an-essential-work-in-progress/" target="_blank" title="Oana-Maria Pop">stated at the beginning of this year</a>: <i>“As evidence suggests, innovation – both as a field of study and as a practical discipline – has gained considerable traction over the past 15 years. As organizations become broader and more complex, the need for a systematic approach to new product, service or business development techniques strengthens accordingly. And this is merely the tip of the iceberg – there are multiple insights on why communities can benefit from an organized approach to innovation – a process at the heart of our everyday (business) lives. As of today, this approach is becoming a reality and work slowly progresses towards the creation of a unified Innovation Management Standard. Why the delay? Plainly because relating innovation to standardization is something most practitioners still find counter-intuitive”.</i></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>&nbsp;</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;">But that work successfully concluded this last June. In that successful result some stakeholders and supranational bodies such as AENOR in Spain and SIS in Sweden were crucial, integrated and collaborating inside the CEN/TC 389 Innovation Management technical committee, that was created (by CEN) in November 2008 to support a culture of innovation in Europe and accelerate the access of innovation to both domestic and global markets. Note: similar to the worldwide ISO, at the European level, Brussels-based <a href="http://www.cen.eu/cen/pages/default.aspx" target="blank">CEN</a> (the European Committee for Standardization) is the solely recognized organization for the planning drafting and adoption of European Standards in all major areas of business except electro-technology and telecommunications.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Concretely, the Spanish standard <a href="http://www.aenor.es/aenor/certificacion/innovacion/innovacion_sistemas_166002.asp">UNE 166002</a> (Gestión de la I+D+i) was published by AENOR in 2006 and bring a consistent set of guidelines&nbsp;on which&nbsp;the new European Standard has been built. Now AENOR is working in adapting (light changes) its UNE 166002 Standard to&nbsp;fully meet the UNE-CEN/TS 16555-1:2013. <b>TISSAT is certified in UNE 166002 since 2010.</b></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></div><div style="text-align: justify;">This Technical Specification provides guidance on establishing and maintaining an innovation management system (IMS). It is applicable to all public and private organisations regardless of sector, type or size. This document provides guidance on:</div>-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; understanding the context of the organisation;<br />-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; establishing the leadership and commitment of top management;<br />-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; planning for innovation success;<br />-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; identifying and fostering innovation enablers/driving factors;<br />-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; developing the innovation management process;<br />-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; evaluating and improving the performance of the innovation management system;<br />-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; understanding and using innovation management techniques.<br /><br /><div style="text-align: justify;">By using this document, organisations can increase their awareness of the value of an IMS, establish such a system, expand their capacity for innovation, and ultimately generate more value for the organisation and its interested parties. Since the innovation management system outlined in this document follows the PDCA structure (plan-do-check-act), so it can be integrated within other standardised business management systems existing in the organisations, e.g. <strong>EN ISO 9001, EN ISO 14001</strong>, etc. <strong>That’s the case of TISSAT, where these&nbsp;3 Standards are fully integrated.</strong></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Finally, it should be noticed that the UNE-CEN/TS 16555-1:2013 is part of a family of Standards (on which the TC 389 is currently working on) as shown in the next table:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div align="center"><table border="1" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="height: 309px; width: 584px;"><tbody><tr><td colspan="4"><b>CEN/TS 16555 &nbsp; Standards Family</b></td></tr><tr><td width="91"><div align="center"><b>CEN/TS</b></div></td><td width="315"><div align="center"><b>Title</b></div></td><td width="89"><div align="center"><b>Status</b></div></td><td width="135"><div align="center"><b>Estimated Date</b></div></td></tr><tr><td width="91"><div align="center"><strong>16555-1</strong></div></td><td width="315">Innovation &nbsp; Management – Part 1: Innovation Management System</td><td width="89"><div align="center"><strong>Published</strong></div></td><td width="135"><div align="center">2013-07</div></td></tr><tr><td width="91"><div align="center"><strong>16555-2</strong></div></td><td width="315">Innovation &nbsp; Management – Part 2: Strategic Intelligence Management.</td><td width="89"><div align="center">Draft</div></td><td width="135"><div align="center">2014-12</div></td></tr><tr><td width="91"><div align="center"><strong>16555-3</strong></div></td><td width="315">Innovation &nbsp; Management – Part 3: Innovation Thinking</td><td width="89"><div align="center">Draft</div></td><td width="135"><div align="center">2014-12</div></td></tr><tr><td width="91"><div align="center"><strong>16555-4</strong></div></td><td width="315">Innovation &nbsp; Management – Part 4: Intellectual Property Management</td><td width="89"><div align="center">Draft</div></td><td width="135"><div align="center">2014-12</div></td></tr><tr><td width="91"><div align="center"><strong>16555-5</strong></div></td><td width="315">Innovation &nbsp; Management – Part 5: Collaboration Management</td><td width="89"><div align="center">Draft</div></td><td width="135"><div align="center">2014-12</div></td></tr><tr><td width="91"><div align="center"><strong>16555-6</strong></div></td><td width="315">Innovation &nbsp; Management – Part 6: Creativity Management</td><td width="89"><div align="center">Draft</div></td><td width="135"><div align="center">2014-12</div></td></tr><tr><td width="91"><div align="center"><strong>16555-7</strong></div></td><td width="315">Innovation &nbsp; Management – Part 7: Innovation Management Assessment</td><td width="89"><div align="center">Draft</div></td><td width="135"><div align="center">2014-02</div></td></tr></tbody></table></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="35100bd7a7ffdbba650568d19a883f3e" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/07/tissat-recertifies-its-energy.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">Tissat, leader in the field of Data Centers and owner of Walhalla, the first Tier IV Data Center offering these services in Spain, becomes <span style="text-decoration: underline;">one of the only two companies in Spain</span> that have obtained this quality certification and energy efficiency for its Data Centers.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">This standard specifies requirements for establishing, implementing, maintaining and improving an energy management system, allowing Tissat to have a systematic approach and thus achieve continuous improvement in energy performance, including energy efficiency, energy security, energy use and consumption. This certificate helps Tissat continually reduce its use and its costs of energy and the emission of greenhouse gases.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">The application of this standard for about two years as well as the monitoring of the best practices established by the “European Code of Conduct for Data Centers”, along with other measures that accompany and support this standard (ex. DCIM system) have allowed to the Tissat’s Data Center Walhalla reaching a <strong>PUE of 1.15, measured according</strong> to the strict and continuous level measurement of <strong>type 3 defined by ASHRAE, the Green Grid, the Uptime Institute</strong> and so on.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Note: This TISSAT certification have been recently improved by the&nbsp;<a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-ld" target="_blank" title="post 2013-feb-06">AENOR’s EA0044:2013</a> <a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-oL" target="_blank" title="Data Centres Energetic Sustainability Certification">Data Centres Energetic Sustainability Certification</a>, &nbsp;that&nbsp; accredits that a Data Centre accomplishes with the established energy audits, as well as energy and carbon footprint management systems, contributing to mitigate climate change.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/requisitos-establecidos-y-compromisos-adquiridos-iso-50001.jpg"><img alt="Requisitos establecidos y compromisos adquiridos ISO 50001" class="size-full wp-image-1591 aligncenter" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/requisitos-establecidos-y-compromisos-adquiridos-iso-50001.jpg?w=529" /></a></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c04d2db9688af9b4fc1e64f5be7833c0" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/09/europe-is-leading-dcim-adoption.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">In a recent <a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-qe" target="_blank" title="post 2013-sep-12">post</a> (titled “<a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-qe" target="_blank" title="post 2013-sep-12">Third-Party DataCentres are becoming increasingly attractive rather than Enterprise DataCentres, according to a recent Uptime Institute’s&nbsp;Survey</a>“) I refer to the The Uptime Institute’s <b>“<a href="http://uptimeinstitute.com/2013-survey-results" target="_blank">Data Center Industry Survey</a>” (2013)</b>: <a href="http://uptimeinstitute.com/2013-survey-results">http://uptimeinstitute.com/2013-survey-results</a><b>. </b>Among other <b>points, </b>that survey&nbsp;analyzes DCIM software adoption and show that is high this year, reaching a 38% among respondents, with the major driver being capacity planning; however in 2012, in spite of&nbsp;enormous interest in and that a fair percentage were already using tools that could be described as DCIM, there was no single concerted focus on what DCIM needed to be deployed.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-level-of-adoption-by-uptime-institute.jpg"><img alt="DCIM-Level of adoption-by-Uptime Institute" class="size-medium wp-image-1641 aligncenter" height="94" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-level-of-adoption-by-uptime-institute.jpg?w=300&amp;h=94" width="300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><b>Besides the adoption rate is even higher in Europe, which leads global DCIM adoption at nearly 50%.</b> Also, large organizations and colocation companies have adopted DCIM in the 50% range.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">As Uptime Institute recognizes, both industry-watchers and DCIM vendors have suggested that 38% adoption is too high. So where is the discrepancy? 2 facts could clarify the subject according to The Uptime Institute:</div><ul style="text-align: justify;"><li><div style="text-align: justify;">Uptime Institute’s audience base tends to be larger, more advanced data center owners and operators – Uptime Institute Network members, Tier-certified &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;data center owners, etc. – therefore, more likely to be ahead on leading-edge technology adoption.</div></li><li><div style="text-align: justify;">Also, the term DCIM has been used to include anything from a home-grown system of spreadsheets and monitors, to an advanced suite of fully integrated tools spanning multiple data centers.</div></li></ul><div style="text-align: justify;">Please, let me analyze the latter point. In order to solve the problem, this year Uptime Institute provided respondents with 451 Research’s definition of DCIM before the question, in order to provide clarity:</div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div style="text-align: justify;">DCIM is defined as a <i>data center-wide or organization-wide system or suite that collects and manages information about a data center’s assets, resource use and operational status</i>.</div></blockquote><div style="text-align: justify;">By the way I think <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Gartner’s definition</span> is quite better and clarifying<i>:</i></div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div style="text-align: justify;"><em><strong>DCIM is the integration of information technology and facility management disciplines to centralize monitoring, management and intelligent capacity planning of a data center’s critical systems. It enables a common, real-time monitoring and management platform for all interdependent systems across IT and facility infrastructures</strong></em>. (Note: Therefore, it enables the monitoring and collection of low-level infrastructure data to enable intelligent analysis by individuals with domain expertise (e.g., capacity planners and facilities planners), as well as holistic analysis of the overall infrastructure, and in consequence, a full DCIM solution provides detailed monitoring and measurement of data center performance, utilization and energy consumption, supporting more-efficient, cost-effective and greener environments).</div></blockquote>So, The Uptime Institute asked respondents specifically to exclude spreadsheets, BIM-type drafting programs and basic BMS systems. But I think do not eliminate partial solutions without intention or possibility to afford the whole dimension of DCIM.<br /><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Now let me introduce a new survey, carried out by IDC and this is summarized in the infographic that you can find <a href="http://www.findwhitepapers.com/force-download.php?id=28499" target="_blank" title="IDC infographic">here</a>.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-unified-management-by-idc.jpg"><img alt="DCIM-Unified management-by-IDC" class="size-medium wp-image-1644 aligncenter" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-unified-management-by-idc.jpg?w=272&amp;h=300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">According to IDC survey 92% of DataCenter manager see DCIM as the solution to traditional DC problems:</div><ul style="text-align: justify;"><li><div style="text-align: justify;">Inconsistent Data Information.</div></li><li><div style="text-align: justify;">Divided Data Center Operations.</div></li><li><div style="text-align: justify;">Inconsistent Data Center Maturity.</div></li></ul><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-traditional-dc-problems-by-idc.jpg"><img alt="DCIM-traditional DC problems-by-IDC" class="size-medium wp-image-1645 aligncenter" height="300" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-traditional-dc-problems-by-idc.jpg?w=185&amp;h=300" width="185" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">And those problems result in that 84% of data centers have had issues with power, space, cooling capacity, assets and uptime. These issues went on to negatively impact the business process:</div><ul style="text-align: justify;"><li><div style="text-align: justify;">31% – Delay in application rollouts</div></li><li><div style="text-align: justify;">30% – Disrupted ability to provide service to customers</div></li><li><div style="text-align: justify;">27% – Forced to spend unplanned OPEX budget</div></li><li><div style="text-align: justify;">26% – Need to roll back an application deployment.</div></li></ul><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">In the other hand, coming to the Uptime Institute survey and concretely to one of the points stated in the first paragraph of this post, 70% of respondents listed “improving capacity planning” as a top driver for buying DCIM. All other drivers were distant runners up. Capacity planning mistakes will be expensive, and could cripple a business. The industry is hungry for any solution that will help make this exercise less of a guessing game. Also, in second place (a 30%), is concerned with indentifying availability threats in advance:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-adoption-drivers-by-uptime-institute.jpg"><img alt="DCIM-adoption drivers-by-Uptime Institute" class="size-medium wp-image-1647 aligncenter" height="130" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-adoption-drivers-by-uptime-institute.jpg?w=300&amp;h=130" width="300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">And when asked about the features wished in DCIM the responses were:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-level-of-adoption-of-features-by-uptime-institute.jpg"><img alt="DCIM-Level of adoption of features-by-Uptime Institute" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1649" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-level-of-adoption-of-features-by-uptime-institute.jpg?w=529&amp;h=382" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Answers that fit perfectly with the survey done by IDC that concludes that about 70% of respondents wish the next 4 functionalities:</div><ul style="text-align: justify;"><li><div style="text-align: justify;">Real-time monitoring, including power and temperature</div></li><li><div style="text-align: justify;">Alerts and alarms for power and cooling</div></li><li><div style="text-align: justify;">Inventory and asset management</div></li><li><div style="text-align: justify;">Capacity analysis and planning</div></li></ul><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-functionalities-desired-by-idc.jpg"><img alt="DCIM functionalities desired-by-IDC" class="size-medium wp-image-1651 aligncenter" height="240" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-functionalities-desired-by-idc.jpg?w=300&amp;h=240" width="300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Finally, changing the subject, concerning to barriers to adopt DCIM Over 60% of Uptime Institute respondents globally said cost was the primary barrier to DCIM adoption, and the second one (but with a 37%, i.e. far from the first one), the integration of DCIM with the existing systems:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-adoption-barriers-by-uptime-institute.jpg"><img alt="DCIM-adoption barriers-by-Uptime Institute" class="size-medium wp-image-1652 aligncenter" height="137" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-adoption-barriers-by-uptime-institute.jpg?w=300&amp;h=137" width="300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">And the fact is that while small companies are deploying inexpensive DCIM tools (48% report spending less than $100k), the largest companies are spending significantly more for scalability and features (24% report spending over $300k):</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-cost-for-purchase-not-subscription-by-uptime-institute1.jpg"><img alt="DCIM-cost for purchase-not subscription-by-Uptime Institute" class="size-medium wp-image-1655 aligncenter" height="98" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-cost-for-purchase-not-subscription-by-uptime-institute1.jpg?w=300&amp;h=98" width="300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Note: in the above tables cost doesn’t reflect the investment in human resources needs (from training to specialized technicians and so on).</div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="cf2248a9274473bc65b32bbc0ec56f97" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/09/third-party-datacentres-are-becoming.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">The Uptime Institute, a division of The 451 Group, recently has published the results of its third annual <b>“Data Center Industry Survey” (2013).</b> The survey was developed to collect data on an annual basis around Digital Infrastructure deployment trends, procurement plans, operations and management practices, and other topics that impact the mission-critical data center industry.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Note: You can get a free copy of 2013 report at <a href="http://uptimeinstitute.com/2013-survey-results">http://uptimeinstitute.com/2013-survey-results</a> and the 2012 one at <a href="http://uptimeinstitute.com/2012-survey-results">http://uptimeinstitute.com/2012-survey-results</a>.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">This year, the survey &nbsp;gathers responses &nbsp;(during spring 2013) from 1,000 data center facilities operators, IT managers and senior executives from around the world (mainly from North America but with a growing number from Europe, Asia and Latin America) and most of them have responsibilities for more than one site. The survey covers different areas as DC budgets, Cloud Computing, Energy Efficiency and Green certifications, DCIM adoption, and so on.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">It shows consolidation in tendency in most areas but also some surprising trends changes:</div><ul style="text-align: justify;"><li>The <b>global average of the PUE numbers</b> the respondents were seeing was reported to be at 1,65, a great reduction from the 1,98 reported in 2012 survey, or the one of 2.5 reported in 2011.</li><li>The percentage of companies pursuing green data center certifications like US Green Building Council’s LEED program or Energy Star grew from 48% in 2012 to 58% in 2013.</li><li>Furthermore, the survey found that Enterprise <b>public cloud adoption rose</b> from 10% in 2012 to 17% in 2013, <b>however private cloud adoption decrease </b>slightly: only 44 per cent deploying private clouds this year, compared with 49 per cent in 2012. According to survey <i>“This seems to suggest that the companies who could make use of a private cloud platform have made the investment, and companies on the fence are either going to public cloud or walking away from the hype cycle”</i> . It also said that large enterprises are almost twice as likely to implement public clouds than smaller enterprises.</li><li>Prefab modular DC designs are on the slide: 53% of respondents said no interest from the last year 42%; and adoption is still around 8% as in the 2012 survey (however 2012 doubled 2011).</li><li>Reported DCIM software adoption is high, a 38% among respondents, with the major driver being capacity planning. (Note: however in 2012, in spite of&nbsp; enormous interest in and that a fair percentage were already using tools that could be described as DCIM, &nbsp;there was no single concerted focus on what DCIM needed to be deployed).</li></ul><br /><br /><div style="text-align: justify;">However, probably, <u>the new and most significant result found is</u> that are <b>the most significant DataCenter budget grow is occurring in the “third party” companies (</b>77% of third-party data centre providers said they had received large, 10% or more, year-over-year budget increases this year, compared with just 47% of enterprise data centres), <b><span style="text-decoration: underline;">reflecting a shift in spending away from enterprise-owned data centres and toward outsourced options</span>. </b>According to Matt Stansberry, Uptime Institute director of content and publications, <i>“This isn’t the end of the enterprise-owned data centre, but it should serve as a wakeup call. Going forward, enterprise data centre managers will need to be able to collect cost and performance data, and articulate their value to the business in order to compete with third-party offerings”.</i></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>&nbsp;</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Note: The Uptime Institute defines <i>“third party”</i> in this surveys as <i>“companies that provide computing capacity as service in any form”</i> (SaaS or other cloud computing services, multi-tenant collocation, or wholesale DC providers).</div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="49dfb490fcdd6f7671e1799194580fd9" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/10/openspack-havana-release-has-been.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">Please, let me copy this e-mail sent by Thierry Carrez to all&nbsp;OpenStack community:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><em>Hello everyone,</em><br /><em>&nbsp;</em><br /><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>It is my great pleasure to announce the final release of OpenStack 2013.2. It marks the end of the “Havana” 6-month-long development cycle, which saw the addition of two integrated components (Ceilometer and Heat), the completion of more than 400 feature blueprints and the fixing of more than 3000 reported bugs !</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>&nbsp;</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>You can find source tarballs for each integrated project, together with lists of features and bugfixes, at:</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>OpenStack Compute:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="https://launchpad.net/nova/havana/2013.2">https://launchpad.net/nova/havana/2013.2</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>OpenStack Object Storage: <a href="https://launchpad.net/swift/havana/1.10.0">https://launchpad.net/swift/havana/1.10.0</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>OpenStack Image Service:&nbsp; <a href="https://launchpad.net/glance/havana/2013.2">https://launchpad.net/glance/havana/2013.2</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>OpenStack Networking:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="https://launchpad.net/neutron/havana/2013.2">https://launchpad.net/neutron/havana/2013.2</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>OpenStack Block Storage:&nbsp; <a href="https://launchpad.net/cinder/havana/2013.2">https://launchpad.net/cinder/havana/2013.2</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>OpenStack Identity:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="https://launchpad.net/keystone/havana/2013.2">https://launchpad.net/keystone/havana/2013.2</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>OpenStack Dashboard:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="https://launchpad.net/horizon/havana/2013.2">https://launchpad.net/horizon/havana/2013.2</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>OpenStack Metering:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="https://launchpad.net/ceilometer/havana/2013.2">https://launchpad.net/ceilometer/havana/2013.2</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>OpenStack Orchestration:&nbsp; <a href="https://launchpad.net/heat/havana/2013.2">https://launchpad.net/heat/havana/2013.2</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>&nbsp;</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>The Havana Release Notes contain an overview of the key features, as well as upgrade notes and current lists of known issues. You can access them at:</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em><a href="https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/ReleaseNotes/Havana">https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/ReleaseNotes/Havana</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>&nbsp;</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>In 19 days, our community will gather in Hong-Kong for the OpenStack </em><em>Summit: 4 days of conference to discuss all things OpenStack and a Design Summit to plan the next 6-month development cycle, codenamed “Icehouse”. It’s not too late to join us there, see <a href="http://www.openstack.org/summit/openstack-summit-hong-kong-2013/">http://www.openstack.org/summit/openstack-summit-hong-kong-2013/</a> for more details.</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>&nbsp;</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>Congratulations to everyone who contributed to this development cycle and participated in making this awesome release posible!</em></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="220d6d74fb8cba3159798e0061375097" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/10/personal-data-privacy-europes-cloud.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">Currently the Personal Data Privacy is on everyone’s lips after this summer revelation by Edward Snowden about a US Government data collection program called PRISM, and it becomes even more fashionable right now that the analysis of released top secret documents have&nbsp; shown &nbsp;the extent of spying by the National Security Agency (NSA) on electronic communications has reached some European Prime Ministers, or for mention another example “Le Monde” journal has revealed that the NSA gathered more than 70 million French phone calls in a single month “targeting not only people suspected of being involved in terrorism <span style="text-decoration: underline;">but also high-profile individuals from the world of business</span> or politics”.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">So, I’d like to come back in this blog to the Data Privacy and its relationship with the intrinsically free Cloud data movements, and the possible impact on a (not wished, but perhaps needed) Cloud Regulation: for example, the European Parliament busied itself attaching amendments to its data privacy regulation before Snoweden’s revelations and now is weighing to address cloud computing that will actually signify a Cloud Regulations. In short, it’s basically a dilemma between:</div><ul style="text-align: justify;"><li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">On one hand, it is about the progress, the technical advances and the global business that Cloud technologies can foster</span>. In a post written about a year ago (<a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-eo" target="_blank" title="post 22-jun-2012">“Europe behind the US on Cloud”</a>),&nbsp; analyzing the Gartner’s report about why Cloud penetration is more delayed in Europe than in US and according Gartner, it was stated that a possible cause was these Personal Data Privacy Regulations that were seen as a protectionist barrier that precludes Cloud business growing (basically because of the Europe’s diverse and ever-changing data privacy regulations inhibit the movement of personal data to the cloud, and EU policy-making processes and practices can hinder business). And it’s clear to me that, in exchange, also non EU companies (mainly American ones) are suffering this policy because they become less competitive having to adapt their products and/or services to E.U. privacy laws. Therefore, at the end, business and technical advances are slowing …</li></ul><ul style="text-align: justify;"><li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">On the other hand, it is about human and civil rights</span>. As an European citizen, I’ve got no doubt about some data privacy protection is needed, without which Aldous Huxley’s “Big Brother” world will happen and police-state mentality will success. Even, <span style="text-decoration: underline;">someone perhaps could to persuade me that</span> it might be fair for Governments to have access to our private communications via the internet, <span style="text-decoration: underline;">in some circumstances under the right and well-known conditions and under the control of a trustworthy independent judiciary</span>. It’s difficult to debate about. And, at the end will be driven to the important and even more difficult debate about <strong>how democracy can protect itself </strong>(from terrorism and other radical ideas)<strong> without leaving been “democracy”</strong> (in other case, terrorism will have won the war, even it loses the battles). <span style="text-decoration: underline;">But this a technical post, so let me keep close to technical/economical subjects.</span></li></ul><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Of course some people (in both sides of Atlantic, but more in the west side) will think that these European laws are less about data security and more about limiting the power of American corporations and making easier the growing of European companies. However many EU officers and Parliament members have states that <i>“it’s not about protectionism but about ensuring customers will receive the proper level of guarantees in terms of data protection and access across Europe”</i>, because as Neelie Kroes (the European Commission vice president in charge of telecommunications and information policy) said<i>, “we need to realize that European citizens will not embrace the cloud if they are worried for their privacy or for the security of their data”</i>. And I share these ideas.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Furthermore, about this economic impact, it also be noted that, <u>in reverse, <span style="text-decoration: underline;">NSA is accused of conducting industrial espionage</span></u> in countries all around the world, even allied countries, and the reason to do that is <i>“we collect this information for many important reasons: for one, it could provide the United States and our allies early warning of international financial crises which could negatively impact the global economy. It also could provide insight into other countries’ economic policy or behavior which could affect global markets” (</i>I’ll come back to this subject in further post).</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Besides, another point to be taken into account is that personal data are been monetized in different ways by a lot of companies. Two very different factions of people exist, one who values privacy and one that could care less (and, of course, in the middle a lot of variants): for some people, privacy is not valued (they do no bear that its personal data are monetized and shared across platforms), but for others, privacy is sacred (they will even restrict their online presence and social networking). The problem, shown with clarity by the Snowden’s disclosures, is that neither faction actually knows much about what the US government (and other companies) can access and what it cannot and what is the real and full usage that is going to be made with those data.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">In the other side, there’s a risk of going too far and effectively putting a significant barrier to business, and in the current economic situation that could have a broader and negative impact in European and non European companies and businesses. So, <b>finding the balance is key</b> <b>and it’s not easy to solve this dilemma between Personal Data Privacy and Business Regulation, even harder when the business is around a technology like the Cloud where </b>free movements of data is intrinsic a one of its advantages, so they can travel (or be copied for availability reasons) from a country to another changing the jurisdiction over them and the laws to be applied.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">And another conclusion is that also data security must be improved (the use of strong encryption that can protect user data from all but the most intense decryption efforts).</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Finally, another worrying reflection to made is that NSA has shown that it is also subjected to the same risks of Data Loss (it doesn’t matter the way) as any other business company, and Snowden is certainly not the only one who had access to those private data of other people …</div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="aa6a24378148b60d10ecbc88ca846df2" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/11/analysis-of-several-cloud-adoption.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">A 451 Research study reports that market for cloud services is growing rapidly (as showed in an <a href="http://www.interxion.com/sectors/cloud/hosting-providers/the-evolution-of-the-european-cloud-market/" target="_blank" title="Interxion report">Interxion study</a>), predicting a CAGR (Compound Annual Growth Rate) of 24% from 2011 to 2015. Besides, that report compares the cloud market with the traditional hosting market. (Note: The hosting market consists of dedicated hosting and managed hosting; and to be able to make a comparison between cloud and the hosting market the study have chosen to leave out SaaS from Cloud market and reduce cloud computing to IaaS and PaaS). When comparing the cloud computing to the traditional hosting market, as showed in the next figure, we see that although <span style="text-decoration: underline;">cloud computing share</span> is growing rapidly (CAGR of 42%), with a total value of $4.8bn in 2012, it <span style="text-decoration: underline;">is still a relatively small share (18%) compared to the hosting market</span>:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/hosting-vs-cloud-by-interxion.jpg"><img alt="Hosting vs Cloud-by-Interxion" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1721" height="339" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/hosting-vs-cloud-by-interxion.jpg?w=529&amp;h=339" width="529" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">The above table shows how the provision of infrastructure services is still dominated by hosting providers offering traditional hosting services, but cloud growing figures let foresee that cloud-based technologies will start to overtake the traditional market.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Besides, IT spends are shifting from traditional IT services from Cloud Services:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/traditional-it-services-spends-vs-cloud-services-spends-by-aerohive-networks.jpg"><img alt="Traditional IT Services spends vs Cloud Services spends-by-Aerohive Networks" class="size-medium wp-image-1722 aligncenter" height="142" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/traditional-it-services-spends-vs-cloud-services-spends-by-aerohive-networks.jpg?w=300&amp;h=142" width="300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Besides, according to a <a href="http://www.pcconnection.com/IPA/PM/Brands/Cisco/PCCB2B/~/media/F6D6A531FB6943ACB374E8B06C8B8397.ashx?v=1" target="_blank" title="Cloud survey by PC Connection">study developed by PC-Connections</a>, 69% of organizations are considering implementing Cloud or already have some application in the cloud:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/cloud-implementation-by-pc-connection.jpg"><img alt="Cloud Implementation-by-PC Connection" class="size-medium wp-image-1723 aligncenter" height="173" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/cloud-implementation-by-pc-connection.jpg?w=300&amp;h=173" width="300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">And 50% of organizations have assessed its environments to determine if they are suitable for Cloud:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/assessment-of-your-it-environemt-for-cloud-by-pc-connection.jpg"><img alt="Assessment of your IT environemt for Cloud-by-PC Connection" class="size-medium wp-image-1724 aligncenter" height="143" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/assessment-of-your-it-environemt-for-cloud-by-pc-connection.jpg?w=300&amp;h=143" width="300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Therefore, let’s go deep in the Cloud Market, and we’ll review its current drivers and barriers; given that in the last year I‘ve treating direct or indirectly different sorts of Cloud barrier in several posts <i>(“<a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-mr" target="_blank" title="post 2013-mar-25">Cloud Computing Countries Ranking, or the Cloud Confusion even among market analyses: BSA vs Gartner vs IDC</a>”</i>, <i>“<a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-kD" target="_blank" title="post 2013-jan-24">Interoperability: a key feature to ask your Cloud Service Provider for</a>”</i>, <i>“<a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-jy" target="_blank" title="post 2013-jan-03">An infographic about Security and other Cloud Barriers</a>”</i>, <i>“<a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-gK" target="_blank" title="post 2012-oct-03">Cloud Computing and the EU Digital Agenda: A step in the right way, but too short</a>” </i>and so forth) let me focus in the drivers, and we’ll do it extracting data (as done in the prologue of this post) of several cloud market reports, that in some cases show different numeric results, even contradictory, but that they agree in the main: the relationship and importance of the main drivers.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">According to the third annual <b>“<a href="http://uptimeinstitute.com/2013-survey-results" target="_blank" title="Uptime Insitute's DC Industry Survey">Data Center Industry Survey</a>” (2013)</b> of The Uptime Institute, there are a lot of factors driving public cloud adoption, from speed of deployment, scalability and potential cost savings. But the breakout driver for cloud computing adoption in 2013 is end-user or customer demand. In 2012, only 13% of respondents listed customer demand as a top driver, versus 43% in 2013, making it the leading driver over all other factors driving public cloud deployments:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/top-cloud-drivers-the-uptime-insitute.jpg"><img alt="Top cloud drivers-The Uptime Insitute" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1725" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/top-cloud-drivers-the-uptime-insitute.jpg?w=529&amp;h=247" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Similar results are obtained by the <a href="https://plus.google.com/112439116430579376217/posts/jUkVRKNCMrm)," target="_blank" title="cloud journey  infographic: how IT is evolving (By Orange)">study conducted by Orange</a>, although the figures (and consequently the ranking) are different:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/top-reasons-for-implementing-cloud-by-orange.jpg"><img alt="Top reasons for Implementing Cloud-by-Orange" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1726" height="333" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/top-reasons-for-implementing-cloud-by-orange.jpg?w=529&amp;h=333" width="529" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Referring to this subject, <a href="http://public.dhe.ibm.com/common/ssi/ecm/en/zsl03216usen/ZSL03216USEN.PDF" target="_blank" title="Private Clouds Will Use Hybrid Infrastructure (by Forreste on behalf of IBM)">a study conducted by Forrester Research </a>(in behalf of IBM) shows that the 2 top applications that companies are interested in moving to the Cloud are clearly driven by the user: both the external customer and the internal employees:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/top-2-types-of-applications-to-host-on-cloud-by-forrester.jpg"><img alt="Top 2 Types of applications to host on Cloud-by-Forrester" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1727" height="157" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/top-2-types-of-applications-to-host-on-cloud-by-forrester.jpg?w=529&amp;h=157" width="529" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><b>&nbsp;&nbsp;</b></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><b><b>&nbsp;</b></b></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><b><b>In consequence <b>all of them agree on:</b></b></b></div><blockquote><h3 style="text-align: justify;"><em><span style="background-color: #ffd966; font-family: inherit;">the importance of cost reduction as well as the growing importance of focusing in the customer demands as key drivers.</span></em></h3></blockquote><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Besides, curiously, there are gradual changes in&nbsp;the way enterprises procure technology. With or without the blessing of IT, departmental and line-of-business managers are increasingly going direct to providers for SaaS apps or IaaS offerings.&nbsp;&nbsp;In fact, Gartner forecasts that the CFO (Chief Financial Officer) will spend as much <span style="text-decoration: underline;">on technology</span> as the CIO (Chief Information Officer) by 2017. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">A lot of that investment will go to customer-facing “systems of engagement”</span>, mainly relating to e-commerce, which needs cloud infrastructure to scale properly and meet the <span style="text-decoration: underline;">highly variable demands of public Web and mobile apps</span>.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Finally, directly in relation with the last sentence, according to <a href="https://plus.google.com/112439116430579376217/posts/PwQDgDvqhaN" target="_blank" title="Aerohive's Cloud Infographic about Adoption of Cloud Services">an Aerohive Networks infographic</a> the 3 main advantages of using Cloud Services are:</div><ol style="text-align: justify;"><li>Instant Scalability</li><li>Fast Deployment</li><li>Automated backup &amp; updates</li></ol><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/topd-advantages-of-cloud-services-by-aerohive-networks.jpg"><img alt="top advantages of Cloud Services-by-Aerohive Networks" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1728" height="206" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/topd-advantages-of-cloud-services-by-aerohive-networks.jpg?w=529&amp;h=206" width="529" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">And clearly the first two of them are aligned (and the third too) with the increasing user demand which forecast is based on, at least, the next points:</div><ul style="text-align: justify;"><li>90% of organizations will support corporate applications on personal devices by the end of 2014 &nbsp;(<i>Gartner, “Plan Now for the Hyperconverged Enterprise Network”, May 2012</i>) ,</li><li>1,04 billions of smartphones and tablets will be shipped in 2014&nbsp; overcoming for first time the number of normal mobiles (IDC, <a href="http://www.idc.com/tracker/showproductinfo.jsp?prod_id=36">Worldwide Quarterly Mobile Phone Tracker</a>,)</li><li>and Morgan &amp; Stanley estimates that the mobile web will be bigger that desktop internet by the end of 2015.</li></ul><br /><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/90-of-organizations-will-support-corporate-applications-on-personal-devices.jpg"><img alt="90% of organizations will support corporate applications on personal devices" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1729" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/90-of-organizations-will-support-corporate-applications-on-personal-devices.jpg?w=529&amp;h=226" /></a></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="635b26a7423e80d81f67cf4b6e518c44" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/11/personal-data-privacy-europes-cloud.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">The more the data disclosed by Snowden are analyzed, the bigger Personal Data Privacy worries become, as the news from my last post are showing; so let me come back to the subject, but from another point of view.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-r8" target="_blank" title="post 2013-oct-30">In my last post</a>, speaking about the dilemma between Personal Data Privacy and Europe’s Cloud Regulation, we simplify the problem and make a trick: we mix any kind of personal data from basic data (name, age, sex, …, phone numbers, addresses: post, e-mail, social networks, etc.), to phone and internet conversations and communications, trough hobbies, preferences, likes and so on.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Of course a lot of legal and ethical business can be done with those data (if you decide to make them public): from direct one-to-one marketing that offers only what you can really be interested in (e.g. adventure travels if you love them) and doesn’t disturb you what anything else (e.g. not offering you meal foods if you are vegetarian), to corporate image watching or legal technology watching, through social network based results forecasts, and so on. But also it must be ensured that these data are not used to discriminate you on the basis of your religion, political or sexual preferences for mentioning only a clear example. So I think all of us will agree that some protection is needed, especially when we are speaking about human and civil rights. In reverse, copying from other blog, maybe you can agree with Britain’s Foreign Secretary, William Hague who last June said: <i>“If you are a law-abiding citizen of this country going about your business and your personal life you have nothing to fear about the British state or the intelligence services listening to your phone calls or anything like that”</i>, but my perception is that a lot of citizens (as me) will think that those unfortunate words are laying the foundations for a dangerous police-state mentality.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">The BSA (Business Software Alliance), an organization I have a lot of discrepancies with (because of the way they use to get its goals), in the beginning of the year published a <a href="http://cloudscorecard.bsa.org/2012/assets/PDFs/BSA_GlobalCloudScorecard.pdf" target="_blank" title="BSA report">report</a> (see my post titled <a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-mr" target="_blank" title="post 2013-mar-25"><i>“Cloud Computing Countries Ranking, or the Cloud Confusion even among market analyses: BSA vs Gartner vs IDC”</i></a> on&nbsp;25th March 2013) about the best 24 countries prepared for the Cloud. The countries were scored taking into account their laws and regulations for provision of cloud watching seven areas: 1.- <b>data privacy</b>, 2.- cyber security, 3.- cyber crime control, 4.- preservation of intellectual property, 5.- technology interoperability and legal harmonization, 6.- free trade, and 7.- infrastructure IT; in other words, if they have a comprehensive suite of modern laws that support and facilitate the digital economy and cloud computing. And its result was that the top ten countries are Japan, Australia, Germany, United States, France, Italy, UK, Korea, Spain, and Singapore. (Please, note the big European countries presence: Germany in the 3rd place, and France in the 5th, Italy in the 6<sup>th</sup>, United Kingdom in the 7th and Spain in the 9<sup>th</sup>, contradicting in some way the aforementioned Gartner report). Moreover, curiously <span style="text-decoration: underline;">BSA does take into account as first criterion “data privacy”</span>, so I wonder what its weigh was in the final score, because it isn’t the strong point of the United States, is it?. So I think we need to explore deeper this “data privacy” criterion …</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Focusing only on the latter subject, I mean the data privacy criterion, <b>the top 5 countries ranked best for privacy are Spain, the Czech Republic, Iceland, Norway, and Slovenia,</b> according to BackgroundChecks.org that uses 6 criteria (the fist 4 are positive and the 2 last are negative) to rank them:</div><ol style="text-align: justify;"><li>Government has privacy laws</li><li>There are fines for violating privacy laws</li><li>Government actively protect free speech</li><li>Government does not restrict access to Internet</li><li>Government use spyware</li><li>Government filters or censors the Internet</li></ol><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/the-privacy-scoreboard.jpg"><img alt="The Privacy Scoreboard" class="size-full wp-image-1704 aligncenter" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/the-privacy-scoreboard.jpg?w=529" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">This picture is extracted from an infographic that you can find here: <a href="http://techcitynews.com/2013/10/15/these-5-countries-were-ranked-best-for-privacy-infographic/">http://techcitynews.com/2013/10/15/these-5-countries-were-ranked-best-for-privacy-infographic/</a>.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">This infographic also has an area dedicated to the countries that spies to its citizens as US, China, Malaysia, Syria, Nigeria, Iran and Bahrain, explaining the reasons why they have the dubious honour of being placed in this shame corner. <span lang="EN-US" style="font-family: &quot;Palatino Linotype&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-ansi-language: EN-US; mso-bidi-font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;; mso-bidi-language: AR-SA; mso-bidi-theme-font: minor-bidi; mso-fareast-font-family: Calibri; mso-fareast-language: EN-US; mso-fareast-theme-font: minor-latin;">(Note: you can get it in the above reference/link)</span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f17a0a8f516ca6a423cb0cacca504edf" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/11/personal-data-privacy-europes-cloud_15.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">This is the third and probably last one of this consecutive series of posts I’ve dedicated to Personal Privacy.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;As I already said in previous posts, these days fortunately I’ve caught in an “work jam” (I’ve said “fortunately” because I leave in a country, Spain, where the current unemployment rate is about 25%, difficult to understand for anyone, but fortunately it seems to be changing). This work-jam is the reason this post has been delayed so far, despite after the meeting I’m going to speak about I felt compelled to write immediately, just after finishing it, but you know, I have to meet other obligations.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">The fact is that yesterday I was invited by an excellent professional and business man, Javier Peris (a good friend of mine) to the VII National Congress of IT Government, Auditing and Security and (Congreso Nacional de Auditoría, Seguridad y Gobierno de TI) organized by ISACA at my born town, Valencia (the third biggest city in Spain). In spite of the work-jam I decided to attend because of friendship. The well-structured and interest of the subjects to be covered and the quality of the speakers and other involved professional as well as stakeholders. As in precedent Congresses, this year all of the speakers were great too, and <span style="text-decoration: underline;">these is the reason my worries during and after the meeting are stronger</span>. (By the way the Congress ends today but I’m not been able to attend; so maybe some of my worries could be solved today).</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Going to the subject, one of the most appealing event (in my opinion and in spite of&nbsp;other interesting subjects focused by other speaker as Carmen Serrano, Florencio Cano, Javier Zubieta o Javier Cao) was a round table about “Cyber War”.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">During the whole discussion I was amazed to discover no one face up the unfortunate recent facts disclosed by Snoweden. I thought, perhaps, people were afraid the discussion became about political issues instead of the technical aspects and business consequences. ISACA’s Congress (as this blog is) is a technical meeting, but treating that subject is very easy that the discussion evolves toward important political issues related with the subject. Due to I share that fear about the evolution of the discussion I decided to wait (and people who knows me will guess how difficult it was to me) to see when someone would introduce the argument that <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Europe has been (probably it follows currently) cyber attacked by the United States of America</span>.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Let me say it once again, I’m not going to discuss if we can be allied in the NATO with a country that spies our Europe Prime Ministers as well as our business leader(and take advantage of it, as themselves recognized for the cases of Brazil or Japan espionage), neither I’m going yo discuss if USA behavior is evolving toward a “policy state” and/or Aldous Huxley’s “Big Brother” society, <span style="text-decoration: underline;">HOWEVER I really wonder </span>(because that was was one of the other subjects treated in the ISACA Congres)<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> if Europe can keep signing the <b>Safe Harbour</b> &nbsp;agreement with US about complying with the</span> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Directive_95/46/EC_on_the_protection_of_personal_data" target="_blank" title="Directive 95/46/EC on the protection of personal data">EU Directive 95/46/EC on the protection of personal data</a>. I also wonder myself how we can “sell” security prevention, assessment, auditing and consulting tasks about “data privacy” knowing not only hackers but Governmental agencies under NO-Legal-control can break and the latter infringe it with complete impunity.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Recently, <a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-rs" target="_blank" title="post 2013-nov-06">in my last post</a>, titled <i>“<a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-rs" target="_blank" title="post 2013-nov-06">Personal Data Privacy &amp; Europe’s Cloud Regulation: the privacy approach (Spain and other European countries are the leaders)</a>”,</i>as its title announces I showed how Spain and Other European countries are the in the firsts position of the privacy protection ranking. Here, in Spain, we have the LOPD law that fully agrees and math the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Directive_95/46/EC_on_the_protection_of_personal_data" target="_blank" title="Directive 95/46/EC on the protection of personal data">EU Directive 95/46/EC on the protection of personal data</a>; besides the Spanish Public Administration must follow the “National Security Layout” (ENS or “Esquema Nacional de Seguridad”) and recently it has been released a law for securing “critical industries”. All of them are good (although many people think they could be better) because of its focus on improve IT security of subjects that “affect” to the citizens (in one way or other).</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Consequently, in summary &nbsp;and without going deep in this subject) they are also good for today business in, at least, two ways: citizens will trust in, and also because it fosters business about how to implement the appropriate security measures, to meet the regulation compliances, and to audit all of them (some of the ISACA Congress speakers treated these points). So I wonder myself how no on introduce early the problems of consequences of US behaviour.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Therefore, at the end, I decided to deliver the question to the round table. And the conclusion of the answers, <span style="text-decoration: underline;">and of the silences</span>, was VERY WORRYING: </div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><strong>“RESIGNATION” !!!</strong></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">And now it's when I understand better why (although very slowly) the European Commission wants to regulate more strictly about some related subjects, despite that measures (as I stated in the <a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-r8" target="_blank" title="post 2013-oct-30">post</a> titled <i>“<a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-r8" target="_blank" title="post 2013-oct-30">Personal Data Privacy &amp; Europe’s Cloud Regulation: the dilemma</a>”</i>) may cause a negative impact in both business and innovation.</div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d04052b3cdc52759f261cc6c08f6e828" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/11/rsa-europe-2013-uk-governments-cyber.html"><![CDATA[<div class="tweet-row tweet-text userselect" style="-webkit-user-select: text; margin-top: 6px; padding: 0px; word-wrap: break-word;"><div class="dir-ltr" dir="ltr" style="direction: ltr; unicode-bidi: embed;"><span style="background-color: rgba(255, 255, 255, 0);">RSA Europe 2013: UK government’s cyber-sharing programme is flawed, admits scheme’s own advisor<a class="twitter-timeline-link activeLink dir-ltr tco-link" data-url="http://itpp.me/1clYcWX" dir="ltr" href="http://t.co/ecpjFDaMMN" rel="nofollow" style="direction: ltr; outline: none; text-decoration: none; unicode-bidi: embed;" target="_blank">itpp.me/1clYcWX</a>&nbsp;<a class="twitter-hashtag dir-ltr" dir="ltr" href="https://mobile.twitter.com/search/?q=%23cybersecurity&amp;s=hash" style="direction: ltr; outline: none; text-decoration: none; unicode-bidi: embed;"><span style="opacity: 0.6; outline: none;">#</span>cybersecurity</a></span></div><div style="-webkit-tap-highlight-color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0); background-color: white; color: #333333; font-family: Georgia, Palatino, 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif !important; font-size: 18px !important; line-height: 24px !important;"><br /></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="456aa25ea8d3a35f995fa6e2d42ae4c7" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/12/openstack-keeps-gaining-momentum-as.html"><![CDATA[<div class="post-entry"><div style="text-align: justify;">A&nbsp;few weeks ago, Gartner analyst  Allessandro Perilli recently says the project has a long way to go  before it’s truly an enterprise-grade platform. In fact, in a <a href="http://blogs.gartner.com/alessandro-perilli/why-vendors-cant-sell-openstack-to-enterprises/" target="_blank" title="Alessandro Perilli's post">blog post</a> he says that <i>“despite marketing efforts by vendors and favorable press, enterprise adoption remains in the very earliest stages”</i> … The main reasons for that, in its opinion, are:</div><ul><li><i>Lack of clarity about what OpenStack does.</i><i></i></li><li><i>Lack of transparency about the business model.</i><i></i></li><li><i>Lack of differentiation.</i><i></i></li><li><i>Lack of pragmatism.</i><i></i></li></ul><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">OpenStack backers rebuffed such claims,  and I must recognize that I’m biased because I work in a European  company (Tissat, based in Spain, and with several DataCentres and one of  them -Walhalla- certified as Tier IV by the Uptime Institute) that offer IaaS  Services using OpenStack. But I also have to recognize that OpenStack is  a solution that is continuously evolving and growing, and therefore I  agree with some of the statement of Mr.&nbsp; Perilli, but I disagree with  its main conclusion:</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Maybe he’s right and the fact that big  companies are contributing to its code as well as they also are  supporting and using it to deliver services it’s unusual, but let me  mention some of them that are supporting and using it: <b>RackSpace</b> and <b>Nasa</b> (maybe they aren’t the biggest, but they were the first ones), <b>IBM</b> (IBM’s open cloud architecture), <b>HP</b> (HP Cloud Services), <b>Cisco </b>(WebEx  Service), they don’t seem small player, do they?&nbsp; (I beg your pardon  for the irony). Besides, relatively smaller companies are contributing  to, supporting and selling services on OpenStack as the traditional  Linux Distro Providers: <b>RedHat, Novell</b> (Suse), <b>Canonical</b> (Ubuntu). Finally other big player that are using OpenSack are <b>PayPal-eBay, Yahoo, CERN </b>(the European Organization for Nuclear Research), <b>ComCast</b>, <b>MercadoLibre, Inc</b>. (e-commerce services), San Diego Supercomputer Center, and so on., that aren’t small player either …</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Could you think in player in the IT  providers market as big as the firsts mentioned? Sure, Microsoft,  Google, Oracle, … Well, surprise, <span style="text-decoration: underline;">last week <b>Oracle </b>announced that they embrace OpenSatck</span>.  Yes, although Oracle acquired Nimbula on March (and maybe the Nimbula  shift from its own proprietary private cloud approach to become an  OpenStack-compatible software supplier was the first sign of the  change), they are going to integrates OpenStack cloud with its  technologies: “<i>Oracle Sponsors OpenStack Foundation; Offers Customers Ability To Use OpenStack To Manage Oracle Cloud Products and Services”.</i> Oracle’s announcement said that:<i></i></div><ul style="text-align: justify;"><li>Oracle Linux will include integrated OpenStack deployment capabilities.</li><li>Solaris too will get OpenStack deployment integrations</li><li>Oracle Compute Cloud and Oracle Storage Cloud services will be integrated with OpenStack</li><li>Likewise, Oracle ZS3 Series network attached storage, Axoim Storage  Systems, and StorageTek Tape Systems will all get integrated.</li><li>Oracle Exalogic Elastic Cloud hardware for running applications will get its own OpenStack integration as well.</li><li>And so on.</li></ul><div style="text-align: justify;">i.e. Oracle speaks about a significant  new support for OpenStack in an extremely ambitious manner, pretty much  saying that it would support OpenStack as a management framework across  an expansive list of Oracle products. Evidently, Oracle movement is a  great support for OpenStacck (and for my thesis, too, and probably  another point against Mr. Pirelli’s opinion) …</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">However, to be honest, &nbsp;let me doubt (at  the moment) about the ultimate motivations and objectives of Oracle:  I’ve got the impression that Oracle is simply ceding to the pressing of  the market, adjusting to the sign of the times, but it’s not committed  to what makes OpenStack means: a collaborative and inclusive community:  On one hand,&nbsp; as I stated that in my <em>&nbsp;</em><a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-ns" target="_blank" title="post of 2013-Apr-11">“Cloud Movements (2nd part): Oracle’s fight against itself (and the OpenStack role)”</a><strong>&nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;post that <b>Oracle is fighting against itself</b> due to its traditional and profitable business model is challenged by  the Cloud model, and it has been delaying its adoption as much as  possible (as IBM did when its mainframes ran mission-critical  applications on legacy databases, and a new -by then- generation of  infrastructure vendors -DEC, HP, Sun, Microsoft and Oracle- challenged  it and disrupted the old IBM model): it was conflicted about selling the  lower-priced, lower-margin servers needed to run them (even Oracle CEO  Larry Ellison used to disdain Cloud Computing, e.g. he called cloud  computing “nonsense” in 2009). On the other hand, the recent Oracle  announce doesn’t necessarily imply a change in this matter.</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Besides the Oracle movement raise  suspicions, even disbelief, not only in me but in other people. Let me  quote some paragraphs of Randy Bias’ (co-founder and CEO of cloud  software supplier CloudScalin post titled <a href="http://www.informationweek.com/cloud/software-as-a-service/oracle-supports-openstack-lip-service-or-real-commitment/d/d-id/1113068?goback=%2Egde_3239106_member_5817370136629235716#%21" target="_blank" title="Randy Bias' post">“Oracle Supports OpenStack: Lip Service Or Real Commitment?”</a>. Randy’s position could be summarized in its words <i>“</i><i>Oracle  is the epitome of a traditional enterprise vendor and to have it  announce this level of support for OpenStack is astonishing”</i>. Randy also wonders <i>“Can  Oracle engage positively with the open-source meritocracy that  OpenStack represents? Admittedly, at first blush it’s hard to be  positive, given Oracle’s walled-garden culture.”</i> And to back its answer, Randy review some Oracle facts:</div><div style="text-align: justify;"></div><ul><li>“<i>Oracle essentially ended  OpenSolaris as an open-source project, leaving third-party derivatives  of OpenSolaris (such as those promulgated by Joyent and Nexenta) out in  the cold, having to fork OpenSolaris to Illumos.</i></li><li><i>Similarly, the open-source  community’s lack of trust can be seen ultimately in the forking of MySQL  into MariaDB over concerns about Oracle’s support and direction of the  MySQL project. Google moved to MariaDB, and all of the major Linux  distributions are switching to it as well”.</i></li></ul><br /><div style="text-align: justify;"><b></b></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">However, finally Randy concludes: <i>“</i><i>It’s  hard not to have a certain amount of pessimism about Oracle’s  announcement. However, I’m hopeful that this signals an understanding of  the market realities and that its intentions are in the right place. We  will know fairly soon how serious it is based on code contributions to  OpenStack, which can be tracked at Stackalytics. (So far, there are zero  commits from Oracle and only two from Nimbula, Oracle’s recent cloud  software acquisition.). Personally, I’m happy to see Oracle join the  party. It further validates the level of interest in OpenStack from the  enterprise and reinforces that we’re all building a platform for the  future”.</i></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">And the last words of Randy gets me back  to my initial point: I really think OpenStack is already a mature enough  platform to make business (in all the ways other IT products or  solutions) as the giants and other big companies of IT area are showing  (IBM, HP, Cisco, Oracle, RackSpace, Yahoo, PayPal, ComCast, RedHat,  Novell, Canonical, etc.).</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Finally, let me end this post with some partial pictures extracted from an Infographic elaborated by OpenStack (you can get <a href="http://http//www.openstack.org/blog/2013/11/openstack-user-survey-october-2013/" target="_blank" title="OpenStack Usage Infographic">the whole infographic here</a>):</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">The current OpenStack deployment comprises 56 countries:</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-openstack-deployments.jpg"><img alt="Current OpenStack Deployments" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1761" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-openstack-deployments.jpg?w=529&amp;h=335" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Covering any-size organizations and a wide range of industry sectors:</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-opensatck-organizations-size.jpg"><img alt="Current OpenSatck Organizations Size" class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-1760" height="150" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-opensatck-organizations-size.jpg?w=142&amp;h=150" width="142" /></a>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-openstack-industry-sectors.jpg"><img alt="Current OpenStack Industry Sectors" class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-1763" height="146" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-openstack-industry-sectors.jpg?w=150&amp;h=146" width="150" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Besides, any type of deployments is currently made:</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-openstack-type-of-deployments.jpg"><img alt="Current OpenStack Type of Deployments" class="size-medium wp-image-1766 aligncenter" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-openstack-type-of-deployments.jpg?w=286&amp;h=300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">And currently the 10 types of applications most deployed on OpenStack are:</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-openstack-type-of-workloads.jpg"><img alt="Current OpenStack Type of Workloads" class="size-medium wp-image-1767 aligncenter" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-openstack-type-of-workloads.jpg?w=194&amp;h=300" /></a></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="70c915fd7ca20ebb253ab8f406e7ce8a" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/05/cern-another-big-giant-that-is-going-to.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">CERN is another “big giant” that is going to use OpenStack. In fact, right now is deploying the OpenStack cloud this month, and it has already been in use by pilot testers with 250 new VMs being created each day.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">The figures are impressive: 150.000 virtual machine, running on 16.000 physical machines distributed in two DataCenters (the oldest in Genève and the new one in Budapest) that will provide IaaS to Nearly 11,000 physicists across the globe working on official CERN experiments would be eligible to use this private cloud: <em>“Scientists will be able to request whatever amount of CPU, memory, and storage space they need. They will also be able to get a virtual machine with the requested amounts within 15 minutes”.</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">This approach let media publish that:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;&nbsp;</div><div><h1 class="heading" style="text-align: center;">150,000 cloud virtual machines will help solve mysteries of the Universe</h1><h2 class="standalone-deck" style="text-align: center;">&nbsp;&nbsp;</h2><h2 class="standalone-deck" style="text-align: center;">OpenStack, Puppet used to build cloud for world's largest particle accelerator.</h2><div class="standalone-deck">&nbsp;</div><div class="standalone-deck">&nbsp;</div><div align="right" style="text-align: center;">&nbsp;</div></div>The full new and more details <a href="http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2013/05/150000-cloud-virtual-machines-will-help-solve-mysteries-of-the-universe/?utm_campaign=Tweets+Q2+2013&amp;utm_source=linkedin&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_content=42817" target="_blank" title="new about CERN and OpenStack">can be read</a> in:<br /><a href="http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2013/05/150000-cloud-virtual-machines-will-help-solve-mysteries-of-the-universe/?utm_campaign=Tweets+Q2+2013&amp;utm_source=linkedin&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_content=42817">http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2013/05/150000-cloud-virtual-machines-will-help-solve-mysteries-of-the-universe/?utm_campaign=Tweets+Q2+2013&amp;utm_source=linkedin&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_content=42817</a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d109f4dbb9db7d1ca7d1cf1855198ea3" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/05/tissat-becomes-part-of-uk-cloudstore-g.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">I am absolutely proud of announcing that TISSAT has got into the <a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-nG" target="_blank" title="post 2013-may-2">“UK CloudStore”</a>, a&nbsp;UK Government&nbsp;marketplace designed to make the process of selecting Cloud services easier, simpler and quite cheaper for Public Sector Procurement Officers.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">This success&nbsp;becomes more important because&nbsp;the UK Government has just confirmed that it has adopted a 'Cloud First' policy (similar to the&nbsp;US one), making it mandatory for buyers of IT products and services in central government to consider purchases through the cloud as their first option: Cabinet Office Minister said that the policy will drive wider adoption of cloud computing in the public sector, boosting business through the G-Cloud programme's CloudStore, and ensuring the public sector buys IT in a 'quicker, cheaper, more competitive way'.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">This is the TISSAT's press release:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><b>Tissat, 07th&nbsp;May 2013 – </b>Tissat, Spanish company specializing in the Mission-Critical Outsourcing and Cloud Computing services, has been successful as a supplier under the Governments G-Cloud framework within the United Kingdom. Thus, Tissat becomes part of the UK Cloud Store, a platform for suppliers to offer their services for Cloud computing created by the British government.</div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;">Thus, the British government intends to promote maximum transparency in procurement of such cloudservices within the public sector. These enable a channel for the acquisition of products and services, as a catalog “on line” that contains all the information from various providers and the services they offer.</div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;">Moreover, being successful suppliers &nbsp;it may be seen as a product and/or service with good value for money, quick and efficient offering quality solutions at reasonable prices.</div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><b>—————</b></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em><b>About Tissat</b></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><strong><em>&nbsp;</em></strong></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>Tissat, Spanish company leader in asset management technology and provider of Cloud Computing services, ContactCenter and Business Development, possess an excellent position in the provision of services and application development for the end client, under a model of efficiency and management energy management unique at European level. Its new CPD, Walhalla (Tier IV) represents an industrialization model of own designed CPD own ready to host cloud computing services and able to provide international hosting.</em></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="aee87ff1a8fc629be4cec8352583e366" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/06/it-evolution-boosted-by-functional.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">For everybody who understands Spanish, I recommend this 10 minute video that review the IT evolution to explain (with subtle humor sense, since the interviewer is Guillermo Fesser, a Spanish humorist, one of members of comic duo “goma-espuma”, i.e. “foam rubber” in English) how initially expensive IT devices developed for handicapped people now have become cheap and commonly used gadgets. At the end, the video claims for the <b><i>“Functional Diversity”</i></b> as a new positive concept, <span class="tgtColl" direction="target" id="ctl00_cC_ucResEM_lblTranslation" lang="1033">instead of</span> disability or handicap, and a revitalizing incentive that boosts innovation.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Note: the term <em>“divertad”</em> is an invented word, resulting of contraction of two Spanish words: “diversidad” y “libertad”, used for Javier Romañach (the interviewed human rights activist, who also is an Internet pioneer in Spain) to say goodbye.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div>Hereafter, I quote Javier’s Word:<br /><br /><br /><div style="padding-left: 30px;"><i>Un vídeo de 10 minutos para estudiantes de tecnología:</i></div><div style="padding-left: 30px;"><i>&nbsp;</i></div><div style="padding-left: 30px;"><i><a href="http://www.canaluned.com/#frontaleID=F_RC&amp;sectionID=S_TELUNE&amp;videoID=10907">http://www.canaluned.com/#frontaleID=F_RC&amp;sectionID=S_TELUNE&amp;videoID=10907</a></i><i></i></div><div style="padding-left: 30px;"><i>&nbsp;<a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/javier-romac3b1ach1.jpg"><img alt="Javier Romañach" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1576" height="335" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/javier-romac3b1ach1.jpg?w=529&amp;h=335" width="529" /></a></i></div><div style="padding-left: 30px;"><a href="http://www.canaluned.com/#frontaleID=F_RC&amp;sectionID=S_TELUNE&amp;videoID=10907"><b><i> &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; </i></b></a><i></i></div><div style="padding-left: 30px;"><i>Salud y divertad,</i></div><div style="padding-left: 30px;"><i>Javier Romañach</i></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c2d7442f404e2ddede249f4772b95272" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/06/private-cloud-vs-public-cloud-one-of.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">A few day ago <a href="http://www.opendatacenteralliance.org/newsroom/blog/blogauthors/item/bhargavi-srivathsan" title="Bhargavi Srivathsan">Bhargavi Srivathsan</a> publishes a <a href="http://www.opendatacenteralliance.org/newsroom/blog/item/the-future-of-private-cloud?category_id=1" target="_blank" title="Bhargavi's post">post</a> in the <a href="http://www.opendatacenteralliance.org/" target="_blank" title="Open Data Center Alliance website">Open Data Center Alliance </a>website fostering an interesting discussion about comparison between Private Cloud and Public Cloud. This discussion was going to be analyzed in detail in ad-hoc panel in the <a href="http://www.opendatacenteralliance.org/forecast2013/">Forecast 2013</a>, on June 18th. Unfortunately I could meet that panel (I’m based in Spain), so maybe other ideas were added to the ones stated by Bhargavi in its post (in fact, the idea of Bhargavi was to warn and prepare the discussion in Forecast 2013).</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">I disagree with some of the point that Bhargavi said in its blog. So let me first copy the main Bhargavi’s paragraphs:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><i>What is a Private Cloud? It is a complete cloud infrastructure that is dedicated to the needs of a single organization, typically implemented within the firewall of the organization employing internally available resources and controlled by the IT department. Now, how is this different from a public cloud? In a public cloud, the services are delivered over a network that is open to public access and data travels through an un-trusted network.</i></div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><em>&nbsp;</em></div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><i>So is private cloud better than public cloud? It depends. There is definitely a choice to make. While private and public clouds share several architectural similarities, there are clear differences. A private cloud solution comes with the following advantages:</i>&nbsp;</div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><blockquote class="tr_bq"><ul><li><em>Better control over data (and data security)</em></li><li><em>Ability to balance and provision resources with very little turnaround time</em></li><li><em>Better risk control&nbsp;</em></li></ul></blockquote></blockquote><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><i>Obviously, there are some disadvantages in choosing a private cloud. Private clouds generally more costs upfront – there are costs associated with maintenance, planning for redundancy to avoid data loss, involving additional personnel to handle all operations in-house.</i></div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><em>&nbsp;</em></div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><em>&nbsp;</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><strong>So let me show my opinion about:</strong></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></div><div style="text-align: justify;">First, according to <a href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-145/SP800-145.pdf" target="_blank" title="NIST Cloud Definition paper">NIST Cloud definitions</a>, Private Cloud could be operated for the same organization that uses it (as Bhargavi stated) but also for an external provider (e.g., we offer that services to our Customers).</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Second, in order to be a real and authentic Cloud it should be mutitenancy (<a href="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/nistpubs/800-145/SP800-145.pdf" target="_blank" title="NIST Cloud Definition paper">NIST definition again</a>), that implies that the Private Cloud, although dedicated to the same company/organization, the infrastructures are shared between different department of that company: each one of them becomes a different tenant; evidently, usually, that implies big companies (<span style="text-decoration: underline;">see Note 1</span>). So, in general, the <i>“ability to balance and provision resources”</i> is not a difference with the Public Cloud: this issue is roughly the same in both Public and “real” Private Clouds. However, I agree with the other 2 points a Private Cloud offer both better control over data (and data security) and better risk control that Public Cloud.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Finally, I also agree with Bhargavi that one disadvantage of the Private Cloud is the price: it’ll be more expensive than the Public Cloud either you own it, or you uses the services of a provider; part of&nbsp;the facts for that are the ones Bhargavi said, but for me there’s one more important (because, in some way, it is mostly the root cause of them): in spite of a real multitenant (departments of a large company)&nbsp;the usage percentage of infrastructures of Private Cloud will be, in general, lower that the Public Cloud usage percentage, so the Public Cloud prices can be cheaper because of the better usage of infrastructures, better usage of technicians operating the cloud, and so on.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;&nbsp;</div><div style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: justify;"><b>Note (1):</b> For not large enough companies the “Community Cloud” could be the answer if “private” approach is needed; in this model, according to NIST definition, the cloud infrastructure is provisioned for exclusive use by a specific community of consumers from organizations that have shared concerns, e.g., mission, security requirements, policy, and compliance considerations; besides, as in the case of private cloud, the cloud may be owned, managed, and operated by one or more of the organizations in the community, a third party, or some combination of them, and it may exist on or off premises).</div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d186014a1244d8b63811f2d30efcf090" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/07/the-european-standard-for-innovation.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">On June, 2013, was approved the UNE-CEN/TS 16555-1:2013, the European Standard for Innovation Management, and finally on July, the 4th was finally published.</div><div class="post-entry"><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">As Oana-Maria Pop (Senior Editor of IM) <a href="http://www.innovationmanagement.se/2013/02/25/code-name-cents-16555-1-innovation-management-an-edifying-conversation-about-an-essential-work-in-progress/" target="_blank" title="Oana-Maria Pop">stated at the beginning of this year</a>: <i>“As evidence suggests, innovation – both as a field of study and as a practical discipline – has gained considerable traction over the past 15 years. As organizations become broader and more complex, the need for a systematic approach to new product, service or business development techniques strengthens accordingly. And this is merely the tip of the iceberg – there are multiple insights on why communities can benefit from an organized approach to innovation – a process at the heart of our everyday (business) lives. As of today, this approach is becoming a reality and work slowly progresses towards the creation of a unified Innovation Management Standard. Why the delay? Plainly because relating innovation to standardization is something most practitioners still find counter-intuitive”.</i></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>&nbsp;</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;">But that work successfully concluded this last June. In that successful result some stakeholders and supranational bodies such as AENOR in Spain and SIS in Sweden were crucial, integrated and collaborating inside the CEN/TC 389 Innovation Management technical committee, that was created (by CEN) in November 2008 to support a culture of innovation in Europe and accelerate the access of innovation to both domestic and global markets. Note: similar to the worldwide ISO, at the European level, Brussels-based <a href="http://www.cen.eu/cen/pages/default.aspx" target="blank">CEN</a> (the European Committee for Standardization) is the solely recognized organization for the planning drafting and adoption of European Standards in all major areas of business except electro-technology and telecommunications.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Concretely, the Spanish standard <a href="http://www.aenor.es/aenor/certificacion/innovacion/innovacion_sistemas_166002.asp">UNE 166002</a> (Gestión de la I+D+i) was published by AENOR in 2006 and bring a consistent set of guidelines&nbsp;on which&nbsp;the new European Standard has been built. Now AENOR is working in adapting (light changes) its UNE 166002 Standard to&nbsp;fully meet the UNE-CEN/TS 16555-1:2013. <b>TISSAT is certified in UNE 166002 since 2010.</b></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></div><div style="text-align: justify;">This Technical Specification provides guidance on establishing and maintaining an innovation management system (IMS). It is applicable to all public and private organisations regardless of sector, type or size. This document provides guidance on:</div>-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; understanding the context of the organisation;<br />-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; establishing the leadership and commitment of top management;<br />-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; planning for innovation success;<br />-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; identifying and fostering innovation enablers/driving factors;<br />-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; developing the innovation management process;<br />-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; evaluating and improving the performance of the innovation management system;<br />-&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; understanding and using innovation management techniques.<br /><br /><div style="text-align: justify;">By using this document, organisations can increase their awareness of the value of an IMS, establish such a system, expand their capacity for innovation, and ultimately generate more value for the organisation and its interested parties. Since the innovation management system outlined in this document follows the PDCA structure (plan-do-check-act), so it can be integrated within other standardised business management systems existing in the organisations, e.g. <strong>EN ISO 9001, EN ISO 14001</strong>, etc. <strong>That’s the case of TISSAT, where these&nbsp;3 Standards are fully integrated.</strong></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><strong>&nbsp;</strong></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Finally, it should be noticed that the UNE-CEN/TS 16555-1:2013 is part of a family of Standards (on which the TC 389 is currently working on) as shown in the next table:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div align="center"><table border="1" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="height: 309px; width: 584px;"><tbody><tr><td colspan="4"><b>CEN/TS 16555 &nbsp; Standards Family</b></td></tr><tr><td width="91"><div align="center"><b>CEN/TS</b></div></td><td width="315"><div align="center"><b>Title</b></div></td><td width="89"><div align="center"><b>Status</b></div></td><td width="135"><div align="center"><b>Estimated Date</b></div></td></tr><tr><td width="91"><div align="center"><strong>16555-1</strong></div></td><td width="315">Innovation &nbsp; Management – Part 1: Innovation Management System</td><td width="89"><div align="center"><strong>Published</strong></div></td><td width="135"><div align="center">2013-07</div></td></tr><tr><td width="91"><div align="center"><strong>16555-2</strong></div></td><td width="315">Innovation &nbsp; Management – Part 2: Strategic Intelligence Management.</td><td width="89"><div align="center">Draft</div></td><td width="135"><div align="center">2014-12</div></td></tr><tr><td width="91"><div align="center"><strong>16555-3</strong></div></td><td width="315">Innovation &nbsp; Management – Part 3: Innovation Thinking</td><td width="89"><div align="center">Draft</div></td><td width="135"><div align="center">2014-12</div></td></tr><tr><td width="91"><div align="center"><strong>16555-4</strong></div></td><td width="315">Innovation &nbsp; Management – Part 4: Intellectual Property Management</td><td width="89"><div align="center">Draft</div></td><td width="135"><div align="center">2014-12</div></td></tr><tr><td width="91"><div align="center"><strong>16555-5</strong></div></td><td width="315">Innovation &nbsp; Management – Part 5: Collaboration Management</td><td width="89"><div align="center">Draft</div></td><td width="135"><div align="center">2014-12</div></td></tr><tr><td width="91"><div align="center"><strong>16555-6</strong></div></td><td width="315">Innovation &nbsp; Management – Part 6: Creativity Management</td><td width="89"><div align="center">Draft</div></td><td width="135"><div align="center">2014-12</div></td></tr><tr><td width="91"><div align="center"><strong>16555-7</strong></div></td><td width="315">Innovation &nbsp; Management – Part 7: Innovation Management Assessment</td><td width="89"><div align="center">Draft</div></td><td width="135"><div align="center">2014-02</div></td></tr></tbody></table></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="35100bd7a7ffdbba650568d19a883f3e" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/07/tissat-recertifies-its-energy.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">Tissat, leader in the field of Data Centers and owner of Walhalla, the first Tier IV Data Center offering these services in Spain, becomes <span style="text-decoration: underline;">one of the only two companies in Spain</span> that have obtained this quality certification and energy efficiency for its Data Centers.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">This standard specifies requirements for establishing, implementing, maintaining and improving an energy management system, allowing Tissat to have a systematic approach and thus achieve continuous improvement in energy performance, including energy efficiency, energy security, energy use and consumption. This certificate helps Tissat continually reduce its use and its costs of energy and the emission of greenhouse gases.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">The application of this standard for about two years as well as the monitoring of the best practices established by the “European Code of Conduct for Data Centers”, along with other measures that accompany and support this standard (ex. DCIM system) have allowed to the Tissat’s Data Center Walhalla reaching a <strong>PUE of 1.15, measured according</strong> to the strict and continuous level measurement of <strong>type 3 defined by ASHRAE, the Green Grid, the Uptime Institute</strong> and so on.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Note: This TISSAT certification have been recently improved by the&nbsp;<a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-ld" target="_blank" title="post 2013-feb-06">AENOR’s EA0044:2013</a> <a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-oL" target="_blank" title="Data Centres Energetic Sustainability Certification">Data Centres Energetic Sustainability Certification</a>, &nbsp;that&nbsp; accredits that a Data Centre accomplishes with the established energy audits, as well as energy and carbon footprint management systems, contributing to mitigate climate change.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/requisitos-establecidos-y-compromisos-adquiridos-iso-50001.jpg"><img alt="Requisitos establecidos y compromisos adquiridos ISO 50001" class="size-full wp-image-1591 aligncenter" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/requisitos-establecidos-y-compromisos-adquiridos-iso-50001.jpg?w=529" /></a></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c04d2db9688af9b4fc1e64f5be7833c0" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/09/europe-is-leading-dcim-adoption.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">In a recent <a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-qe" target="_blank" title="post 2013-sep-12">post</a> (titled “<a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-qe" target="_blank" title="post 2013-sep-12">Third-Party DataCentres are becoming increasingly attractive rather than Enterprise DataCentres, according to a recent Uptime Institute’s&nbsp;Survey</a>“) I refer to the The Uptime Institute’s <b>“<a href="http://uptimeinstitute.com/2013-survey-results" target="_blank">Data Center Industry Survey</a>” (2013)</b>: <a href="http://uptimeinstitute.com/2013-survey-results">http://uptimeinstitute.com/2013-survey-results</a><b>. </b>Among other <b>points, </b>that survey&nbsp;analyzes DCIM software adoption and show that is high this year, reaching a 38% among respondents, with the major driver being capacity planning; however in 2012, in spite of&nbsp;enormous interest in and that a fair percentage were already using tools that could be described as DCIM, there was no single concerted focus on what DCIM needed to be deployed.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-level-of-adoption-by-uptime-institute.jpg"><img alt="DCIM-Level of adoption-by-Uptime Institute" class="size-medium wp-image-1641 aligncenter" height="94" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-level-of-adoption-by-uptime-institute.jpg?w=300&amp;h=94" width="300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><b>Besides the adoption rate is even higher in Europe, which leads global DCIM adoption at nearly 50%.</b> Also, large organizations and colocation companies have adopted DCIM in the 50% range.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">As Uptime Institute recognizes, both industry-watchers and DCIM vendors have suggested that 38% adoption is too high. So where is the discrepancy? 2 facts could clarify the subject according to The Uptime Institute:</div><ul style="text-align: justify;"><li><div style="text-align: justify;">Uptime Institute’s audience base tends to be larger, more advanced data center owners and operators – Uptime Institute Network members, Tier-certified &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;data center owners, etc. – therefore, more likely to be ahead on leading-edge technology adoption.</div></li><li><div style="text-align: justify;">Also, the term DCIM has been used to include anything from a home-grown system of spreadsheets and monitors, to an advanced suite of fully integrated tools spanning multiple data centers.</div></li></ul><div style="text-align: justify;">Please, let me analyze the latter point. In order to solve the problem, this year Uptime Institute provided respondents with 451 Research’s definition of DCIM before the question, in order to provide clarity:</div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div style="text-align: justify;">DCIM is defined as a <i>data center-wide or organization-wide system or suite that collects and manages information about a data center’s assets, resource use and operational status</i>.</div></blockquote><div style="text-align: justify;">By the way I think <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Gartner’s definition</span> is quite better and clarifying<i>:</i></div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div style="text-align: justify;"><em><strong>DCIM is the integration of information technology and facility management disciplines to centralize monitoring, management and intelligent capacity planning of a data center’s critical systems. It enables a common, real-time monitoring and management platform for all interdependent systems across IT and facility infrastructures</strong></em>. (Note: Therefore, it enables the monitoring and collection of low-level infrastructure data to enable intelligent analysis by individuals with domain expertise (e.g., capacity planners and facilities planners), as well as holistic analysis of the overall infrastructure, and in consequence, a full DCIM solution provides detailed monitoring and measurement of data center performance, utilization and energy consumption, supporting more-efficient, cost-effective and greener environments).</div></blockquote>So, The Uptime Institute asked respondents specifically to exclude spreadsheets, BIM-type drafting programs and basic BMS systems. But I think do not eliminate partial solutions without intention or possibility to afford the whole dimension of DCIM.<br /><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Now let me introduce a new survey, carried out by IDC and this is summarized in the infographic that you can find <a href="http://www.findwhitepapers.com/force-download.php?id=28499" target="_blank" title="IDC infographic">here</a>.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-unified-management-by-idc.jpg"><img alt="DCIM-Unified management-by-IDC" class="size-medium wp-image-1644 aligncenter" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-unified-management-by-idc.jpg?w=272&amp;h=300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">According to IDC survey 92% of DataCenter manager see DCIM as the solution to traditional DC problems:</div><ul style="text-align: justify;"><li><div style="text-align: justify;">Inconsistent Data Information.</div></li><li><div style="text-align: justify;">Divided Data Center Operations.</div></li><li><div style="text-align: justify;">Inconsistent Data Center Maturity.</div></li></ul><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-traditional-dc-problems-by-idc.jpg"><img alt="DCIM-traditional DC problems-by-IDC" class="size-medium wp-image-1645 aligncenter" height="300" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-traditional-dc-problems-by-idc.jpg?w=185&amp;h=300" width="185" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">And those problems result in that 84% of data centers have had issues with power, space, cooling capacity, assets and uptime. These issues went on to negatively impact the business process:</div><ul style="text-align: justify;"><li><div style="text-align: justify;">31% – Delay in application rollouts</div></li><li><div style="text-align: justify;">30% – Disrupted ability to provide service to customers</div></li><li><div style="text-align: justify;">27% – Forced to spend unplanned OPEX budget</div></li><li><div style="text-align: justify;">26% – Need to roll back an application deployment.</div></li></ul><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">In the other hand, coming to the Uptime Institute survey and concretely to one of the points stated in the first paragraph of this post, 70% of respondents listed “improving capacity planning” as a top driver for buying DCIM. All other drivers were distant runners up. Capacity planning mistakes will be expensive, and could cripple a business. The industry is hungry for any solution that will help make this exercise less of a guessing game. Also, in second place (a 30%), is concerned with indentifying availability threats in advance:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-adoption-drivers-by-uptime-institute.jpg"><img alt="DCIM-adoption drivers-by-Uptime Institute" class="size-medium wp-image-1647 aligncenter" height="130" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-adoption-drivers-by-uptime-institute.jpg?w=300&amp;h=130" width="300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">And when asked about the features wished in DCIM the responses were:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-level-of-adoption-of-features-by-uptime-institute.jpg"><img alt="DCIM-Level of adoption of features-by-Uptime Institute" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1649" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-level-of-adoption-of-features-by-uptime-institute.jpg?w=529&amp;h=382" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Answers that fit perfectly with the survey done by IDC that concludes that about 70% of respondents wish the next 4 functionalities:</div><ul style="text-align: justify;"><li><div style="text-align: justify;">Real-time monitoring, including power and temperature</div></li><li><div style="text-align: justify;">Alerts and alarms for power and cooling</div></li><li><div style="text-align: justify;">Inventory and asset management</div></li><li><div style="text-align: justify;">Capacity analysis and planning</div></li></ul><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-functionalities-desired-by-idc.jpg"><img alt="DCIM functionalities desired-by-IDC" class="size-medium wp-image-1651 aligncenter" height="240" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-functionalities-desired-by-idc.jpg?w=300&amp;h=240" width="300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Finally, changing the subject, concerning to barriers to adopt DCIM Over 60% of Uptime Institute respondents globally said cost was the primary barrier to DCIM adoption, and the second one (but with a 37%, i.e. far from the first one), the integration of DCIM with the existing systems:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-adoption-barriers-by-uptime-institute.jpg"><img alt="DCIM-adoption barriers-by-Uptime Institute" class="size-medium wp-image-1652 aligncenter" height="137" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-adoption-barriers-by-uptime-institute.jpg?w=300&amp;h=137" width="300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">And the fact is that while small companies are deploying inexpensive DCIM tools (48% report spending less than $100k), the largest companies are spending significantly more for scalability and features (24% report spending over $300k):</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-cost-for-purchase-not-subscription-by-uptime-institute1.jpg"><img alt="DCIM-cost for purchase-not subscription-by-Uptime Institute" class="size-medium wp-image-1655 aligncenter" height="98" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/dcim-cost-for-purchase-not-subscription-by-uptime-institute1.jpg?w=300&amp;h=98" width="300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Note: in the above tables cost doesn’t reflect the investment in human resources needs (from training to specialized technicians and so on).</div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="cf2248a9274473bc65b32bbc0ec56f97" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/09/third-party-datacentres-are-becoming.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">The Uptime Institute, a division of The 451 Group, recently has published the results of its third annual <b>“Data Center Industry Survey” (2013).</b> The survey was developed to collect data on an annual basis around Digital Infrastructure deployment trends, procurement plans, operations and management practices, and other topics that impact the mission-critical data center industry.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Note: You can get a free copy of 2013 report at <a href="http://uptimeinstitute.com/2013-survey-results">http://uptimeinstitute.com/2013-survey-results</a> and the 2012 one at <a href="http://uptimeinstitute.com/2012-survey-results">http://uptimeinstitute.com/2012-survey-results</a>.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">This year, the survey &nbsp;gathers responses &nbsp;(during spring 2013) from 1,000 data center facilities operators, IT managers and senior executives from around the world (mainly from North America but with a growing number from Europe, Asia and Latin America) and most of them have responsibilities for more than one site. The survey covers different areas as DC budgets, Cloud Computing, Energy Efficiency and Green certifications, DCIM adoption, and so on.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">It shows consolidation in tendency in most areas but also some surprising trends changes:</div><ul style="text-align: justify;"><li>The <b>global average of the PUE numbers</b> the respondents were seeing was reported to be at 1,65, a great reduction from the 1,98 reported in 2012 survey, or the one of 2.5 reported in 2011.</li><li>The percentage of companies pursuing green data center certifications like US Green Building Council’s LEED program or Energy Star grew from 48% in 2012 to 58% in 2013.</li><li>Furthermore, the survey found that Enterprise <b>public cloud adoption rose</b> from 10% in 2012 to 17% in 2013, <b>however private cloud adoption decrease </b>slightly: only 44 per cent deploying private clouds this year, compared with 49 per cent in 2012. According to survey <i>“This seems to suggest that the companies who could make use of a private cloud platform have made the investment, and companies on the fence are either going to public cloud or walking away from the hype cycle”</i> . It also said that large enterprises are almost twice as likely to implement public clouds than smaller enterprises.</li><li>Prefab modular DC designs are on the slide: 53% of respondents said no interest from the last year 42%; and adoption is still around 8% as in the 2012 survey (however 2012 doubled 2011).</li><li>Reported DCIM software adoption is high, a 38% among respondents, with the major driver being capacity planning. (Note: however in 2012, in spite of&nbsp; enormous interest in and that a fair percentage were already using tools that could be described as DCIM, &nbsp;there was no single concerted focus on what DCIM needed to be deployed).</li></ul><br /><br /><div style="text-align: justify;">However, probably, <u>the new and most significant result found is</u> that are <b>the most significant DataCenter budget grow is occurring in the “third party” companies (</b>77% of third-party data centre providers said they had received large, 10% or more, year-over-year budget increases this year, compared with just 47% of enterprise data centres), <b><span style="text-decoration: underline;">reflecting a shift in spending away from enterprise-owned data centres and toward outsourced options</span>. </b>According to Matt Stansberry, Uptime Institute director of content and publications, <i>“This isn’t the end of the enterprise-owned data centre, but it should serve as a wakeup call. Going forward, enterprise data centre managers will need to be able to collect cost and performance data, and articulate their value to the business in order to compete with third-party offerings”.</i></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>&nbsp;</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Note: The Uptime Institute defines <i>“third party”</i> in this surveys as <i>“companies that provide computing capacity as service in any form”</i> (SaaS or other cloud computing services, multi-tenant collocation, or wholesale DC providers).</div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="49dfb490fcdd6f7671e1799194580fd9" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/10/openspack-havana-release-has-been.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">Please, let me copy this e-mail sent by Thierry Carrez to all&nbsp;OpenStack community:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><em>Hello everyone,</em><br /><em>&nbsp;</em><br /><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>It is my great pleasure to announce the final release of OpenStack 2013.2. It marks the end of the “Havana” 6-month-long development cycle, which saw the addition of two integrated components (Ceilometer and Heat), the completion of more than 400 feature blueprints and the fixing of more than 3000 reported bugs !</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>&nbsp;</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>You can find source tarballs for each integrated project, together with lists of features and bugfixes, at:</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>OpenStack Compute:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="https://launchpad.net/nova/havana/2013.2">https://launchpad.net/nova/havana/2013.2</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>OpenStack Object Storage: <a href="https://launchpad.net/swift/havana/1.10.0">https://launchpad.net/swift/havana/1.10.0</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>OpenStack Image Service:&nbsp; <a href="https://launchpad.net/glance/havana/2013.2">https://launchpad.net/glance/havana/2013.2</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>OpenStack Networking:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="https://launchpad.net/neutron/havana/2013.2">https://launchpad.net/neutron/havana/2013.2</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>OpenStack Block Storage:&nbsp; <a href="https://launchpad.net/cinder/havana/2013.2">https://launchpad.net/cinder/havana/2013.2</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>OpenStack Identity:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="https://launchpad.net/keystone/havana/2013.2">https://launchpad.net/keystone/havana/2013.2</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>OpenStack Dashboard:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="https://launchpad.net/horizon/havana/2013.2">https://launchpad.net/horizon/havana/2013.2</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>OpenStack Metering:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="https://launchpad.net/ceilometer/havana/2013.2">https://launchpad.net/ceilometer/havana/2013.2</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>OpenStack Orchestration:&nbsp; <a href="https://launchpad.net/heat/havana/2013.2">https://launchpad.net/heat/havana/2013.2</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>&nbsp;</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>The Havana Release Notes contain an overview of the key features, as well as upgrade notes and current lists of known issues. You can access them at:</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em><a href="https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/ReleaseNotes/Havana">https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/ReleaseNotes/Havana</a></em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>&nbsp;</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>In 19 days, our community will gather in Hong-Kong for the OpenStack </em><em>Summit: 4 days of conference to discuss all things OpenStack and a Design Summit to plan the next 6-month development cycle, codenamed “Icehouse”. It’s not too late to join us there, see <a href="http://www.openstack.org/summit/openstack-summit-hong-kong-2013/">http://www.openstack.org/summit/openstack-summit-hong-kong-2013/</a> for more details.</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>&nbsp;</em></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><em>Congratulations to everyone who contributed to this development cycle and participated in making this awesome release posible!</em></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="220d6d74fb8cba3159798e0061375097" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/10/personal-data-privacy-europes-cloud.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">Currently the Personal Data Privacy is on everyone’s lips after this summer revelation by Edward Snowden about a US Government data collection program called PRISM, and it becomes even more fashionable right now that the analysis of released top secret documents have&nbsp; shown &nbsp;the extent of spying by the National Security Agency (NSA) on electronic communications has reached some European Prime Ministers, or for mention another example “Le Monde” journal has revealed that the NSA gathered more than 70 million French phone calls in a single month “targeting not only people suspected of being involved in terrorism <span style="text-decoration: underline;">but also high-profile individuals from the world of business</span> or politics”.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">So, I’d like to come back in this blog to the Data Privacy and its relationship with the intrinsically free Cloud data movements, and the possible impact on a (not wished, but perhaps needed) Cloud Regulation: for example, the European Parliament busied itself attaching amendments to its data privacy regulation before Snoweden’s revelations and now is weighing to address cloud computing that will actually signify a Cloud Regulations. In short, it’s basically a dilemma between:</div><ul style="text-align: justify;"><li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">On one hand, it is about the progress, the technical advances and the global business that Cloud technologies can foster</span>. In a post written about a year ago (<a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-eo" target="_blank" title="post 22-jun-2012">“Europe behind the US on Cloud”</a>),&nbsp; analyzing the Gartner’s report about why Cloud penetration is more delayed in Europe than in US and according Gartner, it was stated that a possible cause was these Personal Data Privacy Regulations that were seen as a protectionist barrier that precludes Cloud business growing (basically because of the Europe’s diverse and ever-changing data privacy regulations inhibit the movement of personal data to the cloud, and EU policy-making processes and practices can hinder business). And it’s clear to me that, in exchange, also non EU companies (mainly American ones) are suffering this policy because they become less competitive having to adapt their products and/or services to E.U. privacy laws. Therefore, at the end, business and technical advances are slowing …</li></ul><ul style="text-align: justify;"><li><span style="text-decoration: underline;">On the other hand, it is about human and civil rights</span>. As an European citizen, I’ve got no doubt about some data privacy protection is needed, without which Aldous Huxley’s “Big Brother” world will happen and police-state mentality will success. Even, <span style="text-decoration: underline;">someone perhaps could to persuade me that</span> it might be fair for Governments to have access to our private communications via the internet, <span style="text-decoration: underline;">in some circumstances under the right and well-known conditions and under the control of a trustworthy independent judiciary</span>. It’s difficult to debate about. And, at the end will be driven to the important and even more difficult debate about <strong>how democracy can protect itself </strong>(from terrorism and other radical ideas)<strong> without leaving been “democracy”</strong> (in other case, terrorism will have won the war, even it loses the battles). <span style="text-decoration: underline;">But this a technical post, so let me keep close to technical/economical subjects.</span></li></ul><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Of course some people (in both sides of Atlantic, but more in the west side) will think that these European laws are less about data security and more about limiting the power of American corporations and making easier the growing of European companies. However many EU officers and Parliament members have states that <i>“it’s not about protectionism but about ensuring customers will receive the proper level of guarantees in terms of data protection and access across Europe”</i>, because as Neelie Kroes (the European Commission vice president in charge of telecommunications and information policy) said<i>, “we need to realize that European citizens will not embrace the cloud if they are worried for their privacy or for the security of their data”</i>. And I share these ideas.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Furthermore, about this economic impact, it also be noted that, <u>in reverse, <span style="text-decoration: underline;">NSA is accused of conducting industrial espionage</span></u> in countries all around the world, even allied countries, and the reason to do that is <i>“we collect this information for many important reasons: for one, it could provide the United States and our allies early warning of international financial crises which could negatively impact the global economy. It also could provide insight into other countries’ economic policy or behavior which could affect global markets” (</i>I’ll come back to this subject in further post).</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Besides, another point to be taken into account is that personal data are been monetized in different ways by a lot of companies. Two very different factions of people exist, one who values privacy and one that could care less (and, of course, in the middle a lot of variants): for some people, privacy is not valued (they do no bear that its personal data are monetized and shared across platforms), but for others, privacy is sacred (they will even restrict their online presence and social networking). The problem, shown with clarity by the Snowden’s disclosures, is that neither faction actually knows much about what the US government (and other companies) can access and what it cannot and what is the real and full usage that is going to be made with those data.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">In the other side, there’s a risk of going too far and effectively putting a significant barrier to business, and in the current economic situation that could have a broader and negative impact in European and non European companies and businesses. So, <b>finding the balance is key</b> <b>and it’s not easy to solve this dilemma between Personal Data Privacy and Business Regulation, even harder when the business is around a technology like the Cloud where </b>free movements of data is intrinsic a one of its advantages, so they can travel (or be copied for availability reasons) from a country to another changing the jurisdiction over them and the laws to be applied.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">And another conclusion is that also data security must be improved (the use of strong encryption that can protect user data from all but the most intense decryption efforts).</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Finally, another worrying reflection to made is that NSA has shown that it is also subjected to the same risks of Data Loss (it doesn’t matter the way) as any other business company, and Snowden is certainly not the only one who had access to those private data of other people …</div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="aa6a24378148b60d10ecbc88ca846df2" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/11/analysis-of-several-cloud-adoption.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">A 451 Research study reports that market for cloud services is growing rapidly (as showed in an <a href="http://www.interxion.com/sectors/cloud/hosting-providers/the-evolution-of-the-european-cloud-market/" target="_blank" title="Interxion report">Interxion study</a>), predicting a CAGR (Compound Annual Growth Rate) of 24% from 2011 to 2015. Besides, that report compares the cloud market with the traditional hosting market. (Note: The hosting market consists of dedicated hosting and managed hosting; and to be able to make a comparison between cloud and the hosting market the study have chosen to leave out SaaS from Cloud market and reduce cloud computing to IaaS and PaaS). When comparing the cloud computing to the traditional hosting market, as showed in the next figure, we see that although <span style="text-decoration: underline;">cloud computing share</span> is growing rapidly (CAGR of 42%), with a total value of $4.8bn in 2012, it <span style="text-decoration: underline;">is still a relatively small share (18%) compared to the hosting market</span>:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/hosting-vs-cloud-by-interxion.jpg"><img alt="Hosting vs Cloud-by-Interxion" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1721" height="339" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/hosting-vs-cloud-by-interxion.jpg?w=529&amp;h=339" width="529" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">The above table shows how the provision of infrastructure services is still dominated by hosting providers offering traditional hosting services, but cloud growing figures let foresee that cloud-based technologies will start to overtake the traditional market.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Besides, IT spends are shifting from traditional IT services from Cloud Services:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/traditional-it-services-spends-vs-cloud-services-spends-by-aerohive-networks.jpg"><img alt="Traditional IT Services spends vs Cloud Services spends-by-Aerohive Networks" class="size-medium wp-image-1722 aligncenter" height="142" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/traditional-it-services-spends-vs-cloud-services-spends-by-aerohive-networks.jpg?w=300&amp;h=142" width="300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Besides, according to a <a href="http://www.pcconnection.com/IPA/PM/Brands/Cisco/PCCB2B/~/media/F6D6A531FB6943ACB374E8B06C8B8397.ashx?v=1" target="_blank" title="Cloud survey by PC Connection">study developed by PC-Connections</a>, 69% of organizations are considering implementing Cloud or already have some application in the cloud:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/cloud-implementation-by-pc-connection.jpg"><img alt="Cloud Implementation-by-PC Connection" class="size-medium wp-image-1723 aligncenter" height="173" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/cloud-implementation-by-pc-connection.jpg?w=300&amp;h=173" width="300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">And 50% of organizations have assessed its environments to determine if they are suitable for Cloud:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/assessment-of-your-it-environemt-for-cloud-by-pc-connection.jpg"><img alt="Assessment of your IT environemt for Cloud-by-PC Connection" class="size-medium wp-image-1724 aligncenter" height="143" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/assessment-of-your-it-environemt-for-cloud-by-pc-connection.jpg?w=300&amp;h=143" width="300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Therefore, let’s go deep in the Cloud Market, and we’ll review its current drivers and barriers; given that in the last year I‘ve treating direct or indirectly different sorts of Cloud barrier in several posts <i>(“<a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-mr" target="_blank" title="post 2013-mar-25">Cloud Computing Countries Ranking, or the Cloud Confusion even among market analyses: BSA vs Gartner vs IDC</a>”</i>, <i>“<a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-kD" target="_blank" title="post 2013-jan-24">Interoperability: a key feature to ask your Cloud Service Provider for</a>”</i>, <i>“<a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-jy" target="_blank" title="post 2013-jan-03">An infographic about Security and other Cloud Barriers</a>”</i>, <i>“<a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-gK" target="_blank" title="post 2012-oct-03">Cloud Computing and the EU Digital Agenda: A step in the right way, but too short</a>” </i>and so forth) let me focus in the drivers, and we’ll do it extracting data (as done in the prologue of this post) of several cloud market reports, that in some cases show different numeric results, even contradictory, but that they agree in the main: the relationship and importance of the main drivers.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">According to the third annual <b>“<a href="http://uptimeinstitute.com/2013-survey-results" target="_blank" title="Uptime Insitute's DC Industry Survey">Data Center Industry Survey</a>” (2013)</b> of The Uptime Institute, there are a lot of factors driving public cloud adoption, from speed of deployment, scalability and potential cost savings. But the breakout driver for cloud computing adoption in 2013 is end-user or customer demand. In 2012, only 13% of respondents listed customer demand as a top driver, versus 43% in 2013, making it the leading driver over all other factors driving public cloud deployments:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/top-cloud-drivers-the-uptime-insitute.jpg"><img alt="Top cloud drivers-The Uptime Insitute" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1725" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/top-cloud-drivers-the-uptime-insitute.jpg?w=529&amp;h=247" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Similar results are obtained by the <a href="https://plus.google.com/112439116430579376217/posts/jUkVRKNCMrm)," target="_blank" title="cloud journey  infographic: how IT is evolving (By Orange)">study conducted by Orange</a>, although the figures (and consequently the ranking) are different:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/top-reasons-for-implementing-cloud-by-orange.jpg"><img alt="Top reasons for Implementing Cloud-by-Orange" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1726" height="333" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/top-reasons-for-implementing-cloud-by-orange.jpg?w=529&amp;h=333" width="529" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Referring to this subject, <a href="http://public.dhe.ibm.com/common/ssi/ecm/en/zsl03216usen/ZSL03216USEN.PDF" target="_blank" title="Private Clouds Will Use Hybrid Infrastructure (by Forreste on behalf of IBM)">a study conducted by Forrester Research </a>(in behalf of IBM) shows that the 2 top applications that companies are interested in moving to the Cloud are clearly driven by the user: both the external customer and the internal employees:</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/top-2-types-of-applications-to-host-on-cloud-by-forrester.jpg"><img alt="Top 2 Types of applications to host on Cloud-by-Forrester" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1727" height="157" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/top-2-types-of-applications-to-host-on-cloud-by-forrester.jpg?w=529&amp;h=157" width="529" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><b>&nbsp;&nbsp;</b></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><b><b>&nbsp;</b></b></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><b><b>In consequence <b>all of them agree on:</b></b></b></div><blockquote><h3 style="text-align: justify;"><em><span style="background-color: #ffd966; font-family: inherit;">the importance of cost reduction as well as the growing importance of focusing in the customer demands as key drivers.</span></em></h3></blockquote><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Besides, curiously, there are gradual changes in&nbsp;the way enterprises procure technology. With or without the blessing of IT, departmental and line-of-business managers are increasingly going direct to providers for SaaS apps or IaaS offerings.&nbsp;&nbsp;In fact, Gartner forecasts that the CFO (Chief Financial Officer) will spend as much <span style="text-decoration: underline;">on technology</span> as the CIO (Chief Information Officer) by 2017. <span style="text-decoration: underline;">A lot of that investment will go to customer-facing “systems of engagement”</span>, mainly relating to e-commerce, which needs cloud infrastructure to scale properly and meet the <span style="text-decoration: underline;">highly variable demands of public Web and mobile apps</span>.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Finally, directly in relation with the last sentence, according to <a href="https://plus.google.com/112439116430579376217/posts/PwQDgDvqhaN" target="_blank" title="Aerohive's Cloud Infographic about Adoption of Cloud Services">an Aerohive Networks infographic</a> the 3 main advantages of using Cloud Services are:</div><ol style="text-align: justify;"><li>Instant Scalability</li><li>Fast Deployment</li><li>Automated backup &amp; updates</li></ol><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/topd-advantages-of-cloud-services-by-aerohive-networks.jpg"><img alt="top advantages of Cloud Services-by-Aerohive Networks" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1728" height="206" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/topd-advantages-of-cloud-services-by-aerohive-networks.jpg?w=529&amp;h=206" width="529" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">And clearly the first two of them are aligned (and the third too) with the increasing user demand which forecast is based on, at least, the next points:</div><ul style="text-align: justify;"><li>90% of organizations will support corporate applications on personal devices by the end of 2014 &nbsp;(<i>Gartner, “Plan Now for the Hyperconverged Enterprise Network”, May 2012</i>) ,</li><li>1,04 billions of smartphones and tablets will be shipped in 2014&nbsp; overcoming for first time the number of normal mobiles (IDC, <a href="http://www.idc.com/tracker/showproductinfo.jsp?prod_id=36">Worldwide Quarterly Mobile Phone Tracker</a>,)</li><li>and Morgan &amp; Stanley estimates that the mobile web will be bigger that desktop internet by the end of 2015.</li></ul><br /><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/90-of-organizations-will-support-corporate-applications-on-personal-devices.jpg"><img alt="90% of organizations will support corporate applications on personal devices" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1729" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/90-of-organizations-will-support-corporate-applications-on-personal-devices.jpg?w=529&amp;h=226" /></a></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="635b26a7423e80d81f67cf4b6e518c44" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/11/personal-data-privacy-europes-cloud.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">The more the data disclosed by Snowden are analyzed, the bigger Personal Data Privacy worries become, as the news from my last post are showing; so let me come back to the subject, but from another point of view.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-r8" target="_blank" title="post 2013-oct-30">In my last post</a>, speaking about the dilemma between Personal Data Privacy and Europe’s Cloud Regulation, we simplify the problem and make a trick: we mix any kind of personal data from basic data (name, age, sex, …, phone numbers, addresses: post, e-mail, social networks, etc.), to phone and internet conversations and communications, trough hobbies, preferences, likes and so on.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Of course a lot of legal and ethical business can be done with those data (if you decide to make them public): from direct one-to-one marketing that offers only what you can really be interested in (e.g. adventure travels if you love them) and doesn’t disturb you what anything else (e.g. not offering you meal foods if you are vegetarian), to corporate image watching or legal technology watching, through social network based results forecasts, and so on. But also it must be ensured that these data are not used to discriminate you on the basis of your religion, political or sexual preferences for mentioning only a clear example. So I think all of us will agree that some protection is needed, especially when we are speaking about human and civil rights. In reverse, copying from other blog, maybe you can agree with Britain’s Foreign Secretary, William Hague who last June said: <i>“If you are a law-abiding citizen of this country going about your business and your personal life you have nothing to fear about the British state or the intelligence services listening to your phone calls or anything like that”</i>, but my perception is that a lot of citizens (as me) will think that those unfortunate words are laying the foundations for a dangerous police-state mentality.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">The BSA (Business Software Alliance), an organization I have a lot of discrepancies with (because of the way they use to get its goals), in the beginning of the year published a <a href="http://cloudscorecard.bsa.org/2012/assets/PDFs/BSA_GlobalCloudScorecard.pdf" target="_blank" title="BSA report">report</a> (see my post titled <a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-mr" target="_blank" title="post 2013-mar-25"><i>“Cloud Computing Countries Ranking, or the Cloud Confusion even among market analyses: BSA vs Gartner vs IDC”</i></a> on&nbsp;25th March 2013) about the best 24 countries prepared for the Cloud. The countries were scored taking into account their laws and regulations for provision of cloud watching seven areas: 1.- <b>data privacy</b>, 2.- cyber security, 3.- cyber crime control, 4.- preservation of intellectual property, 5.- technology interoperability and legal harmonization, 6.- free trade, and 7.- infrastructure IT; in other words, if they have a comprehensive suite of modern laws that support and facilitate the digital economy and cloud computing. And its result was that the top ten countries are Japan, Australia, Germany, United States, France, Italy, UK, Korea, Spain, and Singapore. (Please, note the big European countries presence: Germany in the 3rd place, and France in the 5th, Italy in the 6<sup>th</sup>, United Kingdom in the 7th and Spain in the 9<sup>th</sup>, contradicting in some way the aforementioned Gartner report). Moreover, curiously <span style="text-decoration: underline;">BSA does take into account as first criterion “data privacy”</span>, so I wonder what its weigh was in the final score, because it isn’t the strong point of the United States, is it?. So I think we need to explore deeper this “data privacy” criterion …</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Focusing only on the latter subject, I mean the data privacy criterion, <b>the top 5 countries ranked best for privacy are Spain, the Czech Republic, Iceland, Norway, and Slovenia,</b> according to BackgroundChecks.org that uses 6 criteria (the fist 4 are positive and the 2 last are negative) to rank them:</div><ol style="text-align: justify;"><li>Government has privacy laws</li><li>There are fines for violating privacy laws</li><li>Government actively protect free speech</li><li>Government does not restrict access to Internet</li><li>Government use spyware</li><li>Government filters or censors the Internet</li></ol><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/the-privacy-scoreboard.jpg"><img alt="The Privacy Scoreboard" class="size-full wp-image-1704 aligncenter" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/11/the-privacy-scoreboard.jpg?w=529" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">This picture is extracted from an infographic that you can find here: <a href="http://techcitynews.com/2013/10/15/these-5-countries-were-ranked-best-for-privacy-infographic/">http://techcitynews.com/2013/10/15/these-5-countries-were-ranked-best-for-privacy-infographic/</a>.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">This infographic also has an area dedicated to the countries that spies to its citizens as US, China, Malaysia, Syria, Nigeria, Iran and Bahrain, explaining the reasons why they have the dubious honour of being placed in this shame corner. <span lang="EN-US" style="font-family: &quot;Palatino Linotype&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-ansi-language: EN-US; mso-bidi-font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;; mso-bidi-language: AR-SA; mso-bidi-theme-font: minor-bidi; mso-fareast-font-family: Calibri; mso-fareast-language: EN-US; mso-fareast-theme-font: minor-latin;">(Note: you can get it in the above reference/link)</span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f17a0a8f516ca6a423cb0cacca504edf" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/11/personal-data-privacy-europes-cloud_15.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: justify;">This is the third and probably last one of this consecutive series of posts I’ve dedicated to Personal Privacy.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;As I already said in previous posts, these days fortunately I’ve caught in an “work jam” (I’ve said “fortunately” because I leave in a country, Spain, where the current unemployment rate is about 25%, difficult to understand for anyone, but fortunately it seems to be changing). This work-jam is the reason this post has been delayed so far, despite after the meeting I’m going to speak about I felt compelled to write immediately, just after finishing it, but you know, I have to meet other obligations.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">The fact is that yesterday I was invited by an excellent professional and business man, Javier Peris (a good friend of mine) to the VII National Congress of IT Government, Auditing and Security and (Congreso Nacional de Auditoría, Seguridad y Gobierno de TI) organized by ISACA at my born town, Valencia (the third biggest city in Spain). In spite of the work-jam I decided to attend because of friendship. The well-structured and interest of the subjects to be covered and the quality of the speakers and other involved professional as well as stakeholders. As in precedent Congresses, this year all of the speakers were great too, and <span style="text-decoration: underline;">these is the reason my worries during and after the meeting are stronger</span>. (By the way the Congress ends today but I’m not been able to attend; so maybe some of my worries could be solved today).</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Going to the subject, one of the most appealing event (in my opinion and in spite of&nbsp;other interesting subjects focused by other speaker as Carmen Serrano, Florencio Cano, Javier Zubieta o Javier Cao) was a round table about “Cyber War”.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">During the whole discussion I was amazed to discover no one face up the unfortunate recent facts disclosed by Snoweden. I thought, perhaps, people were afraid the discussion became about political issues instead of the technical aspects and business consequences. ISACA’s Congress (as this blog is) is a technical meeting, but treating that subject is very easy that the discussion evolves toward important political issues related with the subject. Due to I share that fear about the evolution of the discussion I decided to wait (and people who knows me will guess how difficult it was to me) to see when someone would introduce the argument that <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Europe has been (probably it follows currently) cyber attacked by the United States of America</span>.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Let me say it once again, I’m not going to discuss if we can be allied in the NATO with a country that spies our Europe Prime Ministers as well as our business leader(and take advantage of it, as themselves recognized for the cases of Brazil or Japan espionage), neither I’m going yo discuss if USA behavior is evolving toward a “policy state” and/or Aldous Huxley’s “Big Brother” society, <span style="text-decoration: underline;">HOWEVER I really wonder </span>(because that was was one of the other subjects treated in the ISACA Congres)<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> if Europe can keep signing the <b>Safe Harbour</b> &nbsp;agreement with US about complying with the</span> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Directive_95/46/EC_on_the_protection_of_personal_data" target="_blank" title="Directive 95/46/EC on the protection of personal data">EU Directive 95/46/EC on the protection of personal data</a>. I also wonder myself how we can “sell” security prevention, assessment, auditing and consulting tasks about “data privacy” knowing not only hackers but Governmental agencies under NO-Legal-control can break and the latter infringe it with complete impunity.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Recently, <a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-rs" target="_blank" title="post 2013-nov-06">in my last post</a>, titled <i>“<a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-rs" target="_blank" title="post 2013-nov-06">Personal Data Privacy &amp; Europe’s Cloud Regulation: the privacy approach (Spain and other European countries are the leaders)</a>”,</i>as its title announces I showed how Spain and Other European countries are the in the firsts position of the privacy protection ranking. Here, in Spain, we have the LOPD law that fully agrees and math the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Directive_95/46/EC_on_the_protection_of_personal_data" target="_blank" title="Directive 95/46/EC on the protection of personal data">EU Directive 95/46/EC on the protection of personal data</a>; besides the Spanish Public Administration must follow the “National Security Layout” (ENS or “Esquema Nacional de Seguridad”) and recently it has been released a law for securing “critical industries”. All of them are good (although many people think they could be better) because of its focus on improve IT security of subjects that “affect” to the citizens (in one way or other).</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Consequently, in summary &nbsp;and without going deep in this subject) they are also good for today business in, at least, two ways: citizens will trust in, and also because it fosters business about how to implement the appropriate security measures, to meet the regulation compliances, and to audit all of them (some of the ISACA Congress speakers treated these points). So I wonder myself how no on introduce early the problems of consequences of US behaviour.</div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">Therefore, at the end, I decided to deliver the question to the round table. And the conclusion of the answers, <span style="text-decoration: underline;">and of the silences</span>, was VERY WORRYING: </div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: center;"><strong>“RESIGNATION” !!!</strong></div><div style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</div><div style="text-align: justify;">And now it's when I understand better why (although very slowly) the European Commission wants to regulate more strictly about some related subjects, despite that measures (as I stated in the <a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-r8" target="_blank" title="post 2013-oct-30">post</a> titled <i>“<a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-r8" target="_blank" title="post 2013-oct-30">Personal Data Privacy &amp; Europe’s Cloud Regulation: the dilemma</a>”</i>) may cause a negative impact in both business and innovation.</div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d04052b3cdc52759f261cc6c08f6e828" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/11/rsa-europe-2013-uk-governments-cyber.html"><![CDATA[<div class="tweet-row tweet-text userselect" style="-webkit-user-select: text; margin-top: 6px; padding: 0px; word-wrap: break-word;"><div class="dir-ltr" dir="ltr" style="direction: ltr; unicode-bidi: embed;"><span style="background-color: rgba(255, 255, 255, 0);">RSA Europe 2013: UK government’s cyber-sharing programme is flawed, admits scheme’s own advisor<a class="twitter-timeline-link activeLink dir-ltr tco-link" data-url="http://itpp.me/1clYcWX" dir="ltr" href="http://t.co/ecpjFDaMMN" rel="nofollow" style="direction: ltr; outline: none; text-decoration: none; unicode-bidi: embed;" target="_blank">itpp.me/1clYcWX</a>&nbsp;<a class="twitter-hashtag dir-ltr" dir="ltr" href="https://mobile.twitter.com/search/?q=%23cybersecurity&amp;s=hash" style="direction: ltr; outline: none; text-decoration: none; unicode-bidi: embed;"><span style="opacity: 0.6; outline: none;">#</span>cybersecurity</a></span></div><div style="-webkit-tap-highlight-color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0); background-color: white; color: #333333; font-family: Georgia, Palatino, 'Helvetica Neue', Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif !important; font-size: 18px !important; line-height: 24px !important;"><br /></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="456aa25ea8d3a35f995fa6e2d42ae4c7" url="http://carloscebrianmartinez.blogspot.com/2013/12/openstack-keeps-gaining-momentum-as.html"><![CDATA[<div class="post-entry"><div style="text-align: justify;">A&nbsp;few weeks ago, Gartner analyst  Allessandro Perilli recently says the project has a long way to go  before it’s truly an enterprise-grade platform. In fact, in a <a href="http://blogs.gartner.com/alessandro-perilli/why-vendors-cant-sell-openstack-to-enterprises/" target="_blank" title="Alessandro Perilli's post">blog post</a> he says that <i>“despite marketing efforts by vendors and favorable press, enterprise adoption remains in the very earliest stages”</i> … The main reasons for that, in its opinion, are:</div><ul><li><i>Lack of clarity about what OpenStack does.</i><i></i></li><li><i>Lack of transparency about the business model.</i><i></i></li><li><i>Lack of differentiation.</i><i></i></li><li><i>Lack of pragmatism.</i><i></i></li></ul><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">OpenStack backers rebuffed such claims,  and I must recognize that I’m biased because I work in a European  company (Tissat, based in Spain, and with several DataCentres and one of  them -Walhalla- certified as Tier IV by the Uptime Institute) that offer IaaS  Services using OpenStack. But I also have to recognize that OpenStack is  a solution that is continuously evolving and growing, and therefore I  agree with some of the statement of Mr.&nbsp; Perilli, but I disagree with  its main conclusion:</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Maybe he’s right and the fact that big  companies are contributing to its code as well as they also are  supporting and using it to deliver services it’s unusual, but let me  mention some of them that are supporting and using it: <b>RackSpace</b> and <b>Nasa</b> (maybe they aren’t the biggest, but they were the first ones), <b>IBM</b> (IBM’s open cloud architecture), <b>HP</b> (HP Cloud Services), <b>Cisco </b>(WebEx  Service), they don’t seem small player, do they?&nbsp; (I beg your pardon  for the irony). Besides, relatively smaller companies are contributing  to, supporting and selling services on OpenStack as the traditional  Linux Distro Providers: <b>RedHat, Novell</b> (Suse), <b>Canonical</b> (Ubuntu). Finally other big player that are using OpenSack are <b>PayPal-eBay, Yahoo, CERN </b>(the European Organization for Nuclear Research), <b>ComCast</b>, <b>MercadoLibre, Inc</b>. (e-commerce services), San Diego Supercomputer Center, and so on., that aren’t small player either …</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Could you think in player in the IT  providers market as big as the firsts mentioned? Sure, Microsoft,  Google, Oracle, … Well, surprise, <span style="text-decoration: underline;">last week <b>Oracle </b>announced that they embrace OpenSatck</span>.  Yes, although Oracle acquired Nimbula on March (and maybe the Nimbula  shift from its own proprietary private cloud approach to become an  OpenStack-compatible software supplier was the first sign of the  change), they are going to integrates OpenStack cloud with its  technologies: “<i>Oracle Sponsors OpenStack Foundation; Offers Customers Ability To Use OpenStack To Manage Oracle Cloud Products and Services”.</i> Oracle’s announcement said that:<i></i></div><ul style="text-align: justify;"><li>Oracle Linux will include integrated OpenStack deployment capabilities.</li><li>Solaris too will get OpenStack deployment integrations</li><li>Oracle Compute Cloud and Oracle Storage Cloud services will be integrated with OpenStack</li><li>Likewise, Oracle ZS3 Series network attached storage, Axoim Storage  Systems, and StorageTek Tape Systems will all get integrated.</li><li>Oracle Exalogic Elastic Cloud hardware for running applications will get its own OpenStack integration as well.</li><li>And so on.</li></ul><div style="text-align: justify;">i.e. Oracle speaks about a significant  new support for OpenStack in an extremely ambitious manner, pretty much  saying that it would support OpenStack as a management framework across  an expansive list of Oracle products. Evidently, Oracle movement is a  great support for OpenStacck (and for my thesis, too, and probably  another point against Mr. Pirelli’s opinion) …</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">However, to be honest, &nbsp;let me doubt (at  the moment) about the ultimate motivations and objectives of Oracle:  I’ve got the impression that Oracle is simply ceding to the pressing of  the market, adjusting to the sign of the times, but it’s not committed  to what makes OpenStack means: a collaborative and inclusive community:  On one hand,&nbsp; as I stated that in my <em>&nbsp;</em><a href="http://wp.me/p2cqZY-ns" target="_blank" title="post of 2013-Apr-11">“Cloud Movements (2nd part): Oracle’s fight against itself (and the OpenStack role)”</a><strong>&nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;post that <b>Oracle is fighting against itself</b> due to its traditional and profitable business model is challenged by  the Cloud model, and it has been delaying its adoption as much as  possible (as IBM did when its mainframes ran mission-critical  applications on legacy databases, and a new -by then- generation of  infrastructure vendors -DEC, HP, Sun, Microsoft and Oracle- challenged  it and disrupted the old IBM model): it was conflicted about selling the  lower-priced, lower-margin servers needed to run them (even Oracle CEO  Larry Ellison used to disdain Cloud Computing, e.g. he called cloud  computing “nonsense” in 2009). On the other hand, the recent Oracle  announce doesn’t necessarily imply a change in this matter.</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Besides the Oracle movement raise  suspicions, even disbelief, not only in me but in other people. Let me  quote some paragraphs of Randy Bias’ (co-founder and CEO of cloud  software supplier CloudScalin post titled <a href="http://www.informationweek.com/cloud/software-as-a-service/oracle-supports-openstack-lip-service-or-real-commitment/d/d-id/1113068?goback=%2Egde_3239106_member_5817370136629235716#%21" target="_blank" title="Randy Bias' post">“Oracle Supports OpenStack: Lip Service Or Real Commitment?”</a>. Randy’s position could be summarized in its words <i>“</i><i>Oracle  is the epitome of a traditional enterprise vendor and to have it  announce this level of support for OpenStack is astonishing”</i>. Randy also wonders <i>“Can  Oracle engage positively with the open-source meritocracy that  OpenStack represents? Admittedly, at first blush it’s hard to be  positive, given Oracle’s walled-garden culture.”</i> And to back its answer, Randy review some Oracle facts:</div><div style="text-align: justify;"></div><ul><li>“<i>Oracle essentially ended  OpenSolaris as an open-source project, leaving third-party derivatives  of OpenSolaris (such as those promulgated by Joyent and Nexenta) out in  the cold, having to fork OpenSolaris to Illumos.</i></li><li><i>Similarly, the open-source  community’s lack of trust can be seen ultimately in the forking of MySQL  into MariaDB over concerns about Oracle’s support and direction of the  MySQL project. Google moved to MariaDB, and all of the major Linux  distributions are switching to it as well”.</i></li></ul><br /><div style="text-align: justify;"><b></b></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">However, finally Randy concludes: <i>“</i><i>It’s  hard not to have a certain amount of pessimism about Oracle’s  announcement. However, I’m hopeful that this signals an understanding of  the market realities and that its intentions are in the right place. We  will know fairly soon how serious it is based on code contributions to  OpenStack, which can be tracked at Stackalytics. (So far, there are zero  commits from Oracle and only two from Nimbula, Oracle’s recent cloud  software acquisition.). Personally, I’m happy to see Oracle join the  party. It further validates the level of interest in OpenStack from the  enterprise and reinforces that we’re all building a platform for the  future”.</i></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">And the last words of Randy gets me back  to my initial point: I really think OpenStack is already a mature enough  platform to make business (in all the ways other IT products or  solutions) as the giants and other big companies of IT area are showing  (IBM, HP, Cisco, Oracle, RackSpace, Yahoo, PayPal, ComCast, RedHat,  Novell, Canonical, etc.).</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Finally, let me end this post with some partial pictures extracted from an Infographic elaborated by OpenStack (you can get <a href="http://http//www.openstack.org/blog/2013/11/openstack-user-survey-october-2013/" target="_blank" title="OpenStack Usage Infographic">the whole infographic here</a>):</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">The current OpenStack deployment comprises 56 countries:</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-openstack-deployments.jpg"><img alt="Current OpenStack Deployments" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1761" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-openstack-deployments.jpg?w=529&amp;h=335" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Covering any-size organizations and a wide range of industry sectors:</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-opensatck-organizations-size.jpg"><img alt="Current OpenSatck Organizations Size" class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-1760" height="150" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-opensatck-organizations-size.jpg?w=142&amp;h=150" width="142" /></a>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-openstack-industry-sectors.jpg"><img alt="Current OpenStack Industry Sectors" class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-1763" height="146" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-openstack-industry-sectors.jpg?w=150&amp;h=146" width="150" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Besides, any type of deployments is currently made:</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-openstack-type-of-deployments.jpg"><img alt="Current OpenStack Type of Deployments" class="size-medium wp-image-1766 aligncenter" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-openstack-type-of-deployments.jpg?w=286&amp;h=300" /></a></div><div style="text-align: justify;">And currently the 10 types of applications most deployed on OpenStack are:</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-openstack-type-of-workloads.jpg"><img alt="Current OpenStack Type of Workloads" class="size-medium wp-image-1767 aligncenter" src="http://tissat.files.wordpress.com/2013/12/current-openstack-type-of-workloads.jpg?w=194&amp;h=300" /></a></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>