<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="everyueveryme.livejournal.com">
	<documents count="48">
		<document id="b7e2e808558c545cf11ab94f2268499b" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/135255.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001q6wf9" alt="2011" height="600" width="500" border="0" /><br />(water brush,pen & digital stuff)</div><br />This Winter seems like a lot of people isn't very happy that a new year is starting.In fact,looks like they're mostly happy that 2010 is over.Guess it was a rough year for them.Me,you ask? It was a good,quite productive and inspiring year...actually,I wish it didn't finish so soon as I haven't finished lots of things and projects yet.Then again,I suppose that's what 2011 is here for,since time is always relative.And just for making things more exciting,this happens to be the first year of a whole decade.<br /><br />Now,today is also the LJversary of this corner of the web.It was 7 years ago when I began posting here.It's also been 7 years of discovering and meeting some of the most great people on the internets.That's a good enough reason for celebrating this day,so if you're reading this don't stop and go ahead.You're part of it —and by the way,THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR THAT!<br /><br />Okay now,Are you ready to show 2011 that dreams do become true? Come along,the fun it's only beggining! (if you don't believe me,just listen to Kate Micucci's words and music):<br /><lj-embed id="51" /><br /><br />Have a Most Epic & Excellent <s>Year</s> Decade!
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="60cef739c700c879fabf4cd9576ba844" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/135665.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001q7831" alt="Man&#39;s Life" height="645" width="500" border="0" /><br />(marker & some digital retouching)</div><br />What you see here is the lineart of a recreation of the cover of Man's Life,a pulp magazine.It was made for <a href="http://repulped.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">RePulped</a> (<span  class="ljuser  i-ljuser     "  lj:user="repulpedfeed" ><a href="http://repulpedfeed.livejournal.com/profile"  class="i-ljuser-profile" ><img  class="i-ljuser-userhead"  src="http://l-stat.livejournal.com/img/syndicated.gif?v=6283?v=111.1" /></a><a href="http://repulpedfeed.livejournal.com/" class="i-ljuser-username"    ><b>repulpedfeed</b></a></span>),a new blog about new versions of old pulp covers.<a href="http://repulped.blogspot.com/2011/01/u-aka-uriel-duran-repulps-mans-life-may.html" target="_blank">The final image is already posted there</a> along with the original cover.<br />There's not much else to say,except that sure this kind of image brings a new point of view to the Super Mario games and their plot based upon the eternal struggle between men and turtles.Or something like that.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b23e001805a211821b36ac5458e6e20c" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/135793.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001qcqhy" alt="Doodle Yourself As..." height="700" width="500" border="0" /><br />(pen,marker & digital color)</div><br />I stumbled upon this meme on Tumblr (via <a href="http://littlemisspaintbrush.tumblr.com/post/1121026258/doodle-yourself-as-meme" target="_blank">LittleMissPaintbrush</a>) and looked like fun.<br /><strong>1)</strong> I'm a bit predictable with this,but if I were a monster I'd be the Big Bad Wolf in fairy tales and viking legends<br /><strong>2)</strong> Still predictable.But I must say that I find fascinating how cocoa beans are actually very sour yet they become very sweet when transformed into chocolate.<br /><strong>3)</strong> Okay,if I were a woman very probably I'd look like MTV's Daria.But I'd also wear a Vampira/Morticia/Elvira dress at least once per week.<br /><strong>4)</strong> It's no secret I'd love to be Superman,but I think Madman is closer to my lifestyle<br /><strong>5)</strong> I choose Robocop only because I woke up with the movie theme stuck on my head<br /><strong>6)</strong> Don't ask!<br /><strong>7)</strong> Sharks may be powerful and dolphins may be the smart ones,but everybody knows sea turtles are actually the awesomest aquatic lifeforms,right? Plus,if you saw Finding Nemo,you know they behave like surfers so that's extra coolness points. <br /><strong>8)</strong> My favorite game is the Darkstalkers series,but I already drew myself as a wolf monster.So my second choice is Haomaru from the Samurai Shodown/Samurai Spirits series. <br /><strong>9)</strong> Yup,that's me.I'm not tagging anyone in particular so anyone can do the meme if wanting to.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e636dea5740c7d7b6ea2339aa80aeb" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/136083.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001qeh44" alt="Pac-Man" height="730" width="460" border="0" /><br />(brush...but also enough computer stuff to say it's practically an all-digital illo)</div><br /><br />Here's a brand new picture for the <a href="http://ilustrandoqueesgerundio.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">Ilustrando Que Es Gerundio</a> blog.The chosen theme was Classic Arcade Games.<br />With Pac-man I have kind of a love-hate thing.I've always liked the graphic design of the game and the general concept of a character chased by ghosts in a dark maze.But I don't like playing the game...blame it on the fact that I've never reached the 3rd stage.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="13c193daef599570aa0007ec20e5898c" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/136300.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001qge07" alt="Silver Surfer &amp; Ghost Rider" height="685" width="460" border="0" /><br />(brush & digital stuff —Ghost Rider & Silver Surfer ™ & © Marvel Characters,Inc.)</div><br /><br />Have you heard this tune titled 'Silver Surfer,Ghost Rider Go!' by Trentemøller? It's good.Here,go ahead and listen (<a href="http://www.fileden.com/files/2009/2/11/2316276//SilverSurferGhostRiderGo.mp3" target="_blank">direct link here</a> for those reading via RSS):<br /><lj-embed id="53" /><br />It's great how it sounds like part surf rock,part modern electronic music and part something out from the soundtrack of an action movie.It fits both characters.<br />Oddly,as far as I can remember there has never been a team-up between Ghost Rider and Silver Surfer.Somebody really should do that comic book...just look at it:one is a ghost in flames,the other is a silvery alien —<em>They Fight Crime!</em>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1e86a871934ee23ea022c952faeb041e" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/136493.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001qk6gd" alt="The Joker" height="600" width="350" border="0" /><br />(water brush)</div><br />In the comic books,Bruce Wayne choose to use a bat costume to scare criminals up.But if he truly wanted to become a fearful creature he should have used a clown costume instead,as the Joker clearly demonstrates.On the other hand,the most creepy thing about him is that he's actually not using a costume.No wonder then why he became one of the most popular supervillains ever.And in case you were wondering,no,I didn't like the Ledger version —looked way too much like Beetlejuice and behaved more like a psycho rather a sociopath.But I suppose that's just personal preferences.<br /><br />Anyways,this pic was made for <a href="http://corneredblog.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">Cornered</a>,a blog dedicated to showcase reinterpretations of corner art used in comic books.As usual whenever I participate in this kind of blog projects,what you see here is the lineart —<a href="http://corneredblog.blogspot.com/2011/01/uriel-duran-corners-joker.html" target="_blank">the final,colored illo is alrready posted there</a>.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c77d9ed44641f9235de0a492ca08f32a" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/136848.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001qqsdt" alt="Glad To See You" height="450" width="600" border="0" /><br />(paperless image)</div><br />A new experiment of illustration based upon a real model (need the practice cause I still suck at likeness,y'know).<br />Depicted here is the gal known as GladToSeeYou,and she's the creative curator behind <a href="http://gladtoseeyou.tumblr.com/" target="_blank">Yeah I'm Afraid Of Sharks But Not The Dark</a>.It's a swell Tumblr blog featuring classic cinema,vintage fashion and a little inspiring randomness to spice things up.Really,you should go visit —you won't regret it.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="cccfbcab3cf8263ba6efe280ce9331f0" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/137010.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r0x91" alt="Pink Panther" height="680" width="450" border="0" /><br />(technical pen & digital stuff)</div><br />This started as a phone doodle —I'm not sure but I think I was talking with a cousin about sushi bars.While scanning it,suddenly I thought about coloring it in pink.And so it became some sort of a Pink Panther tribute...not the cartoon character exactly but the abstract idea behind Blake Edward's movie.Or something like that.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="77dca4127a7baf49a8ce60c1f7bfe182" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/137375.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r1fwa" alt="Perhapanauts" height="547" width="550" border="0" /><br />(technical pen & brush —The Perhapanauts © Todd Dezago & Craig Rousseau)</div><br />Over at the <a href="http://blog.perhapanauts.com/" target="_blank">Perhapablog</a> Todd Dezago had the idea of doing an art challenge.The concept was recreating classic comic book covers featuring the characters from the Perhapanauts series.And yup,you guessed right,I had to draw something.So I made a version of Amazing Spider-man Annual #21 (best known as the now out of continuity wedding issue).<br />Posted here is the lineart —the final colored image is <a href="http://blog.perhapanauts.com/2011/02/pc4-uriel-duran.html" target="_blank">already posted over there</a>.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="21898f10cc397b076f6e02753c234448" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/137613.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r2811" alt="Rabbit Year" height="680" width="450" border="0" /><br />(technical pen,brush and digital stuff)</div><br />????!<br />Happy New Year! It's the 1st day of the tiger month on Chinese calendar so that means it's year 4708,the year of the White (Metal) Rabbit (or cat,if you're in Vietnam).<br /><br />Chinese folklore describe rabbit as related to yin forces.A gentle,affectionate and shy creature,the rabbit has no conflicts with any other animals —except the chicken.As everyone knows,rabbits are good at multiplying and so rabbit years are described as very fertile ones.However,they don't bring huge prosperity at all because rabbits are more on the gentle and silent side of things (in luck matters,basically it means that most everyone should expect to have the same luck they had the previous year).The main characteristic of rabbit years is that they're peaceful and so they're best for relaxing and getting in touch with family,friends and inner nature.<br /><br />Hope that this year of the rabbit brings you some good fortune and prosperity!
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4f11c86e10f5baccc9e4f0e2eb33902" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/137907.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r4a0t.jpg" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /><br />(brush & digital stuff —Automan © 20th Century Fox Film Corporation)</div><br />I wasn't looking forward to Tron Legacy,since the original movie actually made me asleep when I was younger and cuter.While watching the movie I kept thinking that The Matrix was a better sequel/remake/whatever if you think about worlds inside computers.Then I also remembered that Tron already had another unofficial sequel using costumes with bright lights and more action:<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automan" target="_blank">Automan</a>.Now,if something needs a remake/sequel/whatever,that TV series is.I mean,that series was okay for its time but no one can deny that it was poor executed in many aspects so there's a good reason to make it all over again and make it right this time —hey,isn't that supposed to be the point of remakes after all?<br /><br />Anyway,I felt in the mood of redesigning Automan so here it is &uarr;<br />But what's Automan without a suit made of an animated texture? Fortunately,current HTML & CSS technology can be used for that —behind the cut,there're some experiments I made:<br /><a name="cutid1"></a><div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img style="background:url(&#39;http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r7p37.gif&#39;) #ffffff; margin:0 auto 20px" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r63s0.gif" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /><br /><img style="background:url(&#39;http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r82tp.gif&#39;) #ffffff; margin:0 auto 20px" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r550h.png" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /><br /><img style="background:url(&#39;http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r9xxk.gif&#39;) #ffffff; margin:0 auto 20px" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r63s0.gif" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /><br /><img style="background:url(&#39;http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001ra10q.gif&#39;) #ffffff; margin:0 auto 20px" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r63s0.gif" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /><br /><img style="background:url(&#39;http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001rbdaa.gif&#39;) #ffffff; margin:0 auto 20px" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r550h.png" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /><br /><img style="background:url(&#39;http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001rcy6b.gif&#39;) #ffffff; margin:0 auto 20px" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r550h.png" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /><br /><img style="background:url(&#39;http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001rdhe0.gif&#39;) #ffffff; margin:0 auto 20px" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r550h.png" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /><br /><img style="background:url(&#39;http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001reyp1.gif&#39;) #000; margin:0 auto 20px" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r63s0.gif" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /><br /><img style="background:#fff; margin:0 auto 20px" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r550h.png" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /></div><a name='cutid1-end'></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="51736e73a7ad58a54730cd055272ccc5" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/138126.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001rh75z" alt="The Quick Brown Fox Jumps Over The Lazy Dog" height="610" width="401" border="0" /><br />(brush pen and digital post-production)</div><br /><div><p class="equisup"><strong class="omega">ENGLISH.- </strong><span class="english">Guess what? Because I needed a digital font with accents and special characters,I took my handwriting and created a font with it.<br />Now,I thought that perhaps some others could also find it useful.And there's the additional fact that in the last years I've been using lots of freeware and free content from the web.So those are more than good reasons for sharing and giving away the font for free.<br /><br />Yeah,free.Gratis.No cost and all freedom to use it.<br /><br />It's my first atempt at creating fonts and my handwriting is perhaps a bit imperfect to begin with but hey,if you like it,go ahead,download it and have fun.And if you do find it useful,don't forget to let me know so I'll know if I should keep creating fonts or not.<br /><br /><a href="http://www.garabatorama.com/goodies/Lo-Fi_Font.zip" target="_blank">Right-click and download it right here.</a></span></p><p class="zetaup"><strong class="omega">ESPAÑOL.- </strong>Adivina qué.Dado que necesitaba una fuente tipográfica con acentos y signos especiales,agarré mi letra a mano e hice una fuente digital con la misma.<br />Ahora bien,se me ocurrió que quizás alguien más podría también encontrarla útil.Añadámosle el hecho de que en los últimos años he estado usando montones de freeware y contenidos gratuitos en la web..Así que esas son razones más que buenas para compartir y ofrecer la fuente de modo gratuito.<br /><br />Sí,gratis.De a grapa.Sin costo y con toda libertad de uso.<br /><br />Es mi primer intento creando fuentes y mi letra a mano es de antemano un poco imperfecta por principio de cuentas pero,vale pues,si te gusta,adelante,descárgala y diviértete.Y si te resulta de utilidad no olvides hacérmelo saber para ver si me animo a seguir o no creando fuentes.<br /><br /><a href="http://www.garabatorama.com/goodies/Lo-Fi_Font.zip" target="_blank">Dale click derecho y descárgale justo aquí.</a> </p><div style="height:1px; clear:both"></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="43d683207f163e49c3d1eaf6fdb9a755" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/138421.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001rreqd" alt="El Naco Asesino" height="255" width="400" border="0" /><br />(brush & technical pen)</div><br />It all began with a game of Dungeons & Dragons...it was rather boring so no one was into character and more into poking fun at each other.A friend was playing as a knight with a magic sword but was acting more like a maniac killer from an 80s' slasher film.Carlo Angie,another friend,started calling him 'El naco asesino y su machete sagrado' (The killing naco and his sacred machete).It sounded really funny and then someone said 'What if El Naco Asesino was a genuine comic book character?'<br />And so El Naco Asesino (with his loyal sidekick Macuarrito) was born.But instead of a psycho knight he became a Mexican vigilante.More exactly,the Mexican parody version of Batman —and Daredevil and Azrael and The Punisher and Conan The Barbarian.Carlo Angie wrote some ideas and I drew them.Nothing big,there were only a few pages and gags that made it into Xerox fanzines and that was all.<br /><br />Unfortunately,Carlo Angie died some years ago.But I'm still alive so that means that El Naco Asesino can also still be alive —as far as a fictional character can be,of course.And posted here,is an updated version of the origin story —or at least the short version because the full origin includes the moment when a gas container landed on El Naco's head,and then he went to Catemaco to retrieve his sacred machete from the hands of a mad nuclear scientist (hey,I said it was a parody version!)<br /><br /><a name="cutid1"></a><div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001rswwc" alt="El Naco Asesino 01" height="850" width="550" border="0" /><br /><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001rthh8" alt="El Naco Asesino 02" height="850" width="550" border="0" /></div><a name='cutid1-end'></a><br />PS.-In case you're wondering what the heck is a <em>naco</em> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Naco_%28slang%29" target="_blank">you can look that up on wikipedia</a>.Still,the naco concept on Mexican culture is much more complex and hard to explain because in the end,all and every Mexican is a little <em>naco</em> on the inside.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="21421e2d2c8aa3c28eafef71e1407de1" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/138998.html"><![CDATA[&darr; A few days ago this photo of Spider-man riding an ostrich showed up on Tumblr's Radar.<br /><div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001s0x40" alt="Spider-man &amp; ostrich" height="470" width="300" border="0" /></div><br />This is the kind of things that current comic books are always missing —the fun of being a superhero and being able to do everything and whatever in a literally way.Anyway,since Peter Parker has never had a pet (I think he had a puppy on the Sunday newspaper strips but I'm not very sure) it's cool that his first one could be an ostrich.I mean,he already fights regularly a Rhino,a Lizard,a Vulture,a hunter dressed as a lion and a scientist with octupus arms,so trust me,an ostrich fits perfectly.<br /><br />Because the idea is simply great I had to make my own version:<br /><div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001rzbhg" alt="Spider-man &amp; Spider-ostrich" height="592" width="500" border="0" /><br />(water brush,technical pen and digital stuff —Spider-man ™ & © Marvel Characters Inc.)</div><br /><br /><a name="cutid1"></a><div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001s11tr" alt="Amazing Spider-man cover" height="658" width="430" border="0" /><br />(same as above plus even more digital stuff)</div><a name='cutid1-end'></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3cdece8a8112f48a839cd54cfa69489f" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/139062.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001s8cy1" alt="Little Red Riding Hood - Untold Ending" height="738" width="500" border="0" /><br />(pen,marker & digital stuff)</div><br />This illo was made specially for <a href="http://redproject.tumblr.com/post/3748041055/this-is-post-3-000-and-still-counting-indeed" target="_blank">the 3,000 post of The Red Project</a> —you know,my silly Tumblr blog where I keep collecting and curating things about Little Red Riding Hood.<br />Honestly,I never imagined to reach that number.Wonder if it's time I need a new hobby to distract me from this other hobby or something.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="debb1ad0dcfd40a0fa92cd80c04f217" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/139499.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001sbbdw" alt="Lil&#39; something" height="580" width="450" border="0" /><br />(paperless image)</div><br />Today I should have been typing some articles due this Tuesday.<br />And maybe eating something.<br />Instead of that,I kept iTunes playing non-stop while experimenting with some Photoshop™ brushes.Yeah,a man has to have his priorities,y'know.<br />Anyways,while doing that I found a minute or two for doing this image you see.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="948d2ca6bd01334460076cbd458d545f" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/139619.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><a name="cutid1"></a><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001sebwe" alt="Ari Dee &amp; Ponylegs" height="750" width="440" border="0" /><a name='cutid1-end'></a><br />(pen,brushpen & digital stuff)</div><br />I'm guessing some of you were expecting this:a new illustration based upon the lovely Miss Ponylegs (go visit her at <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/seizure_chavez/" target="_blank">Flickr</a>,<a href="http://ponyrides.tumblr.com" target="_blank">Tumblr</a> and <a href="http://www.godsgirls.com/girls/Pony" target="_blank">Godsgirls.com</a> —NSFW links).But this time she's not alone because along with her is the not less charming Miss Ari Dee,whom also kindly allowed me to use her likeness (she's available on <a href="http://thearidee.tumblr.com/" target="_blank">Tumblr</a> and <a href="http://www.godsgirls.com/members/ari" target="_blank">Godsgirls</a> —NSFW links,too).<br /><br />About this illo I felt a bit more confident with these portrait experiments but also thought I still can achieve more.So yup,it's a safe bet I'll keep doing them in the future whenever I find time for that.We shall see then.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="519cc9d4262e2652ac4c4a8ab82d0748" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/139971.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001sse5a" alt="Sinforoso Bigfoot" height="550" width="500" border="0" /><br />(water brush & digital stuff)</div><br /><strong>Hometown:</strong> Saskatchewan<br /><strong>Likes: </strong>Slim Whitman's music,vintage Western movies,Tex-mex food<br /><strong>Dis-likes: </strong>Tourists,people that don't believe in his existence and think that he's a gorilla<br /><strong>Super Powers: </strong>He can ride a horse,pet a dog and hold his breath underwater<br /><strong>Personality: </strong>Really loud and very kind.Sometimes he can get angry quickly but he's also quick at forgetting and forgiving.<br />PS.-The middle 'S' stands for Sasquatch,of course
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d624938fc54278e2789acf1d5a85584e" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/140075.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001sxc2t" alt="Dinosaur" height="427" width="600" border="0" /><br />(paperless image)</div><br />It's been quite a while since I posted any dinosaurs around here so here's this one.<br />Don't ask me about what species it is supposed to be though,because I drew it in between lunch and some chores and couldn't use any of my reference books.However,It does look like a weird hybrid of ceratosaurus,allosaurus,gorgosaurus and some other feathered theropod (yeah,I know,I'm such a nerd in this topic).If necessary,I'll simply call him Heathcliff.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="952e19266f0723e0cac3e42c38e9a73" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/140387.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001sz4zg" alt="Marvin The Martian" height="475" width="600" border="0" /><br />(brushpen & digital stuff —Marvin The Martian ™ & © Warner Bros. Entertainment Inc.)</div><br />Back when I was growing up with the TV as my babysitter,I thought that Marvin The Martian was a little kid.Mostly because he was short,had a childish voice in the old Spanish dubbings,and he wore some cool sneakers.It was a bit shocking finding out that he was an adult all along.<br />So let this pic be an image of a hopeful future where Marvin does grow up and becomes a badass space invader —with cool shoes,of course.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="275aae2619802d124777728a4a243cfd" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/140883.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001t3dz2" alt="Daredevil" height="810" width="300" border="0" /><br />(brushpen & digital stuff —Daredevil ™ & © Marvel Characters, Inc.)</div><br />What you see is something I made for the <a href="http://corneredblog.blogspot.com" target="_blank">Cornered blog</a> (<span  class="ljuser  i-ljuser     "  lj:user="corneredfeed" ><a href="http://corneredfeed.livejournal.com/profile"  class="i-ljuser-profile" ><img  class="i-ljuser-userhead"  src="http://l-stat.livejournal.com/img/syndicated.gif?v=6283?v=111.1" /></a><a href="http://corneredfeed.livejournal.com/" class="i-ljuser-username"    ><b>corneredfeed</b></a></span>).<br />I really don't have much else to say about these besides the fact that it's amazing how animated gifs can be used to create unique images that make the web stand out as an original canvas rather than simply something to replicate what is already made on printed forms.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5d9c611b98b2b88feb27852e0cda3984" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/141173.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001t610b/s640x480" alt="Popeye and Bluto" height="500" width="600" border="0" /><br />(brushpen & digital stuff —Popeye & Bluto © & ™ King Features Syndicate Inc.)</div><br /><br />A true warrior never gives up and just keeps up fighting.But then come those times when,you know,you simply don't know what to do.Because the opponent in front of you doesn't have a face you can punch at.<br />These last days have been a bit hard for me.I urgently needed some distraction (i.e. some face to punch...nothing serious or dramatic,folks,honest —just something to remind me about what I am,what I do and why I don't give up).<br />Since I couldn't think about anything better I came up with this image of Popeye fighting Bluto.Not sure if that says something,besides the known fact that I'm a Popeye fan (yeah,I know,I'm a fan of way too many things...but hey,<em>I yam what I yam and that's all what I yam</em>).
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8be6b1cd1cd2495a5478c81841f587c0" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/141486.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001t93z0" alt="Sgt. Fury - Jack Kirby" height="840" width="550" border="0" /><br />(water brush & digital stuff —Nick Fury ™ & © Marvel Characters, Inc.)</div><br />The other day over at the <a href="http://kirbymuseum.org/blogs/dynamics" target="_blank">Kirby Dynamics</a> blog there was posted a <a href="http://kirbymuseum.org/blogs/dynamics/2011/04/20/sgt-fury-commission-pencils/" target="_blank">hi-res image of a pencil commission piece by the King Kirby</a>.And so I went ahead and inked it but that wasn't enough and I also colored it —<a href="http://kirbymuseum.org/blogs/dynamics/2011/05/04/sgt-fury-inks-by-u/" target="_blank">the inks without color</a> can be seen at Kirby Dynamics.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ff678a68208a879d83ec12591d0101" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/141992.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001ta236" alt="Death" height="780" width="550" border="0" /><br />(paperless image —Death ™ & © DC Comics Inc.)</div><br />I made these digital doodles all through this week in between meals and works.Yeah,I know,it's weird the way I don't settle in one single style but what the hey,creativity is supposed to be about experimenting all time and exploring multiple choices,ain't it? <br />Then again,perhaps some might say that it's more like that I'm a schizo with multiple personalities.<br />Anyways,I thought it'd be interesting showing the whacky different ways I visualize the friendliest character from Neil Gaiman's <em>magnum opus</em>.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b7e2e808558c545cf11ab94f2268499b" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/135255.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001q6wf9" alt="2011" height="600" width="500" border="0" /><br />(water brush,pen & digital stuff)</div><br />This Winter seems like a lot of people isn't very happy that a new year is starting.In fact,looks like they're mostly happy that 2010 is over.Guess it was a rough year for them.Me,you ask? It was a good,quite productive and inspiring year...actually,I wish it didn't finish so soon as I haven't finished lots of things and projects yet.Then again,I suppose that's what 2011 is here for,since time is always relative.And just for making things more exciting,this happens to be the first year of a whole decade.<br /><br />Now,today is also the LJversary of this corner of the web.It was 7 years ago when I began posting here.It's also been 7 years of discovering and meeting some of the most great people on the internets.That's a good enough reason for celebrating this day,so if you're reading this don't stop and go ahead.You're part of it —and by the way,THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR THAT!<br /><br />Okay now,Are you ready to show 2011 that dreams do become true? Come along,the fun it's only beggining! (if you don't believe me,just listen to Kate Micucci's words and music):<br /><lj-embed id="51" /><br /><br />Have a Most Epic & Excellent <s>Year</s> Decade!
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="60cef739c700c879fabf4cd9576ba844" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/135665.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001q7831" alt="Man&#39;s Life" height="645" width="500" border="0" /><br />(marker & some digital retouching)</div><br />What you see here is the lineart of a recreation of the cover of Man's Life,a pulp magazine.It was made for <a href="http://repulped.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">RePulped</a> (<span  class="ljuser  i-ljuser     "  lj:user="repulpedfeed" ><a href="http://repulpedfeed.livejournal.com/profile"  class="i-ljuser-profile" ><img  class="i-ljuser-userhead"  src="http://l-stat.livejournal.com/img/syndicated.gif?v=6283?v=111.1" /></a><a href="http://repulpedfeed.livejournal.com/" class="i-ljuser-username"    ><b>repulpedfeed</b></a></span>),a new blog about new versions of old pulp covers.<a href="http://repulped.blogspot.com/2011/01/u-aka-uriel-duran-repulps-mans-life-may.html" target="_blank">The final image is already posted there</a> along with the original cover.<br />There's not much else to say,except that sure this kind of image brings a new point of view to the Super Mario games and their plot based upon the eternal struggle between men and turtles.Or something like that.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b23e001805a211821b36ac5458e6e20c" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/135793.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001qcqhy" alt="Doodle Yourself As..." height="700" width="500" border="0" /><br />(pen,marker & digital color)</div><br />I stumbled upon this meme on Tumblr (via <a href="http://littlemisspaintbrush.tumblr.com/post/1121026258/doodle-yourself-as-meme" target="_blank">LittleMissPaintbrush</a>) and looked like fun.<br /><strong>1)</strong> I'm a bit predictable with this,but if I were a monster I'd be the Big Bad Wolf in fairy tales and viking legends<br /><strong>2)</strong> Still predictable.But I must say that I find fascinating how cocoa beans are actually very sour yet they become very sweet when transformed into chocolate.<br /><strong>3)</strong> Okay,if I were a woman very probably I'd look like MTV's Daria.But I'd also wear a Vampira/Morticia/Elvira dress at least once per week.<br /><strong>4)</strong> It's no secret I'd love to be Superman,but I think Madman is closer to my lifestyle<br /><strong>5)</strong> I choose Robocop only because I woke up with the movie theme stuck on my head<br /><strong>6)</strong> Don't ask!<br /><strong>7)</strong> Sharks may be powerful and dolphins may be the smart ones,but everybody knows sea turtles are actually the awesomest aquatic lifeforms,right? Plus,if you saw Finding Nemo,you know they behave like surfers so that's extra coolness points. <br /><strong>8)</strong> My favorite game is the Darkstalkers series,but I already drew myself as a wolf monster.So my second choice is Haomaru from the Samurai Shodown/Samurai Spirits series. <br /><strong>9)</strong> Yup,that's me.I'm not tagging anyone in particular so anyone can do the meme if wanting to.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e636dea5740c7d7b6ea2339aa80aeb" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/136083.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001qeh44" alt="Pac-Man" height="730" width="460" border="0" /><br />(brush...but also enough computer stuff to say it's practically an all-digital illo)</div><br /><br />Here's a brand new picture for the <a href="http://ilustrandoqueesgerundio.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">Ilustrando Que Es Gerundio</a> blog.The chosen theme was Classic Arcade Games.<br />With Pac-man I have kind of a love-hate thing.I've always liked the graphic design of the game and the general concept of a character chased by ghosts in a dark maze.But I don't like playing the game...blame it on the fact that I've never reached the 3rd stage.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="13c193daef599570aa0007ec20e5898c" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/136300.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001qge07" alt="Silver Surfer &amp; Ghost Rider" height="685" width="460" border="0" /><br />(brush & digital stuff —Ghost Rider & Silver Surfer ™ & © Marvel Characters,Inc.)</div><br /><br />Have you heard this tune titled 'Silver Surfer,Ghost Rider Go!' by Trentemøller? It's good.Here,go ahead and listen (<a href="http://www.fileden.com/files/2009/2/11/2316276//SilverSurferGhostRiderGo.mp3" target="_blank">direct link here</a> for those reading via RSS):<br /><lj-embed id="53" /><br />It's great how it sounds like part surf rock,part modern electronic music and part something out from the soundtrack of an action movie.It fits both characters.<br />Oddly,as far as I can remember there has never been a team-up between Ghost Rider and Silver Surfer.Somebody really should do that comic book...just look at it:one is a ghost in flames,the other is a silvery alien —<em>They Fight Crime!</em>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1e86a871934ee23ea022c952faeb041e" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/136493.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001qk6gd" alt="The Joker" height="600" width="350" border="0" /><br />(water brush)</div><br />In the comic books,Bruce Wayne choose to use a bat costume to scare criminals up.But if he truly wanted to become a fearful creature he should have used a clown costume instead,as the Joker clearly demonstrates.On the other hand,the most creepy thing about him is that he's actually not using a costume.No wonder then why he became one of the most popular supervillains ever.And in case you were wondering,no,I didn't like the Ledger version —looked way too much like Beetlejuice and behaved more like a psycho rather a sociopath.But I suppose that's just personal preferences.<br /><br />Anyways,this pic was made for <a href="http://corneredblog.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">Cornered</a>,a blog dedicated to showcase reinterpretations of corner art used in comic books.As usual whenever I participate in this kind of blog projects,what you see here is the lineart —<a href="http://corneredblog.blogspot.com/2011/01/uriel-duran-corners-joker.html" target="_blank">the final,colored illo is alrready posted there</a>.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c77d9ed44641f9235de0a492ca08f32a" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/136848.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001qqsdt" alt="Glad To See You" height="450" width="600" border="0" /><br />(paperless image)</div><br />A new experiment of illustration based upon a real model (need the practice cause I still suck at likeness,y'know).<br />Depicted here is the gal known as GladToSeeYou,and she's the creative curator behind <a href="http://gladtoseeyou.tumblr.com/" target="_blank">Yeah I'm Afraid Of Sharks But Not The Dark</a>.It's a swell Tumblr blog featuring classic cinema,vintage fashion and a little inspiring randomness to spice things up.Really,you should go visit —you won't regret it.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="cccfbcab3cf8263ba6efe280ce9331f0" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/137010.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r0x91" alt="Pink Panther" height="680" width="450" border="0" /><br />(technical pen & digital stuff)</div><br />This started as a phone doodle —I'm not sure but I think I was talking with a cousin about sushi bars.While scanning it,suddenly I thought about coloring it in pink.And so it became some sort of a Pink Panther tribute...not the cartoon character exactly but the abstract idea behind Blake Edward's movie.Or something like that.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="77dca4127a7baf49a8ce60c1f7bfe182" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/137375.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r1fwa" alt="Perhapanauts" height="547" width="550" border="0" /><br />(technical pen & brush —The Perhapanauts © Todd Dezago & Craig Rousseau)</div><br />Over at the <a href="http://blog.perhapanauts.com/" target="_blank">Perhapablog</a> Todd Dezago had the idea of doing an art challenge.The concept was recreating classic comic book covers featuring the characters from the Perhapanauts series.And yup,you guessed right,I had to draw something.So I made a version of Amazing Spider-man Annual #21 (best known as the now out of continuity wedding issue).<br />Posted here is the lineart —the final colored image is <a href="http://blog.perhapanauts.com/2011/02/pc4-uriel-duran.html" target="_blank">already posted over there</a>.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="21898f10cc397b076f6e02753c234448" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/137613.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r2811" alt="Rabbit Year" height="680" width="450" border="0" /><br />(technical pen,brush and digital stuff)</div><br />????!<br />Happy New Year! It's the 1st day of the tiger month on Chinese calendar so that means it's year 4708,the year of the White (Metal) Rabbit (or cat,if you're in Vietnam).<br /><br />Chinese folklore describe rabbit as related to yin forces.A gentle,affectionate and shy creature,the rabbit has no conflicts with any other animals —except the chicken.As everyone knows,rabbits are good at multiplying and so rabbit years are described as very fertile ones.However,they don't bring huge prosperity at all because rabbits are more on the gentle and silent side of things (in luck matters,basically it means that most everyone should expect to have the same luck they had the previous year).The main characteristic of rabbit years is that they're peaceful and so they're best for relaxing and getting in touch with family,friends and inner nature.<br /><br />Hope that this year of the rabbit brings you some good fortune and prosperity!
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4f11c86e10f5baccc9e4f0e2eb33902" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/137907.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r4a0t.jpg" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /><br />(brush & digital stuff —Automan © 20th Century Fox Film Corporation)</div><br />I wasn't looking forward to Tron Legacy,since the original movie actually made me asleep when I was younger and cuter.While watching the movie I kept thinking that The Matrix was a better sequel/remake/whatever if you think about worlds inside computers.Then I also remembered that Tron already had another unofficial sequel using costumes with bright lights and more action:<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automan" target="_blank">Automan</a>.Now,if something needs a remake/sequel/whatever,that TV series is.I mean,that series was okay for its time but no one can deny that it was poor executed in many aspects so there's a good reason to make it all over again and make it right this time —hey,isn't that supposed to be the point of remakes after all?<br /><br />Anyway,I felt in the mood of redesigning Automan so here it is &uarr;<br />But what's Automan without a suit made of an animated texture? Fortunately,current HTML & CSS technology can be used for that —behind the cut,there're some experiments I made:<br /><a name="cutid1"></a><div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img style="background:url(&#39;http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r7p37.gif&#39;) #ffffff; margin:0 auto 20px" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r63s0.gif" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /><br /><img style="background:url(&#39;http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r82tp.gif&#39;) #ffffff; margin:0 auto 20px" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r550h.png" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /><br /><img style="background:url(&#39;http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r9xxk.gif&#39;) #ffffff; margin:0 auto 20px" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r63s0.gif" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /><br /><img style="background:url(&#39;http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001ra10q.gif&#39;) #ffffff; margin:0 auto 20px" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r63s0.gif" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /><br /><img style="background:url(&#39;http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001rbdaa.gif&#39;) #ffffff; margin:0 auto 20px" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r550h.png" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /><br /><img style="background:url(&#39;http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001rcy6b.gif&#39;) #ffffff; margin:0 auto 20px" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r550h.png" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /><br /><img style="background:url(&#39;http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001rdhe0.gif&#39;) #ffffff; margin:0 auto 20px" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r550h.png" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /><br /><img style="background:url(&#39;http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001reyp1.gif&#39;) #000; margin:0 auto 20px" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r63s0.gif" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /><br /><img style="background:#fff; margin:0 auto 20px" src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001r550h.png" alt="Automan" height="740" width="450" border="0" /></div><a name='cutid1-end'></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="51736e73a7ad58a54730cd055272ccc5" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/138126.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001rh75z" alt="The Quick Brown Fox Jumps Over The Lazy Dog" height="610" width="401" border="0" /><br />(brush pen and digital post-production)</div><br /><div><p class="equisup"><strong class="omega">ENGLISH.- </strong><span class="english">Guess what? Because I needed a digital font with accents and special characters,I took my handwriting and created a font with it.<br />Now,I thought that perhaps some others could also find it useful.And there's the additional fact that in the last years I've been using lots of freeware and free content from the web.So those are more than good reasons for sharing and giving away the font for free.<br /><br />Yeah,free.Gratis.No cost and all freedom to use it.<br /><br />It's my first atempt at creating fonts and my handwriting is perhaps a bit imperfect to begin with but hey,if you like it,go ahead,download it and have fun.And if you do find it useful,don't forget to let me know so I'll know if I should keep creating fonts or not.<br /><br /><a href="http://www.garabatorama.com/goodies/Lo-Fi_Font.zip" target="_blank">Right-click and download it right here.</a></span></p><p class="zetaup"><strong class="omega">ESPAÑOL.- </strong>Adivina qué.Dado que necesitaba una fuente tipográfica con acentos y signos especiales,agarré mi letra a mano e hice una fuente digital con la misma.<br />Ahora bien,se me ocurrió que quizás alguien más podría también encontrarla útil.Añadámosle el hecho de que en los últimos años he estado usando montones de freeware y contenidos gratuitos en la web..Así que esas son razones más que buenas para compartir y ofrecer la fuente de modo gratuito.<br /><br />Sí,gratis.De a grapa.Sin costo y con toda libertad de uso.<br /><br />Es mi primer intento creando fuentes y mi letra a mano es de antemano un poco imperfecta por principio de cuentas pero,vale pues,si te gusta,adelante,descárgala y diviértete.Y si te resulta de utilidad no olvides hacérmelo saber para ver si me animo a seguir o no creando fuentes.<br /><br /><a href="http://www.garabatorama.com/goodies/Lo-Fi_Font.zip" target="_blank">Dale click derecho y descárgale justo aquí.</a> </p><div style="height:1px; clear:both"></div></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="43d683207f163e49c3d1eaf6fdb9a755" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/138421.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001rreqd" alt="El Naco Asesino" height="255" width="400" border="0" /><br />(brush & technical pen)</div><br />It all began with a game of Dungeons & Dragons...it was rather boring so no one was into character and more into poking fun at each other.A friend was playing as a knight with a magic sword but was acting more like a maniac killer from an 80s' slasher film.Carlo Angie,another friend,started calling him 'El naco asesino y su machete sagrado' (The killing naco and his sacred machete).It sounded really funny and then someone said 'What if El Naco Asesino was a genuine comic book character?'<br />And so El Naco Asesino (with his loyal sidekick Macuarrito) was born.But instead of a psycho knight he became a Mexican vigilante.More exactly,the Mexican parody version of Batman —and Daredevil and Azrael and The Punisher and Conan The Barbarian.Carlo Angie wrote some ideas and I drew them.Nothing big,there were only a few pages and gags that made it into Xerox fanzines and that was all.<br /><br />Unfortunately,Carlo Angie died some years ago.But I'm still alive so that means that El Naco Asesino can also still be alive —as far as a fictional character can be,of course.And posted here,is an updated version of the origin story —or at least the short version because the full origin includes the moment when a gas container landed on El Naco's head,and then he went to Catemaco to retrieve his sacred machete from the hands of a mad nuclear scientist (hey,I said it was a parody version!)<br /><br /><a name="cutid1"></a><div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001rswwc" alt="El Naco Asesino 01" height="850" width="550" border="0" /><br /><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001rthh8" alt="El Naco Asesino 02" height="850" width="550" border="0" /></div><a name='cutid1-end'></a><br />PS.-In case you're wondering what the heck is a <em>naco</em> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Naco_%28slang%29" target="_blank">you can look that up on wikipedia</a>.Still,the naco concept on Mexican culture is much more complex and hard to explain because in the end,all and every Mexican is a little <em>naco</em> on the inside.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="21421e2d2c8aa3c28eafef71e1407de1" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/138998.html"><![CDATA[&darr; A few days ago this photo of Spider-man riding an ostrich showed up on Tumblr's Radar.<br /><div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001s0x40" alt="Spider-man &amp; ostrich" height="470" width="300" border="0" /></div><br />This is the kind of things that current comic books are always missing —the fun of being a superhero and being able to do everything and whatever in a literally way.Anyway,since Peter Parker has never had a pet (I think he had a puppy on the Sunday newspaper strips but I'm not very sure) it's cool that his first one could be an ostrich.I mean,he already fights regularly a Rhino,a Lizard,a Vulture,a hunter dressed as a lion and a scientist with octupus arms,so trust me,an ostrich fits perfectly.<br /><br />Because the idea is simply great I had to make my own version:<br /><div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001rzbhg" alt="Spider-man &amp; Spider-ostrich" height="592" width="500" border="0" /><br />(water brush,technical pen and digital stuff —Spider-man ™ & © Marvel Characters Inc.)</div><br /><br /><a name="cutid1"></a><div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001s11tr" alt="Amazing Spider-man cover" height="658" width="430" border="0" /><br />(same as above plus even more digital stuff)</div><a name='cutid1-end'></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3cdece8a8112f48a839cd54cfa69489f" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/139062.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001s8cy1" alt="Little Red Riding Hood - Untold Ending" height="738" width="500" border="0" /><br />(pen,marker & digital stuff)</div><br />This illo was made specially for <a href="http://redproject.tumblr.com/post/3748041055/this-is-post-3-000-and-still-counting-indeed" target="_blank">the 3,000 post of The Red Project</a> —you know,my silly Tumblr blog where I keep collecting and curating things about Little Red Riding Hood.<br />Honestly,I never imagined to reach that number.Wonder if it's time I need a new hobby to distract me from this other hobby or something.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="debb1ad0dcfd40a0fa92cd80c04f217" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/139499.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001sbbdw" alt="Lil&#39; something" height="580" width="450" border="0" /><br />(paperless image)</div><br />Today I should have been typing some articles due this Tuesday.<br />And maybe eating something.<br />Instead of that,I kept iTunes playing non-stop while experimenting with some Photoshop™ brushes.Yeah,a man has to have his priorities,y'know.<br />Anyways,while doing that I found a minute or two for doing this image you see.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="948d2ca6bd01334460076cbd458d545f" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/139619.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><a name="cutid1"></a><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001sebwe" alt="Ari Dee &amp; Ponylegs" height="750" width="440" border="0" /><a name='cutid1-end'></a><br />(pen,brushpen & digital stuff)</div><br />I'm guessing some of you were expecting this:a new illustration based upon the lovely Miss Ponylegs (go visit her at <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/seizure_chavez/" target="_blank">Flickr</a>,<a href="http://ponyrides.tumblr.com" target="_blank">Tumblr</a> and <a href="http://www.godsgirls.com/girls/Pony" target="_blank">Godsgirls.com</a> —NSFW links).But this time she's not alone because along with her is the not less charming Miss Ari Dee,whom also kindly allowed me to use her likeness (she's available on <a href="http://thearidee.tumblr.com/" target="_blank">Tumblr</a> and <a href="http://www.godsgirls.com/members/ari" target="_blank">Godsgirls</a> —NSFW links,too).<br /><br />About this illo I felt a bit more confident with these portrait experiments but also thought I still can achieve more.So yup,it's a safe bet I'll keep doing them in the future whenever I find time for that.We shall see then.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="519cc9d4262e2652ac4c4a8ab82d0748" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/139971.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001sse5a" alt="Sinforoso Bigfoot" height="550" width="500" border="0" /><br />(water brush & digital stuff)</div><br /><strong>Hometown:</strong> Saskatchewan<br /><strong>Likes: </strong>Slim Whitman's music,vintage Western movies,Tex-mex food<br /><strong>Dis-likes: </strong>Tourists,people that don't believe in his existence and think that he's a gorilla<br /><strong>Super Powers: </strong>He can ride a horse,pet a dog and hold his breath underwater<br /><strong>Personality: </strong>Really loud and very kind.Sometimes he can get angry quickly but he's also quick at forgetting and forgiving.<br />PS.-The middle 'S' stands for Sasquatch,of course
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d624938fc54278e2789acf1d5a85584e" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/140075.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001sxc2t" alt="Dinosaur" height="427" width="600" border="0" /><br />(paperless image)</div><br />It's been quite a while since I posted any dinosaurs around here so here's this one.<br />Don't ask me about what species it is supposed to be though,because I drew it in between lunch and some chores and couldn't use any of my reference books.However,It does look like a weird hybrid of ceratosaurus,allosaurus,gorgosaurus and some other feathered theropod (yeah,I know,I'm such a nerd in this topic).If necessary,I'll simply call him Heathcliff.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="952e19266f0723e0cac3e42c38e9a73" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/140387.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001sz4zg" alt="Marvin The Martian" height="475" width="600" border="0" /><br />(brushpen & digital stuff —Marvin The Martian ™ & © Warner Bros. Entertainment Inc.)</div><br />Back when I was growing up with the TV as my babysitter,I thought that Marvin The Martian was a little kid.Mostly because he was short,had a childish voice in the old Spanish dubbings,and he wore some cool sneakers.It was a bit shocking finding out that he was an adult all along.<br />So let this pic be an image of a hopeful future where Marvin does grow up and becomes a badass space invader —with cool shoes,of course.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="275aae2619802d124777728a4a243cfd" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/140883.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001t3dz2" alt="Daredevil" height="810" width="300" border="0" /><br />(brushpen & digital stuff —Daredevil ™ & © Marvel Characters, Inc.)</div><br />What you see is something I made for the <a href="http://corneredblog.blogspot.com" target="_blank">Cornered blog</a> (<span  class="ljuser  i-ljuser     "  lj:user="corneredfeed" ><a href="http://corneredfeed.livejournal.com/profile"  class="i-ljuser-profile" ><img  class="i-ljuser-userhead"  src="http://l-stat.livejournal.com/img/syndicated.gif?v=6283?v=111.1" /></a><a href="http://corneredfeed.livejournal.com/" class="i-ljuser-username"    ><b>corneredfeed</b></a></span>).<br />I really don't have much else to say about these besides the fact that it's amazing how animated gifs can be used to create unique images that make the web stand out as an original canvas rather than simply something to replicate what is already made on printed forms.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5d9c611b98b2b88feb27852e0cda3984" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/141173.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001t610b/s640x480" alt="Popeye and Bluto" height="500" width="600" border="0" /><br />(brushpen & digital stuff —Popeye & Bluto © & ™ King Features Syndicate Inc.)</div><br /><br />A true warrior never gives up and just keeps up fighting.But then come those times when,you know,you simply don't know what to do.Because the opponent in front of you doesn't have a face you can punch at.<br />These last days have been a bit hard for me.I urgently needed some distraction (i.e. some face to punch...nothing serious or dramatic,folks,honest —just something to remind me about what I am,what I do and why I don't give up).<br />Since I couldn't think about anything better I came up with this image of Popeye fighting Bluto.Not sure if that says something,besides the known fact that I'm a Popeye fan (yeah,I know,I'm a fan of way too many things...but hey,<em>I yam what I yam and that's all what I yam</em>).
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8be6b1cd1cd2495a5478c81841f587c0" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/141486.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001t93z0" alt="Sgt. Fury - Jack Kirby" height="840" width="550" border="0" /><br />(water brush & digital stuff —Nick Fury ™ & © Marvel Characters, Inc.)</div><br />The other day over at the <a href="http://kirbymuseum.org/blogs/dynamics" target="_blank">Kirby Dynamics</a> blog there was posted a <a href="http://kirbymuseum.org/blogs/dynamics/2011/04/20/sgt-fury-commission-pencils/" target="_blank">hi-res image of a pencil commission piece by the King Kirby</a>.And so I went ahead and inked it but that wasn't enough and I also colored it —<a href="http://kirbymuseum.org/blogs/dynamics/2011/05/04/sgt-fury-inks-by-u/" target="_blank">the inks without color</a> can be seen at Kirby Dynamics.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ff678a68208a879d83ec12591d0101" url="http://everyueveryme.livejournal.com/141992.html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center; font-style:italic;"><img src="http://pics.livejournal.com/everyueveryme/pic/001ta236" alt="Death" height="780" width="550" border="0" /><br />(paperless image —Death ™ & © DC Comics Inc.)</div><br />I made these digital doodles all through this week in between meals and works.Yeah,I know,it's weird the way I don't settle in one single style but what the hey,creativity is supposed to be about experimenting all time and exploring multiple choices,ain't it? <br />Then again,perhaps some might say that it's more like that I'm a schizo with multiple personalities.<br />Anyways,I thought it'd be interesting showing the whacky different ways I visualize the friendliest character from Neil Gaiman's <em>magnum opus</em>.
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>