<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="angelooc.com">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="d3c760aa0be04701d72421a330a67431" url="http://angelooc.com/2013/01/02/with-a-little-help-from-my-apps/"><![CDATA[Happy New Year! It is offically 2013, the first year since 1987 where each number is unique. No doubt you&#8217;ve made some New Year resolutions or goals that you wish to get moving on this year. The toughest part about New Year resolutions is the follow-through. How do you keep yourself motivated throughout the year [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=angelooc.com&#038;blog=41702964&#038;post=353&#038;subd=angelooc&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a2dfe3fc7131abb3e45e418b1da541ae" url="http://angelooc.com/2013/01/04/buzzfeed-follows-led-zeppelins-path/"><![CDATA[I had an epiphany while listening to Led Zeppelin. Now, don’t ask me how the Internet came to my mind during a Led Zeppelin song, but it did. Being a bit of a rock and roll trivia nerd, I am well aware of Led Zeppelin’s liberal use of old blues songs and riffs in their music. In [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=angelooc.com&#038;blog=41702964&#038;post=358&#038;subd=angelooc&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="dfa390ac00a230bc3c7b6569dd5a991e" url="http://angelooc.com/2013/01/15/my-take-facebook-graph-search/"><![CDATA[Facebook today unveiled their latest project, Graph Search. The social network giant is looking to expand into the field of search, long dominated by Google. Graph search&#8217;s goal is to help you answer questions about people you know, people you may know, and people you don&#8217;t know but may be connected too. It&#8217;s best to [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=angelooc.com&#038;blog=41702964&#038;post=364&#038;subd=angelooc&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6118d3df5fe932a3917ae79c17952a" url="http://angelooc.com/2013/01/20/can-facebook-become-a-verb-for-search/"><![CDATA[This is a continuation of my thoughts from My Take: Facebook Graph Search One big hurdle that Facebook must overcome is changing the way the mainstream population thinks about Search. In fact, the mainstream population doesn&#8217;t think of &#8220;search&#8221;, they think of Google. Ask any of your non techie friends about &#8220;search&#8221; and I bet [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=angelooc.com&#038;blog=41702964&#038;post=368&#038;subd=angelooc&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="873ac51549f29c1d3225a8b25318ab74" url="http://angelooc.com/2013/01/26/sharing-unique-content/"><![CDATA[I want to comment on a blog post from on Doktor Spin why he&#8217;s not retweeting stories from tech news organizations like Mashable, TechCrunch, The Verge, etc. It&#8217;s not because he is dismissing the quality of their work, instead he wants to find other voices within the blogosphere that will add value. I definitley recommend [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=angelooc.com&#038;blog=41702964&#038;post=439&#038;subd=angelooc&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e2404d1ff24e528331d303a559aae55b" url="http://angelooc.com/2013/02/03/oreo-takes-advantage-of-super-bowl-blackout/"><![CDATA[Now this is great social media marketing in action! Oreo jumped on the power outage in the superdome during the Super Bowl.  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=angelooc.com&#038;blog=41702964&#038;post=446&#038;subd=angelooc&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2dc7cceddeb986ec490fee93f622ca87" url="http://angelooc.com/2013/03/29/best-80s-mashups/"><![CDATA[I&#8217;m a big fan of mashups, especially when they involve &#8217;80s songs. If you&#8217;re asking yourself: what is a mashup? Well, dictionary.com defines it best: a recording that combines vocal and instrumental tracks from two or more recordings. So I decided to find the ten best &#8217;80s mashups, in my opinion, of course. There are tons of great ones out there, so whittling it down to ten was [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=angelooc.com&#038;blog=41702964&#038;post=572&#038;subd=angelooc&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fa28230469f7f6af16fa7120698264dd" url="http://angelooc.com/2013/04/06/vintage-social-networking/"><![CDATA[Reblogged from Wrong Hands: This is a great picture that shows the different real world sources of inspiration for our major social networks.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=angelooc.com&#038;blog=41702964&#038;post=592&#038;subd=angelooc&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3345f204d523b284e9b8cca45776602e" url="http://angelooc.com/2013/05/01/twitter-music/"><![CDATA[As a music fan, few things in life rival the feeling of discovering an awesome new artist or an undeniably catchy song. Since the rise of broadband Internet and the explosion of digital music, there is more music available than at any point in history.  With so much music out there, where do you start? [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=angelooc.com&#038;blog=41702964&#038;post=654&#038;subd=angelooc&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="eb7eedd1e86abcd17178c8a83eaa3609" url="http://angelooc.com/2013/05/02/social-media-wish-list/"><![CDATA[As a social media power user, I always find myself wishing for certain features that would make my digital social life simpler. I&#8217;m not asking for anything complex or out of the ordinary.  Or at least I don&#8217;t think I am.  Here are  my top 5 items on my social media wish list. Let me know [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=angelooc.com&#038;blog=41702964&#038;post=657&#038;subd=angelooc&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>