<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="www.annieblogs.com">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="70c96c9cfedb9081662eca07eff6ddcd" url="http://www.annieblogs.com/2013/12/16/12-days-of-speak-love-day-8/"><![CDATA[On the eighth day of Speak Love, Zon-der-van gave to you, an autographed Speak Love, Speak Love Revolution, and a grey Speak Love t-shirt! . . . . . I&#8217;m having the best time with these giveaways. But seriously. THE BEST TIME. All you have to do to be entered to win this set of [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b2d8261143a6ec6fbcba3d7af5c56e48" url="http://www.annieblogs.com/2013/12/17/12-days-of-speak-love-day-9/"><![CDATA[. . . . . On the ninth day of Speak Love, Zon-der-van gave to you, an autographed Speak Love, Speak Love Revolution, and a pink Speak Love t-shirt! . . . . . All you have to do to be entered to win this set of books and a tshirt is leave a comment [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="cb874f2c731200b9b40d04a5de4e4ea2" url="http://www.annieblogs.com/2013/12/17/christmas-conundrum-and-ecards/"><![CDATA[Here&#8217;s my problem. I love Christmas cards. Like, I love them so much. I love snail mail. I love seeing beautiful pictures of my friends and family. I love the handwriting on the outside of the envelope. I love displaying them across the garland in my dining room. But I have yet to have the [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="16b7ccdc8aecd918e5278cd85d9e5a90" url="http://www.annieblogs.com/2013/12/18/12-days-of-speak-love-day-10/"><![CDATA[On the tenth day of Speak Love, Zon-der-van gave to you, an autographed Speak Love, and a Skype coffee date with MEEEEEEE! . . . . . So we&#8217;ll pretty much just make our own hot drinks and hop online and chat for a few minutes about whatever you want. Except fantasy football, I really [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5fec3d409fb3098e13b3f0689b410e5f" url="http://www.annieblogs.com/2013/12/19/12-days-of-speak-love-day-11/"><![CDATA[On the eleventh day of Speak Love, Zon-der-van gave to you, an autographed Speak Love, and a Girls of Grace CD! . . . . . All you have to do to be entered to win this book and Girls of Grace CD (that I love and listen to all the time) is leave a [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9b6b16cf93058d0f7817d85a933ba541" url="http://www.annieblogs.com/2013/12/20/12-days-of-speak-love-day-12/"><![CDATA[On the TWELTH day of Speak Love, Zon-der-van gave to you, an autographed Speak Love, an autographed Perfectly Unique, Speak Love Revolution, a Girls of Grace CD, a grey Speak Love tshirt, a white Speak Love tshirt, fancy notecards, a Speak Love necklace, AND A PAIR OF SPEAK LOVE EARRINGS! . . . . . [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b897837f2d2bbbced0a156f7d43c23e0" url="http://www.annieblogs.com/2013/12/30/13-highlights-of-2013/"><![CDATA[I find it necessary to recap my life at the end of every year. Or, close to at least. If you&#8217;ve got too much time on your hands, here is my 2007 recap and my 2008 recap. In 2009, I didn&#8217;t want to officially recap apparently, I barely survived the stress of 2010, and in [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7a7f07ea9212c83fe1703124c3ace9be" url="http://www.annieblogs.com/2013/12/31/happy-new-year-darlin/"><![CDATA[This great New Year song by Chris Rice is on repeat today at my house. Happy New Year, darlin&#8217;. May 2014 be more than you ever dreamed.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="44067ba4015d551a05b930f739326288" url="http://www.annieblogs.com/2014/01/06/what-is-2014-for-you/"><![CDATA[2014 came in like a lamb. Where in years past, we&#8217;ve dressed to the nines and danced until our feet were dirty and brown and exhausted, rolling home in the 1s or 2s after celebrating all night with friends, this year was different. We ordered pizza. We put together a puzzle of a New England [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7b4934f71f34499878ca5816fba127f" url="http://www.annieblogs.com/2014/01/08/what-i-learned-from-a-burst-pipe/"><![CDATA[It&#8217;s cold in Nashville. Like single digits cold and we do not know what to do with our lives except hole up and stay home and instagram pictures of a snowflake or a screenshot of the weather app saying &#8220;yes, world. It&#8217;s THIS COLD in Nashville.&#8221; I&#8217;m going to tell this story short and sweet: [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>