<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="perlani.typepad.com">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="2df181827e6faa5e65c6b7c7505fd99d" url="http://perlani.typepad.com/my_weblog/2006/05/its-been-four-a.html"><![CDATA[It’s been four and a half years, 12 issues, 7,000 subscribers and 21,000 newsletter recipients since I started the Stanford Social Innovation Review... and it’s time for me to move on. I’m pretty pleased with what we’ve been able to...
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6d9913384593332288974f6cdb3c837d" url="http://perlani.typepad.com/my_weblog/2006/07/socially-redeem.html"><![CDATA[I live in Palo Alto, in the heart of Silicon Valley and in the middle of this so called “social web” revolution where the new deities are MySpace and YouTube. These new social-networking technologies put the tools for sharing information...
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="68805b7716f0329c610b82914ae94c94" url="http://perlani.typepad.com/my_weblog/2006/11/startup-funding.html"><![CDATA[Everyone in the nonprofit world knows what a slow grind it is to get funding from foundations. It can take up to nine months. Since foundations are frequently compared to venture capital firms because they supposedly take risks, I hope...
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b6b68aba74d89e748c8f1e0c3ebafc7f" url="http://perlani.typepad.com/my_weblog/2006/12/our-global-wa-1.html"><![CDATA[Whenever I talk to human services nonprofits, I hear the same problem: “Our funding is being cut by the government and no one is giving us a check to fill in the gap.” One long-term ED lamented, “What will happen...
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4031e7061ed9c130a53a69a895856b8f" url="http://perlani.typepad.com/my_weblog/2007/01/behind-the-scen.html"><![CDATA[For the first time, a foundation director has revealed the inner workings of the grantmaking process. Candid, funny and painfully accurate at times, Thank You For Submitting Your Proposal, a new book by Martin Teitel, the executive eirector of the...
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="193f7c4e5885b8944840f9fe8c8d9939" url="http://perlani.typepad.com/my_weblog/2007/04/common-app-plea.html"><![CDATA[Raise your hands, my fellow EDs and development directors, if you are tired of writing 15 different grant applications to 15 different foundations. What ever happened to the common grant application form? Some grantmaking associations now have their own common...
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f1f8e9eb7abd8741806a0b88fc5b133c" url="http://perlani.typepad.com/my_weblog/2007/04/live-from-cof-h.html"><![CDATA["We literally had a fire door between the investing division and program division,” said Doug Stamm, executive director of the Meyer Memorial Trust, today at the Council of Foundations conference. “You had to walk the equivalent of four bowling lanes...
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="decd9702279272cc0e418a62b01b3426" url="http://perlani.typepad.com/my_weblog/2007/05/does-your-progr.html"><![CDATA[“I’ve randomly inserted pictures of my grandkids in my progress reports,” one executive director of a prominent mid-Atlantic nonprofit told me. “I’ve inserted lines like, ‘If you really read this, call me.’” He was bemoaning the fact that he’s forced...
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5e48c2987f7e96a46a95179c7a3cd543" url="http://perlani.typepad.com/my_weblog/2007/06/americas-least-.html"><![CDATA[It feels like Apple has been on the cover of every newspaper and magazine this month. People gush about how much they love their iPod and admire Steve Jobs and his company. Yet very few people ever talk about the...
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1d939314f771dae0690a912665355bb7" url="http://perlani.typepad.com/my_weblog/2007/08/nonprofits-shou.html"><![CDATA[I couldn’t agree more with Robert Egger’s call for nonprofits to challenge the prohibition of their involvement in politics. “The nonprofit world cannot allow the country’s future to be determined by a political process in which it has no role,”...
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>