<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com">
	<documents count="25">
		<document id="2e17c5eef59efc1bfa04582582f07093" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2011/08/how-much-protein-do-i-need.html"><![CDATA[
<br />What is protein? How much protein do we need? Is it possible to eat too much protein? These are important questions for people who want to lead a healthy lifestyle. Protein is a very important part of our diet and can benefit us greatly if we get the right amounts. 
<br /><strong>
<br /> What is protein?</strong>Protein is one of the basic building blocks of the human body, making up about 16 percent of our total body weight. Muscle, hair, skin, and connective tissue are mainly made up of protein. However, protein plays a major role in all our cells and most fluids in our bodies.
<br />
<br />Also many of our body’s important chemicals such as hormones, enzymes and neurotransmitters and even our DNA, are at least partially made up of protein. Although our bodies are good at “recycling” protein, we use up protein constantly, so it is important to replace it daily.
<br />
<br />Proteins are made up of smaller units called amino acids. Our bodies cannot produce nine of the amino acids, so it is essential to include all these amino acids in our diets. Animal proteins such as meat, eggs, and dairy products all have amino acids, and many plants have some of them. Proteins from corn, grains, beans and vegetables tend to be of lower quality. That is why vegetarians or vegans need to get their protein from a variety of sources.
<br /><strong>
<br />How much protein do we need?</strong>
<br />The standard method used by nutritionists to estimate our minimum daily protein requirement is to multiply the body weight in kilograms by .8 or weight in pounds by .37. This is the number of grams of protein that should be the daily minimum. According to this method, someone weighing 150 lbs. should eat 55 grams of protein per day, a 200-pound person should get 74 grams, and a 250-pound person should eat 92grams.
<br />
<br /><strong>Is it ok to eat more protein than recommended? </strong>In a review of the research, the National Academy of Sciences reported that the only known danger from high-protein diets is for individuals with kidney disease. After careful study, they recommend that 10 percent to 35 percent of daily calories come from protein. They point out that increased protein could be helpful in treating obesity. There is also accumulating evidence that extra protein may help prevent osteoporosis.
<br />In conclusion, protein is an essential part of your diet and consuming the right amounts can help increase energy, weight loss and possibly osteoporosis. Come find out more about eating healthy at my next Transition overviews: August 23rd, at 7pm at River Valley Church and August 31st at Liberty Christian Church. Please RSVP. 
<br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f01f861193a808aae248ca56bab58286" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2011/08/whats-holding-you-back-from-healthier.html"><![CDATA[There are many people who desperately want to lead a healthier lifestyle but are not sure how to get started or are afraid to try because they have failed before. They have tried several different diets, or they keep trying to do the same one, only to end up with the same results and are now even more discouraged. This is usually when they give up and figure their lot in life is to be overweight, and unhealthy. 
<br />So what is holding them back from seeking help and moving forward? Here are some of the reasons or excuses I have heard from people: 
<br />•	I don’t think I can do it
<br />•	It’s too hard
<br />•	I can’t afford it
<br />•	I don’t feel like it
<br />•	I don’t have the time
<br />
<br />We often do things based on feelings. If we don’t “feel” like it, we don’t do it, even when we know it’s healthier. If we can learn to focus on the consequences verses rewards of not doing something or doing something, then we are more apt to follow through.  For example, I don’t always feel like exercising, but I know it’s good for me and I will feel much better afterwards. This motivates me to exercise again, and I now love to do it!
<br />
<br />Many times we defeat ourselves before we even get started. We’ve already convinced ourselves we can’t do it so we don’t even try. Setting our mind is one of the most beneficial things you can do. To set your mind is to determine decisively what you will think, what you believe and what you will or will not do. Determine that you will become healthier no matter what it takes and don’t give up! 
<br />
<br />I have seen many of my clients succeed when they at first lacked the confidence to even try. Once they started they got more and more confidence, while getting encouragement and support from the group and coach, which lead to their success. This wouldn’t have happened if they wouldn’t have taken that step of faith. 
<br />I encourage you to take a step of faith and come to my next Transitions overview on August 23rd at River Valley Church in Martinsville. With faith nothing is impossible! 
<br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="902ad138302f088c65086a218a12361c" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2011/09/breaking-sugar-addiction.html"><![CDATA[Breaking free from a dependency on sugar is much easier said than done. There is an unhealthy abundance of sugar in the American diet. It’s hard to find foods in our stores that don’t add sugar, which is why so many of us are addicted to the sweet stuff and are suffering with several health problems. <br /><br /><br />Because the roots of sugar addiction are both physical and emotional, you need a combination of physical and psychological approaches. The less you eat sugar, the less you will crave it. If you get withdrawal symptoms, know they will only last a few days and then you'll feel more balanced and energetic than ever.<br /><br />Here are some tactics that may help you break your sugar addiction: <br /><br />• Keep sugary products out of your house. Eat enough healthy food to satisfy your hunger. Eat snacks like fruit, carrots, red pepper, cherry tomatoes, dates, and dried fruit to satisfy your sweet tooth. Drink plenty of water, too. Frozen fruit, whole or pureed, makes a delicious alternative to ice cream. Once you have cleansed your system, your taste buds will become more sensitive, and these whole natural foods will taste sweeter and more satisfying. <br /><br />• Eat three regular meals each day that combine complex carbohydrates (vegetables, whole grains, and fruits), lean protein (poultry, fish, meat, dairy, tofu) and healthy fats (omega-3's, olive oil and other cold-pressed oils). This will help you maintain a steady blood sugar level throughout the day and reduce your sugar cravings. Also, eat a diet high in fiber which will help reduce sugar cravings.<br /><br />• Take a multivitamin and mineral supplement. Chromium picolinate and l-glutamine can help reduce cravings for some people.<br /><br />• Get plenty of sleep, sunlight and exercise which can help reduce sugar cravings.<br /><br />• Learn to identify what’s causing your cravings. Many people turn to sugary foods when they are stressed, bored or tired. Instead, try exercising, meditating or doing something fun that you enjoy.<br /><br />• Be kind to yourself. To end the struggle with sugar, learn to nourish your body well and respond compassionately to your own feelings. <br /><br />In conclusion, addiction to sugar has lead to a variety of health problems such as obesity, hypertension, and heart problems to name a few. Overcoming sugar addiction is important if you plan to live a long, healthy life, and want your family to also. If you’re serious, contact me about my upcoming Transitions classes where you will learn how to beat the sugar addiction so it doesn’t beat you! <br /><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7e51d076dcbde42d9a949f3ae0d610d7" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2011/09/changing-inside-out.html"><![CDATA[I have been very impressed with one of my client’s lifestyle transition and how it’s not only changed her life but her two young girls as well. Not only has she changed her eating habits, she has been determined to break the obesity cycle and teach her children how to eat healthier, exercise and take care of themselves. <br /><br /><br />When I asked Margaret if it was ok to use her testimony, she was very excited because her passion is to help others overcome the obesity cycle and live life to the fullest.<br /><br />Here is what Margaret shared with me:<br /><br />I have lost 155 pounds and I have people ask me all of the time how I did it. Most assume that I had the stomach surgery; some think that I have discovered some magic potion that will help them too. The answer is not magic and it is not without change. Changing starts on the inside and then the outside starts to show the progress. It is a decision that you make with yourself and God to take care of your body. <br /><br />If I had a nickel for every time that someone said to me “I would do ANYTHING to lose this extra 10 lbs”, I would be rich. But when given the opportunity, you find that the statement “anything” has lots of strings attached. “I won’t eat vegetables” or “I can’t survive without my chocolate”. Before you know it, there isn’t much that most people will change. <br /><br />I died slowly for years convincing myself that my diet was “not so bad”. I had a major wakeup call that caused my thinking to change. I made the decision to start taking care of myself. I decided to love and nurture my body and get the most out of life. I started working with Coach Irene Greiner on Transitions Lifestyle this year because she had the tools that I needed. She works with a plan that helped me to understand what my body needs and what things I should avoid and why I should follow that pattern. Now I design what I put in my mouth to give myself the best nutrition possible and I feel wonderful today!<br /><br />I took my girls roller skating yesterday and I skated right along with them. My resting days are over. Someday when I am called home I hope that instead of saying “She just didn’t take care of herself”, they will say that I turned my family’s life around. I am so glad that I stopped giving excuses to cover my lifestyle and decided to transition to a new life entirely with much prayer and much dedication. <br /><br />Margaret has been an inspiration to so many because of her hard work, commitment and perseverance! I hope you also will be inspired to “Transition into a healthier lifestyle too!”<br /><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="138580db212573c4ecf644c17c9c6b34" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2011/09/have-you-taken-reality-check-on-your.html"><![CDATA[<br /><br />How many times have you told yourself it’s time for me to start eating healthier and exercising? So many people talk about making a change but when the reality sets in on how much work it is they give up. They prefer to keep living their lives just as they are, even though they feel tired, stressed and out of shape. <br /><br />These questions may help you make an honest reality check:<br /><br />1. Do you believe once you reach a certain size or weight, you’ll be happy? <br /><br />Have you said to yourself, “Once I reach a certain weight I’ll be happy.” If so, what happens if you never reach that goal weight? Are you therefore, never happy? Or, if you do reach that magical weight, but then realize this has nothing to do with your happiness. <br /><br />Many people don’t understand that the weight is only a symptom of the underlying problem. However, if you work on the true issue, you’ll be happier and much more likely to care for yourself so that your unhealthy lifestyle is no longer a concern. <br /><br />2. Do you look for a shortcut or an easier approach to achieve what you want? It takes dedication, commitment, and perseverance to accomplish what is worthwhile. Hard work is necessary to accomplish anything that is vitally significant in your life. First, you need to determine why you want to accomplish a healthier lifestyle. Don’t take the easy way out! Although, it’s tempting when hard work is involved, it will be worth the effort!<br /><br />3. Do you frequently use excuses to get yourself out of doing what it takes to achieve your goals? So many people just want to talk about making changes but when it comes down to doing the hard work, they prefer to offer excuses as to why they continue to live as they are. Don’t be a victim to your excuses! If you are making excuses you are not ready to make a serious change in your life.<br /><br />4. Do you consider giving up when you experience minor setbacks? <br /><br />Everyone experiences struggles, but don’t allow them to prevent you from pressing through. The best way to look at setbacks is to see them as challenges and a part of your progress. If you overcome them, and reach your goals despite of them, your ultimate sense of accomplishment will be much greater than if it was an effortless task.<br /><br />In conclusion, if you are living an unhealthy lifestyle, be honest with yourself about what you need to do to make changes. Don’t be afraid of making the commitment to change, and don’t just talk about it - do it! 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="109397956a1c607dddf28489616eba76" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2011/09/tackling-childhood-obesity.html"><![CDATA[<br /><br />Childhood obesity is a serious problem in the United States. Between 16 and 33 percent of children and adolescents are obese. The recent statistic in Indiana is 29.9 % of children are obese. Consequently, unhealthy weight gain can be contributed to lack of exercise and poor diet. Obesity often occurs in children due to overweight parents. Children who are obese usually become overweight adults - and the cycle continues!<br /><br />Changing family behaviors is crucial. Rather than singling out children the whole family must make healthy changes. Here are some helpful hints that can help:<br /><br />• Start small. Gradual changes are easiest to incorporate into your daily routine, and to maintain long term. Start by making a few small changes, such as turning off the TV during dinner, switching from soda to skim milk or water, snack healthy such as apples and peanut butter instead of chips and cookies. Take a family walk or bike ride after dinner once a week. Increase activity each week.<br /><br />• Set goals. Set realistic, measurable goals for each family member, and then establish family goals. For example, your child's goal might be to eat fruit for afternoon snacks. Your goal might be to take a brisk walk three days a week. The family's goal might be to limit fast-food meals to once a month.<br /><br />• Recognize triggers. Be prepared for situations that will tempt you to fall back into bad habits. If you're used to eating popcorn at the movies, only bring enough money for admission, or agree that you'll share a small carton of popcorn rather than ordering separate treats.<br /><br />• Celebrate accomplishment. Frequent rewards can help keep your family motivated. When your child meets a goal offer praise and attention instead of food rewards. When your family meets a goal, brainstorm healthy ways to celebrate your success. You might try a family movie night, a weekend picnic or a trip to a fun park. <br /><br />• Keep it positive. Focus on healthy lifestyle changes, rather than your child's appearance or a number on the scale. Remember, treating childhood obesity will take some time and dedication to replace bad habits with new, healthier behaviors.<br /><br />• Be Determined. It takes time to develop and maintain new healthy habits. Encourage everyone to not give up. Do your best as a parent to make it fun and educate on why it’s important to develop healthy habits now. <br /><br />Making lifestyle changes can be challenging, especially when you're busy juggling the demands of everyday life. If your family encourages and supports each other, then most likely you will beat the obesity cycle. Eventually healthy habits will become routine, and you'll be on your way to overcoming childhood obesity and improving your family's health.<br /><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a9e26333a066228f3890c82b596b71a5" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2011/10/maximize-your-workout-by-proper.html"><![CDATA[<br /><br />Eating properly, the right amounts at the right time will optimize your workouts by giving you the energy and nutrients your body craves. <br /><br />Here are some tips on eating and exercise to assist you in maximizing your workout:<br /><br />1. Eat Breakfast - If you exercise in the morning, get up early enough to eat breakfast, waiting 2-3 hours for a large meal or 1-2 for smaller meals. Most of the energy you got from dinner the previous night is used up by morning, and your blood sugar may be low. Eating a large amount before you exercise can leave you feeling sluggish, or worse, with a case of diarrhea or stomach cramps. Eating too little may not give you the energy to keep you feeling strong throughout your workout<br /><br />Here are some sample meals that provide protein to help build muscle: <br /><br />• Steal cut oatmeal with a few berries<br /><br />• 4 egg whites or 1 whole egg with some chopped veggies.<br /><br />• 1 whole wheat waffle with 1 tablespoon of natural almond or peanut butter <br /><br />• Protein, high fiber shake with berries or banana – 8oz<br /><br />2. Snack healthy – Most people can eat small snacks right before exercise but if eaten to soon before won’t give you added energy but it will help keep up your blood sugar.<br /><br />Good snack options:<br /><br />• Apple with peanut butter or almond butter<br /><br />• Low glycemic protein bar<br /><br />• Protein and fiber shake<br /><br />• Handful of almonds<br /><br />3. Eat after you exercise - To help your muscles recover and to replace their glycogen stores, eat a meal that contains both protein and carbohydrates within two hours of your exercise session if possible. If you aren't hungry after your workout, drink juice or a fruit smoothie to provide replenishing carbohydrates. <br /><br />Good post-workout food choices include: Almonds or walnuts, plain Greek yogurt with fruit, apple with peanut butter or string cheese, or regular meal consisting of lean meat, tofu and vegetables. <br /><br />• Drink plenty of water – Replenishing your fluids is necessary for optimizing your workout. You need water before, during and after exercise. To stay well hydrated the America College of Sports Medicine recommends: Drink roughly 2 to 3 cups of water during the two to three hours before your workout, ½ cup to 1 cup of water every 15-20 minutes during and 2-3 cups after your workout for every pound of weight you lose during the workout. <br /><br />Here is a quote from Coach Shannon Wallace: “Train like an athlete no matter who you are. Some people think that athletes are someone that jumps high, runs fast, and can catch a ball. That is a reality-disconnect. We all have the same bio-mechanics—we all sit, walk and stand. We can all train like an athlete. So what are you waiting for?<br /><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="30dbb13638d184a5fcb350098e06c32e" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2011/10/workplace-exercise-burning-calories-at.html"><![CDATA[<br /><br />Even if you work at a desk all day, you don’t need to take it constantly sitting down. Make fitness a part of your work day. Here are some ways to incorporate exercise into your office routine: <br /><br />1. Make the most of your commute - Walk or bike to work. If you drive park a few blocks away and walk the rest of the way or park at the far end of the parking lot. Also, take the stairs rather than the elevator, walk briskly or even run a few extra times up and down.<br /><br />2. Look for opportunities to stand - You'll burn more calories standing than sitting. Stand while on the phone. Better yet, try a standing desk. Eat lunch standing up. Trade instant messaging and phone calls for walks to other desks or offices<br /><br />3. Take Fitness Breaks – Take some time to go to a gym that’s nearby if you can on your lunch break or go for a fast walk around the building. Eat a small protein snack such as almonds or almond butter on an apple before you work out, and then eat a veggie wrap or lean meat wrap with veggies after. <br /><br />4. Try a fitness ball instead of an office chair - Consider trading your desk chair for a firmly inflated fitness or stability ball, as long as you're able to safely balance on the ball. You'll improve your balance and tone your core muscles while sitting at your desk. You can even use the fitness ball for wall squats, abdominal crunches or other workplace exercises during the day. <br /><br />5. Keep fitness equipment in your office – Store resistance bands, weights, or if there is room in your office, an elliptical or treadmill. Use arm weights between meetings, while on the phone or any time you can sneak them in. <br /><br />6. Organize a group to walk with – This will help keep you motivated and accountable.<br /><br />7. Conduct meetings on the go - When it's practical, schedule walking meetings or walking brainstorming sessions. Do laps inside your building or, if the weather cooperates, take your walking meetings outdoors.<br /><br />8. Try a treadmill desk - If you're ready to take workplace exercise to the next level, consider a treadmill with a computer screen on a stand, a keyboard on a table or a specialized treadmill-ready vertical desk. In fact, Mayo Clinic researchers estimate that overweight office workers who replace sitting computer time with walking computer time by two to three hours a day could lose 44 to 66 pounds in a year. The pace doesn't need to be brisk, nor do you need to break a sweat. The faster you walk, however, the more calories you'll burn. <br /><br />Now that you have some ideas on working in some exercise, make it happen! Commit to do some form of exercise each day and you will not only get in shape, and have more energy; you will find you are more productive. What are you waiting for? Get moving! <br /><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="913b167e53662054bc19820915096f77" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2011/11/rev-up-your-metabolism-can-it-be-done.html"><![CDATA[Rev up Your Metabolism: Can it be done?<br /><br /><br />Not all metabolisms are created equal. Some people are blessed with faster metabolisms than some and seem to be able to eat anything without gaining weight. For others, their bodies seem to cling to a heavier weight no matter what they do. <br /><br />The speed at which your body burns calories is called “metabolic rate.” Your sex, height, weight, genetics, age, lifestyle, and body composition affect your metabolism. Your metabolism plays a significant role in weight management: The faster your metabolism, the more calories you'll burn, and the less likely that you'll be overweight. <br /><br />Here are a few dos and don’ts for revving up your metabolism:<br /><br />• There are several opinions about foods that can boost your metabolism but nothing proven. Some studies I have read say that spicy foods can increase your metabolism but only if eaten two to three times a week. There have also been rumors that grapefruit increases your body's ability to burn calories because of its acidity, but there are no studies to substantiate that myth.”<br /><br />• Don’t skip meals. Skipping meals can actually cause your metabolism to slow down. Denying the body of essential nutrients put your body in starvation mode and through off your metabolism. Eating 4-6 meals a day can speed up your metabolism, as long as they are healthy meals. <br /><br />• Drink water. Lack of water can slow the metabolic rate just as lack of food can, says John Acquaviva, PhD, assistant professor of health and human performance at Roanoke College in Salem, Va. "Since water is the body's most important nutrient, the liver will turn its concentration to water retention instead of doing other duties such as burning fat." <br /><br />• Tone Up. Muscle dictates metabolism so the more muscle you have the more calories you will burn – even while you’re sleeping! Muscle is more metabolically active than fat, so replacing your fat stores with lean muscle allows you to maintain your weight much more easily.<br /><br />• Aerobic Activity can increase your metabolism. Most exercise experts say to do at least 6o minutes of moderate exercise a day such as walking, gardening, or cleaning. Although, if you want to burn more calories, it’s necessary to get your heart rate up. This also is important for your cardiovascular system to stay healthy.<br /><br />• Adjust your metabolism as you get older. To maintain a stable weight, adjust your caloric intake and physical activity. You may need fewer calories, especially if you decrease your exercise. <br /><br />In conclusion, eating 4-6 healthy meals a day, staying toned and exercising regularly can keep your metabolism revved up. Also, it will help you maintain a healthy weight; have more energy and live an all around healthier life! <br /><br /><script src="http://mawidget.marketamerica.com/IPD.aspx?wid=10665&prodID=2267&pcID=5E42527A564F59&portalID=pressingon&refEmail=0A1F112E0B1C2D0501280215021402274B170802&prdCountry=USA&merchCountry=USA&width=315&height=210&format=json"></script>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5500e58ab5126999d088589f942a597c" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2011/11/ten-tips-to-avoid-holiday-weight-gain.html"><![CDATA[<br /><br />Research has shown that most adults usually gain around 5-10 pounds over the holidays. There are ways you can prevent this from happening during such a tempting time. Remember, you are in control – not your appetite! Here are 10 tips if followed, can help you survive the holidays!<br /><br />• <strong>Don’t skip workouts.</strong> Exercise will help you burn those extra calories you are taking in this time of year. It also helps with stress which contributes to weight gain. <br /><br />• <strong>Plan ahead.</strong> Plan beforehand what you are going to eat. If there are several of your favorites, just have a small portion of each. <br /><br />• <strong>Don’t skip breakfast.</strong> A lot of people think if you skip a meal you can save room for more at the party. By doing this you will gorge yourself and slow down your metabolism which will in turn store all the food you’ve eaten as fat. <br /><br />• <strong>Eat more fruits &amp; Veggies</strong>. Doing this will fill you up, and is much healthier than the traditional party snacks. <br /><br /><strong>• Limit the sweets</strong>. Sweets are a temptation for many during the holidays. Allow yourself a cookie, a piece of pie or whatever your favorite dessert is but it will need to be compensated for later. Reduce your caloric intake to make up for it and burn those extra calories by exercising. <br /><br /><strong>• Don’t go to a party hungry</strong>. Before you go, eat a healthy snack that is high in fiber and protein such as Greek yogurt with fruit and flaxseed or a high fiber protein shake. This will help you not crave appetizers or snacks when you get there. <br /><br /><strong>• Use a small plate</strong>. Smaller plates can stop you from getting so much. Just don’t make several trips to get more! Try to stick to one serving. <br /><br /><strong>• Don’t over indulge on the alcohol.</strong> Stick to a light beer or 1 glass of wine instead of heavy eggnog. After that, stick to drinking calorie free drinks such as water, tea and coffee – not soda. <br /><br /><strong>• Don’t allow others to sabotage you.</strong> There is always someone who will want to sabotage your healthy eating plan. Remember, you are not trying to please them, more importantly; you are on your way to a healthier lifestyle! <br /><br /><strong>• Focus on socializing.</strong> Try not to stand around the food while engaging in conversation. Go to a room without all the snacks and focus on having a meaningful conversation. It will be much more rewarding. <br /><br />In conclusion, if you can follow these tips you will survive the holidays without gaining the extra pounds like you may normally do. What an awesome way to start the New Year – feeling better and looking better!<br /><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3b865d85bdc733469908d8a5527ca38d" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2011/11/top-5-foods-that-can-help-lower.html"><![CDATA[There are many benefits of eating a healthy diet, but many people don’t realize the importance of eating heart healthy foods that can help prevent high cholesterol levels and help lower cholesterol in those who have high cholesterol.  A few simple tweaks to your diet can help you stay off cholesterol medication. These are the top 5 foods the Mayo Clinic recommends to maintain healthy cholesterol levels:  1. Oatmeal, oat bran and high-fiber foods – Whole oats contains soluble fiber which reduces your low-density lipoprotein (LDL), the "bad" cholesterol. Soluble fiber is also found in such foods as kidney beans, apples, pears, barley and prunes. Soluble fiber can reduce the absorption of cholesterol into your bloodstream. Five to 10 grams or more of soluble fiber a day decreases your total and LDL cholesterol. Consuming 1 1/2 cups of cooked oatmeal provides 6 grams of fiber. If you add fruit, such as bananas, you'll add about 4 more grams of fiber. Steal cut oats or whole oats, not quick cooking oats will give you what you need.  2. Flax seed or flax oil - In reducing the risk factors of coronary heart disease, recent research has shown that flaxseed's high Omega-3 fatty acid and its soluble fiber content have helped to reduce serum triglycerides and blood pressure. It can also reduce the hardening effects of cholesterol on cell membranes.   3. Walnuts, almonds and other nuts – They can reduce blood cholesterol and are rich in polyunsaturated fatty acids. Walnuts also help keep blood vessels healthy. Eating about a handful of nuts a day may reduce the risk of heart disease. Just make sure you eat raw nuts without all the salt and sugar. They are a great substitute for croutons or cheese on salads.  4. Olive oil - Olive oil contains a potent mix of antioxidants that can lower your "bad" (LDL) cholesterol but leave your "good" (HDL) cholesterol untouched. The Food and Drug Administration recommends adding two tablespoons of olive oil a day instead of other fats in your diet to get the heart healthy benefits. Extra virgin olive oil will give you the most benefits.  5. Fish - Eating fatty fish can be heart-healthy because of its high levels of omega-3 fatty acids, which can reduce blood pressure and risk of developing blood clots. In people who have already had heart attacks, fish oil or omega-3 fatty acids — reduces the risk of sudden death. The highest levels of omega 3’s are in certain fish such as, salmon, albacore tuna, mackerel, lake trout, herring and sardines and halibut.   In conclusion, for these foods to be of benefit to your diet, you may also need to make other changes as well such as, radically reducing processed foods, sweets and fast foods. Exercise daily and take necessary supplements that are highly absorbable. As a lifestyle wellness coach, I would be happy to help you get started on your journey to a healthier lifestyle.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ebd085a971c3f3c46a7750b781fb5154" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2011/12/obstacles-to-valuing-your-health.html"><![CDATA[<br /><br />In my last article, I listed several reasons why we don’t value our health or for that matter our lives. My hope in this article is to cause you to think about how valuable you are. My number one frustration as a coach is that my clients don’t take their health seriously until it’s too late and they have a major illness or disease. <br /><br />Here are some more reasons we don’t invest time or money to take care of ourselves: <br /><br />• Lack of a support system. If you don’t have others in your life that will support you, it is very difficult to develop a healthy lifestyle. Many times my clients sabotage themselves or allow others to sabotage them. They start off excited and ready to make a change and then someone plants a seed of doubt in them, and because they don’t value themselves, they give up.<br /><br />When having the accountability and encouragement of a coach and good social network a person is twice as likely to succeed. This is why my groups are more successful than one on one coaching clients. It’s very important to position others in your life that have a positive outlook and want to help you succeed. <br /><br />• Lack of commitment. One thing I always say before my client begins my TLS Weight Loss class is “Are you ready and committed to making a change?” If they hesitate, I encourage them to really think about how important their health is to them. Many want to be healthy but are not willing to make the necessary changes it takes to become healthier. If this is the case, I recommend they wait until they are ready.<br /><br />• Lack of willpower. Willpower can be a great thing if you have it but the problem comes when you begin to Reason. For example, Reason can talk you out of going for your morning jog when it’s cold and gloomy out. “Your right, it says, it’s too yucky to jog.” <br /><br />I’m sure you have found that when you really don’t want to do something, you can talk yourself out of it! Willpower and discipline are critically important for a successful life, but willpower alone is not usually enough to bring you across the finish line. Drawing your strength from God can help you do all things.<br /><br />Finally, valuing your life and investing in yourself is vital to become happy and healthy. My hope is that you will realize how valuable you are!
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d112f3db461692a465cd4c52aadca26f" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2011/12/why-we-dont-value-our-health.html"><![CDATA[<br /><br />Taking care of your health is not an indulgence, its respecting yourself, others and God. When you don’t take care of your health, you can end up sick and debilitated while putting a burden on others who must take care of you.<br /><br />Throughout my coaching practice I have come to discover several reasons why people don’t value themselves as they should. My passion as a coach is to educate and help people to grasp how valuable they are in hopes they will invest some time in their health so as to lead the life God has intended for them. <br /><br />Here are some reasons we don’t invest time or money to take care of ourselves: <br /><br />1. Lack of knowledge - Many people don’t realize how foods impact their body. They have never had any education on nutrition. They rely on fast food and prepackaged meals that have no or very little nutritional value. Their lives are so hectic; they don’t take time to eat sensibly. Once they can understand how easy and affordable it is to eat healthy many adjust their eating habits. <br /><br />2. We have a distorted image of how we are to look – We have been inundated with media telling us how we should look, but on the other hand, obesity is so prevalent -it’s almost the norm!<br /><br />3. We don’t recognize the importance of exercise – Being too busy to exercise is one of the common excuses I hear from my clients. Exercise is essential to our overall well-being. Here are just a few of the benefits: stress reliever, improves moods, and boosts energy, plus many more! Exercise needs to be a priority in your life so that you can accomplish the things that are important. <br /><br />4. We don’t enjoy our lives – I am dismayed by a number of my clients that fall into this category. They are so busy; they cut everything they enjoy out of their lives. God never intended our lives to be mundane and stressful. Once you can learn the impact stress has on your physical and emotional well –being, you can begin to understand what a crime against yourself this is. Life is too short not to be enjoyed!<br /><br />5. Some have become addicted to selflessness – Yes, it’s important to help others and it should be a major part of your life, but not to the extent of ignoring your basic needs. For some, the only thing that gives them meaning is doing for others. Everything in life must have a balance or something breaks down and often it’s us. <br /><br />There are several other reasons why we don’t take care of ourselves so make sure you read my next article. Above all, value your life – it’s the greatest gift you will ever receive!<br /><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1f932c4d172b1ecab6cc8114f75cef7b" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2012/01/can-supplements-help-boost-your-energy.html"><![CDATA[<br /><br />Energy supplements have become one of the most popular categories of supplements. It seems like everyone these days needs an energy boost. Hectic lifestyles seem to be one of the main reasons for lack of energy and a desire for something that can help.<br /><br />But do they work? Some energy supplements may help but you need to know what you are looking for. Otherwise, supplements you buy could just leave you hundreds of dollars poorer and no less sluggish.<br /><br />Here is some information that may help guide you to the supplements that can benefit you the most. It’s also important to get advice from a physician who has been educated on supplementation:<br /><br />To help break it down, I will divide these energy supplement ingredients into three categories: <br /><br />1. Stimulants – Can help rev up the metabolism. Here are lists of energy supplements which contain these: <br /><br />• Caffeine - is a common ingredient in just about any product marketed for energy, while an energy drink might have 20 other ingredients, the one you really feel is likely to be caffeine. Caffeine can step up your metabolism and can even give you greater mental clarity. Although, most experts say to have no more than 2 cups a day. <br /><br />• Herbal sources of caffeine and related compounds like guarana, yerba mate, and kola nut<br /><br />• Green tea (also a source of caffeine) - also provides a related compound, theophylline, as well as the antioxidant epigallocatechin gallate (EGCG). Possibly, because of these specific compounds, green tea may have unique effects on mental and physical energy.<br /><br />• Capsaicin (red pepper) - the ingredient that makes chili peppers hot; is sometimes used for its alleged stimulant properties, but more for a metabolic boost than for improvements in physical or mental energy.<br /><br />• Asian Ginseng - is not a caffeine derivative, but it may also serve as a mild stimulant. There is some scientific research that shows it can have positive effects on psychological and physical health.<br /><br />• Bitter Orange (specifically, the ingredient synephrine) – is an extract from the rind of a different citrus species than that used for classic orange juice, is another energy supplement unrelated to caffeine. Though it has not been studied much, some experts fear there could be some risks taking it. Its active ingredient- synephrine is chemically similar to ephedrine which was pulled off the market in 2004 because of some serious health risks. <br /><br />For lack of space, I will need to continue the other categories next week. The bottom line: Will these supplements boost energy? Yes, stimulants like these most likely will rev up your metabolism temporarily, but the key is eating healthy, exercising as well as taking a superior line of supplements. <br /><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6d030ac01779524ed115d0df2db89846" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2012/01/can-supplements-help-boost-your-energy_22.html"><![CDATA[<br /><br />Last week I gave some information on supplements that may help you get an energy boost. With today’s hurried lifestyles we need all the energy we can get! <br /><br />Here are some other substances that may affect energy metabolism:<br /><br />• Coenzyme Q10 (CoQ10) - is the vital nutrient that initiates energy production at the cellular level that powers the heart and acts as a powerful antioxidant when combined with vitamin E. It plays a vital role in health maintenance. It contributes to a healthy cardiovascular system, periodontal health, healthy blood sugar levels, and maintenance of cholesterol and triglyceride concentrations.<br /><br />• B vitamins, like vitamin B6, vitamin B12, folic acid, thiamine, niacian- these are necessary to take because they are water soluble and our bodies do not produce them. They help decrease stress and improve mood, and maintain healthy levels of serotonin.<br /><br />• Creatine, carnitine - might actually decrease athletic performance in longer-term physical activity and carries some risk. Some experts say it can interfere with sweating, thus contributing to dehydration, muscle strain, and cramps. <br /><br />Deficiencies in these vitamins are common. People who are deficient in CoQ10 and B vitamins can definitely benefit from taking supplements. Who is likely to be deficient? Athletes who push themselves hard might be depleted in these nutrients. Also, people who have poor diets or take regular medications, such as acid blockers, anti-inflammatories, antibiotics, blood pressure, cholesterol lowering medication and several more can become deficient. <br /><br />Also, we can no longer get all the vitamins in our foods any longer since our soil is depleted, and pesticides and chemicals have been added to our fruits, vegetables and meats. Not to mention the poor diet most Americans have. <br /><br />Some other energy supplements that are popular with my clients are Mochatonix which contains an ingredient – Advantra Z. When combined with exercise, can help to the body burn fat, build lean muscle mass, and increase physical performance. Not only does it provide additional energy, it can help the body use more efficiently the energy stored in fat. <br /><br />In conclusion, there is a lot to learn about supplementation and how it can truly help you feel more energetic and stay healthy.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1f7023b8239e3fd44d52b577567f3e6e" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2012/01/dont-make-resolution-make-lifestyle.html"><![CDATA[<br /><br />It’s that time of year again when many of us makes a resolution to lose weight and live healthier- but why don’t these resolutions last? In this article I will give you a few reasons why resolutions to lose weight don’t work. <br /><br />1. <strong>Diets don’t work</strong>. Diets are a temporary way of life. On the quest to lose weight many people try quick fix diets such as, shakes, low calorie foods, fad diets, health clubs and other weight loss attempts. Being overweight is like wearing a bull’s eye — you are a target for companies trying to make money from your condition. Restrictive diets do not work; you must make a lifestyle change. <br /><br />"Lifestyle change will work if you have realistic expectations, good support, and choose a plan that you can stick with -- a plan that will give you moderate change over a long time Fernstrom tells WebMD. <br /><br />2. <strong>Behaviors do not change automatically</strong>. Instead of riding the diet roller coaster up and down, you need to make a constant effort to change. If you don’t change your lifestyle behaviors, don’t expect to achieve or maintain a healthy weight. That is why most diet plans don’t work; you are not taught how to eat for a lifetime, change your behavior or incorporate exercise. <br /><br />3. <strong>Diet is affected by social issues</strong>. This happens when you are with your family and friends. In the American setting, unhealthy eating and dietary patterns is often encouraged. This makes it very difficult to keep healthy lifestyle changes going. Don’t allow others to discourage you and cause you to give up; keep your focus to accomplish what you set out to, no matter the cost.<br /><br />4. <strong>Lack of accountability</strong>. Many people try to reach their weight loss goals on their own. Usually, they quickly give up because no one is there to inspire or encourage them to press past the challenges. Having a coach is crucial for success. Just as a good coach helps their team win the game with education, encouragement and inspiration, so a Lifestyle Coach can help you achieve your goals of weight-loss and a healthy lifestyle<br /><br />It’s time for a different approach. It’s time to find the answer that’s right for you. That answer is making a lifestyle change that will last, not a temporary solution that will fail. Start with a positive attitude and determination to stop the diet roller coaster!
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2542a191456a4179077f87d51f3a1852" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2012/02/are-you-at-risk-for-sitting-disease-how.html"><![CDATA[<br />Are You at Risk for Sitting Disease?<br /><br />How much do you sit throughout the day? Medical experts have started referring to long periods of inactivity and its negative consequences as “Sitting Disease.” People can spend up to half of their day sitting, whether it is at their work station or on their couch. New studies are saying what has been suspected for a while; if you’re sitting for long periods of time, you may be at risk for cancer, diabetes, heart disease and obesity.<br /><br />In fact, in a study presented at the American Institute for Cancer Research’s annual conference, there have been 90,000 cancer deaths that can be attributed to the fact that people are exercising less than ever. Breast cancer has also been linked to inactivity.<br /><br />Consequently, when you’re seated your muscles’ electrical activity drops, which incites a flow of unwanted metabolic effects. The body’s calorie-burning mechanisms slow and insulin efficiency drops, escalating the risk of diabetes. Obesity becomes a concern because enzymes that break down lipids and triglycerides also drop, bringing levels of good (HDL) cholesterol down with them (Dr. Neil Baum’s blog). What’s more, even regular exercise doesn’t seem to outweigh the ills of sitting through the workday.<br /><br />Here are some tips to help you revamp your lifestyle to become more physically active:<br /><br />• (NEAT) Nonexercise Activity Thermogenesis. If you sit at a desk all day, you may consider stretching, bending and turning several times throughout the day. Also, try mixing standing and sitting. <br /><br />• Take regular breaks. Most people know lack of exercising will cause weight gain, but this doesn’t usually motivate them to become more active. It helps to get moving often with small goals. Stretch out your entire body, all the muscles that are cramped. If you do it five or six times a day, you'll start to notice a difference." <br /><br />• Exercise while watching television. It’s time to bring the treadmill, bike or elliptical out of the basement and put it in front of your TV. This is how a client told me they lost weight. They made the commitment to get on their treadmill every time they watched TV for at least an hour. <br /><br />• End your workday with more energy. Prolonged sitting at work can tire you out, which makes you fill exhausted by the time 5 p.m. approaches. If you take a brisk, 15-minute walk in the afternoon, you'll be far more productive in your last two hours. Making time to get a little exercise in will give you more energy all day long. <br /><br />Lastly, whatever you can do to move more do it! Walk, stretch, stand, ride a bike or get on an elliptical. Not only will you feel more energetic, improve your moods and decrease your chance for several diseases, you will also prolong your life span and quality of life! So what are you waiting for?<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-_C0JO8obP2k/Ty3SlIirG9I/AAAAAAAAAB0/dIXcfJ8fp9M/s1600/gty_overweight_person_jef_110410_wg.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="180" sda="true" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-_C0JO8obP2k/Ty3SlIirG9I/AAAAAAAAAB0/dIXcfJ8fp9M/s320/gty_overweight_person_jef_110410_wg.jpg" width="320" /></a></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4b9bca99646205ba8794b85b5452163e" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2012/02/overcome-loser-mentality.html"><![CDATA[<br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-UyaJjP3CYRs/T0mcqB6UQzI/AAAAAAAAACE/KLCDyuNIxHA/s1600/TLS%2520Logo%5B1%5D.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" lda="true" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-UyaJjP3CYRs/T0mcqB6UQzI/AAAAAAAAACE/KLCDyuNIxHA/s1600/TLS%2520Logo%5B1%5D.jpg" /></a></div><br /><br />There are many people who desperately want to lead a healthier lifestyle but are not sure how to get started or are afraid to try because they have failed before. They have tried several different diets, or they keep trying to do the same one, only to end up with the same results and are now even more discouraged. This is usually when they give up and figure their lot in life is to be overweight, and unhealthy. <br /><br />So what is holding them back from seeking help and moving forward? Here are some of the reasons or excuses I have heard from people: <br /><br />• I don’t think I can do it<br /><br />• It’s too hard<br /><br />• I can’t afford it<br /><br />• I don’t feel like it<br /><br />• I don’t have the time<br /><br />We often do things based on feelings. If we don’t “feel” like it, we don’t do it, even when we know it’s healthier. If we can learn to focus on the consequences verses rewards of not doing something or doing something, then we are more apt to follow through. For example, I don’t always feel like exercising, but I know it’s good for me and I will feel much better afterwards. This motivates me to exercise again, and I now love to do it!<br /><br />Many times we defeat ourselves before we even get started. We’ve already convinced ourselves we can’t do it so we don’t even try. Set your mind to determine decisively what you will think, what you believe and what you will or will not do. Establish that you will become healthier no matter what it takes and don’t give up! <br /><br />I have seen many of my clients succeed when they at first lacked the confidence to even try. Once they started they got more and more confidence, while getting encouragement and support from the group and coach, which lead to their success. This wouldn’t have happened if they wouldn’t have taken that step of faith and overcome that loser mentality. <br /><br />If you seriously want to improve your lifestyle, you may consider joining my group competition – “TLS Lose to Win.” I am looking for four people to coach who need to lose weight and make a change. The group will be entered in a national competition and can win large cash prizes. Contact me by February 25th if you are interested. <br /><br />In conclusion, as one of my clients so adequately put it: “Champions make decisions to birth a better future; losers make excuses to stay the same as today.” I believe God has placed champions in each of us; it’s up to us to start living it out! <br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8a59e33742f9b2f16f342bf6f79bba47" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2012/03/preventing-cycle-ofchildhood-obesity-in.html"><![CDATA[<br /><div align="center" class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt; text-align: center;"><b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><span style="font-size: 14pt; line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">Preventing the Cycle of Childhood Obesity<o:p></o:p></span></span></b></div><br /><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"><span style="font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">In my previous article I gave some daunting statistics on childhood obesity, one of them being that over nine million children over the age of nine are considered extremely overweight or obese. <o:p></o:p></span></span></div><br /><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"><span style="font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">Many times I hear my clients tell me that it’s impossible to get their children to eat healthy. In our day and age children are inundated with poor food choices not only in school, fast food restaurants or a friend’s house but also because of what we as parents provide. We have a choice and a responsibility to be the parent and provide healthy food for our children, but it can be a challenge. <o:p></o:p></span></span></div><br /><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"><span style="font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">That is why I decided to share how one of my client’s has overcome the cycle of obesity by being strong enough to change poor eating habits that have caused herself and her children to become overweight. Here is Margaret’s story:<o:p></o:p></span></span></div><br /><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"><span style="font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">When you have a child, you are entrusted to be their protector and their provider.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>Three square meals a day and a warm bed to sleep in are two basics and the list grows from there.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>The problem is that three square meals a day is a title that does not come with a manual.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>Is that Macaroni and cheese from a box?<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>Is that Ravioli from a can?<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>Is that a bologna sandwich loaded with catsup and pickles?<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>As mothers we depend on that happy satisfied smile on our little ones face to tell us that they are satisfied with what they have consumed.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>Three pieces of pizza and a soda pop has never been good for the body but it will bring a smile out of a child in a quick minute.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>And when we believe they are content then we are content.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span><o:p></o:p></span></span></div><br /><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">My family and I were facing this.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>They only ate what I fed them.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>I was totally responsible for their diet so the extra weight that they were carrying around was my issue and not so much theirs.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>It was quickly becoming theirs, however. </span></div><br /><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">When I started Transitions Lifestyle I realized that their diet was all wrong.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>They should be eating five times a day, not three and they should never eat canned or prepackaged meals.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp;&nbsp; </span>Changing what I provided for them and then packing their lunches for school were necessary.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>I cannot say that they did not oppose the change.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>They wanted the candy bars and lunchables back in the house, but I stood my ground and before you know it, in a matter of a few weeks, the extra weight that they were starting to show, was coming off.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span></span></div><br /><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">Next week I will continue Margaret’s story because I believe it can help parents who struggle with convincing their children to eat healthy.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>Don’t get discouraged, and be persistent – you can win the battle!</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-1Wg_Cq4vf4g/T11mWj9B2FI/AAAAAAAAACM/099sQcQUJ2Y/s1600/PARADE%25202%5B1%5D.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="282" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-1Wg_Cq4vf4g/T11mWj9B2FI/AAAAAAAAACM/099sQcQUJ2Y/s320/PARADE%25202%5B1%5D.jpg" width="320" /></a></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="34b7c6fb4ff6a955b4417387f59bc9da" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2012/06/five-ways-exercise-can-lead-to.html"><![CDATA[<br />  <br /><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">The next time you begin craving sweets or want to down half a pizza, go take a hike or a jog. Exercise, especially cardio exercise can help decrease your cravings. Here are five ways exercise can help you maintain a healthy lifestyle:<o:p></o:p></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpFirst" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 0.5in; mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-fareast-font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">1.<span style="font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font: 7pt/normal &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">In a recent study that was published by <i style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;">Appetite, </i>people who took a brisk fifteen minute walk, cut their cravings for chocolate by 12%. Not only does it cut cravings for sweets, but it also can cause you to crave healthier foods. Why ruin a great workout by eating junk food!<o:p></o:p></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 0.5in; mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-fareast-font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">2.<span style="font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font: 7pt/normal &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Lose the belly fat. <span style="color: #222222;">A study in the journal <i>Obesity </i>found that just 80 minutes of cardio a week slows weight gain and even stopped participants from gaining visceral fat which is the dangerous kind inside the abdomen, and has been linked to diabetes and cardiovascular disease. </span><o:p></o:p></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 0.5in; mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-fareast-font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">3.<span style="font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font: 7pt/normal &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="color: #222222; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Exercise can diffuse nicotine cravings. Research shows that 10-15 minute aerobic sessions triggers changes in the brain which decreases cravings in smokers. Cardio exercise has also been found to decrease thoughts of smoking. </span><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"><o:p></o:p></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 0.5in; mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-fareast-font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">4.<span style="font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font: 7pt/normal &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Vigorous activity can help maintain healthy vision. It has also been discovered that people who ran 1.2 – 2.5 miles a day had a 19 percent lower risk of developing age-related macular degeneration, while those who ran more cut their chance by 42 to 54 percent, according to a study from <i>Investigative Ophthalmology &amp; Visual Science</i>. Cardio exercise may also decrease cataract risk</span><span style="color: #222222; font-family: &quot;Arial&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 10pt; line-height: 115%;">.</span><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"><o:p></o:p></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpLast" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt 0.5in; mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-fareast-font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">5.<span style="font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font: 7pt/normal &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Exercise can decrease the risk of breast cancer. In study done by <i style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;">Medicine &amp; Science</i> <i style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;">Sports &amp; Exercise</i> it has been found that women who do moderate exercise for 2.5 hours a week or rigorous activity for 75 minutes a week decrease their chance of dying of breast cancer by a third. <o:p></o:p></span></div><br /><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt 0.25in;"><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Aerobic exercise and sweat also helps your body release toxins that are stored in fat. When toxins are built up in our body, we experience various health issues. Many people, who only do mild to moderate exercise, are not getting the benefits of a vigorous workout. <o:p></o:p></span></div><br /><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt 0.25in;"><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">In conclusion, cardio exercise is important to maintaining a healthier lifestyle. Not only will you feel better and have more energy, you will also decrease your risk of several diseases, obesity and other health issues.<o:p></o:p></span></div><br /><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt 0.25in;"><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"><span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp;</span>So put on your sneakers and take a vigorous walk or run today.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>Think of all the benefits of exercise; enjoy your heart pumping, your legs moving and your body sweating!<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>You may not feel good at first but you will be thankful you did!<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span><o:p></o:p></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="66f63d1490367141ea474e32bd8d2f41" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2012/06/time-management-healthy-living-goes.html"><![CDATA[<br /><br />  <br /><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"><span style="font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">Many people that are successful in all areas of life are people who know how to manage their time. Not only are they organized, they accomplish what they set out to do. Do you ever look at highly successful people and wander how they do all that they do and still manage to exercise and eat healthy? <o:p></o:p></span></span></div><br /><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"><span style="font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">Here are some tips that may help you manage your time while including a health regimen: <o:p></o:p></span></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpFirst" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 0.5in; mso-list: l1 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Calibri; mso-bidi-theme-font: minor-latin;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">1.</span><span style="font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font: 7pt/normal &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><span style="font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Daily track your time.</span></b><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"> <span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp;</span>If you’ve ever tried to lose weight, a nutritionist may tell you to keep a food journal because it keeps you from eating mindlessly. It’s the same with time. Write down what you’re doing as often as you can so you know what to eliminate and how you can spend it more productively.</span><span style="font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"><o:p></o:p></span></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 0.5in;"><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">A lot of our time is spent unproductively for example; at night you may spend time watching TV. Instead of just sitting there, use this time to get on your elliptical while your favorite show is on or record it later so you can watch while you exercise in the morning. <o:p></o:p></span></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 0.5in; mso-list: l1 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -0.25in;"><b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Calibri; mso-bidi-theme-font: minor-latin;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">2.</span><span style="font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font: 7pt/normal &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span></b><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">It all starts in the morning. <span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp;</span></span></b><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">What you do in the morning usually determines what the rest of your day looks like. When you have an unproductive morning, this seems to dictate the rest of your day. <b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><o:p></o:p></b></span></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 0.5in;"><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">Start your day with some personal growth such as, reading a daily devotional or inspirational message. Praying for your day can keep you on track, and helps you set your priorities. Map out your day by writing in your day planner.<o:p></o:p></span></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 0.5in; mso-list: l1 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -0.25in;"><b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Calibri; mso-bidi-theme-font: minor-latin;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">3.</span><span style="font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font: 7pt/normal &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span></b><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Build your habits. </span></b><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Turning a desire into a ritual requires willpower. Use these steps to optimize your routine:<b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><o:p></o:p></b></span></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 1in; mso-add-space: auto; mso-list: l0 level1 lfo2; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="color: black; font-family: Symbol; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Symbol; mso-fareast-font-family: Symbol;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">·<span style="font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font: 7pt/normal &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Start at a slow pace – </span></b><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Go to bed 15 minutes early so you can get your exercise regimen in. Then the next week increase it to 20 minutes earlier.<b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><o:p></o:p></b></span></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 1in; mso-add-space: auto; mso-list: l0 level1 lfo2; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="color: black; font-family: Symbol; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Symbol; mso-fareast-font-family: Symbol;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">·<span style="font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font: 7pt/normal &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Monitor your energy – </span></b><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Eating right and exercising daily will give you the energy you need to have a productive day.<b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><o:p></o:p></b></span></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 1in; mso-add-space: auto; mso-list: l0 level1 lfo2; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="color: black; font-family: Symbol; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Symbol; mso-fareast-font-family: Symbol;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">·<span style="font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font: 7pt/normal &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Choose one habit at a time to work on –</span></b><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"> If you want to run, pray and begin to eat healthier, pick one at a time until you have it accomplished and then begin the other.<b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><o:p></o:p></b></span></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 1in; mso-add-space: auto; mso-list: l0 level1 lfo2; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="color: black; font-family: Symbol; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Symbol; mso-fareast-font-family: Symbol;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">·<span style="font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font: 7pt/normal &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Chart your progress – </span></b><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">This will help you see how you are doing and what you need to change to form your habit. When you feel as if you’ve forgotten something such as brushing your teeth, then you know you have formed a habit. <b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><o:p></o:p></b></span></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpLast" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt 1in; mso-add-space: auto; mso-list: l0 level1 lfo2; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="color: black; font-family: Symbol; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Symbol; mso-fareast-font-family: Symbol;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">·<span style="font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font: 7pt/normal &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Use external motivations – </span></b><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Promise yourself something you really enjoy once you’ve successfully formed a habit. <b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><o:p></o:p></b></span></span></div><br /><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"><span style="color: black; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">In conclusion, if you will learn how to manage your time, and set priorities you are on your way to a healthier and more productive life!<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span><o:p></o:p></span></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c1981bc5eed0c40b154c0b027f4ac23d" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2012/08/supplementation-and-adhd.html"><![CDATA[<br />  <br /><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Many people that have children who have been diagnosed with ADHD or that have it themselves have wandered if vitamins and supplements can help with ADHD as an alternative to medication. This has been a question I seem to get asked often so I thought I would share what I’ve learned about supplementation and ADHD with my training and research. Since I am not a health professional, I recommend you seek help with one that is open to alternative medicine. <o:p></o:p></span></div><br /><em><b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;">What is ADHD?</b></em><br /><a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmedhealth/PMH0002518/" target="_blank" title="ADHD definition - PubMed Health"><span style="color: windowtext; text-decoration: none; text-underline: none;">Attention Deficit and Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) </span></a>seems to be a common developmental and behavioral disorder characterized by lack of concentration, distractibility, hyperactivity, and impulsiveness that are inappropriate for the child’s age.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span><br />  <br /><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"><span style="background: white; color: black; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Over the past few decades, alternative or complementary medicine<span class="apple-converted-space">&nbsp;</span>has grown in popularity. More and more people are looking for nontraditional approaches to personal health and healing. These diverse remedies are sometimes used in the place of typical medical approaches. Several alternative remedies are safe, relatively affordable, and easily accessible. They also very rarely have the harmful side effects.<o:p></o:p></span></div><br /><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt;"><span style="background: white; color: black; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">It is important to get educated on what works and what doesn’t even if it is a natural supplement, there is no guarantee its safe. Here are a few supplements that have been researched and have shown to be beneficial with ADHD as well as ADD:<o:p></o:p></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpFirst" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 0.5in; mso-list: l1 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="color: black; font-family: Symbol; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Symbol; mso-fareast-font-family: Symbol;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">·<span style="font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font: 7pt/normal &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span><b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><span style="background: white; color: black; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Zinc</span></b><span style="background: white; color: black; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"> – Some studies have shown that children with ADHD have lower levels of Zinc in their body. </span><span class="apple-converted-space"><span style="background: white; color: black; font-family: &quot;Arial&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 10pt; line-height: 115%;">&nbsp;</span></span><span style="background: white; color: black; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">And some scientists have reported improved symptoms in children with ADHD who took zinc supplements along with traditional medicine. <o:p></o:p></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 0.5in; mso-list: l1 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="color: black; font-family: Symbol; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Symbol; mso-fareast-font-family: Symbol;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">·<span style="font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font: 7pt/normal &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span><b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><span style="background: white; color: black; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Omega 3</span></b><span style="background: white; color: black; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"> - There is some evidence that fish oil can help improve ADHD symptoms. Fish oil contains omega-3 fatty acids. Some studies suggest, in children with ADHD who are 8 to 12 years old, fish oil supplementation could improve mental skills. For instance, it may help improve a child's ability to organize activities.<o:p></o:p></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 0.5in;"><span style="background: white; color: black; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">In a study published in a 2007 issue of the "Journal of Developmental and Behavioral Pediatrics," researchers studied the affect of fish oil and evening primrose oil on children aged between 7 to 12 years with ADHD. In the background to their study they explain that various developmental problems including ADHD have been linked to deficiencies in polyunsaturated fatty acids. <o:p></o:p></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt 0.5in; mso-list: l0 level1 lfo2; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="color: black; font-family: Symbol; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Symbol; mso-fareast-font-family: Symbol;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">·<span style="font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font: 7pt/normal &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span><b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><span style="background: white; color: black; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Carnitine </span></b><span style="background: white; color: black; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">– Is an amino acid which is important for energy production. </span><span style="color: black; font-family: &quot;Arial&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 10pt; line-height: 115%;"><br /></span><span style="background: white; color: black; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">The University of Michigan recommends taking 100mg of carnitine for each 2.2 pounds of body weight, up to a maximum of 4g daily, to help improve behavior. <o:p></o:p></span></div><br /><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpLast" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt 0.5in; mso-list: l0 level1 lfo2; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="color: black; font-family: Symbol; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Symbol; mso-fareast-font-family: Symbol;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">·<span style="font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font: 7pt/normal &quot;Times New Roman&quot;;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span><b style="mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;"><span style="background: white; color: black; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Magnesium </span></b><span style="border: 1pt windowtext; color: black; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-border-alt: none windowtext 0in; padding: 0in;">– According</span><span style="background: white; color: black; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"> to the University of Michigan children with ADHD may have low levels of magnesium. A 1997 study published in "Magnesium Research" found that 200mg of magnesium daily for six months reduced hyperactive behavior in children with ADHD</span><span style="background: white; color: black; font-family: &quot;Arial&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 10pt; line-height: 115%;">.</span><span style="background: white; color: black; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"><o:p></o:p></span></div><span style="border: 1pt windowtext; color: black; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-ansi-language: EN-US; mso-bidi-language: AR-SA; mso-border-alt: none windowtext 0in; mso-fareast-font-family: Calibri; mso-fareast-language: EN-US; mso-fareast-theme-font: minor-latin; padding: 0in;">Finally, diet also plays a big part in reducing symptoms of ADHD</span><span style="border: 1pt windowtext; color: black; font-family: &quot;Arial&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-ansi-language: EN-US; mso-bidi-language: AR-SA; mso-border-alt: none windowtext 0in; mso-fareast-font-family: Calibri; mso-fareast-language: EN-US; mso-fareast-theme-font: minor-latin; padding: 0in;">. </span><span style="border: 1pt windowtext; color: black; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-ansi-language: EN-US; mso-bidi-language: AR-SA; mso-border-alt: none windowtext 0in; mso-fareast-font-family: Calibri; mso-fareast-language: EN-US; mso-fareast-theme-font: minor-latin; padding: 0in;">Children who have healthy diets; plenty of fruits and vegetables, whole grains and organic meats, can also improve symptoms. </span><span style="border: 1pt windowtext; color: black; font-family: &quot;Arial&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%; mso-ansi-language: EN-US; mso-bidi-language: AR-SA; mso-border-alt: none windowtext 0in; mso-fareast-font-family: Calibri; mso-fareast-language: EN-US; mso-fareast-theme-font: minor-latin; padding: 0in;"><br style="mso-special-character: line-break;" /><br style="mso-special-character: line-break;" /></span><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2ae44852ab2b2f9ed223cfcd52804f89" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2012/09/healthy-living-as-deterrent-to-hearing.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif;"><b>Note: This is an article from a fellow blogger- John O'Connor</b></span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 12pt;">It used to be that many people assumed that little could be done to prevent hearing loss. &nbsp;They believed that hearing loss was inevitable as they grew older and that their everyday lifestyles contributed nothing toward losing the ability to hear. &nbsp;However, doctors today argue that a person's lifestyle directly influences how well that person can hear as he or she grows older. &nbsp;Certain habits can be discarded or altered if people want to protect their sense of hearing. &nbsp;</span><span style="font-family: Times, serif; font-size: 13.5pt;"><br /><br /></span><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 12pt;">In fact,</span><span style="font-family: Times, serif; font-size: 13.5pt;"><a href="http://www.nidcd.nih.gov/health/hearing/pages/noise.aspx"><span style="color: black; font-family: &quot;Arial&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt; text-decoration: none; text-underline: none;"> </span><span style="color: #1155cc; font-family: &quot;Arial&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">loud noises continue to be the greatest risk to one's hearing</span></a></span><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 12pt;">. &nbsp;People who work in noisy conditions or listen to loud music compromise their ability to hear well. &nbsp;Frequent exposure to loud noises damages a person's eardrums and sometimes causes it to rupture. &nbsp;For that reason, doctors urge people to limit their exposure to such noises or wear ear plugs if they work in noisy environments.</span><span style="font-family: Times, serif; font-size: 13.5pt;"><br /><br /></span><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 12pt;">Likewise, people can take preventative measures to protect their hearing by eating a healthy diet. &nbsp;Diabetes has been identified as one of the conditions that contribute to hearing loss. &nbsp;In fact, many diabetics report that they no longer hear as well as they did before they developed this condition. &nbsp;While many people are not aware of the link between diet and hearing loss, doctors note that people who eat healthy, get plenty of exercise, and avoid gaining too much weight overtime often hear better and keep their sense of hearing longer.</span><span style="font-family: Times, serif; font-size: 13.5pt;"><br /><br /></span><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 12pt;">Moreover, people who smoke also put themselves at risk for losing their ability to hear well as they grow older. &nbsp;More than 70% of smokers report hearing loss, leading doctors to believe that smoking has a direct effect on people's inability to hear. &nbsp;Even individuals who are regularly exposed to secondhand smoke indicate a compromised hearing ability. &nbsp;For that reason, physicians also encourage people to quit smoking if they value their sense of hearing.</span><span style="font-family: Times, serif; font-size: 13.5pt;"><br /><br /></span><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 12pt;">Aside from watching one's diet, exercising, and avoiding cigarette use, many doctors recommend that people clean out their ears regularly. &nbsp;This suggestion would appear to be common sense; however, some people do not think to remove excess wax from their ear canals and when doing so, remove wax in a harmful way. &nbsp;&nbsp;Even so, periodically washing one's ears out with rubbing alcohol or hydrogen peroxide helps remove wax build up in the ear canals. &nbsp;To ensure safety, visit your doctor to have wax properly removed from your ear canals.</span><span style="font-family: Times, serif; font-size: 13.5pt;"><br /><br /></span><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 12pt;">If you feel you are beginning to lose your hearing, a trip to the audiologist could be very helpful. &nbsp;An audiologist will be able to run certain tests to determine base line hearing levels. &nbsp;With these results, they will be able to provide tips on how to further protect your hearing or in some cases recommend the use of a</span><span style="font-family: Times, serif; font-size: 13.5pt;"><a href="http://www.earq.com/"><span style="color: black; font-family: &quot;Arial&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt; text-decoration: none; text-underline: none;"> </span><span style="color: #1155cc; font-family: &quot;Arial&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">hearing aid</span></a></span><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 12pt;"> to help better hearing. &nbsp;Following the tips mentioned above and making healthy lifestyle changes not only will improve your health but also protect your hearing.&nbsp;</span>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="31b0c33714d15ff5e354b7a7633ee0a8" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2012/12/accountability-can-help-with-weight-loss.html"><![CDATA[<br /><div align="center" class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt; line-height: 115%;">Accountability is important factor in being successful with your weight-loss goals. Many people try to lose weight on their own only to find themselves back where they started. We need that voice of reason, stability, and rationality encouraging us to persevere and not give up. That is why having a friend or a coach is a vital component in helping you reach your goals.<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">A friend can usher you to a place of break through when you want to give in to that chocolate cake or bag of chips. When that inevitable time comes, it can be hard to stay focused and get back on track. Accountability partners encourage you to move forward when quitting would be the easiest route.&nbsp; <o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Here are some ways to stay accountable:<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpFirst" style="mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -.25in;"><!--[if !supportLists]--><span style="font-family: Symbol; font-size: 12.0pt; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Symbol; mso-fareast-font-family: Symbol;">·<span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman'; font-size: 7pt; line-height: normal;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span><!--[endif]--><b><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Set up a healthy eating plan. </span></b><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Ask your accountability partner to check with you every day to see if you are sticking with it and to not allow you to cheat. If you need education on nutrition and what you should be eating, hire an expert to help you</span><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt; line-height: 115%;"><o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -.25in;"><!--[if !supportLists]--><span style="font-family: Symbol; font-size: 12.0pt; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Symbol; mso-fareast-font-family: Symbol;">·<span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman'; font-size: 7pt; line-height: normal;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span><!--[endif]--><b><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Journal.</span></b><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;"> Record your meals, snacks as well as, feelings that trigger your unhealthy eating. A coach can bring authority and expertise where as a friend may only offer suggestions.</span><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt; line-height: 115%;"><o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -.25in;"><!--[if !supportLists]--><span style="font-family: Symbol; font-size: 12.0pt; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Symbol; mso-fareast-font-family: Symbol;">·<span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman'; font-size: 7pt; line-height: normal;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span><!--[endif]--><b><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">Create a Timeline. </span></b><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman', serif; font-size: 12pt; line-height: 115%;">When setting up accountability for yourself, establishing a realistic but aggressive timeline will help you succeed. For example, "I want to lose 10 pounds" is not as effective as "I want to lose 10 pounds by my birthday." For large goals, benchmarks are an important part of the timeline. Instead of deciding to lose 48 lbs. in a year, commit to losing 4 lbs. per month for 12 months. This keeps you on track for success instead of pushing hard in the last weeks of your timeline.</span><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt; line-height: 115%;"><o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpLast" style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt; text-indent: -0.25in;"><!--[if !supportLists]--><span style="font-family: Symbol; font-size: 12pt;">·<span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman'; font-size: 7pt;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span><!--[endif]--><b><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Rewards. </span></b><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Building rewards into your weight-loss accountability may help keep you on track also. &nbsp;Give yourself some kind of recognition as you reach different benchmarks. For some, this may mean a new outfit in the size you are striving to reach, or a spa day. I recommend for weight-loss goals, not to have food-based rewards. This sets you up for defeat. <b><o:p></o:p></b></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"><span style="font-size: small;">After you begin seeing results, momentum will build and you may not need to have an accountability partner although, it&nbsp;</span>doesn't<span style="font-size: small;">&nbsp;hurt to have someone asking you every now and then how you’re doing. &nbsp;If you could use accountability, support and education, consider joining my Transitions Lifestyle class. Contact me for more information.&nbsp;<o:p></o:p></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c8e332f36f9afb63c85603eb08193174" url="http://coachirenegreiner.blogspot.com/2013/04/here-is-healthy-tasty-breakfast-food.html"><![CDATA[Here is a healthy &amp; tasty breakfast food. You can even freeze these for later:<br /><br /><br /><div class="MsoNormal"><b><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt; line-height: 115%;">Oatmeal Pancakes <o:p></o:p></span></b></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">Flour, wheat, whole grain 1 ¼ cup or gluten free pancake mix<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">1 Tbsp ground flax seed<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">Baking soda ½ tsp<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">1 ½ cup Coconut milk<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">2 large Eggs<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">1 Tsp Vanilla<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">1 Tbsp Butter, unsalted <o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">1 Tbsp coconut oil or coconut butter<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">Baking powder ½ tsp<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">Old fashioned rolled oats ½ cup<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">1 Cup berries, apples or bananas<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">½ Cup chopped walnuts if desired<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><br /></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpFirst" style="text-indent: -0.25in;"><!--[if !supportLists]--><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Verdana; mso-fareast-font-family: Verdana;">1.<span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman'; font-size: 7pt;">&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span><!--[endif]--><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">Mix flour (whole wheat pastry flour), flax seed, oatmeal, baking powder, and baking soda.<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="text-indent: -0.25in;"><!--[if !supportLists]--><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Verdana; mso-fareast-font-family: Verdana;">2.<span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman'; font-size: 7pt;">&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span><!--[endif]--><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">Stir in 1 ½ cups coconut milk, the eggs (beaten) and butter (melted) until smooth and vanilla. (Stir in a little more coconut milk if batter becomes too thick. For waffles, just add 1 more egg and tbsp oil.<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="text-indent: -0.25in;"><!--[if !supportLists]--><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Verdana; mso-fareast-font-family: Verdana;">3.<span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman'; font-size: 7pt;">&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span><!--[endif]--><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">Stir in berries, bananas &amp; nuts<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="text-indent: -0.25in;"><!--[if !supportLists]--><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Verdana; mso-fareast-font-family: Verdana;">4.<span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman'; font-size: 7pt;">&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span><!--[endif]--><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">For pancakes, melt coconut oil in griddle and place over medium heat.<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="text-indent: -0.25in;"><!--[if !supportLists]--><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Verdana; mso-fareast-font-family: Verdana;">5.<span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman'; font-size: 7pt;">&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span><!--[endif]--><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">Pour 2-3 tbsp of batter into frying pan.<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="text-indent: -0.25in;"><!--[if !supportLists]--><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Verdana; mso-fareast-font-family: Verdana;">6.<span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman'; font-size: 7pt;">&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span><!--[endif]--><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">Cook 2-3 minutes, or until bubbles from on top of pancakes. Flip the pancake and cook for another 2-3 minutes.<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpLast" style="text-indent: -0.25in;"><!--[if !supportLists]--><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Verdana; mso-fareast-font-family: Verdana;">7.<span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman'; font-size: 7pt;">&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span><!--[endif]--><span style="font-family: &quot;Verdana&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 12.0pt;">For waffles, add about 1 cup of batter to a hot waffle iron and close the lid. Allow waffle to cook until steam no longer comes out of the sides or until waffle is light brown and slightly crisp. Top with fruit.</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jreNS-WUTMQ/UWy3oeQIwaI/AAAAAAAAAD8/I8m2outKg-A/s1600/pancakes.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jreNS-WUTMQ/UWy3oeQIwaI/AAAAAAAAAD8/I8m2outKg-A/s1600/pancakes.jpg" /></a></div><o:p></o:p><br />
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>