<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="essentialsforhealthyliving.com">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="177ded383052ad70875231adc449db41" url="http://essentialsforhealthyliving.com/ayurvedic-detox/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ayurvedic-detox"><![CDATA[&#160; With all of the diets, cleanses and detoxes being promoted, why did I choose to do an Ayurvedic Detox? During my studies at the Institute for Integrative Nutrition, I was exposed to a myriad of dietary theories, one of which was Ayurveda.  Ayurveda is a personalized approach to health, where understanding your unique mind-body [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a62e34dd569d804b7a0d8ea054faa1de" url="http://essentialsforhealthyliving.com/beets-picky-eaters-gall-bladders/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=beets-picky-eaters-gall-bladders"><![CDATA[What do beets, picky eaters and gall bladders have in common, you ask? As a child, there were 3 things I despised in the food realm – liver, lima beans and beets! Mom always made a fresh, home-cooked meal for dinner. In fact, I only recall eating out once in a while. It was never [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f2047b2cca596a94563a1d9e5fa8ce24" url="http://essentialsforhealthyliving.com/create-a-to-do-list/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=create-a-to-do-list"><![CDATA[It&#8217;s time to create a To-Do-List! If you already work with a To-do-list, then you are aware of its tremendous value!   In those times of overwhelm and stress go back to your list and read the items you’ve listed one by one, it will help you to focus. All you need is a simple [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="71b04b4058a1cca44f58c44619e68a76" url="http://essentialsforhealthyliving.com/effective-ways-to-manage-stress-eating/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=effective-ways-to-manage-stress-eating"><![CDATA[&#160; Do you turn to food, alcohol or nicotine for comfort when you&#8217;re stressed or anxious? What may feel comforting and soothing at the time, can make you feel worse, weigh more, and fill you with guilt in the end. If you tend to turn to food, alcohol or nicotine as a way to cope [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d980c2afc1860aa10babfc8bfc196834" url="http://essentialsforhealthyliving.com/health-benefits-in-coconut-oil/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=health-benefits-in-coconut-oil"><![CDATA[&#160; What is this nut that’s so hard to crack? Coconut is cropping up everywhere these days—coconut water, coconut flour, shredded coconut, coconut milk, coconut oil, coconut cream. When I was a young girl we’d shake them to check for water inside (an indication of a good coconut, according to my mom). The next task [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="987ab8d00e0bb0e0061601d98f2f0ba1" url="http://essentialsforhealthyliving.com/health-benefits-of-garlic/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=health-benefits-of-garlic"><![CDATA[Garlic, also known as Allium sativum, was found in Egyptian pyramids and ancient Greek temples as an offering to the Gods. Both cherished and sought for its healing powers, Hippocrates, considered the father of western medicine, was said to have used garlic to treat cancerous tumors, pneumonia, digestive disorders, as a diuretic and for other [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9c187db1df90fe11c0a1f3b895e2aa47" url="http://essentialsforhealthyliving.com/self-love-and-self-confidence/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=self-love-and-self-confidence"><![CDATA[&#160; I’ve had writer’s block for several months. I suppose because I’ve had so much going on in my own life that being able to clear my mind and allow the thoughts to freely flow sort of fell off my plate. There was a time not so long ago that I was writing 2 articles [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9c535e9a1fcac7392eb598dbf604dbd5" url="http://essentialsforhealthyliving.com/set-realistic-goals/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=set-realistic-goals"><![CDATA[It&#8217;s time to set realistic goals!   We all have them&#8230; those times when suddenly everything has be worked on and completed NOW, and then&#8230; &#8230; someone asks for help  &#8212; “I hate to ask you for this favor cause I know you’re really busy, but, would you mind helping me with&#8230;”. You cringe and smile, [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e419462c13481bbbff6e79d67867044a" url="http://essentialsforhealthyliving.com/thanksgiving-2013/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=thanksgiving-2013"><![CDATA[I woke up at 5am this morning.  Made coffee and fed the cats – my usual routine.  I always enjoy the quiet solitude of early mornings. It’s crisp and clear outside with birds bathing in the waterfall and squirrels gathering acorns and berries. Haven’t seen the quail for several days &#8211; we have about 30 [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="cc8b09a7d94d5b84a776f412ca51c92" url="http://essentialsforhealthyliving.com/what-exactly-is-a-healthy-lifestyle/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=what-exactly-is-a-healthy-lifestyle"><![CDATA[&#160; &#8230; Before you can be something, or practice something, you need to define what that SOMETHING is. Make sense? There’s a lot of talk these days about getting healthy, eating healthy, being healthy, etc.  The World Health Organization (WHO) defined health as,  &#8220;a state of complete physical, mental, and social well-being; not merely the [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>
