<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="monikamcgillicuddy.com/wordpress">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="ab9fd2ce45a6d191fed621b47ffd73b0" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~3/4olrCJiY6P8/"><![CDATA[ We are very excited to announce we will be known as Berkshire Hathaway HomeServices Verani Realty on January 22nd 2014 Jay and I are thrilled to be affiliated with a brand that is respected worldwide, that has a vision and a mission that aligns with our core beliefs and is headed by a man who [&#8230;]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~4/4olrCJiY6P8" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a571c01bee6c072b20610544edac99d2" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~3/brYuyzr3YTk/"><![CDATA[Hampton NH Holiday Parade It&#8217;s a Vintage Hampton NH Christmas Parade this year&#8230;so think an old- fashioned holiday theme. The parade starts at 1:00pm at the North Hampton- Hampton town line on Dec 7th. A Vintage Christmas and Motorcycles The parade this year, has sure had it&#8217;s share of controversy. Mainly over the decision to [&#8230;]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~4/brYuyzr3YTk" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bd51fb377d806457e1146f6e110835" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~3/cKUkqWOQ7wI/"><![CDATA[15th Annual Special Olympics Penguin Plunge Walking Dead&#8230; err Wet is so apropos. I don&#8217;t know how cold the Atlantic ocean will be next weekend but the winter weather has been unseasonably frigid and I can not imagine anyone jumping into the ocean no matter what the reason!  I guess I am just too in [&#8230;]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~4/cKUkqWOQ7wI" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9e829084f12aec1f74430edea34d3f64" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~3/ec1F2JcnMns/"><![CDATA[Londonderry, N.H., (January 16, 2014) – Verani Realty announced today it finished 2013 as the No. 1 real estate brokerage in New Hampshire in units sold and total volume. Verani Realty agents closed over 3,000 transactions in 2013 and ended the year with a significant share of the New Hampshire real estate market. “Our formula [&#8230;]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~4/ec1F2JcnMns" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a8ed3abbe1e6dd84a1d250dbb2c6fd13" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~3/IxlKFd6gdOw/"><![CDATA[Hampstead New Hampshire Christmas Parade Celebrates 75th anniversary of the Fire Department This year Hampstead NH will step back in time&#8230;. all the way to 1938 as the Fire Department celebrates their 75th anniversary. So nostalgia  is the name of game, as the theme this year is Christmas in 1938.  The parade kicks off on [&#8230;]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~4/IxlKFd6gdOw" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b02f2ba740b11969aeef50a2263549f6" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~3/jA9graMUerI/"><![CDATA[Windham NH Real Estate Market Report As you can see, Windham&#8217;s real estate market is strong. Inventory is up 9.2% over a year ago, Oct. 2012 vs Oct. 2013. It is down 6.6% over a month ago. Inventory is up 2.7% from August through October of this year as compared to last year. Pending Home [&#8230;]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~4/jA9graMUerI" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3a50533869b02c6dd2b807bb73e3ba47" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~3/RN38jiZh-e4/"><![CDATA[Windham NH Real Estate Market Report As you can see, Windham&#8217;s real estate market is strong. Inventory is down 19.2% over a year ago, December 2012 vs December 2013. It is down 20.8% over a month ago. Inventory is down 6.8% from October through December of this year as compared to last year. Pending Home [&#8230;]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~4/RN38jiZh-e4" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7af7a32fa8e6acf47283b338c3b9fb72" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~3/XgoT2dFygpI/"><![CDATA[Hampstead NH Real Estate Market Report As you can see, Hampstead&#8217;s real estate market is still strong. Inventory is down 30.0% over a year ago, Oct. 2012 vs Oct. 2013. It is down 3.4% over a month ago. Inventory is down 29.8% from August through October of this year as compared to last year. Pending [&#8230;]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~4/XgoT2dFygpI" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2c086b0fac90cdf6f52c745f4beddcf1" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~3/yIoAuVqvoHY/"><![CDATA[Hampstead NH Real Estate Market Report Inventory is down 20.0% over a year ago, December. 2012 vs December 2013. It is up 16.7% over a month ago. Inventory is down 25.0% from October through December of this year as compared to last year. Pending Home Sales Up Again Pending sales are up 20.0% over a [&#8230;]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~4/yIoAuVqvoHY" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fa5ccfff2603bed5db7f9779c8a77fbf" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~3/zKK73u-JO-k/"><![CDATA[Hampstead NH Real Estate Market Report Inventory is down 27.3% over a year ago, November. 2012 vs November 2013. It is down 14.3% over a month ago. Inventory is down 32.5% from September through November of this year as compared to last year. Pending Home Sales Down Pending sales are down 54.5% over a month [&#8230;]<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/monikamcgillicuddy/kGqI/~4/zKK73u-JO-k" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>