<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="www.heimsath.com/blog-0">
	<documents count="25">
		<document id="7b9c801516bde124be1f6a7052b5685e" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/100895/Architectural-Watercolor-Prompts-Questions-During-Tour-of-Spain"><![CDATA[<p><img id="img-1376261362161" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Architectural Watercolor Sa Jeronomo.jpeg" alt="Architectural Watercolor Sa Jeronomo" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0">What draws American architects to Europe, generation after generation?</p>
<p>This question came to mind as we were leaving Madrid for Chicago, a long flight home after travel in Spain and Portugal. Maryann and I celebrated our 57th wedding anniversary with a tour around the coast of Spain and France.&nbsp; We’ve been able to see much of Europe over many trips, but this was our first visit to Granada, Seville, Lisbon, Santiago de Compostela, Bilbao, Madrid and Toledo.<br><br>We’ve loved our past visits to Spain.&nbsp; Our most recent trip introduced us to Barcelona. However, decades earlier, we spent a year in Rome on a Fulbright Scholarship, so we know much more about Italy.&nbsp; We’d been looking forward to this tour, a boat trip around the Spanish coast, as a chance to expand our understanding of the culture, and of course, the architecture.<br><br><img id="img-1376261035340" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Architectural Watercolor Lisbon Gate.jpeg" alt="Architectural Watercolor Lisbon Gate" class="alignLeft" style="float: left;" border="0" height="295" width="222">In the 19th century the Grand Tour was essential education for American architects. For several generations, the study European architecture brought first-hand knowledge of great architectural monuments – inspirations for the classical designs eagerly desired by American patrons and practitioners.&nbsp; This era gave way to the modern movement. And while there are a number of modernist icons worth a visit, the typical itinerary for American architects continues to favor the old grand monuments.&nbsp; Why then do architects keep going back when supposedly the design world has moved on?<br><br>One answer may be in the relative young age of our monumental buildings.&nbsp; The incredible Toledo Cathedral, the third largest religious structure after St Peters in Rome and Westminster Abbey in London, was completed in 1492. The Toledo Cathedral took 300 years to complete - the aspiration of generations of sponsors, architects, stone-masons and craftsmen. <br><br>For an architect, the skill and commitment required to produce such a structure is overpowering to consider. Each stone was quarried, moved, hoisted in<img id="img-1376261090724" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Architectural Watercolor Toledo Cathedral Ext.jpg" alt="Architectural Watercolor Toledo Cathedral Ext" class="alignRight" style="float: right;" border="0" height="451" width="370"> place with technologies in practice before Columbus even left Spain for the New World.<br><br>In the hours I spent painting a watercolor of the Toledo Cathedral, I noted the distinct features the evidenced various periods of design. For example the tower began with a square footprint reflecting Moorish architecture of the time.&nbsp; The top was added later - with Gothic and Baroque ornamentation.&nbsp; <br>This is fascinating for an architect.<br><br>Studying historic structures is recognizing the scale and proportion of each element, working together to create a whole.&nbsp; In doing the watercolor of the Cathedral I noted that the two arched openings at the top of the rectangular tower are reflected by three rows of pilasters cascading down the tower above a solid base. And the various periods are reflected at the entry. The Gothic portico is superimposed in front of an earlier higher volume behind.<br><br>Our plane home was halfway across the Atlantic when more of the pull of Europe came to mind.&nbsp; I have always been interested in curvilinear forms. Looking around on the 747 and it is an interior filled with curved wonder. I made a connection; the freedom to work with non-linear shapes isn’t entirely new.&nbsp; Days earlier, I had just finished watercolors of two curvilinear buildings in Europe<img id="img-1376261161611" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Architectural Watercolor San Michael.jpeg" alt="Architectural Watercolor San Michael" class="alignLeft" style="float: left;" border="0" height="287" width="225">.<br>&nbsp; <br>In Madrid we discovered San Miguel, a Counter Reformation Jesuit church with its curved façade, as if the church were bursting out onto the street.&nbsp; This design uses one-dimensional curves, that is the curves are generated by a single axis.<br>&nbsp; <br>The other curvilinear building was a new one, Frank Gerry’s Guggenheim Museum in Bilbao.&nbsp; I painted a scene from above.&nbsp; The Guggenheim is curvilinear but designed using double curvatures, that is, curves generated by multiple axes. In the U S I could see Frank Gerry buildings but could not compare them with facades designed in a different age and aesthetic.<br>&nbsp;<img src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Architectural Watercolor Gugenheim Bilbao.jpg" alt="Architectural Watercolor Gugenheim Bilbao" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0"><br><img id="img-1376261336896" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Architectural Watercolor M &amp; C on the Boat.jpg" alt="Architectural Watercolor M&amp;C on the Boat" class="alignLeft" style="float: left;" border="0" height="132" width="104">As we landed in Chicago, I relished the thought that I was back in only one day, not the weeks of sailing it took 19th century architects to cross the Atlantic.&nbsp; I was home full of creative ideas, happy to share some of my watercolors with the next generation interested in architecture.<img id="img-1376261221540" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Architectural Watercolor Sea Cloud II.jpeg" alt="Architectural Watercolor Sea Cloud II" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0" height="290" width="369"><br><br>&nbsp;<br><br></p>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/100895/Architectural-Watercolor-Prompts-Questions-During-Tour-of-Spain&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fa08fdea6a002271049bee7bd8bff224" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/102122/Adaptive-Reuse-for-School-in-Austin"><![CDATA[<p>Construction ha<img id="img-1380224616477" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Adaptive Reuse School Austin-resized-600.jpg" alt="Adaptive Reuse School construction" class="alignLeft" style="float: left;" height="249" border="0" width="187">s begun on the newest elementary school in Austin, and most of the work is indoors.&nbsp; The new school is an adaptive reuse of an empty commercial building, an innovative solution for the <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://www.austinisd.org" title="Austin Independent School District" target="_blank">Austin Independent School Distri</a></strong></span><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://www.austinisd.org" title="Austin Independent School District" target="_blank">ct</a></strong></span>.&nbsp; For the past year, Heimsath Architects, in joint venture with Architecture Plus, has been working on the conversion of an old manufacturing facility as the best location for a new school to relieve crowding in surrounding facilities.&nbsp; <br><br>When completed, the school will be the largest elementary in AISD.&nbsp; The yet unnamed campus will have classrooms on two floors, a new gym and new cafetorium all within the walls of the existing structure.&nbsp; A portion of the expansive roof will be left in place as a shade cover for an outdoor play area. &nbsp;<br><img id="img-1380225116967" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Adaptive Reuse School Central Corridor-resized-600.jpg" alt="Adaptive Reuse School Central Corridor resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" height="349" border="0" width="485"><br>The adaptive reuse school presents many green building advantages.&nbsp; Compared to a total demolition, the amount of material waste on the site has been minimal.&nbsp; The program has been designed with skylights in the tall ceilings that will bring natural light into every instructional space.&nbsp; A major investment in new roof-top solar panels will generate a substantial percentage of the school’s energy needs.&nbsp; With these, and other innovative green building elements, the District is applying for a LEED gold certification.<br><br>The architects have been working closely with the District, and with Flintco Construction.&nbsp; One of our local television reporters recently toured the construction site and produced a fine report on the early progress of turning a warehouse into a school.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.kxan.com/news/local/austin/old-warehouse-home-to-new-austin-school" target="_blank"><img id="img-1380228409942" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Adaptive reuse school news report-resized-600.png" alt="Adaptive reuse school news report resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0"></a><br><br><em>Too often people assume that demolition is the only answer when you have an older building.&nbsp; Though this project didn't include a historic property, many of the same issues confront adaptive re-use projects.&nbsp; We confront some of the major myths that perpetuate the idea that working with an older building isn't as good as new construction. Download this great resource now.<br></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span class="hs-cta-wrapper" id="hs-cta-wrapper-9c73197e-e83d-4bb4-bb50-1595bec160ce">
    <span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-9c73197e-e83d-4bb4-bb50-1595bec160ce" id="hs-cta-9c73197e-e83d-4bb4-bb50-1595bec160ce">
        <a href="http://cta-redirect.hubspot.com/cta/redirect/25951/9c73197e-e83d-4bb4-bb50-1595bec160ce"><img class="hs-cta-img" id="hs-cta-img-9c73197e-e83d-4bb4-bb50-1595bec160ce" alt="Download Historic Preservation u002D 11 Myth" style="border-width:0px;" src="https://no-cache.hubspot.com/cta/default/25951/9c73197e-e83d-4bb4-bb50-1595bec160ce.png"></a>
    </span>
    <script type="text/javascript">
        (function(){
            var s='hubspotutk',r,c=((r=new RegExp('(^|; )'+s+'=([^;]*)').exec(document.cookie))?r[2]:''),w=window;w[s]=w[s]||c,
                hsjs=document.createElement("script"),el=document.getElementById("hs-cta-9c73197e-e83d-4bb4-bb50-1595bec160ce");
            hsjs.type = "text/javascript";hsjs.async = true;
            hsjs.src = "//cta-service-cms2.hubspot.com/cs/loader.js?pg=9c73197e-e83d-4bb4-bb50-1595bec160ce&pid=25951&hsutk=" + encodeURIComponent(c);
            (document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0]||document.getElementsByTagName("body")[0]).appendChild(hsjs);
            try{el.style.visibility="hidden";}catch(err){}
            setTimeout(function() {try{el.style.visibility="visible";}catch(err){}}, 2500);
        })();
    </script>
</span></div>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/102122/Adaptive-Reuse-for-School-in-Austin&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1c2ac42ec1198ca11ad355549f9fefce" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/103671/Architectural-Design-Process-Shared-Faith-Form-Article"><![CDATA[<br><address>The national journal, Faith &amp; Form, published Ben Heimsath's article "A Shared Process of Creation."&nbsp; He wrote about the architectural design process as a collaborative venture.&nbsp; A design created in a truly shared process has the potential to express a unique sense of spirituality.&nbsp; The journal does not post on-line, so the editor has given us permission to copy the published article for download.&nbsp;</address>&nbsp;
<div style="text-align: center;"><span class="hs-cta-wrapper" id="hs-cta-wrapper-92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7">
    <span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7" id="hs-cta-92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7">
        <a href="http://cta-redirect.hubspot.com/cta/redirect/25951/92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7"><img class="hs-cta-img" id="hs-cta-img-92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7" alt="Download Faithu0026ampu003BForm Article" style="border-width:0px;" src="https://no-cache.hubspot.com/cta/default/25951/92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7.png"></a>
    </span>
    <script type="text/javascript">
        (function(){
            var s='hubspotutk',r,c=((r=new RegExp('(^|; )'+s+'=([^;]*)').exec(document.cookie))?r[2]:''),w=window;w[s]=w[s]||c,
                hsjs=document.createElement("script"),el=document.getElementById("hs-cta-92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7");
            hsjs.type = "text/javascript";hsjs.async = true;
            hsjs.src = "//cta-service-cms2.hubspot.com/cs/loader.js?pg=92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7&pid=25951&hsutk=" + encodeURIComponent(c);
            (document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0]||document.getElementsByTagName("body")[0]).appendChild(hsjs);
            try{el.style.visibility="hidden";}catch(err){}
            setTimeout(function() {try{el.style.visibility="visible";}catch(err){}}, 2500);
        })();
    </script>
</span></div>
<address>&nbsp;</address><address>A shortened version of the article is reformatted for the current blogpost.&nbsp;</address>
<h4>A SHARED PROCESS OF CREATION</h4>
<p>Can we determine whether a new or renovated environment built for prayer is going to convey a sense of spirituality?&nbsp; I believe we can if a congregation has a highly engaged process whereby this fundamental goal is shared equally by the architects and the community.&nbsp; In more than 30 years of work with faith groups, our firm has developed a process for design and project implementation based on our belief that groups can find spirituality as they share in the creative design process.</p>
<p><img id="img-1385871015394" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Architectural-Design-Process-Unity-DRW.jpg" border="0" alt="describe the image" width="547" height="398" style="height: 398px; width: 547px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;">This highly interactive process includes the collaborative session that we call a Design Retreat Workshop.&nbsp; We utilize many established community design principles whereby people are actively engaged in the design process.&nbsp; Held in a neutral setting, the Design Retreat Workshop includes components of both a leadership forum and a problem-solving charette. However, unlike these traditional formats, the event is compressed into one day, and the architects and congregation leaders participate equally in generating design ideas.&nbsp; The goal for the session is simple: everyone present must feel that the group, in the end, has developed one solution that is the "best." A major advantage of this early engagement of the congregation leaders is that the creative interaction continues throughout the rest of the building process. Many significant contributions come from ideas generated or refined from the Design Retreat Workshop.</p>
<p>Journalist James Surowiecki wrote "The Wisdom of Crowds" to explore the extensive economic and sociological research documenting numerous ways that groups of people, large and small, outperform even the most talented individuals in predicting and problem solving.&nbsp; Surowiecki however, offers little insight into the reason this happens. When individuals gather together and find a connection or common purpose, the experience can become so tangible that it may be felt or expressed as an actual presence in the group. In the course of many of our Design Retreat Workshops, this energy has been called many things; the “Holy Spirit,” “God’s Presence,” or a similar expression appropriate to the various religious traditions that have participated. These creative design experiences seem to embody the genius of communal worship. Each experience is remarkably similar, regardless of what it is called.</p>
<br>
<h4>Unity Church of the Hills</h4>
<p>A case study of the Unity Church of the Hills in Austin, Texas, illustrates the process with the creation of a successful spirit-filled environment. This project involved the relocation of the church to a new, undeveloped site. The process for Unity's design and implementation typifies our approach to working with congregations and provides an opportunity for commentary.</p>
<p>In 1999 two-dozen congregation leaders assembled at a local restaurant reserved for the Design Retreat Workshop. Structured discussions focused on what made the two-and-a-half-year-old ministry special. Participants assessed information from a previous small group tour of the existing facilities that helped to generate priorities for the new 14-acre site. The morning exchanges helped to identity the spirit that members felt within the congregation. While many groups describe this spirit through stories of their history, the Unity Church group stressed the connections members already had made with the undeveloped property. One participant shared his revelation when he saw the seller's name, Guthrie O'Donnell, abbreviated as "G O'D" on the subdivision documents. Nearly everyone described a feeling of peacefulness under the canopy of trees even though buildings surrounded the property on all sides.</p>
<p>In the afternoon session, the architects explained that the group should consider itself the authors of the final design. The architects noted that they would be refining the concept, but the basic plan would emerge from this retreat. The Unity participants were separated into brainstorming groups and asked to work with one of the architects to imagine as many solutions as possible. As the brainstorming wrapped up, 11 sketches adorned the walls.</p>
<p>Two preferred plans located buildings in the same clearing near the center of the site. They both featured circular plans for the <img id="img-1385871437629" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Architectural-Design-Process-Unity DRW sketch-resized-600.JPG" border="0" alt="Architectural Design Process Unity DRW sketch resized 600" width="250" height="173" class="alignLeft" style="float: left;">sanctuary. The architects explained that the circle is associated with sacred geometries, and that Renaissance builders saw the circle as a perfect form. The ministers noted that the circle is a powerful symbol in the Unity theology. One plan showed a large entry arch over the narrow drive connecting to the main commercial street. The other featured a masonry wall that parted to emphasize the transition from the parking area to the interior of the site.</p>
<p>The architects suggested ways to merge the two solutions. The entry arch and the parted stone wall could both be used to create a path symbolic of the spiritual journey towards worship. The building placement and the circular sanctuary shown on both plans could become an octagonal plan.<img id="img-1385871590629" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Architectural-Design-Process-Unity-Plan-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Architectural Design Process Unity Plan resized 600" width="298" height="238" class="alignRight" style="float: right;"></p>
<p>The session ended with an affirmation by each participant that the group had developed an inspired design for the property. The ministers, in their closing prayer, cited Unity teaching in describing the powerful goodness of God that had been present in the day's proceedings. The plan sketch from the Design Retreat Workshop closely resembles the completed building, featuring an octagonal sanctuary that stands on the site today.</p>
<p>The collaborative process continued to produce fruitful results. Only four trees were removed to accommodate the parking, drives, and building. The entry arch concept violated numerous codes, but variances were approved unanimously by city agencies.<img id="img-1385871770577" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Architectural-Design-Process-Unity Exterior-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Architectural Design Process Unity Exterior resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<h4>Sharing the Spirit</h4>
<p>Most architects are not trained to share the design process with groups. They often see creativity as an individual effort that is only compromised by outside participation. This approach can cause strained relationships particularly when the client is a church or spiritual community. This unwillingness to share seems particularly incongruous, considering how many architects equate the creative spark with divinity, even suggesting the process of design creativity as a metaphor for understanding God.</p>
<p>Theologically, most contemporary denominations don't believe their buildings contain God. Rather, they share some form of the belief that God is present when "two or more are gathered in God's name." As the Unity process illustrates, something special also happens when people gather to design in God's name. The sense of spirituality so greatly appreciated by the congregation today has its roots in the spirituality experienced by its members as they engaged in the process of creating it.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<address>Read the entire article as published in Faith &amp; Form - download it now.</address><address>&nbsp;</address>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span class="hs-cta-wrapper" id="hs-cta-wrapper-92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7">
    <span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7" id="hs-cta-92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7">
        <a href="http://cta-redirect.hubspot.com/cta/redirect/25951/92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7"><img class="hs-cta-img" id="hs-cta-img-92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7" alt="Download Faithu0026ampu003BForm Article" style="border-width:0px;" src="https://no-cache.hubspot.com/cta/default/25951/92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7.png"></a>
    </span>
    <script type="text/javascript">
        (function(){
            var s='hubspotutk',r,c=((r=new RegExp('(^|; )'+s+'=([^;]*)').exec(document.cookie))?r[2]:''),w=window;w[s]=w[s]||c,
                hsjs=document.createElement("script"),el=document.getElementById("hs-cta-92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7");
            hsjs.type = "text/javascript";hsjs.async = true;
            hsjs.src = "//cta-service-cms2.hubspot.com/cs/loader.js?pg=92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7&pid=25951&hsutk=" + encodeURIComponent(c);
            (document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0]||document.getElementsByTagName("body")[0]).appendChild(hsjs);
            try{el.style.visibility="hidden";}catch(err){}
            setTimeout(function() {try{el.style.visibility="visible";}catch(err){}}, 2500);
        })();
    </script>
</span></div>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/103671/Architectural-Design-Process-Shared-Faith-Form-Article&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9da85666fe92cf42a41582e8f1102892" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/103905/Chapel-of-the-Holy-Cross-Proves-Architectural-Ideas-Take-Time"><![CDATA[<p>How did an unrealized design concept for an urban cathedral eventually give rise to a desert chapel?&nbsp; Some architectural ideas take a long time to develop, but this one really took some interesting twists and turns. This fall, I visited the <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://aplusd.org/exhibitions-future/neverbuilt" title="Never Built:&nbsp; Los Angeles" target="_blank">Never Built:&nbsp; Los Angeles</a></span></strong> show at the A+D Architecture &amp; Design museum in Los Angeles.&nbsp; I was surprised to discover an early, though vastly different, antecedent to the Chapel of the Holy Cross.&nbsp; This intimate chapel is a major icon of modernist architecture and spiritual design, but evidence suggests it started with an idea for a soaring skyscraper.&nbsp; It took several decades, but this architectural idea eventually did get built, and in a very different form.&nbsp; The tower was planned for Los Angeles, but the idea eventually came to fruition in the deserts of Arizona!</p>
<p><img id="img-1386767872946" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Chapel_of_the_Holy_Cross_(Sedona,_Arizona),_exterior_and_landscape-resized-600.jpg" alt="Chapel of the Holy Cross (Sedona, Arizona), exterior and landscape resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0"></p>
<p>According to a wonderful piece on the <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://www.gatewaytosedona.com/popular-articles/item/31-sedona-arizona-landmark-the-chapel-of-the-holy-cross" title="Gateway to Sedona" target="_blank">Gateway to Sedona</a></strong></span> website, the story began in 1930 when, in New York City, a young heiress saw one of the newly built skyscrapers and envisioned the façade with a soaring cross superimposed upon it.&nbsp; Marguerite Staude was a devout Catholic raised in California.&nbsp; She commissioned Lloyd Wright, the son of Frank Lloyd Wright, to realize her vision with a design for a new Cathedral Tower in Los Angeles.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img id="img-1386734008941" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Holy Cross Chapel-Cathedral Tower precedent-resized-600.jpg" alt="Holy Cross Chapel Cathedral Tower precedent resized 600" class="alignLeft" style="float: left;" border="0" height="257" width="181">Evocative sketches for the 50-story tower were on display at the A+D exhibit, along with a much less expressive model constructed from lego blocks.&nbsp; The architect’s roughed-out drawings show a Greek-cross plan of a 4-sided tower.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;Each of the identical facades is formed to feature the massive cross that runs the entire height of the building.&nbsp;&nbsp; Though a site was never selected for the project, the gargantuan size of these crosses would have been hard to miss.&nbsp; For comparison, Houston’s celebrated Transco Tower (now the Williams Tower) is 64 stories.&nbsp; One of Philip Johnson’s late career designs, its iconic image can be seen for miles.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The exhibit notes offers a short explanation that the Archbishop of the LA Diocese rejected the offer and the project was abandoned.&nbsp; No mention is made of any other projects or relationships.&nbsp; Frankly, discovering the connection with the Holy Cross Chapel took some additional research and came as a complete surprise.&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;<img id="img-1386734158681" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Holy Cross Chapel-Cathedral Tower Sketches-resized-600.jpg" alt="Holy Cross Chapel Cathedral Tower Sketches resized 600" class="alignRight" style="float: right;" border="0" height="333" width="251"></p>
<p>According to the LA Times 1988 obituary, Marguerite Staude went on to become an artist and sculptor in her own right.&nbsp; She was also recognized as a patron for the arts.&nbsp; The obituary mentioned the Holy Cross Chapel, but said nothing of the Cathedral design.&nbsp; One look at the Chapel exterior makes it clear that the idea of a dominant cross-form superimposed over a building facade are related.&nbsp; Having the same patron makes the connection even more direct.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>But the links between the two projects are more than circumstantial as the idea nearly took form in Europe.&nbsp; A conversation with Anat Geva, professor of architecture at Texas A&amp;M and an authority on sacred architecture, confirmed the next twist in this story.&nbsp; After getting rejected in LA, Marguerite commissioned Lloyd Wright to develop her vision for a congregation of nuns in Hungary.&nbsp; Plans were underway when World War II brought the program to a halt.&nbsp; In the years after the war, Marguerite decided to focus on her adopted state of Arizona, so the monastery project, like the tower, was abandoned.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Sometimes, the historic trail takes a false turn.&nbsp; As I dutifully checked the Wikipedia page on the Holy Cross Chapel, the history noted that Lloyd Wright’s father, Frank Lloyd Wright, was the one Marguerite turned to when she tried to build in Hungary.&nbsp; But the conversation with Professor Geva put this notion to rest.&nbsp; “I lectured on the Chapel just recently.&nbsp; Lloyd Wright, did both the previous designs, and Stuade really wanted him to do the Chapel.”&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Apparently, Lloyd Wright wasn’t interested in the Arizona chapel project when Marguerite approached him in the 1950’s.&nbsp; So the work of fulfilling her life-long vision was imparted to the San Francisco firm of Anshen and Allen, where project architects Richard Hein and August Strotz finally developed a concrete reality for Marguerite’s long-held vision.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;The selection of the site was also quite a story.&nbsp; Eventually, with the help of Sen. Barry Goldwater, the Chapel was built on National Park land in the Coconino National Forrest.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This time, the local Catholic Diocese accepted her project.&nbsp; A nearby parish continues to maintain and administer the Holy Cross Chapel and holds some worship services there.&nbsp; The chapel is non-denominational and has become a popular pilgrimage site for tourists and seekers of all denominations.&nbsp;</p>
<p><img id="img-1386736966396" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/800px-Chapel_of_the_Holy_Cross-resized-600.jpg" alt="Chapel-of-the-Holy-Cross" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0" height="308" width="411">&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Chapel is designed with a precise, distinctively modernist exterior that is juxtaposed against weathered rocks of the canyon wall.&nbsp; But it is the singular, concrete cross that dominates.&nbsp; The cross rises between two rock formations, as though a force from heaven planted it there.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Never Built: Los Angeles show did remind me of an early lesson from my days in architecture school.&nbsp; I recall hearing at least one critic say, “that’s a good idea, but not for this program.&nbsp; Why not save it for the next project?”&nbsp; From even the few sketches of the Cathedral Tower, it is clear that the concept may have been a bold idea, but it didn’t make sense for a Cathedral.&nbsp; There was no indication of a worship space, and the Diocese would have little or no use for what must have been 50 floors of offices.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Eventually, decades later, the Diocese of Los Angeles did build a new cathedral, the <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://www.olacathedral.org" title="Cathedral of the Angels" target="_blank">Cathedral of the Angels</a></strong></span>.&nbsp; It has a warm and beautifully proportioned interior worship space, and a modest wing for the Diocesean offices (not nearly a tower's worth of offices).&nbsp; I did notice one element on the exterior façade, a simple panel of stone with a superimposed cross, that does reminded me of Holy Cross Chapel.&nbsp; I can only speculate, but perhaps Rafeal Moneo was influenced, if somewhat indirectly, by the image of the Holy Cross Chapel when he designed the exterior of the Cathedral of the Angels.&nbsp; Perhap’s Margurite Staub’s vision did have an influence on the LA Cathedral after all.<img id="img-1386767535138" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/640px-Cathedral_of_Our_Lady_of_Angels,_Los_Angeles-resized-600.JPG" alt="640px Cathedral of Our Lady of Angels, Los Angeles resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0" height="280" width="380"></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<address>How do you create a spiritual place? Ben Heimsath writes about his own convictions for a successful design process in his recent article in Faith&amp;Form magazine.&nbsp; Download the article now.</address><address>&nbsp;</address>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span class="hs-cta-wrapper" id="hs-cta-wrapper-92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7">
    <span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7" id="hs-cta-92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7">
        <a href="http://cta-redirect.hubspot.com/cta/redirect/25951/92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7"><img class="hs-cta-img" id="hs-cta-img-92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7" alt="Download Faithu0026ampu003BForm Article" style="border-width:0px;" src="https://no-cache.hubspot.com/cta/default/25951/92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7.png"></a>
    </span>
    <script type="text/javascript">
        (function(){
            var s='hubspotutk',r,c=((r=new RegExp('(^|; )'+s+'=([^;]*)').exec(document.cookie))?r[2]:''),w=window;w[s]=w[s]||c,
                hsjs=document.createElement("script"),el=document.getElementById("hs-cta-92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7");
            hsjs.type = "text/javascript";hsjs.async = true;
            hsjs.src = "//cta-service-cms2.hubspot.com/cs/loader.js?pg=92a3b669-950b-4b97-be4d-412e974faca7&pid=25951&hsutk=" + encodeURIComponent(c);
            (document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0]||document.getElementsByTagName("body")[0]).appendChild(hsjs);
            try{el.style.visibility="hidden";}catch(err){}
            setTimeout(function() {try{el.style.visibility="visible";}catch(err){}}, 2500);
        })();
    </script>
</span></div>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/103905/Chapel-of-the-Holy-Cross-Proves-Architectural-Ideas-Take-Time&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="720e9a155201937d695e3a1c37f13403" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/83432/The-Church-and-Development-What-s-Missing-Here"><![CDATA[<p>After the 2<sup>nd</sup> World War, many cities in Europe were rebuilt as New Towns.&nbsp; These developments were based on many of the principals of the <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Garden_City_Movement">Garden City Movement</a></strong></span>, promoted by <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ebenezer_Howard">Ebenezer Howard</a></strong></span>.&nbsp; These New Towns became an important precedent for American suburbs, though most often without the encumbrances of the European regulatory environment.&nbsp; But we missed one thing the Europeans got right.&nbsp; The church and development were planned together in many New Towns.&nbsp; American planners, sadly, have given little or no thought to the role of the church in their new communities.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">&nbsp;<img id="img-1336792107903" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Churches-and-development-st-paul's-harlow-street-view-resized-600.png" border="0" alt="Churches and development st paul%27s harlow street view resized 600" width="570" height="479" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /><em>The church is in the center of an New Town in England.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">In the early 1960's, I was a consultant to a NASA research effort to apply space energy technology to the design of urban communities.&nbsp; I was privileged to visit several model European New Towns as they expanded or continued construction.&nbsp; Though we were studying the energy conservation and generating technologies (a generation before our green building movement!),&nbsp; I noted how planners placed&nbsp;churches right in the center of the town.&nbsp; Planners had carefully laid out the commercial downtown and right in the center, a place was reserved for the church.&nbsp; St Paul&rsquo;s Church in the New Town of Harlow in Sussex, Great Britain, for example, is a focal point of the new downtown.</p>
<p><img id="img-1336792982423" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/churches-and-development-St.-Paul's-Church,Harlow-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="churches and development St. Paul%27s Church,Harlow resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>St. Paul's Harlow Towne Centre</em>.</p>
<p><br />There have been a few exceptions.&nbsp; In the 1960s, the planners for the New Town of Columbia Maryland located <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.themeetinghouse.org/concept.htm" title="interdenominational chapels" target="_blank">interdenominational chapels</a></span></strong> in the city center.&nbsp; But the majority of new developments to this day give scant consideration of the church or its role in the life of a community.</p>
<p><br />The typical planning and zoning process places major uses, retail, offices, multi-family and single family together.&nbsp; The church doesn't automatically fit in any one of these, but may be designed to relate to any of them.&nbsp; In some instances, church lots are placed at the edge of a housing area, but often as an afterthought, with little connection to other community resources.&nbsp; Developers are giving considerable attention to amenities such as parks, jogging trails and water features and could easily include plans for churches.&nbsp; Even the new urban settlements ignore the European model and leave churches out of their community or commercial centers. What has happens to the church in most developments is they are relegated to compete with large commercial or industrial buildings for sites along highways, or outside of the main settlement.&nbsp;</p>
<p><br />It is ironic that historically, American towns actually celebrated the location of the church.&nbsp; Nearly as many towns in America have a "Church Street," as have a "Main Street." In the Southwest, the tradition from Spanish settlement often gave the church its own plaza, or at least connected it to the civic plaza at the heart of the town.&nbsp; Another early example is in New Orleans.&nbsp; The heart of the French Quarter is St. Mark's Square, with St. Mark's Cathedral the main focus.</p>
<p><br />Years ago, Heimsath Architects designed <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.cypresscreek.cc/" title="Cypress Creek Christian Church" target="_blank">Cypress Creek Christian Church</a></span></strong> in Spring, Texas as part of an overall master plan for the Cypress Creek Municipal Center. Placement of other municipal facilities, a fire station on one side and a library on the other was designed to maximize the circulation between the city and church functions and to share parking spaces.&nbsp; Over the years, both the church and the city facilities have changed and expanded, but the basic connectivity remains at the heart of the community.&nbsp; Why can't we do more planning like this?</p>
<p><img src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/church-and-development-cypress-creek-christian-church-texas-resized-600.png" border="0" alt="church and development cypress creek christian church texas resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></p>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/83432/The-Church-and-Development-What-s-Missing-Here&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ee74a72e302e6c3c15e6b53a62225ed8" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/84205/Church-Design-Church-Lighting-Control"><![CDATA[<div>
<div><img id="img-1337368991575" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Altman Smart Track.jpg" alt="Altman Smart Track" border="0" width="955" height="716"></div>
<br>More and more we see our church clients wanting lighting control to highlight areas of the worship space. &nbsp;It could be that they want to have a different set of lights to highlight the baptism, it could be that at times they want to light up of the choir area, or maybe they want to have a dim the lights and just have light shining on the pulpit.
<div></div>
<div>Traditionally this is done in one of two ways; simple track lights or a full theatrical dimming system. &nbsp;Theatrical dimming systems give you an immense amount of control and options, but the systems cost a lot of money, are not the prettiest things in the world, and can be intimidating to the average user. &nbsp;Tracks systems give you an inexpensive product that is more attractive, but these systems give you very little control. &nbsp;Usually tracks have 1 or 2 (sometimes 3) control circuits, so your lights have to be grouped into the number of control circuits available.</div>
<div></div>
<div>We have found one possible solution to this problem, and have used it quite successfully in the last couple of projects. &nbsp;The solution is <a href="www.altmanltg.com/smart-track-lighting.htm" title="Altman Smart Track" target="_blank">Altman Smart Track</a>. &nbsp;The Altman system looks just like a track and installs just like a track (and comes in white), so it is a little more attractive than theatrical lighting. &nbsp;The ingenious part of the Altman system is that each head has its own dimming control module and the track has a communication wire in it. &nbsp;This allows each head to have an individual identification number on the control circuit which in turn allows each head to be controlled individually. &nbsp;So there is only one electrical feed and control feed to the track, but every head is independent. &nbsp;Their are options for barn doors, colored lenses, even color-changing LED heads to get the lighting you want.&nbsp;</div>
<div></div>
<div>They have control systems that then let you program different scenes by controlling each head. &nbsp;They even have touch screen panels and lighting control boards to allow the most basic novice and the most advance lighting person to use the system. &nbsp;Typically we have switched to ETC controllers because their dimming systems allow us to pick up other loads like the house lights (even if they are not dimmable) and simply and easily have control over the whole space.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Be sure to discuss your needs and budget with a design professional, full theatrical dimming may be what you need, but the Altman system can get you a lot of functionality for less money.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Tips to think about</div>
</div>
<div>
<ul>
<li>If the space is a multi-purpose space, how are you protecting the lights from balls and other items.</li>
<li>Typically, lights are placed at 45° angles horizontally and vertically from their targets. &nbsp;</li>
<li>The 45° angle means the lights are often high which means you need to think about how you will change them (especially over fixed seating). &nbsp;LEDs help with this as they have much longer lives. &nbsp;Using a dimmed incandescent can greatly extend the life of a incandescent bulb. &nbsp;We sometimes spec higher wattage lamps, so that they never need to get above 3/4 power.</li>
<li>Multiple spots on a target helps with shadows.</li>
<li>Color changing LED heads have really been improving, but you will want to be careful if you are using them to light people.&nbsp;Many of the heads now have more the just Red, Green, Blue LEDs so that you get a more natural skin color. &nbsp;Make sure you test out the heads you are looking at before purchasing a whole bunch of them.</li>
</ul>
<img src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/smart-track-lighting-series-resized-600.jpg" alt="smart track lighting series resized 600" border="0"></div>
<div>Smart Track Offers a variety of Heads for your lightiung needs.</div>
<div></div>
<div>How much do you know about lighting?&nbsp; Do you need an overview of basic terms and technologies?&nbsp; Eric MacInerney has prepared a terrific resource: Lighting Basics - What You Need To Know.&nbsp; Download now, it's free.&nbsp;</div>
<div></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span class="hs-cta-wrapper" id="hs-cta-wrapper-7f1d0bd1-af06-4b2c-bbe6-7dce6683e868">
    <span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-7f1d0bd1-af06-4b2c-bbe6-7dce6683e868" id="hs-cta-7f1d0bd1-af06-4b2c-bbe6-7dce6683e868">
        <a href="http://cta-redirect.hubspot.com/cta/redirect/25951/7f1d0bd1-af06-4b2c-bbe6-7dce6683e868" =""><img class="hs-cta-img" id="hs-cta-img-7f1d0bd1-af06-4b2c-bbe6-7dce6683e868" style="border-width:0px;" src="http://no-cache.hubspot.com/cta/default/25951/7f1d0bd1-af06-4b2c-bbe6-7dce6683e868.png"></a>
    </span>
    <script type="text/javascript">
        (function(){
            var s='hubspotutk',r,c=((r=new RegExp('(^|; )'+s+'=([^;]*)').exec(document.cookie))?r[2]:''),w=window;w[s]=w[s]||c,
                hsjs=document.createElement("script"),el=document.getElementById("hs-cta-7f1d0bd1-af06-4b2c-bbe6-7dce6683e868");
            hsjs.type = "text/javascript";hsjs.async = true;
            hsjs.src = "//cta-service-cms2.hubspot.com/cs/loader.js?pg=7f1d0bd1-af06-4b2c-bbe6-7dce6683e868&pid=25951&hsutk=" + encodeURIComponent(c);
            (document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0]||document.getElementsByTagName("body")[0]).appendChild(hsjs);
            try{el.style.visibility="hidden";}catch(err){}
            setTimeout(function() {try{el.style.visibility="visible";}catch(err){}}, 2500);
        })();
    </script>
</span></div>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/84205/Church-Design-Church-Lighting-Control&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="186d37fc6b62e7c185a7c4cf76d9c878" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/84476/Building-Restoration-After-Catastrophe"><![CDATA[<br />The <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.theatlanticcities.com/neighborhoods/2012/05/when-earthquake-meets-truly-old-buildings/2062/" title="Atlantic Cities" target="_blank">Atlantic Cities</a></span></strong> website ran photos and news this week about the earthquake in Italy.&nbsp; This strikes a chord with us in Central Texas.&nbsp; No, we don't have priceless renaissance buildings here, but we continue to grapple with major events that challenge us to re-examine our building processes and consider key issues of building restoration. &nbsp; <br />
<p><a href="http://www.theatlanticcities.com/neighborhoods/2012/05/when-earthquake-meets-truly-old-buildings/2062/" target="_blank"><img id="img-1337741303110" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Building &amp; Preservation tower fragment-resized-600.png" border="0" alt="Building Restoration Damaged Tower" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></a></p>
These sobering photos remind us to consider all aspects of construction.&nbsp; First and foremost are the life-safety issues.&nbsp; Are there lessons to be learned to reduce the chance of injury or death in a catastrophe?&nbsp; But the bigger questions have to do with the recovery.&nbsp; What can be done to help structures withstand a disaster?&nbsp; How can communities most efficiently re-build in the aftermath? &nbsp;
<p>&nbsp;</p>
Reconstructing buildings is only part of the recovery.&nbsp; How do residents regain their sense of security?&nbsp; Will the changes after the disaster be permanent?&nbsp; Will things ever feel normal again?&nbsp; Are there ways to preserve history or keep connections to the past?&nbsp;
<p><a href="http://austin.ynn.com/content/top_stories/274033/church-celebrates-triumph-over-tragedy" target="_blank"><img id="img-1337741807755" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Building%20&amp;%20Preservation-First%20Baptist%20Dripping%20Springs-resized-600.png" border="0" alt="Building Restoration First Baptist Fire" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></a></p>
&nbsp; <br />Our experience with First Baptist Church in Dripping Springs illustrates the importance of considering all aspects of recovery.&nbsp; In the wake of a tragic fire that destroyed their sanctuary, the congregation was determined to rebuild.&nbsp; With our involvement, they considered their long-term needs and opportunities.&nbsp; &nbsp; <br />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
The church chose to do more than just replace what was lost.&nbsp; They challenged themselves to build for the future.&nbsp; Their new church is bigger, better and more beautiful than ever before.&nbsp; And the congregation is thriving. &nbsp; <br />
<p><img id="img-1337741909791" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Building &amp; Preservation-First Baptist Dripping Springs copy-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Building Restoration First Baptist Steeple" width="332" height="498" class="alignLeft" style="float: left;" /></p>
The historic bell is one of the few items salvaged from the fire.&nbsp; It now hangs prominently from the soaring new steeple.&nbsp; The bell tower never was as high and prominent, but proved to be a wonderful way of preserving and improving on the past.
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/84476/Building-Restoration-After-Catastrophe&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f0fb7c766b2e192a87cbec3a46cb87f1" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/85608/Church-Design-Then-and-Now"><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img id="img-1339987580912" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Christ Episc Temple 1915 int-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Church Design - Christ Episcopal Temple 1915" width="581" height="471" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></p>
<address style="text-align: center;">Christ Episcopal Church in Temple, Texas was built in 1915.</address><address style="text-align: center;">&nbsp;</address>There are so many things that have changed in our society in the past 100 to 150 years, it's surprising that in many ways, today's church is a lot like the place of worship in the 20th, or even the 19th Century.&nbsp; In some important ways, however, church design in the 21st Century can be radically different.&nbsp; While there has been a lot of discussion recently regarding traditional versus contemporary church designs, our experience suggests that most congregations have a strong interest in both.&nbsp; Rather than choosing between two opposites, many groups celebrate their rich heritage of worship while adapting and updating to the present-day world. &nbsp;<br /><img id="img-1340193875495" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/christ episc int after-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Church Design - Christ Episcopal After Restoration" width="471" height="353" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /><address style="text-align: center;">Christ Episcopal Church in Temple, Texas, after the preservation and expansion project.</address>Among the major differences between the modern worship space and a 19th or early 20th Century church would be the technology.&nbsp; We wouldn't see electric lights or projected images in any church gathering.&nbsp; There wouldn't be any amplified music, or microphones for preachers or singers.&nbsp; There would be no air-conditioning or indoor plumbing - that means outhouses, no bathrooms!&nbsp; No one would remind you to turn off your cell phone before the service. &nbsp;<br /><br />The way a congregation used their church building would also be different.&nbsp; <br />Though a congregation would gather for Sunday service, there may be little or no other activities at the church during the week.&nbsp; You wouldn't see a large fellowship hall or large narthex or gathering space.&nbsp; At most there would be a small foyer through which everyone exited, single-file.&nbsp; &nbsp;<address><img id="img-1339988633763" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/UUMC2-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Church Design University UMC 1920's" width="339" height="268" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></address><address>&nbsp;</address><address style="text-align: center;">University United Methodist Church, Austin, Texas - image from the 1920's.</address>&nbsp;There would be no need for a parking lot.&nbsp; Most congregation members lived nearby and nearly everyone would arrive on foot.&nbsp; A few may come by carriage and even fewer may use the newest mode of transportation, the motorcar.&nbsp; In larger towns, people might arrive by street-car or train.&nbsp; And forget handicap access.&nbsp; The church front door was often up a large flight of stairs.&nbsp; The main floor level was raised up high above the street, perhaps to better catch prevailing breezes on hotter days. &nbsp;<br /><br />However, many elements would be quite familiar.&nbsp; There would be a place for reading the gospel and preaching the sermon - we'd recognize the pulpit, though we might call it an ambo.&nbsp; In many Christian churches, the sacraments would have the same meaning and the same elements - a table for the Eucharistic meal, a font for baptism.&nbsp; Today, however, the font may be greatly increased in size and prominence.&nbsp; <br /><br />Some elements have changed in subtle, but important ways.&nbsp; In the old church, the altar would most likely be against a wall and the celebrant would turn his back to the congregation as he faced it.&nbsp; Now, the altar is almost always free-standing, the symbolic table for the gathered community.&nbsp; The minister faces the congregation during the Eucharistic celebration.&nbsp; An altar rail or a rood screen in the old church defined a separation between the congregation and the ministers.&nbsp; Today, some groups may have an altar rail&nbsp; for the distribution of the Eucharist, but large openings make them less of a barrier. <br /><br />In a 19th or early 20th Century church, there would be an emphasis on music, possibly with a pipe organ, or piano and choir.&nbsp; There would be a focus on liturgical arts, in the stained glass, perhaps sculpture, or painting.&nbsp; There might be a sacred landscape, though in the old days, they might call it a Jerusalem garden. &nbsp;<address><img src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/UUMC accessible entry-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Church Desgin - University UMC accessible entery" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></address><address>&nbsp;</address><address>&nbsp;</address><address style="text-align: center;">University United Methodist Church - A new entery plaza makes the historic front door fully accessible.</address><br />We work with many congregations who are stewards of older and sometimes historic churches.&nbsp; We also work with many congregations building new places for worship.&nbsp; A key question always is to look ahead to the decades to come.&nbsp; We find the best solutions focus both the past and the future.&nbsp; This means a focus on those most timeless elements of worship, and a realistic appreciation for flexibility in order to accommodate change.
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/85608/Church-Design-Then-and-Now&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8f1527448934a2085228e0ada44ddbe1" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/86653/Master-Planning-for-Congregations-10-Essentials"><![CDATA[<address>With this post, we begin a three-part series on what it takes to produce a great Master Plan.&nbsp; If you'd like to have a copy of all 10 Essentials, you may download them now.</address><address>&nbsp;</address>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span class="hs-cta-wrapper" style=" border-width: 0px;"  id="hs-cta-wrapper-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1" data-mce-style="border-width: 0px;"> <!--HubSpot Call-to-Action Code --> <span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1" id="hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1"> <a href="http://blog.heimsath.com/master-planning---10-essentials" data-mce-href="http://blog.heimsath.com/master-planning---10-essentials"><img id="hs-cta-img-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1" src="//d1n2i0nchws850.cloudfront.net/portals/25951/e70dd8cd-960e-4156-aed8-ee6fbe418e60-1341958876442/download-master-planning-10-essentials.png?v=1341958876.72" alt="download-master-planning-10-essentials" class="hs-cta-img" style="border-width:0px" mce_noresize="1" data-mce-src="//d1n2i0nchws850.cloudfront.net/portals/25951/e70dd8cd-960e-4156-aed8-ee6fbe418e60-1341958876442/download-master-planning-10-essentials.png?v=1341958876.72" data-mce-style="border-width: 0px;"></a> </span><script type="text/javascript"> (function(){   var hsjs = document.createElement("script");      hsjs.type = "text/javascript";      hsjs.async = true;      hsjs.src = "//cta-service.cms.hubspot.com/cta-service/loader.js?placement_guid=bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1";   (document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0]||document.getElementsByTagName("body")[0]).appendChild(hsjs);   setTimeout(function() {document.getElementById("hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1").style.visibility="hidden"}, 1);   setTimeout(function() {document.getElementById("hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1").style.visibility="visible"}, 2000); })(); </script><!-- HubSpot Call-to-Action Code --> <!-- hs-cta-wrapper --></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
The Master Plan is a crucial first step when a church or religious community prepares for a building program.&nbsp; The success of the Master Plan can determine the success of all the later steps of design, fundraising and construction.<br /><br /><img id="img-1341958587231" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Hands at the table-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Master Planning for Congregations - Collaboration" width="273" height="274" class="alignRight" style="float: right;" />These 10 Essentials have come from experience with literally hundreds of churches and religious communities.&nbsp; When we develop a Master Plan, we are creating a plan for action.&nbsp; These efforts prepare a congregation for the changes and challenges they will encounter in completing a successful building project.<br /><br />1. <em>Examine ministry goals</em> -- who are we?&nbsp; Whom do we serve?&nbsp; Where are we growing now?&nbsp; Where will we need to grow?&nbsp; Many congregations or religious groups have spent considerable time and effort in determining their goals, but sometimes these conversations haven't started. &nbsp;<br /><br />The Master Plan should begin with a review of reports and other documents that clarify the group's mission.&nbsp; An important part of Master Planning is to develop an understanding of how all construction projects and future developments will reinforce the main purpose of the organization. <br /><br />2. <em>Analyze existing programs for current needs and future growth.</em>&nbsp; This analysis is specific to the kinds of spaces that are needed for each use, and the adequacy of the existing facilities in providing for them.&nbsp; Examine immediate needs, but also account for long-term growth. &nbsp;<br /><br />Consider new areas of ministry.&nbsp; Are there activities that currently use little or no space, but will need to be accommodated in the future? <br /><br />3. <em>Thorough assessment of existing buildings considering their potential for adaptive reuse.</em> What changes are needed to address code deficiencies or fix other problems?&nbsp; Would an upgrade or addition make an existing building more useful?&nbsp; Can a new use be accommodated in an existing space? <br /><br />If an existing structure is to be removed or demolished, what are the costs?&nbsp; When any major change is contemplated, consider who will be impacted by the changes or demolition.&nbsp; Have they been adequately included in the decision-making?<img id="img-1341959041412" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Master Plan Watercolor-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Master Planning for Congregations - Watercolor Presentation" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<address style="text-align: center;">Look critically at existing buildings for ways to make upgrades or changes so they can fit with and enhance the new construction.<br /><br /><br /></address>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/86653/Master-Planning-for-Congregations-10-Essentials&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="90d2dab890d26af1961f81fae106410" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/87534/Church-Design-Starts-with-a-Good-Master-Plan-More-Essentials"><![CDATA[<address>&nbsp;<em>This is the second article in a three-part series on church master planning.&nbsp; <br /></em></address><br />The success of any church design can depend on the effectiveness of the master planning process.&nbsp; Here are more of the 10 Essentials of a great Master Plan:<br /><br />4.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;<em>Community involvement program</em>.&nbsp; If your congregation doesn't support the program, it will virtually go nowhere!&nbsp; How the members bring their creativity and ideas into the process is just as important as how they will contribute financially. &nbsp;<br /><br /><img id="img-1343405689115" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Church Master Planning Participation-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Church Master Planning Participation resized 600" width="256" height="200" class="alignRight" style="float: right;" />Our firm has developed a number of ways to bring congregation members and groups of ministry leaders into the design and planning process.&nbsp; Heimsath Architect's Design Retreat Workshop and All-Church Forums have proven to be effective ways of maximizing the effectiveness of community involvement.<br /><br />Ultimately, the Master Plan is developed around those issues that most inspire the congregation to move forward, while offering solutions to problems that may get in the way.<br /><br />5.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;<em>Circulation analysis, including entry, access and connections</em>.&nbsp; This will include issues of parking and drives as well as walks, corridors and use adjacencies.&nbsp; A visitor should have a clear understanding of where to go and how to get around.&nbsp; A large gathering space is essential when groups of people are assembling or departing from large worship or fellowship gatherings.<br /><br /><img id="img-1343406098776" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Church-Master-Plan-watercolor-Good-Shepherd-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Church Master Plan watercolor Good Shepherd resized 600" width="515" height="329" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" />A good layout should minimize the need to cross drives or streets.&nbsp; Consider the surrounding neighborhood in determining the potential for improved site entry and circulation.&nbsp; Think creatively to solve major deficiencies.&nbsp; Could a new sign, a monument, or landscaping mark the entrances? Can street traffic be slowed, or can a street narrowed or closed?<br /><br />6.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;<em>Establish budget expectations</em>.&nbsp; Be conservative with your budget!&nbsp; There are many, many unknowns in the early stages of project planning, so expect that there will be changes and surprises along the way. <br /><br />What will be required for the work to proceed?&nbsp; Have uncertainties or contingencies been accounted for?&nbsp;&nbsp; The budget should include a projected amount for construction (hard-costs) and the expenses associated with development, such as architecture and engineering fees, permitting expenses etc. (soft-costs).<br /><br />We've seen a tendency in some committees to second-guess the master plan budget with comments like: "We can build a building for less than that!"&nbsp; We always hope we can beat our early budgets, and often when a project is further along, we can reduce the numbers.&nbsp; Remember that the Master Plan will set expectations for the whole building program.&nbsp; Your congregation will be delighted if you can complete the project under budget, but no one will complement you for exceeding it! <br /><em></em><address>&nbsp;</address><address><em>If you'd like to have a copy of all 10 Essentials, you may download them now.</em><em></em></address>
<p><br /><span class="hs-cta-wrapper" style="margin-right: auto; margin-left: auto;  width: 399px;  height: 36px; display: block;  border-width: 0px;"  id="hs-cta-wrapper-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1" data-mce-style="margin-right: auto; margin-left: auto; width: 399px; height: 36px; display: block; border-width: 0px;"> <!--HubSpot Call-to-Action Code --> <span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1" id="hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1"> <a href="http://blog.heimsath.com/master-planning---10-essentials" data-mce-href="http://blog.heimsath.com/master-planning---10-essentials"><img id="hs-cta-img-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1" src="//d1n2i0nchws850.cloudfront.net/portals/25951/e70dd8cd-960e-4156-aed8-ee6fbe418e60-1341958876442/download-master-planning-10-essentials.png?v=1341958876.72" alt="download-master-planning-10-essentials" class="hs-cta-img" style="border-width:0px" mce_noresize="1" data-mce-src="//d1n2i0nchws850.cloudfront.net/portals/25951/e70dd8cd-960e-4156-aed8-ee6fbe418e60-1341958876442/download-master-planning-10-essentials.png?v=1341958876.72" data-mce-style="border-width: 0px;"></a> </span><script type="text/javascript"> (function(){   var hsjs = document.createElement("script");      hsjs.type = "text/javascript";      hsjs.async = true;      hsjs.src = "//cta-service.cms.hubspot.com/cta-service/loader.js?placement_guid=bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1";   (document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0]||document.getElementsByTagName("body")[0]).appendChild(hsjs);   setTimeout(function() {document.getElementById("hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1").style.visibility="hidden"}, 1);   setTimeout(function() {document.getElementById("hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1").style.visibility="visible"}, 2000); })(); </script><!-- HubSpot Call-to-Action Code --> <!-- hs-cta-wrapper --></span><br /><br /></p>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/87534/Church-Design-Starts-with-a-Good-Master-Plan-More-Essentials&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1efd842660ff1b480f826975173b8121" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/87554/The-Essentials-of-Master-Planning-Working-With-Congregations"><![CDATA[<em>This is the final in the a three-part series on master planning with congregations.</em> &nbsp;<br><br>The success of the master plan can determine the outcome of a congregation's building program. &nbsp;The time and effort spent in master planning raises important issues early.&nbsp; Participants should help set the vision and establish realistic expectations for the building program to follow.<br><br>7.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;<em>Zoning and development codes</em>.&nbsp; What are the likely steps to<img id="img-1343445536921" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/cornerstone drw closeup-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Master Planning with Congregations-Group Participation" width="206" height="222" class="alignRight" style="float: right;"> gain approval for the first-phase and future phases of construction?&nbsp; Is rezoning, re-subdivision needed?&nbsp; Are there difficult permit issues that may require a public approval process?&nbsp; How long will these take?&nbsp; What happens if the efforts aren't successful?&nbsp; <br><br>A realistic strategy should deal with any variances or changes needed.&nbsp; Though entitlement issues can be complex, the Master Plan should explain the issues so congregation members can understand the reasons for the variances and any contingencies in case the requests are denied.<br><br>8.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;<em>Phasing recommendations</em>.&nbsp; It is highly unlikely that everything can be done all at once.&nbsp; Generally, the most pressing needs should be met in the earliest phases.&nbsp; Also show how later phases will address other needs.&nbsp; Be thoughtful about the size and cost of each phase.&nbsp; Each one should be a realistic "bite-sized" project. &nbsp;<br><br>The Phase One scope and budget may be a challenge, but it must be attainable.&nbsp; Phase One may address a range of issues, even if only small improvements can be made in some areas.&nbsp; For example, a phase-one classroom addition may include a larger room for multi-use functions until a later-phase fellowship hall can be built. &nbsp;<br><img id="img-1343445664018" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/UUMC birdseye cropped-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="UUMC birdseye cropped resized 600" width="188" height="190" class="alignLeft" style="float: left;"><br>Consider the needs of each ministry while construction is underway in each phase.&nbsp; Will temporary facilities be needed?&nbsp; If so, how might they be obtained? &nbsp;<br><br>How will the budget or fundraising impact the phasing?&nbsp; Some elements may be suggested as "extras" that might be included if fundraising goals are exceeded.<br><br>9. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;<em>Scheduling</em>. Rather than promising too much too soon, congregation leaders should set a realistic schedule for implementation.&nbsp; The building process takes time and preparation.&nbsp; Though it may be possible to speed up or "fast track" some projects, generally the trade-off is greater cost and possibly less quality. &nbsp;<br><img id="img-1343446148562" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Church Master Plan HolyTrinityWatercolor-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Master Planning with Congregations Holy Trinity Episcopal" width="458" height="287" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><br>Don't short-change the pre-construction schedule.&nbsp; This time is essential for the architects and engineers to do their work.&nbsp; Consider the time needed for meetings, focus groups and presentations so that congregation members and their needs can be included.<br><br>If there are critical dates or deadlines, how will they be accommodated?&nbsp; Has adequate time been given for obtaining approvals from the congregation or denominational boards or government agencies?&nbsp; How about the time needed for fundraising and financing?&nbsp; Make sure to explain how critical deadlines or actions can impact the start of construction or the completion of the project. <br><br>10.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;<em>Create a strong image &amp; clear presentation</em>. -- Everyone wants to know what it going to look like!&nbsp; A good presentation should include a floor plan or site plan, with one or more 3-D renderings. <br><br>Make sure to explain that the Master Plan images can't be considered final drawings, there will be lots of input and refinements when the project goes through the later design phases. All issues should be explained in sufficient detail and any contingencies noted.&nbsp; The Master Plan presentation should set the stage for accomplishing the work of implementing the program.<br><img src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Master Plan St Francis by the Sea-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Master Plan St Francis by the Sea resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><br><em>The presentation for St. Francis by the Sea on the Outer Banks in North Carolina set a clear image and expectation, contributing to the success of the building program.</em><br><br>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span class="hs-cta-wrapper" id="hs-cta-wrapper-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1">
    <span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1" id="hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1">
        <a href="http://blog.heimsath.com/master-planning---10-essentials"><img class="hs-cta-img" id="hs-cta-img-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1" style="border-width:0px;width:px;height:px;" alt="download-master-planning-10-essentials" src="//d1n2i0nchws850.cloudfront.net/portals/25951/e70dd8cd-960e-4156-aed8-ee6fbe418e60-1341958876442/download-master-planning-10-essentials.png?v=1341958876.72"></a>
    </span>
    <script type="text/javascript">
        (function(){
            var s='hubspotutk',r,c=((r=new RegExp('(^|; )'+s+'=([^;]*)').exec(document.cookie))?r[2]:(function(){var c='0123456789abcdef',s=[],i=0;for(i=0;i<32;i++)s[i]=c[Math.floor(Math.random()*0x10)];return s.join('');})()),w=window;w[s]=w[s]||c,
                hsjs=document.createElement("script"),el=document.getElementById("hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1");
            hsjs.type = "text/javascript";hsjs.async = true;
            hsjs.src = "//cta-service-cms2.hubspot.com/cs/loader.js?pg=bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1&pid=25951&hsutk=" + encodeURIComponent(c);
            (document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0]||document.getElementsByTagName("body")[0]).appendChild(hsjs);
            try{el.style.visibility="hidden";}catch(err){}
            setTimeout(function() {try{el.style.visibility="visible";}catch(err){}}, 2500);
        })();
    </script>
</span></div>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/87554/The-Essentials-of-Master-Planning-Working-With-Congregations&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b0d2d2ec5ee87a1096eb79291a72db77" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/88908/Sacred-Place-is-Home-For-The-Arts"><![CDATA[<p>In the early 1970s our firm had just completed an innovative branch library in a developing area of Northwest Houston. It was an instant community success and shortly thereafter&nbsp;the pastor of a local church, Glen Wilkerson met with me to share his vision for a new kind of church ministry.&nbsp; He wanted to create a sacred place that would also be a home for the arts.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Cypress Creek Christian Church purchased the property adjacent to the library.&nbsp; From Glen's roots in the Disciples of Christ Christian Church, the plan for the new congregation was to include arts organizations and community groups as partners from the very beginning.&nbsp; The Church would develop the property as both a place for worship and a community center.</p>
<p><img id="img-1346433405871" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/sacred-place-and-the-arts-cypress-creek-centrum-resized-600.jpg" alt="sacred place and the arts cypress creek centrum resized 600" class="alignRight" style="float: right;" border="0" height="175" width="253">This vision meant that the buildings should simultaneously serve as a ministry center for the growing church and as home for an active arts scene. We developed a design for the first building that functioned for professional theater and music performances and seamlessly switched to worship services.&nbsp; Opened in the early 1970's, the Centrum, as it was named, proved the vision could work and became a model for other shared-use facilities.&nbsp;</p>
<p>In 1989, Cypress Creek had grown to the point where both the congregation and the performance groups needed a larger venue.&nbsp; The office was called again to work with the congregation to design for the same vision at a larger scale.&nbsp;</p>
<p><img id="img-1346433491157" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Sacred-Place-for-the-Arts-Cypress-Creek-Interior-resized-600.jpg" alt="Sacred Place for the Arts Cypress Creek Interior resized 600" class="alignLeft" style="float: left;" border="0" height="324" width="225">Meeting the requirements for a high-end performance venue, including exacting acoustics, the plans needed to accommodate the Houston Symphony Orchestra.&nbsp; For church needs, the same space was designed as an inspiring and functional place for worship.&nbsp; Our program considered the subtle but important shifts necessary to transform the space from one use to another.&nbsp; Some elements were planned to remain fixed, yet were designed in such a way that they complement the secondary use.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>Today The Cypress Creek Christian Church and Community Center is used by 120 non-profit organizations annually. The original church building (renamed The Forum), continues to be used for gatherings up to 350.&nbsp;&nbsp;The new building now bears the Centrum name, and is one of the major performance venues in the North Houston area.&nbsp; The space seats 900, and hosts a regular music and performance series.&nbsp; A gallery space is reserved for art displays.&nbsp; The congregation fully uses the exact same spaces for many church activities, including many vibrant and music-filled worship services.</p>
<p>As stated on their website -&nbsp;<a href="http://www.cypresscreek.cc/content/view/21/49/" title="The Cypress Creek Christian Community Center&nbsp;" target="_blank"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>The Cypress Creek Christian Community Center&nbsp;</strong></span></a>is a unique community-partnership model for meeting the educational, humanitarian, spiritual, and cultural needs of Northwest Houston</p>
<p>In the four decades since Glen Wilkerson first met with me, Heimsath Architects has worked with many faith communities to incorporate outreach and the arts in their ministry.&nbsp; From our experience with many church and community programs, let us suggest these four key elements.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<h5>1.&nbsp; Commit to multiuse space.</h5>
<p>For the Cypress Creek design, we diagramed activities for each day of the week, from 9 AM to 10PM. We noted all church functions and all planned locations.&nbsp; It became very clear that a great deal of space was available for other non-church uses.&nbsp; More church activities would be added as the church grew, but seeing the hours and hours of unused space helped us in planning for outreach.</p>
<h5>2. Define what is sacred and what is secular.&nbsp;</h5>
<p>It is not that all spaces should separate the two, it is possible sacred and secular can be combined.&nbsp;&nbsp;It is critical, however to consider each function independently.&nbsp; Actively discuss how a place to worship God will transform to a community hall or performance venue.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>At Cypress Creek we designed&nbsp;the first building based on a&nbsp;&nbsp;“double-grid” geometric layout.&nbsp; The focus of some spaces aligns with the 90 degree axis, the focus of others are on the 45 degree grid.&nbsp; This geometry gives the space some excitement, while providing visual cues to distinguish one activity from another.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Another important detail was the placement of the cross as a distinctive cut-out shape in the garden behind the platform.&nbsp; In the early morning light, the cross is visible as the garden glows through the plate-glass windows behind the platform.&nbsp; At night, the outside is dark making the outdoor cross invisible.</p>
<h5>3.&nbsp; Circulation and signage are crucial.&nbsp;</h5>
<p>Nothing is more discouraging&nbsp;&nbsp;than pulling at a door that is locked, or entering a dark entry space and wonder where to go or where the offices are.&nbsp; Many churches have the space for the community and art activities, but they won't necessarily function the same way. With proper planning the expectations of a new visitor can be met with clear circulation.&nbsp; When clear paths and entries aren't readily available, at least use good signage.&nbsp; A person arriving for the first time shouldn't worry about getting lost or disoriented, whether they come for worship, or for the arts.</p>
<h5>4. Make the space exciting and welcoming.&nbsp;</h5>
<p>With more than forty years of constant use, the original Cypress Creek building still conveys an exterior excitement generated by the strong angles and simple geometry.&nbsp; The interior has been upgraded from time to time, but still feels fresh and inviting.&nbsp; Taking the time and effort to make a place feel and function comfortably is worth the investment.&nbsp;</p>
<p><img id="img-1346433803041" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/sacred-place-home-for-the-arts-cypress-creek-resized-600.jpg" alt="sacred place home for the arts cypress creek resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0"></p>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/88908/Sacred-Place-is-Home-For-The-Arts&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="dae8c6516d06348bf623d8094a10049" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/89717/The-Master-Plan-What-It-Does-and-Doesn-t-Do"><![CDATA[<p><img id="img-1347980899755" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Master Plan Do's and Don'ts-resized-600.jpg" alt="Master Plan Do%27s and Don%27ts resized 600" class="alignRight" style="float: right;" border="0" height="233" width="233">Start a business without a business plan?&nbsp; The fact is, you couldn't!&nbsp; No one would lend money or invest in your business unless you laid out a clear vision for the venture.&nbsp;</p>
<p>A facilities master plan is just like a business plan, it is an essential first step for any significant building program. &nbsp;<br>All too often organizations and congregations jump into a building program with no master plan at all.&nbsp; Like a business without a business plan, they're making the job ahead much more difficult and prone to failure.<br><br>People will support a project when they know the priorities, understand how resources will be invested, and when they share in the overall vision for the future. Some groups have a master plan but it's old or outmoded and doesn't convey an overall plan or vision.&nbsp; But many try to start building with no master plan at all.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Does your group or congregation need to be master planning?&nbsp; Download the 10 Essentials of a Master Plan and let us know how we can help.</em>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span class="hs-cta-wrapper" id="hs-cta-wrapper-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1">
    <span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1" id="hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1">
        <a href="http://blog.heimsath.com/master-planning---10-essentials"><img class="hs-cta-img" id="hs-cta-img-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1" style="border-width:0px;width:px;height:px;" alt="download-master-planning-10-essentials" src="//d1n2i0nchws850.cloudfront.net/portals/25951/e70dd8cd-960e-4156-aed8-ee6fbe418e60-1341958876442/download-master-planning-10-essentials.png?v=1341958876.72"></a>
    </span>
    <script type="text/javascript">
        (function(){
            var s='hubspotutk',r,c=((r=new RegExp('(^|; )'+s+'=([^;]*)').exec(document.cookie))?r[2]:(function(){var c='0123456789abcdef',s=[],i=0;for(i=0;i<32;i++)s[i]=c[Math.floor(Math.random()*0x10)];return s.join('');})()),w=window;w[s]=w[s]||c,
                hsjs=document.createElement("script"),el=document.getElementById("hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1");
            hsjs.type = "text/javascript";hsjs.async = true;
            hsjs.src = "//cta-service-cms2.hubspot.com/cs/loader.js?pg=bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1&pid=25951&hsutk=" + encodeURIComponent(c);
            (document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0]||document.getElementsByTagName("body")[0]).appendChild(hsjs);
            try{el.style.visibility="hidden";}catch(err){}
            setTimeout(function() {try{el.style.visibility="visible";}catch(err){}}, 2500);
        })();
    </script>
</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;I have seen many instances where groups who should master plan are confused or have a negative association with master planning.&nbsp; In some cases, there have been previous plans that have failed due to poor organization or unclear expectations.&nbsp; But in most cases, it seems that people just aren't clear about what a master plan does and doesn't do.&nbsp; The following list has been a useful resource to several recent clients.&nbsp; It helped them move forward by being very clear about what to expect from a master plan.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>
<h3><br>Purpose:</h3>
<p>The purpose of the master plan is to establish a conceptual framework and guidelines for the future building and development goals of the Church, Community Building or other group.</p>
<h3><br>What it Does:</h3>
<h4>Establishes a framework for change.</h4>
<p>A master plan is all about preparing for change.&nbsp; These may be drastic, or modest.&nbsp; The need for making improvements of all kinds are organized and directed into concrete proposals.</p>
<h4><br>Prioritizes program requirements.</h4>
<p>People have different interests and priorities.&nbsp; The master plan can emphasize the most important priorities based on the overall needs of the group or community. Lesser priorities, however, can be included and shown fit in the overall plan.</p>
<h4><br>Develops general design image for the development program.</h4>
<p>What will the future look like?&nbsp; How does it change what is currently in place or how will it stay the same?&nbsp; The overall architectural concept can be presented in computer 3-D and/or watercolor rendering.&nbsp; Some groups utilize a walk-through movie to present their ideas.&nbsp; See our blogpost on presentation movies.</p>
<h4><br>Considers phasing options for implementation.</h4>
<p>Everything can't be done at once.&nbsp; The first phase for construction or renovation can be presented as part of the overall master plan.&nbsp; Future phases can be shown with indications of the desired order of implementation.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>
<h4><br>Estimates general costs for future budgeting.</h4>
<p>Early estimates will be based on overall size and configuration of the projected building program.&nbsp; In the master plan stage, an actual project hasn't been refined and costs may drop or rise.&nbsp; We suggest a contingency factor be added to all projections.&nbsp; Be realistic about budgeting and include all anticipated or potential costs.</p>
<h4><br>Anticipates a strategy for permitting process.</h4>
<p>Visions for future construction has to include a realistic assessment of the permits and entitlements required.&nbsp; Approvals often take time, and a master plan should explain what's involved and how long it may take.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img id="img-1347981140369" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/The-Master-Plan-St-John-Lutheran-resized-600.jpg" alt="The Master Plan St John Lutheran resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0" height="304" width="456"></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>The Master Plan for St. John Lutheran Church used color-coding to show all the planned uses.</em></p>
<h3><br>What it Does Not Do:</h3>
<h4>Makes specific design decisions.<br><br>Ties the organization's hands.<br><br>Automatically starts a building program.<br><br>Becomes a static document.<br><br></h4>
<p style="text-align: center;"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/-aLlUBOa5Ks" frameborder="0" height="360" width="480"></iframe></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>This video was produced for Emmaus Catholic Church to present the master plan.&nbsp; We've updated it with images of the completed project.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><br></em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span class="hs-cta-wrapper" id="hs-cta-wrapper-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1">
    <span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1" id="hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1">
        <a href="http://blog.heimsath.com/master-planning---10-essentials"><img class="hs-cta-img" id="hs-cta-img-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1" style="border-width:0px;width:px;height:px;" alt="download-master-planning-10-essentials" src="//d1n2i0nchws850.cloudfront.net/portals/25951/e70dd8cd-960e-4156-aed8-ee6fbe418e60-1341958876442/download-master-planning-10-essentials.png?v=1341958876.72"></a>
    </span>
    <script type="text/javascript">
        (function(){
            var s='hubspotutk',r,c=((r=new RegExp('(^|; )'+s+'=([^;]*)').exec(document.cookie))?r[2]:(function(){var c='0123456789abcdef',s=[],i=0;for(i=0;i<32;i++)s[i]=c[Math.floor(Math.random()*0x10)];return s.join('');})()),w=window;w[s]=w[s]||c,
                hsjs=document.createElement("script"),el=document.getElementById("hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1");
            hsjs.type = "text/javascript";hsjs.async = true;
            hsjs.src = "//cta-service-cms2.hubspot.com/cs/loader.js?pg=bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1&pid=25951&hsutk=" + encodeURIComponent(c);
            (document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0]||document.getElementsByTagName("body")[0]).appendChild(hsjs);
            try{el.style.visibility="hidden";}catch(err){}
            setTimeout(function() {try{el.style.visibility="visible";}catch(err){}}, 2500);
        })();
    </script>
</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Download the 10 Essentials of a Master Plan</p>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/89717/The-Master-Plan-What-It-Does-and-Doesn-t-Do&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b4af3293eedc5656c572761a934a9623" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/89940/Residential-Sun-Shades-They-re-Inexpensive-and-They-Work"><![CDATA[In our hot, humid climate, the best way to beat the heat is to get some shade.&nbsp; For residential architecture, porches, awnings, and trellises are the classic shading devices.&nbsp; There also are tents, and canopies that use fabric materials for shading.&nbsp; A relatively new product, the sun shade, or sun sail, offers good architectural solutions that are permanent, inexpensive and very flexible.<br><br><img src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Sun-shade-underneath-resized-600.jpg" alt="Sun shade underneath resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0">For our region, traditional fabric-covered structures haven't been very popular in the past.&nbsp; Tents or canopies have been used for temporary applications, but thanks to high winds and sudden storms, they aren't permanent solutions.&nbsp; Canvass awnings or porch covers may work in other areas, but the fabrics have tended to fade or become threadbare when subject to the beat down glare of the Texas sun.&nbsp; I had a serious sun problem at my own house recently, so it was time for me to try out the new materials.<br><br>Last summer, the sun and heat were unprecedented. At the house, our side porch was exposed to relentless sun.&nbsp; Our kitchen garden soon became a graveyard of potted plants scorched by a relentless sun. <br><br>This year, in the early spring, we replaced the plants and enjoyed lush growth on the porch all spring long.&nbsp; I used the herbs regularly in my cooking and my wife's new desk had a great view of the brightly colored leaves and flowers.&nbsp; As summer approached, we were determined to keep the porch garden growing.&nbsp; We needed some shade.<br><br>There are a number of solar shade or sun sails options.&nbsp; The simplest are triangular or rectalinear-shaped with anchors at the corners.&nbsp; Unlike the traditional canvass porch or awning covers, these fabrics are woven loosely to allow some light transmission.&nbsp; Though they tend to repel water, they are not water-tight.&nbsp; We found several options that would work for our porch cover and began comparing prices on-line.<br><br>Several local companies have made fabric structures very accessible.&nbsp; They can custom-make interesting shapes for any number of applications.&nbsp; But for our porch shade, nothing could beat the prices we found for a triangle shade that looked like it would work perfectly.&nbsp; Most were in the $100 - $200 range, but we luckily found a sale and ordered a triangle sun shade for $50.00.<br><br>With some pre-planning, we located good places to anchor two of the corners on exterior walls.&nbsp; The outside point of the triangle would need a vertical post or pillar somewhere near the porch stair.&nbsp; Though we could have placed a tall post, we opted instead to bolt a metal bar onto an existing post.<br><br><img id="img-1348458576204" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Sun-shade-exterior-resized-600.jpg" alt="residential-sun-shade-exterior" class="alignLeft" style="float: left;" border="0" height="482" width="348">Now, the summer is nearly over and the sun shade has proven to be amazingly effective.&nbsp; The plants are still green -- I've enjoyed my herbs all summer long.&nbsp; The flowering plants are still thriving, though we've added several like the bougainvilla that don't mind the heat. &nbsp;<br><br>The biggest surprise, however came the moment we set up the sun shade.&nbsp; The triangle not only shaded the porch, but also blocked the sun from the wall with western exposure.&nbsp; Within minutes, the room inside felt cooler.&nbsp; The difference has been so significant, there have been days when the outside sun beat down all day, and we barely needed the air-conditioning.&nbsp; I'm rather certain we saved enough in electrical bills to more than compensate for the total installation cost of less than $100. &nbsp;<br><br>I can recommend a few pointers from what we learned in the process:<br>
<h3>Plan the anchor points carefully. &nbsp;</h3>
We noted several warnings about anchoring the sun sail to the sides of houses.&nbsp; There is significant pull on the corners, so you can't just nail or screw into the siding.&nbsp; We located two of three anchor points so that lag screws could go deep into the framing.&nbsp; For the remaining corner, we would have needed a fairly large post set deep in the ground.&nbsp; We already had some solid posts on our stair, so instead, we anchored the metal bar to one of the existing posts.
<h3>Consider how to maximize the shade.</h3>
For our porch, the worst sun comes late in the day.&nbsp; At that hour, the sun angle is very low, so we angled the sun sail to block as much sun as possible.&nbsp; A commercial establishment in our neighborhood installed a larger version of the same sun sail this summer, but they didn't adjust the angle to block the late afternoon sun.&nbsp; As a result, the structure provides very little shade when it is most needed.
<h3>Be ready to make adjustments.</h3>
Though the shade sail installs quickly, it is a tensile structure.&nbsp; The cables need to be moved around to get the sail to stay fully stretched.&nbsp; Fortunately, I had a patient helper and after several rounds of adjustments, we got the right balance of tension on each point.&nbsp; I kept turnbuckles on all the points in case there needed to be further adjustments, but so far the tension has remained constant. <br>
<h3>Have a quick release.</h3>
When the weather report called for thunderstorms with gusts up to 40 or 50 mph, I was glad we left a hook on at least one of the attachments. The sail looks pretty strong, and the anchors are solid, but hey, it’s a sail.&nbsp; I didn't want my structure taking off in the high winds. I loosened the turnbuckle from the outside anchor and rolled the sail up on the one side between the two walls to ride out the storm. &nbsp;
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<address>&nbsp; We've assembled responses to the most frequently asked questions about Residential Green Buidling.&nbsp; Download your answers here.<br><div style="text-align:center;"><span class="hs-cta-wrapper" id="hs-cta-wrapper-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740">
    <span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740" id="hs-cta-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740">
        <a href="http://www.heimsath.com/residential-green-building-faqs"><img class="hs-cta-img" id="hs-cta-img-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740" style="border-width:0px;width:px;height:px;" alt="bb6a3d7e-cc0d-4073-bdeb-566937490e9a" src="https://hubspot-hubshot.s3.amazonaws.com/hubshot/prod/12/10/05/ee16b4cc-092f-445f-8cf7-aafe7bdb4c66.png"></a>
    </span>
    <script type="text/javascript">
        (function(){
            var s='hubspotutk',r,c=((r=new RegExp('(^|; )'+s+'=([^;]*)').exec(document.cookie))?r[2]:(function(){var c='0123456789abcdef',s=[],i=0;for(i=0;i<32;i++)s[i]=c[Math.floor(Math.random()*0x10)];return s.join('');})()),w=window;w[s]=w[s]||c,
                hsjs=document.createElement("script"),el=document.getElementById("hs-cta-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740");
            hsjs.type = "text/javascript";hsjs.async = true;
            hsjs.src = "//cta-service-cms2.hubspot.com/cs/loader.js?pg=5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740&pid=25951&hsutk=" + encodeURIComponent(c);
            (document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0]||document.getElementsByTagName("body")[0]).appendChild(hsjs);
            try{el.style.visibility="hidden";}catch(err){}
            setTimeout(function() {try{el.style.visibility="visible";}catch(err){}}, 2500);
        })();
    </script>
</span></div></address>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/89940/Residential-Sun-Shades-They-re-Inexpensive-and-They-Work&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a80e5964e81800fb36e621fa7d9dc14b" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/90256/Residential-Tip-Houzz-com"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.houzz.com/projects/45420/Purple-Heron/ls=2" target="_blank"><img id="img-1353960838621" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Screen Shot 2012-11-26 at 2.05.28 PM-resized-600.png" border="0" alt="Heimsath HOUZZ page"></a></p>
<p>If you are thinking about remodeling or building a home, you ought to give Houzz.com a try.&nbsp; It is a repository of 800,000+ pictures that various people have uploaded to the site.&nbsp; With this you can browse and find spaces you like and create idea books that you can share.&nbsp; One of our recent clients used this a lot both to help her understand what she wanted and to communicate this infromation to us.&nbsp; One of the interesting things, is that the pictures she was choosing did not completely jive with some of the initial discussions we were having—especially about color.&nbsp; By reviewing the overall content of all the pictures that she liked, we were able to quickly come to a color and design scheme.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Another interesting aspect of this site is the discussions.&nbsp; Whereas most discussion are asking simple but useful questions like 'who made that light fixture' or what 'color is that on the walls', some of the questions are more in depth and you can get some good design conversations to occur.&nbsp; For example, there was a discussion about how to deal with a front door to which a responder posted a picture of the front door at Purple Heron.&nbsp; I was notified and was then able to discuss what we did and who made our door.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The numbers and variety of pictures makes this site incredibly useful, but the ideabooks and the ability to ask questions and have discussions separate it from just your average image search.</p>
<p>Here is the link to the <a href="http://www.houzz.com/projects/45420/Purple-Heron/ls=2" title="Purple Heron House" target="_self">Purple Heron House</a>, you can see the questions that have been asked.</p>
<p>Check it out, there is lots of good information to be found!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Already a HOUZZ user?</p>
<p>Please Log in and follow us. &nbsp;We will add pictures as projects complete!</p>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/90256/Residential-Tip-Houzz-com&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="36d782891415cec8b86a9966b98c8b8b" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/90501/Residential-Green-Building-Frequently-Asked-Questions"><![CDATA[Many of our clients are interested in green building but still are not sure if it is worth it.&nbsp; Here are answers to some of the most frequently asked questions about green building:<br>
<h3>&nbsp;</h3>
<h3>What is green building?&nbsp; Can it be practical?</h3>
Green building, or sustainable design, refers to a growing concern with maximizing efficiency and reducing waste and energy consumption.&nbsp; While many ideas are still in the experimental stages, there are many green building techniques that have already become established and can be considered best practices in the general building industry.<address>&nbsp;<br><img id="img-1349469280771" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Purple Heron Elevation-resized-600.jpg" alt="Residential-Green-Building-FAQ-Purple-Heron-Ext" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0" height="279" width="455"><br>The recently completed Purple Heron Residence in Austin, Texas was awared the highest 5-star rating from Austin's Green Building Program.</address><address>&nbsp;</address>The focus on green design and construction seems like a recent phenomenon, but has deep historic roots.&nbsp;&nbsp; Pioneers in places like Texas built efficiently with local materials to maximize comfort without electricity or air conditioning, and with limited heating.&nbsp;&nbsp; While innovators continue to develop a dizzying array of new products and technologies, some of the best residential green building ideas are time-honored and practical solutions.&nbsp; These have worked for hundreds, and in some cases, thousands of years.<br>
<h3>&nbsp;</h3>
<h3>Do Green Buildings have to look "high tech?"</h3>
No!&nbsp; Green building does not have a style.&nbsp; Green building is the concept of building environmentally sensitive buildings that use less energy, provide more comfortable living spaces, and use less (and less toxic) materials.&nbsp; This begins by designing your building to take advantage of and work in tune with your natural surroundings—solar, wind, trees, and topography.&nbsp; It may be a coincidence that a lot of the younger designers promoting green building have produced very contemporary homes.&nbsp; These designs can be quite beautiful, but when green features are promoted, many people get the false impression that green design must also be contemporary.<br><br>Looking at historic or traditional houses in your area will often show you what works.&nbsp; For example, in hot central Texas, we see porches that offer spaces for outdoor living while shading walls and windows.&nbsp; Many homes have high ceilings with ceiling fans, and large double-hung windows to coax in the breezes.<br><br>In northern climates, w<img id="img-1349469639423" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Residential-Green-Building-water-cistern-resized-600.jpg" alt="Residential-Green-Building-FAQ-Rainwater-Cistern" class="alignLeft" style="float: left;" border="0" height="403" width="303">here cold is an issue, steep roofs help keep snow from piling up, and smaller windows help limit drafts. &nbsp;Basements extend foundations below the frost line.&nbsp; Fireplaces (usually placed on interior walls) also help keep houses warm. &nbsp;Instead of screened porches, exterior rooms are often enclosed with glass to form 'sunrooms' for cold winter days. &nbsp;<br><br>A good architect can work with green building concepts and come up with just about any style you desire. A glass box in the Alaskan tundra may not be the best concept, but most styles can be developed and built to work efficiently and comfortably in your climate. <br><address>&nbsp;</address><address>This farmhouse has a rainwater tank that has been in use for over four decades.</address><address>&nbsp;</address><br><address>&nbsp;</address><address>&nbsp;</address><address style="text-align: center;">Can't wait for all our Green Building FAQ's?&nbsp; We've assembled responses to the most frequently asked questions about Residential Green Buidling.&nbsp; Download your answers here.</address>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span class="hs-cta-wrapper" id="hs-cta-wrapper-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740">
    <span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740" id="hs-cta-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740">
        <a href="http://www.heimsath.com/residential-green-building-faqs"><img class="hs-cta-img" id="hs-cta-img-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740" style="border-width:0px;width:px;height:px;" alt="bb6a3d7e-cc0d-4073-bdeb-566937490e9a" src="https://hubspot-hubshot.s3.amazonaws.com/hubshot/prod/12/10/05/ee16b4cc-092f-445f-8cf7-aafe7bdb4c66.png"></a>
    </span>
    <script type="text/javascript">
        (function(){
            var s='hubspotutk',r,c=((r=new RegExp('(^|; )'+s+'=([^;]*)').exec(document.cookie))?r[2]:(function(){var c='0123456789abcdef',s=[],i=0;for(i=0;i<32;i++)s[i]=c[Math.floor(Math.random()*0x10)];return s.join('');})()),w=window;w[s]=w[s]||c,
                hsjs=document.createElement("script"),el=document.getElementById("hs-cta-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740");
            hsjs.type = "text/javascript";hsjs.async = true;
            hsjs.src = "//cta-service-cms2.hubspot.com/cs/loader.js?pg=5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740&pid=25951&hsutk=" + encodeURIComponent(c);
            (document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0]||document.getElementsByTagName("body")[0]).appendChild(hsjs);
            try{el.style.visibility="hidden";}catch(err){}
            setTimeout(function() {try{el.style.visibility="visible";}catch(err){}}, 2500);
        })();
    </script>
</span></p>
<address>&nbsp;</address>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/90501/Residential-Green-Building-Frequently-Asked-Questions&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3c2f6aaf7896bb06c6712f4f568ebfe1" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/91056/Austin-s-Alternative-Giving-MetroRail-a-Ride"><![CDATA[Like many Austin residents, I'm quite familiar with our city's alternative transportation system.&nbsp; I cross the rails at MLK or Manor Road or 45th Street - often several times a day.&nbsp; However, I'm always in my car.&nbsp; But a full day of presentations at the Austin Convention Center provided the perfect opportunity to test the train. &nbsp;I've posted my thougths on Austin's transit system in a <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/57784/Using-Alternative-Transportation-Car2Go-MetroRail" title="previous blog" target="_blank">previous blog</a></strong></span> and it was time for an update. &nbsp;I decided to give <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://www.capmetro.org/metrorail/" title="MetroRail" target="_blank">MetroRail</a></strong></span> a ride.<br><br><br><img id="img-1350707124650" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Austin-Alternative-MetroRail-MLK-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Austin Alternative MetroRail MLK resized 600" width="309" height="412" class="alignLeft" style="float: left;">The day before, I brought the car and parked in the Convention Center garage.&nbsp; It isn't the nicest, and it's several blocks from the Center.&nbsp; And I shelled out twelve bucks for my car to sit in a garage all day.&nbsp; It was time to ride the train.<br><br><br>The closest station is at MLK, just west of Airport Blvd.&nbsp; It was easy enough to pull up the schedule online.&nbsp; The trains ran on roughly 30 minute intervals, and there were several I could take in order to arrive before the start of my first meeting at 8am.<br><br><br>I saw three options for getting to the train - I could take a 20-minute walk from the house.&nbsp;&nbsp; This necessitated walking across Airport Blvd at rush hour; not a very desirable prospect.&nbsp; I could have my wife drop me off on her regular commute.&nbsp; But she leaves so early I'd have to take the first train and wait for an hour-plus once I got downtown.&nbsp; I opted for a short drive to the station and hoped for some on-street parking nearby.<br><br><br><img id="img-1350707191878" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Austin-Alternative-MetroRail-&amp;-bikes-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Austin Alternative MetroRail &amp; bikes resized 600" width="233" height="310" class="alignRight" style="float: right;">I left home with enough time to make the 7:14 train.&nbsp; But I hadn't planned on the MLK and Airport Blvd intersection.&nbsp; I got stuck at a long light with three lanes of car commuters coming in from the suburbs.&nbsp; By the time I got through the intersection, I could see the crossing gates were down in front of us.&nbsp; The train was arriving and I was stuck on the wrong side.&nbsp; When the crossing gates rose, the train was pulling out of the station. <br><br><br>Oh well, at least I'd have plenty of time to find parking.&nbsp; As it turns out, the adjacent streets offer a fair amount of free parking.&nbsp; Perhaps these spaces will fill up in time, but for now, it looks like only a few people had the same idea.&nbsp; I pulled behind two cars already parked at the curb. &nbsp;<br><br><br>I walked over to the platform, crossing the tracks as I did so.&nbsp; The signage was pretty clear, I could see the 7:44 to Downtown was on time.&nbsp; I picked up a flyer with information on the trains, and a printed schedule.&nbsp; I looked for the ticket machine, but only saw one for validating tickets.&nbsp; I don't know why you can't buy a ticket on the platform.&nbsp; I finally located the machines back at the street.&nbsp; So I re-crossed the rail tracks to get my ticket.<br><br><img id="img-1350707396266" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Austin-Alternative-Metrorail-Leaving-Downtown-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Austin Alternative Metrorail Leaving Downtown resized 600" width="251" height="335" class="alignLeft" style="float: left;"><br>The ticket machine looked daunting, with lots of options on display.&nbsp; But the screen said "Press any button to get started."&nbsp; By following the prompts on the screen, the transaction was actually pretty simple.&nbsp; All I needed was to insert my dollar and I had a ticket with a note that it was already validated. &nbsp;<br><br><br>The entire time I rode the train, I never saw anyone ask for or check for tickets.&nbsp; I guess someone could jump on without a ticket and no one would ever know.<br><br><br>I still had ten minutes more to wait.&nbsp; The platform was empty, but well-lit.&nbsp; I sat on a comfortable chair and in no time, four or five more riders appeared on the platform, including a young man wheeling his bike.&nbsp; A recorded voice announced the arrival of the downtown train and chiming bells warned us as the vehicle pulled up to the platform.<br><br><br>The MetroRail cars are impressive.&nbsp; The interiors are clean, bright and inviting.&nbsp; There were seats available, though several riders were standing, including several with bikes.&nbsp; I settled into a very comfortable seat and enjoyed picture-window views of some very nice streetscapes of new buildings and older neighborhoods.<br><br><img id="img-1350707281148" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Austin's-Alternative-MetroRail&amp;ConventionCenter-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Austin-Alternative-MetroRail-ConventionCener" width="339" height="452" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><br>The downtown rail stop is adjacent to the Convention Center.&nbsp; We arrived on time and I had plenty of time to get settled into my first session of the day.<br><br><br>The ride home was even more impressive.&nbsp; The ticket machines downtown are closer to the platform.&nbsp; The train arrived early so everyone on the platform took their seats in the comfortable cars while waiting for the 5:26 departure.<br><br><br>My best memory of the day was the view out the window within a minute of departure.&nbsp; I was leaving downtown Austin during rush hour on a Friday afternoon.&nbsp; As we crossed I-35, I could see complete gridlock.&nbsp; All the cars in both directions on the highway were barely moving.&nbsp; Looking towards 7th street, I could see that all the side streets were packed.&nbsp; No one was leaving downtown quickly -- except us.&nbsp; The train gained speed and whisked past the gridlocked cars.&nbsp; The MetroRail, on Friday afternoon at least, trumped all other modes of transportation.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;<img src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Austin-Alternative-MetroRail-Ride-resized-600.jpg" border="0" alt="Austin Alternative MetroRail Ride resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><br><br><br><br>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/91056/Austin-s-Alternative-Giving-MetroRail-a-Ride&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1943a56c14372274cffa59134af4fe12" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/91559/Sustainable-Water-Solutions-Green-Building-Part-1"><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>GREEN BUILDING</strong></p>
As the newest member of the Heimsath staff, I have been offered the opportunity to share some of my interests through this blog. Since I am particularly interested in green building, I wanted to kick off with a series on sustainable water solutions. A little background may be helpful to explain my interest in sustainability. I grew up on a farm in Vermont where waste was closely associated with want, and every part of a resource got used to maximum effect. For example, when my dad cut down a tree, every part was designated for some use: the branches to be piled and burned for ash to spread on the fields as fertilizer, the trunk to be sawn into lumber, the scraps from sawing to be used as fuel to boil maple sap into syrup, and the sawdust as bedding for animals, which would in turn be used for fertilizer. <br><img id="img-1351877214336" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Green Building - Sustainable Resource Use.jpg" alt="Green Building   Sustainable Resource Use" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0"><br>This early training in frugality and careful use of resources developed into an interest in sustainable design and construction, which often seems to me mostly a matter of figuring out the most efficient and sensible way to do things. While in graduate school I worked for the UT Center for Sustainable Design developing materials to educate students about different sustainable design strategies, and I have found opportunities to use this knowledge since then in practice. I hope that this information will be helpful to you as you consider how you wish to integrate elements of sustainable design into your lifestyle or project. <br>
<h4>SUSTAINABLE WATER SOLUTIONS</h4>
<p>We have been lucky enough to get some rain this week in central Texas, which has served as a reminder that water is a rare and increasingly precious commodity in this area and throughout much of the west, as the drought conditions map from the national weather service indicates (this map is updated weekly and can be viewed at: <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://droughtmonitor.unl.edu/" title="http://droughtmonitor.unl.edu/" target="_blank">http://droughtmonitor.unl.edu/</a></strong></span>).<a href="http://droughtmonitor.unl.edu/" target="_blank"><img id="img-1351875825739" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Sustainable Water Solutions - US Drought Map.png" alt="Sustainable Water Solutions - US Drought Map" class="alignCenter" height="458" border="0" width="720"></a> Growing populations combined with long-term drought are making water conservation an increasingly urgent issue. While the southwest has historically seen major droughts in decade-long cycles, recent dry conditions are unprecedented. If extended periods of drought continue, it will be difficult for much of the southwest to support current population levels, let alone continue to grow. Even in areas where plenty of water is available, treating and distributing it can be expensive and energy intensive, providing another incentive to reduce consumption. While some strategies for reducing water consumption have been around for a long time, growing concerns about water conservation have encouraged the development of more products and options. There are a number of strategies that you can employ to make your home use water more efficiently, many of which are simple and easily implemented. Part 1 will look at things that you can do inside your house, while Part 2 will address options for landscaping and water treatment.<br><br><strong>Awareness and patterns of use:</strong> The habits that you develop surrounding water use have a huge impact on your rate of water consumption. For example: do you leave the faucet running when you shave or brush your teeth? Changing this one habit could save hundreds of gallons per year. Doing laundry or running your dishwasher only when you have a full load can also save water. In some cases, doing dishes by hand might be more water efficient than using a dishwasher, especially if you only have a few dishes. Long showers or large baths can also use up more water than needed. In all of these cases, changing your habits can result in substantial savings without changing anything about your living space. <br><br><strong>Low flow fixtures:</strong> While this may seem obvious, many people don’t realize what a difference it can make. It is easy to retrofit existing faucets and showers with aerators and low-flow showerheads for immediate results, and a multitude of great options exist for choosing new fixtures. Using low flow fixtures alone can reduce water usage by 25% - 60% annually. While some of these products have been around for a while, a much greater range of appliances and fixtures is now available, in a variety of styles and functions. Some innovations may seem strange at first, but offer practical alternatives that can be implemented right away. For example, if the water from your sink could be used to flush your toilet, using the water twice before it goes into the sewer system, why not allow your sink to drain into your toilet? Products have been developed that integrate a sink into a toilet tank cover, allowing water to drain directly into the toilet bowl. An example can be seen at <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://sinkpositive.com/site/home/" title="http://sinkpositive.com/site/home/" target="_blank">http://sinkpositive.com/site/home/</a></strong></span>, although there are several other products available as well. All of these options can allow you to incrementally replace or update fixtures in your house, or choose a set of fixtures for a new project that can start it out at a great baseline. <br><br><strong>Recirculate:</strong> Typically our hot water heaters are a long way from our faucets and showers, so we spend a long time running the water and waiting for it to get hot while all of the water that was sitting in the pipes gets wasted. Installing a recirculating pump can solve this problem. When turned on, the pump sends the cold water that was in the pipes back to the hot water heater to get warmed up, while bringing hot water up to the faucet for you to use immediately. A number of these products are available and they are becoming more popular, so your plumber should be familiar with installing them. It is often possible to install them inside the cabinet of an existing sink – consult your plumber to see if this is an option if you are interested in retrofitting.</p>
<p>Next week: Ideas for sustainable water solutions for landscaping and water treatment. <br><br><br><br></p>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/91559/Sustainable-Water-Solutions-Green-Building-Part-1&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="555c79511f0501a3f844b99b546de73" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/91566/Sustainable-Water-Solutions-Green-Outside-Your-Building-Part-2"><![CDATA[<p>Last week I dicussed options for reducing the amount of water that you use inside your house through adapting your habits and installing fixtures or appliances that are more efficient. This week we need to talk about what goes on outside, because a lot of the water that you use never actually enters your house but instead gets used for irrigating landscaping. This water has been processed to make it safe to use for consumption, which is a much bigger investment of energy than needed. There are a number of sustainable water solutions that address not only reducing the amount of water used for irrigation, but also what you can do with water as it comes to your site (in the form of rain) or leaves your house (as greywater). All of these are important considerations in green building.</p>
<p><strong>Plant native landscaping:</strong> The most important thing that you can do to reduce water use for landscaping is to put in native or drought resistant plants. If you are lucky enough to live in Austin, the city provides a great searchable database of plants that are suitable to this area, with information on how much shade and water they need, as well as details on when they bloom, how large they get, and what wildlife might be attracted to them (<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://austintexas.gov/department/plants" title="http://austintexas.gov/department/plants" target="_blank">http://austintexas.gov/department/plants</a></strong></span>). <br><img src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Sustainable Water Solutions - Native and Drought Resistant Landscaping-resized-600.jpg" alt="Sustainable Water Solutions - Native and Drought Resistant Landscaping" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0"><br>If you live elsewhere in Texas or the US, your local nursery should be able to provide you with information about what plants are suitable to your area, or you can find information from the Lady Bird Johnson Wildflower Center on what plants are appropriate to each state at <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://www.wildflower.org/collections/" title="http://www.wildflower.org/collections/" target="_blank">http://www.wildflower.org/collections/</a></strong></span>. It used to be difficult to find native plants, but they are making a comeback in many nurseries and are sometimes even available now at big chains, if you know what to look for. If you commit to planting only new plants that have low water needs, you can slowly transition your landscaping to use less and less water. Grass is one of the biggest water consumers, so you may want to consider replacing lawns with landscaped areas that have native grasses, mulch, or stone landscaping. <br><br><strong>Harvest your own water:</strong> Even drought resistant landscaping still needs a little help sometimes, and you may not be able to give up that last piece of grassy lawn, so even if you do change your landscaping you might also consider collecting water to use for irrigation. Rainwater collection systems can range from simple old barrels under the eaves to fancy underground tanks with their own filtration systems. Many new systems are cropping up in response to increased interest in rainwater collection, so you will have a lot of options to choose from. <br><img src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Sustainable Water Solutions - Rainwater Collection-resized-600.jpg" alt="Sustainable Water Solutions   Rainwater Collection resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0"><br>If you want to start simple, take a look at your roof and see if there are areas where water is concentrated when it comes off the roof (typically this happens in troughs where two roof pitches come together) and put a rain barrel there that you can use to fill a watering can. If you are interested in taking it a step further, install gutters that direct water into a series of storage tanks. These storage tanks can then be connected to a drip irrigation system for your landscaping, which delivers water directly to plant roots where it is needed rather than putting it on the surface to evaporate. Another great source for water during hotter months is condensate from your air conditioner, which can be collected and used to water plants at the times when they most need it. You can locate the condensate drain in your house and see if there is a way to redirect that water toward areas where it is needed. <br><br><strong>Recycle water:</strong> The water from showers, sinks, and washers is generally fairly clean and can often be reused with minimal treatment, as long as harsh detergents and cleaners are avoided. Greywater, as it’s called, can be collected, filtered, and used to flush toilets or irrigate landscaping. Installing a private collection and filtration system can be problematic in urban areas with restrictive regulations, but some new neighborhoods in dry areas like Austin and Phoenix are installing greywater collection systems alongside traditional wastewater collection. While this is a step in water conservation that goes beyond what most people are used to, it is likely to become more common and is worth considering, especially in new construction. <br><br>If you are building a house, find out what the regulations are regarding greywater in your area, and whether future plans might include developing greywater collection. Consider installing a plumbing system that distinguishes between greywater, which can be treated and reused on-site, and blackwater, which needs to go through a sewage or septic system for treatment. If you are permitted to collect and treat your own greywater, there are a good resources available to help you figure out how to use it, for example <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://greywateraction.org/content/about-greywater-reuse" title="http://greywateraction.org/content/about-greywater-reuse" target="_blank">http://greywateraction.org/content/about-greywater-reuse</a></strong></span>. Most greywater can be used directly to irrigate landscaping, but if you generate more than is needed for this or want to reuse the water for other things, you could install a constructed wetland treatment system that also functions as a landscape feature, since certain kinds of plants are particularly good at filtering water and removing the phosphates from detergents. <br><br></p>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/91566/Sustainable-Water-Solutions-Green-Outside-Your-Building-Part-2&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8bd213614fb2b593a58efd7cf5618593" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/93529/Residential-Green-Architecture-Frequently-Asked-Questions-Part-2"><![CDATA[There's lots of talk about green building - but what does it really mean for your project?&nbsp; We've been impressed with many improvements in our industry that have come from the sustainability movement, often referred to as green building.&nbsp; However, not everything that's promoted as green makes sense.&nbsp; Here is the second half of my article on residential green architecture and the frequently asked questions we often encounter -- or download the entire two-part article now:<br>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">&nbsp;<span class="hs-cta-wrapper" id="hs-cta-wrapper-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740">
    <span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740" id="hs-cta-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740">
        <a href="http://cta-redirect.hubspot.com/cta/redirect/25951/5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740" =""><img class="hs-cta-img" id="hs-cta-img-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740" style="border-width:0px;" src="http://no-cache.hubspot.com/cta/default/25951/5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740.png"></a>
    </span>
    <script type="text/javascript">
        (function(){
            var s='hubspotutk',r,c=((r=new RegExp('(^|; )'+s+'=([^;]*)').exec(document.cookie))?r[2]:''),w=window;w[s]=w[s]||c,
                hsjs=document.createElement("script"),el=document.getElementById("hs-cta-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740");
            hsjs.type = "text/javascript";hsjs.async = true;
            hsjs.src = "//cta-service-cms2.hubspot.com/cs/loader.js?pg=5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740&pid=25951&hsutk=" + encodeURIComponent(c);
            (document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0]||document.getElementsByTagName("body")[0]).appendChild(hsjs);
            try{el.style.visibility="hidden";}catch(err){}
            setTimeout(function() {try{el.style.visibility="visible";}catch(err){}}, 2500);
        })();
    </script>
</span></h3>
<h3>Does my building need to be certified in order to be green?</h3>
Not at all.&nbsp; There are a number of very good ratings agencies that focus on one or more areas of green design. You may want the acknowledgment of an outside authority just to feel good about your work, or to help in promoting your project. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<img src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Residential-Green-Architecture-Purple Heron interior-resized-600.jpg" alt="Residential-green-architecture-Purple-Heron-Interior" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0"><br><em>Eric MacInerney's Purple Heron Residence was given a 5-star rating through Austin Energy's Green Building Program.</em><br><br>Most ratings systems cost some amount of time and money to complete the certification.&nbsp; However, a quick read through the requirements of many building rating systems, such as LEED, can suggest great ideas, even if you aren't using the entire system to certify your project.&nbsp; Other ratings systems may help evaluate green building products or strategies.&nbsp; The Energy Star program, for example, sets standards for energy efficiency for a wide variety of household appliances and equipment.&nbsp; Any consumer can use the program and you don't need to register or pay for tracking your project.<br><br>We definitely recommend going green for anything that conserves resources, saves money, or improves quality.&nbsp; Whether or not to spend extra time and expense to register your project is up to you.<br><br>
<h3>Should I consider green building practices?</h3>
Yes, you should.&nbsp; First and foremost, at least look into the opportunities to save money! For example, one of the most basic green building practices is to focus on efficient ways to heat and cool your home. This may reduce or even eliminate your monthly electricity bill. &nbsp;<br><br id="tinymce" class="mceContentBody " style="overflow: auto;"><em><img src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Residential-Green-Architecture-solar-dormer-resized-600.jpg" alt="Residential Green Architecture solar dormer resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0">This solar array was located on a traditional dormer.</em><br><br>Building well, for the long-term is a good investment.&nbsp; Your payoff comes year after year with lower maintenance and utility costs.&nbsp; Your return on investment may come in a higher resale value.&nbsp; Buyers will often pay a premium for a more efficient home. &nbsp;<br><br>Many green building supporters also make a strong connection to conservation in general.&nbsp; Reducing stress on the environment, even in small ways, can be gratifying.<br>
<h3>&nbsp;</h3>
<h3>Does green building cost more?</h3>
Not necessarily.&nbsp; You can spend more, if you choose, but the principles of green building have mostly to do with investing wisely for the long-term.&nbsp; Many choices and strategies don't cost more, or may come with only a modest premium.&nbsp; But like any quality issue, it is up to the building owner or builder to decide what choices to make.&nbsp; And if spending extra can be beneficial, it is up to you to decide. <br>
<h3>&nbsp;</h3>
<h3>More insulation is better, right?</h3>
<em><img src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Caswell insulation &amp; stair-resized-600.jpg" alt="Residential-Green-Architecture-icynene" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0">Spray-on icynene insulation provides high R-Value and creates a great air-tight seal.</em><br><br>OK, this question isn't often asked by our clients, but you would be surprised how much discussion there is about insulation in the building industry.&nbsp; Contrary to popular perceptions, more insulation is not necessarily better.&nbsp; Yes, insulation is crucial, but the best way to make an efficient house depends on your climate. Too much insulation in the wrong places can make little or no difference and be a big waste of money.&nbsp; The right insulation in the right location takes some planning. In our hot, humid climate, there are several major considerations that can help you to make the best use of insulation. &nbsp;<br><br>Since the heat load is higher on the roof than the walls, the roof insulation should be the first consideration. One of the best things you can do is to place the attic insulation under the rafters.&nbsp; A vented roofing system, under-rafter insulation and the use of a radiant barrier offer great protection from the merciless sun. This provides a big benefit to the air conditioning system.&nbsp; When the ducts are inside the insulated envelope, instead of a sweltering attic space, you save a lot of energy.<br><br>It is best to keep the insulation barrier continuous, with no breaks in the materials that separate outside from inside temperatures.&nbsp; Tight seals are important as infiltration or "leaks" can compromise the insulation and even become unintended collection points for moisture.<br><br>Double-or triple-pane windows and well-sealed exterior doors help to keep the hot air out.&nbsp; Consider the crawl-space or foundation as a further opportunity to make use of the moderate temperatures of the earth below, while providing proper barriers to prevent potential infiltration of toxins or gasses.<br><br>Consult with your local architects, builders and materials suppliers and have them discuss seriously the best practices and products for your area.<br>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span class="hs-cta-wrapper" id="hs-cta-wrapper-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740">
    <span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740" id="hs-cta-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740">
        <a href="http://cta-redirect.hubspot.com/cta/redirect/25951/5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740" =""><img class="hs-cta-img" id="hs-cta-img-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740" style="border-width:0px;" src="http://no-cache.hubspot.com/cta/default/25951/5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740.png"></a>
    </span>
    <script type="text/javascript">
        (function(){
            var s='hubspotutk',r,c=((r=new RegExp('(^|; )'+s+'=([^;]*)').exec(document.cookie))?r[2]:''),w=window;w[s]=w[s]||c,
                hsjs=document.createElement("script"),el=document.getElementById("hs-cta-5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740");
            hsjs.type = "text/javascript";hsjs.async = true;
            hsjs.src = "//cta-service-cms2.hubspot.com/cs/loader.js?pg=5902614e-67a0-484c-b14f-da6522e3c740&pid=25951&hsutk=" + encodeURIComponent(c);
            (document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0]||document.getElementsByTagName("body")[0]).appendChild(hsjs);
            try{el.style.visibility="hidden";}catch(err){}
            setTimeout(function() {try{el.style.visibility="visible";}catch(err){}}, 2500);
        })();
    </script>
</span></div>
<br><br id="tinymce" class="mceContentBody ">
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/93529/Residential-Green-Architecture-Frequently-Asked-Questions-Part-2&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="476cb15b8c5908d5fe72e52922bdb01d" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/94297/Architectural-3D-Design-My-Personal-Perspective"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;">A half century ago I was an expert at drawing 3D images with a T-square and triangle.&nbsp; Architects drew on large sheets of vellum or mylar with sharp pencil leads and precise technical pens.&nbsp; The process of laying out a 3-D drawing started by locating the horizon line.&nbsp; We worked from a 2D plan and would then project from the elevations by manually taking each line to the proper vanishing point. We learned to render one-point perspectives for most interiors and two-point perspectives for exterior views.<br><br><img src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Architectural-3D-Design-Clovis-1960-resized-600.jpg" alt="Architectural 3D Design Clovis 1960 resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0"><br><em>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Clovis Heimsath in the Early Days</em><br><br>I was fast. But it still could easily take me an entire day to layout the overall perspective and then erase the "hidden" lines and use shading or line-weight to make the image more legible.&nbsp; Frequently, the line drawing felt too diagrammatic.&nbsp; I learned to embellish my 3D perspectives with watercolors or pen and ink to make presentation renderings.<br><br><br>Sometimes a client liked the first 3D picture of our proposed design so much, they would want another from a different point of view.&nbsp; It was faster the second time since we'd be using the same plan.&nbsp; I'd reestablish the horizon line and place new vanishing points.&nbsp;&nbsp;Within a half day I could have a pretty good new picture, having projected all the walls and roofs as I had before.&nbsp; I might not embellish the rendering to the same detail, though.&nbsp; It took a lot of time to render in the stones on the wall, for example.&nbsp; That was quite a lot of&nbsp;fun and made the picture look good, but I might not have the time to do it twice.<br><br><br>The production of 3D renderings evolved a little when published perspective charts became readily available. You could pop a plan onto a perspective chart that had lines going to vanishing points and save the time of constructing the lines by hand. At the end of the layout, of course, the building had to be&nbsp;brought into 3D&nbsp;by blocking in the elevations in perspective.&nbsp;I was good at 3D drawings and I have always felt we must see a building in 3D to understand the scale and ambience of the elements.<br><br><br>In the early 1980s I began to use an early MacIntosh computer.&nbsp; I tracked down a beta version of MacPersective and soon realized that we were at the cusp of a revolution. This primitive program&nbsp;made it possible to layout a building in plan, while it projected up the elevations to make a wire-frame 3D model. I was one of the first in the office to master this technique.&nbsp; I was delighted to do away with the horizon line and vanishing points.&nbsp; Once I construct a building in the program, I could view it from any location.<br>&nbsp;<br><br>I contacted the inventor of MacPerspective&nbsp;to encourage him to go further.&nbsp;&nbsp; Soon, he had developed an upgrade to automatically erase the hidden lines!&nbsp; These were just the baby steps, but I knew it would only be a matter of time before the use of computer 3D would be second-nature to anyone involved in design or construction. <br><br><br>We've experienced many benchmarks as we've integrated the electronic perspective into our design process.&nbsp; I was an early user of Sketchup, and I still enjoy using the software's flexibility and intuitive interface.&nbsp; Soon, the office started to explore the benefits of real-time walkthroughs.&nbsp; For a while we were power users of Virtus, an early walkthrough program.&nbsp; Our CAD software at the time allowed us, with some effort, to take our 3D diagrams and make short film clips moving through the images.&nbsp; We have a collection of these presentations like the one featured below.&nbsp; Here's a link to our UTube site <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/HeimsathArch" title="HeimsathArch" target="_blank">HeimsathArch</a></span></strong> with architectural videos.<br>&nbsp;<br><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Tio43L_xcM8?list=UUNfTlg5a4izoIHMNvuyFeDQ" frameborder="0" height="360" width="640"></iframe><br>We also soon realized that there was still an important place for the watercolor rendering.&nbsp; I continue to render using our computer images as a starting point, then embellishing the images with my artistic hand. Though it is possible today to use highly refined imaging software, making the final presentation by hand can be much more successful.<br><br><br>But the biggest <img id="img-1358397209988" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Architectural-3D-Design-St Francis-resized-600.jpg" alt="Architectural 3D Design St Francis resized 600" class="alignLeft" style="float: left;" border="0" height="241" width="321">change is still unfolding.&nbsp; Our current CAD software actually keeps its data in a 3D model.&nbsp; This makes it possible to access a real-time image of any part of our building design at any time.&nbsp; Though we continue to export fly through video clips, we prefer to take our computer files to meetings so we can move around and through the spaces.&nbsp; It is the closest thing I know for sharing with clients, consultants or anyone else the images we, as architects, have in our imaginations.</p>
<p><em>You also may enjoy a terrific feature on Clovis and Maryann Heimsath in the January magazine of Texas Architect.&nbsp; Get a link to this feature this in our <a href="http://www.heimsath.com/news/" title="NEWS" target="_blank"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">NEWS</span></strong></a>.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/94297/Architectural-3D-Design-My-Personal-Perspective&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4585fab01fceec17a0a33c41c1ec7fc6" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/96477/The-Church-Design-Process-Does-It-Look-Like-a-Church"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;">In the early stages of a church design, when we begin working with congregation members, someone inevitably will say “I want this to look like a church.” In most instances, the person has a strong image in mind, often based on the church where they grew up.&nbsp; The person may also be expressing displeasure with the current building, which, by implication, does not look like a church. <br><br>But what should a church look like?&nbsp; When a congregation builds, there may be hundreds of images and ideas, but ultimately, only one can be built.&nbsp; What appeals to one person may be wrong for another.&nbsp; If it were easy to resolve these issues, we’d have church forms as simple and un-subtle as the Big Duck.&nbsp; This building leaves no question about its purpose.<br><br><em><img id="img-1363873812486" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/The Big Duck Image-resized-600.jpg" alt="The-Big-Duck-Design-Process" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0" width="206" height="223">The Big Duck on Long Island is a N</em><em>ational Historic Landmark.&nbsp; Originally built by a duck farmer to sell his products, its purpose is immediately obvious.</em><br><br>The church design process is much more difficult than that of other building types.&nbsp; Most people have a hard time putting into words the intensity and deep feelings associated with their faith.&nbsp; These are often connected to places or events that are particularly important.&nbsp; How to relate to those feelings and connections is an on-going challenge in the process of creating an environment for faith. &nbsp;<br><br>There are no formulas or specifications for making a worshipful environment.&nbsp; However, there are many traditions associated with different religions or denominations.&nbsp; These traditions come from many cultures, and a variety of historical periods.&nbsp;&nbsp; In the United States, builders and architects have freely combined traditions from all sorts of religious, cultural or historic periods. <br><br><br><em><img id="img-1363875543622" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/woodlawn exterior-resized-600.jpg" alt="Church-Design-Woodlawn-Baptist" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0">Woodlawn Baptist Church members wanted a strong image for their new sanctuary addition but also wanted to relate to the existing modernist building.</em><br><br>Merely copying or re-creating an old form doesn’t guarantee a successful spiritual experience.&nbsp; In some cases a poor rendition or reference to a traditional form feels out of place or becomes a distraction.&nbsp; And new technologies or building practices provide a host of new opportunities and challenges.&nbsp; For example, the traditional Italian basilica didn’t deal with modern lighting, acoustics, video recording, or projection.<br><br>But starting a design from modern structures and technology offers its own challenges.&nbsp; It can be tempting for an architect to place visually impressive elements in their designs.&nbsp; But a dramatic design may or may not be appropriate for a community of believers.&nbsp; Many new buildings are visually impressive, (galleries, offices, or shopping centers) but they have nothing to do with spirituality.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;<br><br>Careful consideration of each ministry is essential. At a fundamental level, the design needs to accommodate the rituals and rites of a given faith.&nbsp; There may be certain ways that these rites are accommodated in some traditions, but the designers shouldn’t limit itself to just one form.&nbsp; See our previous blog post series on the many ways to <a href="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/56708/Baptismal-Fonts-How-What-Where-Part-1" title="accommodate the rituals of baptism" target="_blank"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>accommodate the rituals of baptism</strong></span></a>. &nbsp;<br><br>The design of a church cannot be a “one-size-fits-all” program.&nbsp; The design team should be closely communicating with the congregation and its leaders.&nbsp; They should expect inspiration to come from both traditional and modern ideas.&nbsp; The church design ultimately should be tailor-fit for each community.<br><br></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><em><img src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Unity exterior front door-resized-600.jpg" alt="Unity-Church-Design-Process" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0">Unity Church of the Hills developed a strong image for their 14 acre site.&nbsp; The welcoming entry is surrounded by a canopy of existing trees.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">I presented a paper at the ACS (Architecture, Culture, and Spirituality) conference several years ago.&nbsp; I equated the process of design with the spiritual journey experienced in other ministry endeavors.&nbsp; The paper included a case study of our work with Unity Church of the Hills in planning for their new site.&nbsp; The church has been settled in their new location for over a decade, and has just recently worked with us to complete a Phase 2 program.&nbsp; Recalling the steps we took in the early planning stages, we used a similar process the second time that also evoked a sense of spirituality from all who participated. <br><br>So what should a church design look like?&nbsp; It might look like almost anything.&nbsp; But above all, it should look like the spiritual home of the group of believers who shaped and formed it.<br><br><em></em></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><em>Need information about designing a church? Learn how a master plan can be an essential first step.&nbsp;</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">&nbsp;<span class="hs-cta-wrapper" id="hs-cta-wrapper-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1">
    <span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1" id="hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1">
        <a href="http://cta-redirect.hubspot.com/cta/redirect/25951/bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1" =""><img class="hs-cta-img" id="hs-cta-img-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1" style="border-width:0px;" src="http://no-cache.hubspot.com/cta/default/25951/bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1.png"></a>
    </span>
    <script type="text/javascript">
        (function(){
            var s='hubspotutk',r,c=((r=new RegExp('(^|; )'+s+'=([^;]*)').exec(document.cookie))?r[2]:''),w=window;w[s]=w[s]||c,
                hsjs=document.createElement("script"),el=document.getElementById("hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1");
            hsjs.type = "text/javascript";hsjs.async = true;
            hsjs.src = "//cta-service-cms2.hubspot.com/cs/loader.js?pg=bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1&pid=25951&hsutk=" + encodeURIComponent(c);
            (document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0]||document.getElementsByTagName("body")[0]).appendChild(hsjs);
            try{el.style.visibility="hidden";}catch(err){}
            setTimeout(function() {try{el.style.visibility="visible";}catch(err){}}, 2500);
        })();
    </script>
</span></p>
<p><em><br></em></p>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/96477/The-Church-Design-Process-Does-It-Look-Like-a-Church&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="89a2e3aab39276ce558b227ae6fbdc73" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/97310/Church-Steeple-Restoration-Our-Lady-of-Guadalupe-in-Austin"><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img id="img-1366159100727" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/church-steeple-restoration-scaffolding-resized-600.jpg" alt="church steeple restoration scaffolding resized 600" class="alignLeft" style="float: left;" border="0" height="352" width="263"></p>
<p>The church steeple restoration at Our Lady of Guadalupe in Austin is nearly complete.&nbsp; The project consisted of replacing most of the exterior materials on the original tower and restoring the original trim profiles. &nbsp;<br><br>The church called upon Heimsath Architect’s expertise when a portion of a column fell to the ground.&nbsp; Originally constructed in the 1950’s, the church tower had been patched and repaired over the years, but recently showed signs of significant deterioration.&nbsp; A large bee colony had made its home in three of the columns, filling them with honeycomb.<br><br>The architects conducted a conditions assessment study and worked with structural engineers to evaluate the extent of the problems.&nbsp; A structural analysis determined that interior supports were still sound.&nbsp; A local bee keeper was called in to give the colony a more suitable home.&nbsp; The restoration program was then focused on rebuilding the exterior with new columns, roofing materials and wood details. &nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img id="img-1366159420747" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/church-steeple-before-restoration-resized-600.jpg" alt="church steeple before restoration resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0" height="386" width="351"><em>The condition of the tower had deteriorated significantly.&nbsp; Well-intentioned patches and repairs had covered or compromised the wood trim profiles.</em></p>
<p>The original copper roofing proved to be in good shape, but the drip edges were not diverting rainwater properly.&nbsp; By resetting the drip edges and re-soldering seams, the copper dome and other roof elements remained intact.&nbsp; The contractor ultimately removed 400 pounds of honeycomb from the tower!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img id="img-1366159706112" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/church-steeple-restoration-column-capital-resized-600.jpg" alt="church steeple restoration column capital resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0" height="284" width="380"><em>The new wood details and profiles show the quality of the steeple's cupola and are an important part of the overall design.</em></p>
<p><br>The congregation included the church steeple restoration as part of a larger program for the historic church building.&nbsp; The completed work includes, roof repairs, brick repointing, stained glass window restoration and protection, wood trim replacement, exterior repainting, and an upgrade of the a/c distribution system.&nbsp; The contractor, <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://www.braun-butler.com" title="Braun and Butler," target="_blank">Braun and Butler,</a></strong></span> scheduled the work so the church could continue to use the space during construction.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Expand your practical knowledge of historic preservation.&nbsp; Sandy Stone, preseravtion architect, explains how to keep these buildings in top shape. Click the link below:</em></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span class="hs-cta-wrapper" id="hs-cta-wrapper-ef887376-22e0-4a10-a0ad-50a26f9c0f4f">
    <span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-ef887376-22e0-4a10-a0ad-50a26f9c0f4f" id="hs-cta-ef887376-22e0-4a10-a0ad-50a26f9c0f4f">
        <a href="http://cta-redirect.hubspot.com/cta/redirect/25951/ef887376-22e0-4a10-a0ad-50a26f9c0f4f" =""><img class="hs-cta-img" id="hs-cta-img-ef887376-22e0-4a10-a0ad-50a26f9c0f4f" style="border-width:0px;" src="http://no-cache.hubspot.com/cta/default/25951/ef887376-22e0-4a10-a0ad-50a26f9c0f4f.png"></a>
    </span>
    <script type="text/javascript">
        (function(){
            var s='hubspotutk',r,c=((r=new RegExp('(^|; )'+s+'=([^;]*)').exec(document.cookie))?r[2]:''),w=window;w[s]=w[s]||c,
                hsjs=document.createElement("script"),el=document.getElementById("hs-cta-ef887376-22e0-4a10-a0ad-50a26f9c0f4f");
            hsjs.type = "text/javascript";hsjs.async = true;
            hsjs.src = "//cta-service-cms2.hubspot.com/cs/loader.js?pg=ef887376-22e0-4a10-a0ad-50a26f9c0f4f&pid=25951&hsutk=" + encodeURIComponent(c);
            (document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0]||document.getElementsByTagName("body")[0]).appendChild(hsjs);
            try{el.style.visibility="hidden";}catch(err){}
            setTimeout(function() {try{el.style.visibility="visible";}catch(err){}}, 2500);
        })();
    </script>
</span></div>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/97310/Church-Steeple-Restoration-Our-Lady-of-Guadalupe-in-Austin&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="13ad52c33922d8202b42742a8a9e5777" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/97463/Church-Closure-No-Easy-Solution"><![CDATA[<p><img id="img-1366597211726" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/church for sale-resized-600.jpg" alt="church-closure-dc-sanctuary-for-sale" class="alignRight" style="float: right;" border="0" height="301" width="242">In the past decade, there have been increasing instances of church closure.&nbsp; So what happens when a church is no longer needed?&nbsp; When a congregation moves, or a denomination consolidates, something must be done with the old places.&nbsp; Other congregations, or sympathetic groups may purchase and re-use the structures.&nbsp; However, without a program or strategy for transition, many of these buildings face demolition, or are re-purposed in ways that cause lingering hurt or sadness for the surrounding community.<br><br>A recent conference in Albany, New York brought together preservationists, developers and public officials to focus on the unique challenges of preserving closed churches.&nbsp; In an article about the conference, the <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="http://www.timesunion.com/default/article/Saving-old-churches-is-their-goal-4337886.php" title="Albany Times Union" target="_blank">Albany Times Union</a></span></strong> quotes our colleague, Tuomi Forrest, of the <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://www.sacredplaces.org" title="Partners for Sacred Places" target="_blank">Partners for Sacred Places</a></strong></span>.&nbsp; “We are on a cusp of accelerated closures and mergers." The number of vacant religious buildings is on the rise and will continue to grow. &nbsp;<br><br>The day-long conference featured panels and presentations with ideas for adapting these structures and examples of successful conversions.&nbsp; There are some good examples of churches converted to condos or apartments.&nbsp; One of my favorite is a project from the 1980’s by Boston architect Graham Gund.&nbsp; He successfully transformed the remains of a church that burned into a condominium project called “Church Court.”<br><br><img id="img-1366597447709" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/church reuse-resized-600.jpg" alt="church-closure-adaptive-reuse" class="alignLeft" style="float: left;" border="0" height="295" width="221">Several years ago, I visited a church in Vermont that was turned into a pharmacy.&nbsp; That visit, and visits to several churches that are for sale, have started me thinking about the re-use of sacred spaces.<br><br>Heimsath Architects has addressed this issue on several occasions with congregations renovating, replacing, or re-purposed their old worship spaces.&nbsp; Sensitivity to the unique issues in each community has been fundamental to making each case a success. &nbsp;<br><br>In the case of <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://www.heimsath.com/Holy-Trinity-Episcopal-Church-Worship-Spaces-Portfolio/" title="Holy Trinity Episcopal Church" target="_blank">Holy Trinity Episcopal Church</a></strong></span>, in Fayetteville, North Carolina, we facilitated a process of discernment with participation of the entire congregation.&nbsp; After considering all alternatives, the large majority agreed that the old chapel should be torn down in order to build a new worship space on the same site.&nbsp; The old chapel was not historic, however, we felt the need for extra sensitivity to this issue.&nbsp; The materials and proportions of our new church design recall the original church.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<img id="img-1366598980121" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/church master plan holytrinitywatercolor-resized-600.jpg" alt="church-closure-replacing-old-chapel" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0" height="294" width="469"> &nbsp;<br><br>But when a congregation leaves an otherwise useful building, it becomes a special challenge to find ways to preserve and/or adapted the structure to new uses.&nbsp; A large number of vintage churches are architectural or community landmarks.&nbsp; The Times Union article also notes an unsuccessful attempt to convert a closed church into a brewery.&nbsp; That brought back an old memory from my childhood in downtown Houston, Texas.&nbsp; A nightclub opened in an old church in the Montrose area.&nbsp; Re-named “the Sanctuary,” the establishment closed quickly, and the church was summarily torn down. &nbsp;<br><br>What happens when a place of sacred worship no longer serves its purpose is a fascinating question.&nbsp; Some religious traditions suggest that a place, once sanctified, can never be abandoned or secularized.&nbsp; Other faith traditions have rituals or activities associated with “de-sanctifying” a space. &nbsp;<img id="img-1366599097998" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Mt Sinai Baptist for Sale-resized-600.jpg" alt="Church-Closure-Mnt-Sanai-For-Sale" class="alignLeft" style="float: left;" border="0" height="240" width="196"><br><br>The conference, sponsored by the <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://www.nylandmarks.org" title="New York Landmarks Conservancy" target="_blank">New York Landmarks Conservancy</a></strong></span>, is just a start in addressing this complicated challenge.&nbsp; The big issues of community sentiment and tradition need to be addressed with exceptional care.&nbsp; One conference attendee mentioned how deeply communities were beset by grief at the prospect of church closure.&nbsp; This just shows again how a place of worship has connections to its neighborhood, its town, and to its congregation that makes it unlike any other building. &nbsp;<br><br><em>Do you need resources for your older church?&nbsp; We’ve collected some of our best practices for reviving and keeping historic buildings, including churches, in good shape.&nbsp; Download “The Care and Feeding of Your Historic Building.”</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span class="hs-cta-wrapper" id="hs-cta-wrapper-ef887376-22e0-4a10-a0ad-50a26f9c0f4f">
    <span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-ef887376-22e0-4a10-a0ad-50a26f9c0f4f" id="hs-cta-ef887376-22e0-4a10-a0ad-50a26f9c0f4f">
        <a href="http://cta-redirect.hubspot.com/cta/redirect/25951/ef887376-22e0-4a10-a0ad-50a26f9c0f4f" =""><img class="hs-cta-img" id="hs-cta-img-ef887376-22e0-4a10-a0ad-50a26f9c0f4f" style="border-width:0px;" src="http://no-cache.hubspot.com/cta/default/25951/ef887376-22e0-4a10-a0ad-50a26f9c0f4f.png"></a>
    </span>
    <script type="text/javascript">
        (function(){
            var s='hubspotutk',r,c=((r=new RegExp('(^|; )'+s+'=([^;]*)').exec(document.cookie))?r[2]:''),w=window;w[s]=w[s]||c,
                hsjs=document.createElement("script"),el=document.getElementById("hs-cta-ef887376-22e0-4a10-a0ad-50a26f9c0f4f");
            hsjs.type = "text/javascript";hsjs.async = true;
            hsjs.src = "//cta-service-cms2.hubspot.com/cs/loader.js?pg=ef887376-22e0-4a10-a0ad-50a26f9c0f4f&pid=25951&hsutk=" + encodeURIComponent(c);
            (document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0]||document.getElementsByTagName("body")[0]).appendChild(hsjs);
            try{el.style.visibility="hidden";}catch(err){}
            setTimeout(function() {try{el.style.visibility="visible";}catch(err){}}, 2500);
        })();
    </script>
</span><br><br></p>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/97463/Church-Closure-No-Easy-Solution&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="beb8f43832111f5996e99288540f529b" url="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/99422/Disappearing-Steeples-Not-These-Churches"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;">How did I miss the eulogy for church steeples?&nbsp; Apparently, in 2011, a reporter from <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://usatoday30.usatoday.com/news/religion/2011-05-01-church-steeple-repair_n.htm" title="US News and World Report" target="_blank">US News and World Report</a></strong></span> noticed lots of disappearing steeples, and penned an article to mark the trend.&nbsp; While there’s no question that some congregations have difficulty maintaining older buildings, our experience is that steeples, and similar structures, are increasingly important for churches and places of worship. &nbsp;<br><br><img id="img-1372021884964" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Disappearing Steeple- Concordia Lutheran tower-resized-600.jpg" alt="Disappearing Steeple  Concordia Lutheran tower resized 600" class="alignRight" style="float: right;" border="0" height="201" width="127">I noticed recently while driving along the outer loop in San Antonio, that several churches have built massive steeples and are using them like billboards to get noticed.&nbsp; I believe this is just one of many ways the traditional steeple is evolving and adapting to modern culture.&nbsp; This photo is Concordia Lutheran Church, San Antonio (Fisher Heck Architects).<br><br>A sampling of some of our recent project illustrates that the steeple is far from dead.&nbsp; It’s being restored or recreated, on older buildings.&nbsp; For new projects, the desire for a soaring vertical structure is still strong.&nbsp;&nbsp; And these sky-reaching, spiritual-connected forms aren’t just for churches. &nbsp;<br><br>So why do people think the church steeple is threatened?&nbsp; There is a well-reported trend of churches struggling to keep up their historic buildings.&nbsp;&nbsp; Steeples are one part of the church building where maintenance is easily deferred or overlooked. So it’s no surprise to see churches with <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://www.vindy.com/photos/2013/jan/10/64677/" title="heart-wrenching losses" target="_blank">heart-wrenching losses</a></strong></span> on the local, even national news. &nbsp;<br><br>Several of our church clients have made the restoration of their historic steeples a high priority.&nbsp; I blogged last month about <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/97310/Church-Steeple-Restoration-Our-Lady-of-Guadalupe-in-Austin" title="Our Lady of Guadalupe’s just completed steeple project" target="_self">Our Lady of Guadalupe’s just completed steeple project</a></strong></span>.&nbsp; Here’s an updated photo of the front elevation.<br><br></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img id="img-1372025584806" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Disappearing Steeple- Our Lady of Guadalupe Austin-resized-600.jpg" alt="Disappearing Steeple  Our Lady of Guadalupe Austin resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0" height="610" width="524"><br><em>Our Lady of Guadalupe Catholic Church Steeple Restoration, Austin, Texas</em></p>
<p><br>For another client, the <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://www.heimsath.com/university-united-methodist-church-historic-preservation-portfolio/" title="University United Methodist Church" target="_self">University United Methodist Church</a></strong></span>, the steeple was the featured element of a major preservation program.&nbsp; This landmark church, a distinctive southwest adaptation of Richardsonian architecture, conducted a full exterior restoration program in 2010.&nbsp; The tower, with its tile roof, crafted limestone walls, and ornamental wood details, should now last well into the next century.<br><img id="img-1372022372112" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Church tower UUMC scaffold 009_2-resized-600.jpg" alt="Church tower UUMC scaffold 009 2 resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0" height="377" width="287"></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><br><em>University United Methodist Church – Steeple Surrounded By Scaffolding</em></p>
<p><br>Designing a new steeple that fits the many styles and forms of contemporary churches is a difficult but exciting challenge.&nbsp; Too many new churches simply go to a catalogue or supplier to buy a pre-designed steeple with little regard to scale or style.&nbsp; While these roof ornaments can signal the presence of a church, they do little to indicate the seriousness or importance of the steeple as an integral part of the worship environment or its design.<br><br>For the <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://www.heimsath.com/first-baptist-dripping-springs-worship-spaces-portfolio/" title="First Baptist Church in Dripping Springs" target="_self">First Baptist Church in Dripping Springs</a></strong></span>, the <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://www.munnsmfg.com" title="Muns Company  " target="_blank">Muns Company </a></strong></span>worked with us to adapt one of their pre-manufactured steeples to fit our design for an updated hill-country church.&nbsp; The congregation re-built a new and bigger building after a tragic fire destroyed their sanctuary.&nbsp; One of the few things saved was the original church bell.&nbsp; The steeple design features the bell hanging proudly within the structure. <br><img id="img-1372022512579" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Disappearing Steeple-1st Baptist Dripping Springs-resized-600.jpg" alt="Disappearing Steeple 1st Baptist Dripping Springs resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0" height="481" width="321"></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><br><em>First Baptist Church, Dripping Springs New Sanctuary</em></p>
<p><br><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://www.heimsath.com/st-albert-of-trapani-worship-spaces-portfolio/" title="St Albert of Trapani  " target="_self">St Albert of Trapani </a></strong></span>presented a different challenge.&nbsp; We designed a major expansion of their original sanctuary, built originally in the 1960’s in a modernist style.&nbsp; The old building didn’t have much of a presence on the main street, so for the redesign, congregation members suggested a steeple.&nbsp; Modernist architecture is characterized by bold, simple forms.&nbsp; The new steeple is a freestanding wall-type structure with a cut-away that features a simple cross.<br><img id="img-1372022635789" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Disappearing Steeple- St Albert of Trapani-resized-600.jpg" alt="Disappearing Steeple  St Albert of Trapani resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0" height="351" width="403"></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><br><em>St. Albert of Trapani Catholic Church, Houston</em></p>
<p><br>A soaring architectural form that marks a worship space isn’t limited to church design.&nbsp; The new Austin Hindu Temple project gave us a chance to work with the traditional architects and artisans who specialize in the highly ornamented temples prescribed for the Hindu faith.&nbsp; The main entry to the temple is the traditional Rajagopuram, or grand entry tower.&nbsp; Priests and worshippers leave their shoes outside and may even wash themselves before proceeding through the portal.&nbsp; We completed the requirements for the structure and layout of the building, based on the requirements of the Sthapathi the architectural expert from India.&nbsp; His craftsmen, or Shilpis, will be working for the next several years in completing the sacred ornamentation.&nbsp; A similar structure in California shows the intricate quality of this construction.<br><img id="img-1372022710443" src="http://www.heimsath.com/Portals/25951/images/Disappearing Steeple- Rajagoporum-resized-600.jpg" alt="Disappearing Steeple  Rajagoporum resized 600" class="alignCenter" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" border="0" height="442" width="321"></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><br><em>Rajagoporum of the Malibu Hindu Temple in California (Architect Unknown)</em><br><br></p>
<p><br>&nbsp;<br><strong><strong><em>Are you responsible for a building program?&nbsp; Deciding what to do, and what’s important is never easy, but a good Master Plan can help.&nbsp; Download these 10 Essential Elements to a Successful Master Plan and see how you can get a good start.</em></strong></strong></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span class="hs-cta-wrapper" id="hs-cta-wrapper-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1">
    <span class="hs-cta-node hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1" id="hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1">
        <a href="http://cta-redirect.hubspot.com/cta/redirect/25951/bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1" =""><img class="hs-cta-img" id="hs-cta-img-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1" style="border-width:0px;" src="https://no-cache.hubspot.com/cta/default/25951/bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1.png"></a>
    </span>
    <script type="text/javascript">
        (function(){
            var s='hubspotutk',r,c=((r=new RegExp('(^|; )'+s+'=([^;]*)').exec(document.cookie))?r[2]:''),w=window;w[s]=w[s]||c,
                hsjs=document.createElement("script"),el=document.getElementById("hs-cta-bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1");
            hsjs.type = "text/javascript";hsjs.async = true;
            hsjs.src = "//cta-service-cms2.hubspot.com/cs/loader.js?pg=bc12c8ad-adc4-4997-8bda-da43d90e7bc1&pid=25951&hsutk=" + encodeURIComponent(c);
            (document.getElementsByTagName("head")[0]||document.getElementsByTagName("body")[0]).appendChild(hsjs);
            try{el.style.visibility="hidden";}catch(err){}
            setTimeout(function() {try{el.style.visibility="visible";}catch(err){}}, 2500);
        })();
    </script>
</span></div>
<img src="http://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=25951&k=14&bu=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/&r=http://www.heimsath.com/blog-0/bid/99422/Disappearing-Steeples-Not-These-Churches&bvt=rss">
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>