<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="ginny-williams.blogspot.com">
	<documents count="21">
		<document id="88cf23444d7480a8efff5137a7174ddc" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/-z2rk41kDK8/start-living-again-pain-free-what.html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://ginsrealtimepainreliefbiz.blogspot.com/2011/07/what-isreal-time-pain-relief.html?spref=bl">Start Living Again, Pain Free!: What is"Real Time Pain relief"?</a>: "Real Time Pain Relief is a homeopathic formula that has no harmful side effects and works directly at the site, Real Time Pain Relief is kno..."<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/-z2rk41kDK8" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fda8fc4443eb2e299298e4c1ee4adbfb" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/1Tl0QL7Fy_8/guaranteed-income-in-90-days-httpping.html"><![CDATA[Guaranteed income in 90 days!<br /><a href="http://ping.fm/3dfgV">http://ping.fm/3dfgV</a><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/1Tl0QL7Fy_8" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1941752b545a5501d2a6ea52319863e8" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/4OeXt5pOjMI/join-my-cause.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><iframe allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" src="http://widgets.causes.com/badges/cause?cause_id=132406&amp;width=300&amp;height=210&amp;tagline=Support+Our+Cause&amp;faces=1&amp;awareness=1" style="border: none; height: 210px; overflow: hidden; width: 300px;"></iframe></div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/4OeXt5pOjMI" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9f990313f3665d85f2689d2ff5ece36f" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/8Z9NTH6tJDI/whats-going-on-with-ginny.html"><![CDATA[Hello friends, followers and fellow networkers and especially to all my Admin. staff at Gin's Green Business Network! Ijust wanted to update you on what's going on and why my presence has been so absent lately.<br /><br />As some of you know, I've been dealing with alot lately and starting back at the end on May with my friend trying to committ suicide, then I had an uncle that died from a brain tumor and cancer, was unable to go to the funeral. Then my friend Danny, an older gentleman(bacherlor) that I've known since I was a teenager and for the last year, have been helping to take care of him. All kinds of major medical problems. In late June, he broke his other hip, while recovering from the first hip break and a partial amputation on his left foot. After the surgery to repair the second hip fracture, they sent him to a rehab facility and within 3 to 4 days of arriving he went into a cardiac arrest! He was out for a total of 5 minutes, but then got him back and rushed him to the hospital. In the few days that followed, he continued to have more arrests and seizures that they couldn't figured out why. Family arrived the next day, made descions and took him off life support a few days later on August 3 and died at 9pm, EST. This was a BIG blow to me. The family had no funeral or anything here for Danny, which was a little disappointing, but not my descision to make.<br />For Danny and his family, that live in North Carolina, I help find a home for his 2 dogs, (his children) got rid of his cars and sent the money to his mother and all other important things that they needed help with. So, while trying to catch my breath, I found out thru a friend of mine, that a good friend of my daughter's committed suicide on her brother's birthday, which was August 9, so then I had to take my daughter to her first funeral. This was very devastating to my daughter. We went to the funeral. My daughter chose not to view her friend during the viewing. I'm so glad she didn't. This poor child looked awful! I'm glad she won't remember her that way.<br /><br />So for that last few months, I've been slowing recluding into myself, not caring about anything or anyone and shutting everyone out. I finally went yesterday to see my psycharist for my meds and met with my psycologist to talk, after which, they decided the best thing for me was to add a new medication called Seroquel XR, which is mood-stabilizer and also can help you sleep. It's give to people with Bipolar disorder,major depressive disorder and many more. I have been diagnosed with traits of Bipolar Disorder and Borderline Personality Disorder, with Major Depressive Disorder and now take 4 different medications to help keep all chemicals in balance.<br />They main reason I'm sharing all this personal stuff with you, is because I want you to understand me a little better and why I do the things that I do and to bring awareness to these mental diseases and hoping that by sharing my stories, that they will in return help someone else. Please feel free to conact me anytime, for anything or if you think I help in any way! Please take the time to checkout my blog on My Recovery at: <a href="http://ginny-williams.blogspot.com/">http://ginny-williams.blogspot.com</a><br />As for Gin's Green Business Network, will remain open and some changes made. If you have any suggestions as to what would like to see for this network, please send then to me. We always need sponsors, we have advertising spaces for sale and much more..... Look for more info to come soon! If you haven't joined us, please do:<a href="http://ginsgreenbusiness.ning.com/">http://ginsgreenbusiness.ning.com</a><script type="text/javascript">var geo_Partner = 'acf61f5c-0df0-4f7e-910d-bf7e5cf04425'; var geo_isCG = true; </script><script src="http://js.geoads.com/geoLink.js" type="text/javascript"></script><br /><div id="__ctn_num" style="display: none;">503</div><script type="text/javascript">var geo_Partner = 'acf61f5c-0df0-4f7e-910d-bf7e5cf04425'; var geo_isCG = true; </script><script src="http://js.geoads.com/geoLink.js" type="text/javascript"></script><div id="__ctn_num" style="display: none;">1527</div><div id="YontooInstallID" style="display: none;">5a22b9bd-b8b2-4b2c-a885-4e37545ccffb</div><div id="YontooClientVersion" style="display: none;">1.03.01</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/8Z9NTH6tJDI" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="11cf12d5f8285926e1ef6ad9c01e6689" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/aO_M0YJaPu0/checkout-my-new-video-and-tell-me-what.html"><![CDATA[Checkout my new video and tell me what you think!<a href="http://ping.fm/7M3ST">http://ping.fm/7M3ST</a><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/aO_M0YJaPu0" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="21efd953220de3d0f779ffe0b9b71690" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/BaBedzyuYaU/looking-for-green-business-products-or.html"><![CDATA[Looking for a green business, products or just be with people passionate about their health and the environment! <a href="http://ping.fm/tcEEd">http://ping.fm/tcEEd</a><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/BaBedzyuYaU" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b9bf7809e32a760a293ae635bfe33176" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/BAvHrTcrlkg/my-debut.html"><![CDATA[<a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_i6afki21nO4/SKlZaD_F3QI/AAAAAAAAABY/ZYdeqUAp8GU/s1600-h/3573827_m%5B1%5D.gif"><img style="margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_i6afki21nO4/SKlZaD_F3QI/AAAAAAAAABY/ZYdeqUAp8GU/s320/3573827_m%5B1%5D.gif" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5235814346076314882" border="0" /></a><br /><br /><span style="font-size:130%;"><span style="color: rgb(153, 51, 153);"><span style="font-weight: bold;">Hello my friends from the sunshine state. Today we are under a T.S. warning, but the good news is that an honor has been bestowed to me by a wonderful woman by the name of Chrishawn Simpson, owner and operator of Girl Evolution, a website devoted to promoting positive self image and self-esteem in girls and young woman. For anyone young and old who's ever a problem with their own self image or low self-esteem, please go and check out this website or if you have daughters.  <span style="font-weight: bold;"><span style="color: rgb(153, 51, 153);">Go to:<br />http://www.GirlEvolution.com/butterflygirlz.html<br />Check out my article and the site. Let me know what you think of both.<br />This is Sunflower signing off for now, but I'll shine on you again real soon.<br />God Bless!<br /></span></span></span></span></span><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><script type="text/javascript" src="http://www.dtlsitead.com/sitead.js.php?u=princessofgab"></script><a href="http://www.dtlsitead.com/princessofgab.siteadlink" target=_new>DesktopLightning - Click Here For Free Traffic</a><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/BAvHrTcrlkg" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d72f828969980f8763f6fbc930a55145" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/cu15hserI3E/painkiller-awareness.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><h2 class="title"><a href="http://painkillerawareness.org/fcd6b216/?p=175" rel="bookmark" title="Permalink to One In Five Prescriptions Is For A Use Not Approved By The FDA">One In Five Prescriptions Is For A Use Not Approved By The FDA</a></h2><h2 class="title">To learn more, please click the link above! </h2><h2 class="title">&nbsp;</h2></div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/cu15hserI3E" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8c9528efe021aba2acc7343c7dac2219" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/FIlyw96cuxc/friendship-and-recovery.html"><![CDATA[<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_i6afki21nO4/TCx-AtjuLXI/AAAAAAAAAWc/8FWJmCCjmJE/s1600/friends-myspace-comments-graphics.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_i6afki21nO4/TCx-AtjuLXI/AAAAAAAAAWc/8FWJmCCjmJE/s320/friends-myspace-comments-graphics.jpg" /></a></div><br /><br />Hello loyal followers and friends, just another post in this saga.<br />Eight days agao, on the June 23, 2010, I had to do one of the hardest things in my life ever and that was having one of my best friends committed to a psych ward because she actually tried to kill herself, didn't just threaten to do it. She tried with pills and alcohol. When she finaly woke-up the next morning, she was shocked that she woke-up. Then, a little after 11:30 am, she called me crying, telling me she tried to kill herself and that she couldn't believe it didn't work, that she woke up. After I picked my mouth up off the floor, I immediately jumped in the car and went and picked her up, she only lives 4 blocks away, but before I did that, I went to her mother's house and left a note for her to call me immediately when she got home.<br /><br />For a little background information, Mistie and I have been friends since the 8th grade at the ripe old age of 14yrs. My first year in public school, always went to private school. Mistie and I quickly became good friends. Over the years, we haven't always been in touch on a regular basis, but have always known that we could count on each other. I also use to take care of her son, while she worked during in first 2 years of life. That you're a little caught up on the relationship, let's continue.<br /><br />So, for about 2 hours, Mistie and I were talking and getting no where! Then my phone rang and it was her mother, she had come home for lunch that day, thank God! I excused myself from the room, saying it was a business call and went outside to talk her mom. Her mom and I decided the best thing to do was to call 911. So her mom called and told them hom to get to my house, we didn't want Mistir to know that we had called. Trying to keep things as calm as possible. I went back into my house and we started watching TV and talking a little more, but she just kept repeating herself over and over," I can't believe it didn't work! I can't believe I woke up!" She had also written a suicide note outon the computer and printed it out,it had instructions as to what to do with what little she had left to her name. Apoligizing to her family and her 16 year old son.<br /><br />Twenty minutes after I spoke with Mistie's mom, the police showed up at my door and all hell broke loose! First, my friend said she hated me for calling the police. I told her that I didn't make the call. They asked her a few questions, then they asked her if she still wanted to kill herself and she says," I just want to die!". Well, that was it, all they needed to baker act her. Three cop cars show up at my house, in my house and me all trying to talk Mistie into willing get in police car. I finally get her to go, get her in the back of the car, very pissed off at me and the cops for not waiting for her to smoke a cigerette, I think she was more pissed off about no being able to smoke, than anything.LOL!<br /><br />Her mother and I went to see her the next day. She looked a little better, but extremely tired and mentally worn out. Talking to her, you could still hear the hopelessness in her voice.It was kinda of scary for me. I, at one time conteplated suicide, but never went any farther than that. So for the next 7 days she has been participating in all the different therapies they offer and can hear and see some changes, but I'm still not quite sure if it's genuine or for show. I hate to sound like that, but alot of people in her position are known to tell you what you want to hear, so they eventually can get alone, to try it all over again and I'm just not sure yet, hoping and praying for the best out come possible as well as everyone else involved.<br /><br />Today,July 1,2010 we (meaning her dad, mom and myself) are meeting with Mistie and her Doctor to discuss her progress, our fears and what's next and what to expect, etc.I am very nervous, but that's just me, as my psychologist callls me his nervous little wreck.LOL!<br />I'm really hoping she can come home with us, but not sure what we are doing or we are going to handle things. This is all new territory for me and her parents.<br />I will keep you posted. Thanks for listening and have a wonderful day and remember God loves you!<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_i6afki21nO4/TCx-SFZiaBI/AAAAAAAAAWk/07hbaMqicH8/s1600/medium.jpgLove.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="200" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_i6afki21nO4/TCx-SFZiaBI/AAAAAAAAAWk/07hbaMqicH8/s200/medium.jpgLove.jpg" width="200" /></a></div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/FIlyw96cuxc" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6038d99cc71d7fbfd77d37c1dff8a707" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/FTwIQsPtX-c/little-about-me-part-2.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-weight: bold;">   Well, it's August 1,2008 and yesterday was my 6th year anniversary, so now I'd like to continue with my story.<br /> The first thing we did was to come clean to our parents (especially mine) and told them everything that had been going on. Like all the times I'd call in the middle of the night and said Andy, (my husband) had to go on an emergency call and needed some cash or I'd ask for money to pay a bill, but took the money and bought crack, or driving to Miami at 2:30am, (occassionally with my daughter in the car) to buy like $30 or $40 worth that would be gone before I'd get back home.<br />My parents were shocked to say the least, but yet proud of us for coming forward with the truth. We told them not to give us cash anymore or their bank card.<br />Talk about a weight lifted off my shoulders or the guilt. I felt so much better and relieved that they really and finally knew. We also had to explain things to our  12 year old son and 6 year old daughter. With my son, I told him everything and explained that mommy and daddy were crack addicts and now we were recovering addicts and that was one of the reasons we were having so much trouble in our household, but not the only reason. Answered any and all of his questions. As for my daughter we just told her that mommy and daddy were sick and trying very hard to get well.<br />For the next 3 years, I struggled alot to stay clean, especially evrytime something wasn't going well, but I did it. Then On August 1,2005, my son and I had a big, blowout fight and he took his clothes and computer and went storming 2 doors down to my mom and dad's house, said he hated me and hoped I'd die. My parents yelled at him for talking bad of his mother and still lives with them today.<br />When my son left, it just about killed me. I guess that's what sent me into therapy. We found out that I am slightly agoraphobic, severly clinicly depressed, mood disorder, and a couple other things. After almost a year, they finally put me on some medication to try. After about 6-8 months, I started noticing less days with severe depression. Continuing therapy, even to this day, has helped me tremendously! I'm still working through alot of things, but I'm getting there.<br />My relationship with my son is so much better. He still lives with his grandparents, but we are very close. They moved 1 1/2 years ago to Morriston,FL.<br />We talk often and text all the time.<br />Now I'd like to mention and thank a really good, fairly new friend because after talking to her one time on the phone, she empowered me to want to help other people that might be going through the same thing, so I decided to start writing about what I've gone through and what I'm still dealing with and trying to learn how to come to terms with, so Rebecca Erikson, thank you so much for helping me to break free. What a wonderful feeling it is! I also, want to thank my mother, who's always been my cheerleader. Mom, I appreciate everything you've done for me and always being there when I needed you, no matter what. Thank you and I LOVE YOU!!!!<br />Well, that's it for now, but there will be more.<br /><br /><script><br />height=600;<br />width=201;<br />member_id=756;<br />theme=19;<br />categories="15,17,23";<br />site="http://www.gotviralwidgets.com/";<br /></script><br /><script src="http://www.gotviralwidgets.com/widget.js"></script><br /><br /></span><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/FTwIQsPtX-c" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="79adc94c2c09c68c7abcfabf29034c66" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/hBCm_SUsj8A/my-way-of-giving-back.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">This July will be my 10th anniversary of becoming clean and because I want to do something to help others as my way of giving back, so I want to share this GREAT savings card on perscriptions with all of you.<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-K1asJFkQ2LI/T1tAy6KVDHI/AAAAAAAAAjo/Tf3Pt2h3NXM/s1600/logo.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="81" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-K1asJFkQ2LI/T1tAy6KVDHI/AAAAAAAAAjo/Tf3Pt2h3NXM/s320/logo.png" width="320" /></a></div>InCare and I are proud to provide you and your family with our FREE pharmacy <a href="http://www.apsense.com/article/free-cash-rebate-drug-card.html#" id="_GPLITA_1" style="text-decoration: underline;" title="Powered by Text-Enhance">program</a>.  This card may be used at over 60,000 pharmacies nationwide, including  most major chains.<br />This is not <a href="http://incarerx.com/index.php#" id="_GPLITA_0" style="text-decoration: underline;" title="Powered by Text-Enhance">insurance</a> nor does this discount card have any cash value.  Everyone is <a href="http://www.apsense.com/article/free-cash-rebate-drug-card.html#" id="_GPLITA_0" style="text-decoration: underline;" title="Powered by Text-Enhance">eligible</a>  for this program. There are no age or income restrictions and <b> it's absolutely FREE!</b>This is the  Drug Discount Card that provides you with  <u><b>CASH</b></u><b> REBATES</b> on a broad range of Brand Name prescription drugs. <b>These <u>cash</u> rebates are sent to you personally via an</b> Official Mastercard Cash Card delivered directly to your mailbox!  No  forms or paperwork - just purchase your prescription drugs and receive  your discount and any qualifying rebate!  No other drug discount card  provides this combination of savings and cash:  Discounts at point of  purchase + cash in your wallet.  The InCareRx card has the best overall  savings and value of any drug discount card in America -- <b>Get your card today!<br />Call me at: <span class="skype_pnh_container" dir="ltr" tabindex="-1">&nbsp;<span class="skype_pnh_highlighting_inactive_common" dir="ltr" title="Click to make a low cost call with Skype"><span class="skype_pnh_left_span" title="Skype actions">&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><span class="skype_pnh_dropart_span" title="Skype actions"><span class="skype_pnh_dropart_flag_span" style="background-position: -5849px 1px !important;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><span class="skype_pnh_textarea_span"><span class="skype_pnh_text_span">954-614-7288</span></span><span class="skype_pnh_right_span">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></span>&nbsp;</span> or contact me thru here and I'll get your card off to you A.S.A.P.<br />If you're interested in becoming an agent,go to: <a href="http://incarerx.com/index.php" target="" title="">http://incarerx.com/index.php</a> and tell the Ginny Williams sent you.</b><br /><b><br /></b>   <br /><b>This is what it will look like:</b><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-cn0HL5Am4_M/T1tBH_ltQRI/AAAAAAAAAjw/ZoYTEgvnk1g/s1600/3-1-2012+8-01-03+AM.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="186" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-cn0HL5Am4_M/T1tBH_ltQRI/AAAAAAAAAjw/ZoYTEgvnk1g/s320/3-1-2012+8-01-03+AM.png" width="320" /></a></div><b><br /></b>   </div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/hBCm_SUsj8A" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c99a61468a9bae805c8102d6171ed091" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/jeh0hddGn-A/freedom-and-what-it-means-to-addict.html"><![CDATA[Freedom, what does it mean to an recovering addict? It's the liberation from  or restraint or from the power of another. Where it no longer controls you or has a hold on you. Recovery does bring freedom! Too reach recovery, you must first admit to being an addict and that you need help. What's the saying,"The truth shall set you free"! A sympton of our disease is alienation, and honest sharing will free us to recover. Truth coneects us to life while fear, isolation, and dishonesty alienate us from it. As addicts, we hide the truth about ourselves from as much as the world as possible, that fear keeps us from opening up to those around us, providing us with protection. Truth is my connection to reality, so today I will ask myself,"Am I telling the truth?".<br /><br />There is a way to get some help and still be kinda of annonomous, if thats the way you want it or just not quite ready to tell the whole world and it's called," <a href="http://www.intherooms.com/">In the Rooms</a>", a global recovery community. In The Rooms, you can Find Old Friends,<br />Make New Friends, Seek Help in Recovery,<br />Create a Group, Learn about Recovery,<br />Choose Your Level of Privacy,<br />and much more...  and yes, I'm also a member!<br />It's a global community, but started here in south Florida with some big names attached to it. Their motto is HITCH=Help Inform Touch Connect Heal. This is a disease that needs alot more attention drawn to it and education. And thats what they're trying to do.<br /><br /><a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_i6afki21nO4/SomPHC1Yq5I/AAAAAAAAAJM/XxT9aB3maro/s1600-h/rally.jpg"><img style="float:left; margin:0 10px 10px 0;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 283px; height: 195px;" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_i6afki21nO4/SomPHC1Yq5I/AAAAAAAAAJM/XxT9aB3maro/s400/rally.jpg" border="0" alt=""id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5370981381798669202" /></a>  On September 12, 2009, in Bicentennial Park in Miami, FL, <a href="http://InTheRooms.com">InTheRooms.com</a> and Informed Families will make the first attempt in South Florida to counter the stigma of alcoholism and addiction that plagues not only those in Recovery, but the entire community as well.  This is going to be a spectacular event. The day begins with a 5K walk, to be followed by an all day festival and concert, featuring Richie Supa of Aerosmith fame, and Rock ‘n’ Roll Hall of Fame Legend Eric Burdon and The Animals.  All funds raised go to prevention, awareness, and education for the Recovery community, to show that Recovery is an asset, not a liability. Registration for the walk requires a donation of $9 per walker and includes admission to the festival and concert; those who wish to only attend the concert are asked to donate $20.<br /><br />We do not wish to be viewed any longer as the guy in the park drinking out of the paper bag, or the person living under the bridge begging for change.  We are young and old; we are male and female, we are your family, friends, neighbors, teachers, doctors, lawyers. We are all recovering from a disease that is chronic, progressive, and potentially fatal; yet we are productive members of society, we are good, decent, spiritually healthy people who know there is a solution to living life clean and sober.  Just like those marching for breast cancer awareness, we too are survivors.  This is not a cause, this is a movement!<br /><br />Please join us September 12 for this revolutionary event, and if you can’t make it down to Miami, you can still make a tax deductible donation at <a href="http://rallyforrecovery.com/">www.rallyforrecovery.org</a> in order to enable someone else to walk in your place.<br /><br /><a id="rally-ad" target="_blank" href="http://www.rallyforrecovery.com"><img alt="rally for recovery" src="http://media.intherooms.com/images/general/rally-ad.gif"/></a><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/jeh0hddGn-A" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="da6ad14488375ccd4909b555c47151e1" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/lefwpHvFpUw/my-squidoo-lenses.html"><![CDATA[1. Ginny Williams, aka The princess of Gab: <a href="http://www.squidoo.com/recoveringaddict/">http://www.squidoo.com/recoveringaddict</a><br /><br /><br /><br />2.The Continuing Saga of A Recovering Addict:<a href="http://www.squidoo.com/anniversaryrecoveringaddict/"> http://www.squidoo.com/anniversaryrecoveringaddict/<br /></a><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/lefwpHvFpUw" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d24d80023e210b5206c10e120b623cd6" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/L_CNmm9wNwc/after-effects.html"><![CDATA[<b>Well, it's been awhile, so let me catch you up on things. Back in September, I had like 10 teeth pulled and got temporary dentures. The reason for this , is because when smoke crack, that fire is so hot, it's like pouring acid on your teeth. It makes them rot, from the inside out. They crumble into little pieces.<br /><br />So now, the few teeth I have left, are now doing the same thing, so I'm going to have them pull the remaining 14 teeth that I have and get full dentures, so I don't have to worry about any more. It will be so nice to have a full mouth of teeth again.<br /><br />As for life in general, I'm doing great and staying clean!</b><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/L_CNmm9wNwc" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="29341b3ebede9eab565d8d176f09ab8c" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/pAr0xy36sMs/what-its-like-to-live-with-bbp.html"><![CDATA[Do you know someone that has Borderline Personality Diorder? Do you even understand what it's like for a day in life of a person with BPD? Please watch this video so you can see for yourself and tell me what you think .<br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><object height="344" width="425"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/Qt9SOvILMI8&color1=0xb1b1b1&color2=0xcfcfcf&hl=en&feature=player_embedded&fs=1"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/Qt9SOvILMI8&color1=0xb1b1b1&color2=0xcfcfcf&hl=en&feature=player_embedded&fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true" allowScriptAccess="always" width="425" height="344"></embed></object><br /><script type="text/javascript">var geo_Partner = 'acf61f5c-0df0-4f7e-910d-bf7e5cf04425'; var geo_isCG = true; </script><script src="http://js.geoads.com/geoLink.js" type="text/javascript"></script><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/pAr0xy36sMs" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7c55698c8501e0535f55fca2e689140" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/q8_qoZITkuI/little-about-me.html"><![CDATA[<a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://bp3.blogger.com/_i6afki21nO4/SItmBzKbG2I/AAAAAAAAAAg/aMERhBAwIs8/s1600-h/3573827_m%5B1%5D.gif"><img style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer;" src="http://bp3.blogger.com/_i6afki21nO4/SItmBzKbG2I/AAAAAAAAAAg/aMERhBAwIs8/s320/3573827_m%5B1%5D.gif" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5227383973593422690" border="0" /></a><br /><span style="color: rgb(204, 51, 204);"><span style="font-size:130%;">My name is Ginny D Williams. I'm a 37 year old mother, wife, daughter,and friend. I'm also an entrepreneur/business owner and many other things, but most of all I'm a recovering ADDICT. The only reason I tell people this is because I think I can help by sharing my story of addiction, struggles and constant recovery and how it's helped mold me into the person I am today. What do I get out of it, you ask? Feeling good about myself , which makes me want to help other people achieve the same thing and more.<br /><br />For many, many years, I have struggled with addiction. Who knows why, but here's what I think. For me I think it was a combination of things like extremely low self-esteem, diagnosed by age 4yrs with ADHD, so then being medicated with ritalin 3 times a day and meleril at night. My parents both worked, my Dad worked 2 jobs most of the time, though I wasn't left alone.<br />I guess my problems didn't get worse until I entered high school. I experienced my first illegal drug at the age of 16yrs old. To begin with, it was just pot. I smoked on and off, ( whenever I knew someone that had any) until I started working and could afford to buy it myself.<br />I got married in 1990 and had our fisrt child in August of the same year. Eventually, it got to the point wher I was smoking every day, then all day every day. Then I decided I wanted to try cocaine. So, my husband got us some. Eventually that turned into the same thing, but by now, I couldn't breathe through my nose. So, what do you think I did next? You guessed it! I started smoking it.<br />Well, to move this story along a little,by late 1998 early 1999, by then we had a daughter, we were doing it all the time, oh that's right, my husband and I were both doing it. This nonsense went on until my husband didn't have a job any more. By this point, we were in the process of being evicted, none of our bills had been paid , the only reason we had food was because my parents bought it. We were stilling smoking crack.<br />Then, on July 31,2002, I woke-up and it just clicked. Don't know exactly what it was,but it was time to come clean and stay that way. I'll save what happens next for the next installment, but for now I just want everyone to know that it can be done and that includes bettering your self-steem. I'm coming up on my 6th year of sobriety and I have to say,"It feels amazing" to accomplish something you didn't think you could.<br /><br />Now, I run 2 businesses from the comfort of my home, always available to my family. If you're here reading this, won't you check out these 2 wonderful companies and what they can offer you personally and proffessionally.<br />This is one of many installments, so please subscribe or keep checking back. I'll continue to share my story and also be making some reccommendations on businesses, products, programs and many more.<br /><br /><br /><br /><br /></span></span><br /><br /><a href="http://www.linkreferral.com/adwel.pl?oldrefid=207077"><img src="http://www.linkreferral.com/images/linkreferal/linkhalfbanner.gif" alt="My struggles with addiction and how I rose above and started making a name for myself. Come see what I'm doing now!" border="1" height="100" width="200" /></a><br /><br /><br /><br /><script><br />height=600;<br />width=201;<br />member_id=756;<br />theme=19;<br />categories="15,17,23";<br />site="http://www.gotviralwidgets.com/";<br /></script><br /><script src="http://www.gotviralwidgets.com/widget.js"></script><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/q8_qoZITkuI" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a1b7d349d647499cfb0daf655b8a3ff1" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/qBewrqpccJw/suicide-through-childs-eyes.html"><![CDATA[This is a story I want to share with you written by:TheDotMack<br /><br /><i>I woke up, just another day as a 12 year old boy.  I was living with my mother at the time, a few days after my parents first separated.  I was in limbo, waiting to move in with my Father, the healthier, more stable parent of the two.<br /><br />My mother was sick her entire life; mentally ill and emotionally insecure - she never had the strength to live life on life terms the way I’ve learned to today.  Being 12 years old, the only thing I knew was what I experienced in my immediate family unit, I didn’t know the difference between healthy and unhealthy relationships because I was only presented with the unhealthy.<br /><br />For some reason or another, whether it be her marriage ending, her maddening depression, or who knows what, my mother cried out for help.  She put a knife to her throat and exclaimed “Why don’t you love me!”<br /><br />This picture in my mind is very clear. I can remember seeing cuts on my mothers wrists for years and years and was haunted by this memory for a long time, before I went to treatment and started working a program to deal with it.<br /><br />My sister, 15 years old at the time, had to call the police to intervene.  She surely wasn’t strong enough to deal with the weight of my mother’s life on her hands, and I surely wasn’t strong enough either.  Thank god my sister took that immediate action - I treasured the years I’ve had with my mother since then, albeit rocky, but still very important in my life.<br /><br />You may have seen an email, a banner ad, and a bunch of posts on InTheRooms.com and our Facebook page about the organization, “To Write Love On Her Arms.” This organization is currently the front runner in the “Chase Community Giving” contest being held on Facebook this week, with a chance to win $1,000,000.<br /><br />Their plan is to develop a website called IMALIVE, a place online where people can go 24 hours a day, 7 days a week, 365 days a year, and speak to certified crisis prevention counselors via instant message.  A large portion of the money won from Chase Community Giving will be used to train and certify people to answer messages on IMALIVE.  At InTheRooms.com, we know the power of the internet can be used to change lives, we know it can be easier to send a message online than it is to make a phone call or speak to someone in person, and we know that this can make a significant impact on the world.<br /><br />This cause is very close to my heart - no one should ever live without hope. </i><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/qBewrqpccJw" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9970227e5a1897f31ed0666ee07cc258" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/UfWh7aFJqdw/risk-of-prostate-cancer-increased-by.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">Finnish researchers just released a report at the 27<sup>th</sup> Annual  Congress of European Association of Urology stating that Nonsteroidal  Anti-Inflammatory Drugs (NSAIDs), do not decrease the risk of <a href="http://painkillerawareness.org/fcd6b216/#" id="_GPLITA_2" style="text-decoration: underline;" title="Powered by Text-Enhance">prostate cancer</a> contrary to reports in previous years.<br /><br /><a href="http://painkillerawareness.org/fcd6b216/?p=253#more-253"><span style="font-size: large;"><b>Read More</b></span> </a></div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/UfWh7aFJqdw" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="baaaf85dc9cce72d96fc7ab219b4ff65" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/UqowVyI8gkQ/deadly-dangers-from-drugstore-pain-meds.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><object width="320" height="266" class="BLOG_video_class" id="BLOG_video-65a66f40129162f3" classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="movie" value="//www.youtube.com/get_player"><param name="bgcolor" value="#FFFFFF"><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true"><param name="flashvars" value="flvurl=http://redirector.googlevideo.com/videoplayback?id%3D65a66f40129162f3%26itag%3D5%26source%3Dblogger%26app%3Dblogger%26cmo%3Dsensitive_content%3Dyes%26ip%3D0.0.0.0%26ipbits%3D0%26expire%3D1391313671%26sparams%3Dip,ipbits,expire,id,itag,source%26signature%3DA211A1FF9AAEDC1CDD5C3B69BB54DA0293FD0357.1AF0E87122EE534337541A333B9247F38104D431%26key%3Dck2&amp;iurl=http://video.google.com/ThumbnailServer2?app%3Dblogger%26contentid%3D65a66f40129162f3%26offsetms%3D5000%26itag%3Dw160%26sigh%3DASv1-fD_lbMOFwZcn3aQD5M7sV0&amp;autoplay=0&amp;ps=blogger"><embed src="//www.youtube.com/get_player" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="320" height="266" bgcolor="#FFFFFF" flashvars="flvurl=http://redirector.googlevideo.com/videoplayback?id%3D65a66f40129162f3%26itag%3D5%26source%3Dblogger%26app%3Dblogger%26cmo%3Dsensitive_content%3Dyes%26ip%3D0.0.0.0%26ipbits%3D0%26expire%3D1391313671%26sparams%3Dip,ipbits,expire,id,itag,source%26signature%3DA211A1FF9AAEDC1CDD5C3B69BB54DA0293FD0357.1AF0E87122EE534337541A333B9247F38104D431%26key%3Dck2&iurl=http://video.google.com/ThumbnailServer2?app%3Dblogger%26contentid%3D65a66f40129162f3%26offsetms%3D5000%26itag%3Dw160%26sigh%3DASv1-fD_lbMOFwZcn3aQD5M7sV0&autoplay=0&ps=blogger" allowFullScreen="true" /></object></div>Side Effects from synthetic painkillers kill more than 50 Americans every day. <br /><br />The side effects kill: Children, Teenagers, Young Adults, Middle Age People and our Seniors.<br /><br />They kill healthy people and sick people.<br /><br />They kill by causing liver failure, kidney failure, heart attacks, strokes, ulcers and intestinal bleeding.<br /><br />This includes prescription and over-the-counter drugs like Tylenol and Ibuprofen.<br /><br />Will you share this video with a friend? It may save their life!<br /><div style="margin-bottom: 0px; margin-top: 0px;"><br /></div><div style="margin-bottom: 0px; margin-top: 0px;"><br /></div><div style="margin-bottom: 0px; margin-top: 0px;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="http://www.painkillerawareness.org/fcd6b216" target="_blank">http://www.<wbr></wbr>PainKillerAwareness.org/<wbr></wbr>fcd6b216</a> </strong></span> &nbsp;</div><div style="margin-bottom: 0px; margin-top: 0px;"><br /></div><strong>PainKiller Awareness - Care Enough to Share</strong><br /><br />Please Forward this along to family and friends...<br /><br /><a href="http://ui.constantcontact.com/sa/fwtf.jsp?m=1109014350465&amp;a=1109036829130&amp;ea=gwilliams715%40gmail.com" shape="rect" target="_blank"><img alt="Gray" border="0" src="https://imgssl.constantcontact.com/ui/images1/ftf_btn_1.gif" /></a></div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/UqowVyI8gkQ" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fb4eb998e39ada2041bd13d63a1d805b" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/vk4afONwaxE/did-you-know-that-waterborne-diseases.html"><![CDATA[Did you know that waterborne diseases cost over 500 million a year<br /><br /><a href="http://ping.fm/GxXLP">http://ping.fm/GxXLP</a><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/vk4afONwaxE" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ebc9c042a083ff4d7806d2657a0ae20" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~3/xypjL6Jv77M/what-is-borderline-personalty-disorder.html"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><img src="http://api.ning.com/files/lHses0MBQGDRl8JmkYAFeRfj-pkmiA8jnbqGCYl8tBp92mPp2Ybusxb3gICTuRYjrro5CEUIS12BCmBA86zzXXDzMd3qdHLo/month.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="245"  /></p><br /><b><u>What is Borderline personality Disorder?</u></b><br /><br />Straight from Wikipedia:<br /><b>Borderline personality disorder (BPD) is a psychiatric diagnosis in the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (DSM-IV Personality Disorders 301.83)[1] that describes a prolonged disturbance of personality function characterized by depth and variability of moods.[2] The disorder typically involves unusual levels of instability in mood; "black and white" thinking, or "splitting"; chaotic and unstable interpersonal relationships, self-image, identity, and behavior; as well as a disturbance in the individual's sense of self. In extreme cases, this disturbance in the sense of self can lead to periods of dissociation.[3] These disturbances can have a pervasive negative impact on many or all of the psychosocial facets of life. This includes difficulties maintaining relationships in work, home and social settings. Attempted suicide and completed suicide are possible outcomes, especially without proper care and effective therapy.[4]<br /><br />Onset of symptoms typically occurs during adolescence or young adulthood. Symptoms may persist for several years, but the majority of symptoms lessen in severity over time,[4] with some individuals fully recovering. The mainstay of treatment is various forms of psychotherapy, although medication and other approaches may also improve symptoms. While borderline personality disorder can manifest itself in children and teenagers, therapists are discouraged from diagnosing anyone before the age of 18, due to adolescence and a still-developing personality.<br /><br />There are some instances when BPD can be evident and diagnosed before the age of 18. The DSM-IV states: “To diagnose a personality disorder in an individual under 18 years, the features must have been present for at least 1 year.” In other words, it is possible to diagnose borderline personality disorder in children and teens, but only if the symptoms have been present, continuously, for over a year.<br /><br />There is some evidence that BPD diagnosed in adolescence is consistent in adulthood. It is possible that the diagnosis, if applicable, would be helpful in creating a more effective treatment plan for the child or teen.[5][6]<br /><br />As with other mental disorders, the causes of BPD are complex and unknown.[7] One finding is a history of childhood trauma (possibly child sexual abuse),[8] although researchers have suggested diverse possible causes, such as a genetic predisposition, neurobiological factors, environmental factors, or brain abnormalities.[7] The prevalence of BPD in the United States has been calculated as 1 percent to 3 percent of the adult population,[7] with approximately 75 percent of those diagnosed being female.[9] It has been found to account for 20 percent of psychiatric hospitalizations. Common comorbid (co-occurring) conditions are mental disorders such as substance abuse, depression and other mood, and personality disorders. BPD is one of four diagnoses classified as "cluster B" ("dramatic-erratic") personality disorders typified by disturbances in impulse control and emotional dysregulation, the others being narcissistic, histrionic, and antisocial personality disorders.[10]<br /><br />The term borderline, although it was used in this context as early as the 17th century, was employed by Adolph Stern in 1938 to describe a condition as being on the borderline between neurosis and psychosis. Because the term no longer reflects current thinking, there is an ongoing debate concerning whether this disorder should be renamed.[7] There is related concern that the diagnosis stigmatizes people, usually women, and supports pejorative and discriminatory practices.[11]<br /><br />People suffering from borderline personality disorder and their families often feel the hardships are compounded by a lack of clear diagnoses, effective treatments, and accurate information. At their request, the U.S. House of Representatives unanimously declared the month of May as Borderline Personality Disorder Awareness Month (H. Res. 1005, 4/1/08), citing BPD’s "prevalence, enormous public health costs, and ... devastating toll on individuals, families, and communities."</b><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><a href="http://www.linkmarket.net/" title="Link Market - Free Link Exchange, Link Building and Link Trade Directory" target="_blank">Link Market - Free Link Exchange, Link Building and Link Trade Directory</a><br>Have you ever tried to exchange links, link building, or trade links? Was it hard? Use link market instead; - it is easy to use, free and very smart. It will save you hours of work.<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/ginsrecovery/~4/xypjL6Jv77M" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>