<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="ovaismehboob.wordpress.com">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="1b177222f1b92b6980f457295331a943" url="http://ovaismehboob.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/enabling-transactions-in-wcf/"><![CDATA[Transaction plays an important role in any business application that involved CRUD operations. To implement transactions, we utilize TransactionScope class that automatically manages transactions and detect the scope of the transaction. You can apply TransactionScope on a block of code and regardless of how many WCF services instances you have opened or operation contracts you [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=ovaismehboob.wordpress.com&#038;blog=16614951&#038;post=677&#038;subd=ovaismehboob&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4df6714f88df8aa9470cdeff39170fae" url="http://ovaismehboob.wordpress.com/2013/03/29/enabling-lazy-loading-in-entity-framework-code-first-model/"><![CDATA[In Entity Framework you can configure several attributes for your Database Context class. In this article I will tell you what Is Lazy Loading and how you can leverage this feature in Code First Model. Lazy Loading is a feature through which the Code First engine loads the navigation objects that belongs to the parent [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=ovaismehboob.wordpress.com&#038;blog=16614951&#038;post=681&#038;subd=ovaismehboob&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="42e3ec798e9294d9fcbc3e4774d56c32" url="http://ovaismehboob.wordpress.com/2013/05/18/reviewed-book-object-oriented-thought-process-by-matt-weisfeld/"><![CDATA[  Being an MVB (Most Valuable Blogger) at DZone, I have gotten an opportunity to review a book named &#8220;Object-Oriented Thought Process – Fourth Edition&#8221;, written by Matt Weisfeld. Following is a review I made for this book, &#8220;A great book to learn the Object oriented principles and start thinking in object terms. Matt has [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=ovaismehboob.wordpress.com&#038;blog=16614951&#038;post=682&#038;subd=ovaismehboob&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1d2c09d06b87a1753b24976356dfd06d" url="http://ovaismehboob.wordpress.com/2013/06/22/bridging-data-between-asp-net-and-silverlight/"><![CDATA[A task comes up to me in which I have to develop a private chat application for some product. I did some research on the XMPP protocol used by Facebook, Google etc. XMPP is a powerful protocol for public chat applications where thousands of users connect with each other. It has a separate XMPP server [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=ovaismehboob.wordpress.com&#038;blog=16614951&#038;post=684&#038;subd=ovaismehboob&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="454f9af570f87bc63a2a738e596e0e39" url="http://ovaismehboob.wordpress.com/2013/07/06/production-deployment-issues-when-asp-net-web-application-access-com-component/"><![CDATA[Earlier last month we developed one project in which we had to use Office Excel COM+ component to save documents into .mht formats after manipulating them which finally displays on the browser window. It was the web application and everything was running fine at the development machine. SYMPTOMS The project got approved and when we [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=ovaismehboob.wordpress.com&#038;blog=16614951&#038;post=688&#038;subd=ovaismehboob&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f5db93c6bc7445d7449caa656161450e" url="http://ovaismehboob.wordpress.com/2013/10/15/reducing-xap-size-of-silverlight-client-apps/"><![CDATA[In this article I would like to share my experience related to the hosting of Silverlight Chat applications on real production servers and accessing it over internet. I developed a Silverlight chat application based on Silverlight 5 and ASP.Net that&#8217;s works perfectly and runs smoothly but sometimes take some time to download and load a [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=ovaismehboob.wordpress.com&#038;blog=16614951&#038;post=694&#038;subd=ovaismehboob&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9f552394e472e11787b5fe1c9678a1c4" url="http://ovaismehboob.wordpress.com/2013/10/28/loading-web-api-controllers-from-other-libraries-when-self-hosting-web-api/"><![CDATA[When Self Hosting Web API, we have to create controllers on the same project, otherwise it does not detect the libraries even if we reference the Web API project where we have all the controllers and classes defined. For example, if we have a Web API project which was hosted over IIS earlier and we [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=ovaismehboob.wordpress.com&#038;blog=16614951&#038;post=698&#038;subd=ovaismehboob&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8361f6a76403f3f381afeb50da8c5936" url="http://ovaismehboob.wordpress.com/2013/11/15/hosted-two-sessions-on-ms-dynamics-crm-and-asp-net-web-api-microsoft/"><![CDATA[As a group leader of Microsoft Technology Practices User Group i.e. http://meetup.com/mstpug, organized two sessions this week at Microsoft Innovation Center, Karachi. First Session: Customizing MS Dynamics CRM Speaker: Asif Fattah Linked In Profile: http://www.linkedin.com/pub/asif-fattah/20/69b/972 Session Duration : 1 hour   Second Session: Detailed Overview on ASP .NET Web API Speaker: Me (Ovais Mehboob Ahmed [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=ovaismehboob.wordpress.com&#038;blog=16614951&#038;post=705&#038;subd=ovaismehboob&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8a81da653083aee2ad24813b770ade79" url="http://ovaismehboob.wordpress.com/2013/11/22/reviewed-book-learning-vaadin-7-second-edition-by-nicolas-frankel/"><![CDATA[I have gotten this opportunity to review the book named &#8216;Learning Vaadin 7- Second Edition&#8217; from Packt (UK based publishing company specializing in focused IT books). Following is a review I made for this book &#8220;This book is a useful step by step guide that focuses on both basic and advanced concepts of Vaadin framework. [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=ovaismehboob.wordpress.com&#038;blog=16614951&#038;post=707&#038;subd=ovaismehboob&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d348e4a9b00837a5c716a55ea40dae2" url="http://ovaismehboob.wordpress.com/2014/01/04/creating-custom-formatter-in-asp-net-web-api-for-specific-formatted-response/"><![CDATA[In this article I will show you how to create a custom formatter in ASP.Net Web API to send formatted response. Before diving into deep, let me give you a quick introduction to formatters Formatters in ASP .NET Web API plays an important role, when the request comes to the server, depending on the media-type, [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=ovaismehboob.wordpress.com&#038;blog=16614951&#038;post=724&#038;subd=ovaismehboob&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>