<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="kimvallee.com">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="cc1e9fceebde4ac4f973c48187dd163b" url="http://kimvallee.com/case-study-lotus-f1-team-afraid-show-human-side/"><![CDATA[<p>Don&#8217;t let what happened to Formula 1 happen to you. I watch Formula 1 racing since the mid-1990s. I saw its progression from being an entertaining sport where the drivers and team owners spoke their minds to an aseptic corporate communications machine. I lost touch. I stopped reading the news. These days, I watch the...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://kimvallee.com/case-study-lotus-f1-team-afraid-show-human-side/" title="Read more about 5 tips for publishing content that matters to your audience">Read more &#187;</a></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com/case-study-lotus-f1-team-afraid-show-human-side/">5 tips for publishing content that matters to your audience</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com">Balancing Act by Kim Vallee</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1992065a60e0a825fbf4039baed927b8" url="http://kimvallee.com/how-retailer-can-use-twitter-generate-sales/"><![CDATA[<p>Seizing the opportunity is not rocket science but many brick-and-mortar retailers, big and small, are missing the boat when it comes to social media. Brick-and-mortar retailers seek ways to drive customers into their stores. Here is a way to drive to your store busy people who don&#8217;t necessarily enjoy shopping. When they know that going to...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://kimvallee.com/how-retailer-can-use-twitter-generate-sales/" title="Read more about Retail Case Study #1: How David&#8217;s Tea uses Twitter to generate more sales">Read more &#187;</a></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com/how-retailer-can-use-twitter-generate-sales/">Retail Case Study #1: How David&#8217;s Tea uses Twitter to generate more sales</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com">Balancing Act by Kim Vallee</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7b6fbd365f137b031cbb96ce82b8dfb1" url="http://kimvallee.com/keeping-advent-calendar-manageable/"><![CDATA[<p>I like some impulsivity when it comes to the little things in my life. I feel that it enables me to better adapt to the situation. This is why I will decide near the end of the afternoon what I will cook for dinner. The same goes with the activities for my son&#8217;s advent calendar....  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://kimvallee.com/keeping-advent-calendar-manageable/" title="Read more about Keeping the advent calendar manageable">Read more &#187;</a></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com/keeping-advent-calendar-manageable/">Keeping the advent calendar manageable</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com">Balancing Act by Kim Vallee</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="357894c68fe7768fbc54770579de20a0" url="http://kimvallee.com/kids-learn-critical-thinking-skills-at-art-museum/"><![CDATA[<p>A recent study involving nearly 11,000 students and almost 500 teachers in a rural community — Bentonville, Arkansas, to be precise — shows that kids acquire important skills when they are exposed to arts. This research suggests that students actually retain a great deal of factual information from their tours. And this is contrary to current museum education beliefs and practices. Jay...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://kimvallee.com/kids-learn-critical-thinking-skills-at-art-museum/" title="Read more about Kids learn critical-thinking skills and more by visiting an art museum">Read more &#187;</a></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com/kids-learn-critical-thinking-skills-at-art-museum/">Kids learn critical-thinking skills and more by visiting an art museum</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com">Balancing Act by Kim Vallee</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="80ac4467f4b418698b21a6704e48a23" url="http://kimvallee.com/mobile-shopping/"><![CDATA[<p>Smartphones have become the shopping companion of the majority of people who enter a store. A study, done in conjunction with the Google Shopper Marketing Agency Council and M/A/R/C Research, states that 84% of smartphone shoppers use their phones while in a physical store. It&#8217;s huge! As a retailer, you need to be ready for...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://kimvallee.com/mobile-shopping/" title="Read more about How smartphones transform the in-store shopping experience">Read more &#187;</a></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com/mobile-shopping/">How smartphones transform the in-store shopping experience</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com">Balancing Act by Kim Vallee</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="62c150e6af0f1162a815a1923bbc006a" url="http://kimvallee.com/setting-goals-2014/"><![CDATA[<p>Before we start, I wish you all the best for 2014. I also hoped that you had fun celebrating the New Year. I did! Have you set your New Year goals, yet? I&#8217;m still working on putting mine in words. Last year, I selected five areas for my year plan. In retrospective, 5 areas are...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://kimvallee.com/setting-goals-2014/" title="Read more about Setting goals for 2014!">Read more &#187;</a></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com/setting-goals-2014/">Setting goals for 2014!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com">Balancing Act by Kim Vallee</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="62ad504cd6b5ef8768b65d91e0dc30ad" url="http://kimvallee.com/three-words-2014/"><![CDATA[<p>Thursday, I wrote about how my plan to capture my year plan with three words. Today, I reveal what they are. Last year was a year of transition work wise. I had the guts to close At Home with Kim Vallee, the lifestyle blog that became my business. I questioned what I truly want to...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://kimvallee.com/three-words-2014/" title="Read more about My Three Words for 2014!">Read more &#187;</a></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com/three-words-2014/">My Three Words for 2014!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com">Balancing Act by Kim Vallee</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3865f6486bca4f8418410cd30d21fa54" url="http://kimvallee.com/uber-christmas-tree-campaign/"><![CDATA[<p>It is even harder for marketers to cut through the noise during the holiday season. I believe that Uber has done it this year with its Christmas tree on-demand delivery service. The #UberTree service will run for one day only in 10 US cities. For $135, an Uber driver will deliver to your front door...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://kimvallee.com/uber-christmas-tree-campaign/" title="Read more about Uber to deliver Christmas trees on-demand for one day only">Read more &#187;</a></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com/uber-christmas-tree-campaign/">Uber to deliver Christmas trees on-demand for one day only</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com">Balancing Act by Kim Vallee</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fe37f1988bfd8a5ff2cde2f8af25139a" url="http://kimvallee.com/validating-whether-or-not-to-publish-content-online/"><![CDATA[<p>A couple months after I started blogging, I developed my brand relevance checklist. I did it to ensure that what I say online would always be consistent with my personal brand and with what readers expect from me. Whenever I get a new post idea, I write a post, a tweet, a status or I...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://kimvallee.com/validating-whether-or-not-to-publish-content-online/" title="Read more about Social Media: Exercising restraints before hitting the publish button">Read more &#187;</a></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com/validating-whether-or-not-to-publish-content-online/">Social Media: Exercising restraints before hitting the publish button</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com">Balancing Act by Kim Vallee</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ce8e1465bdb22d4bea0dd4d1956baa7a" url="http://kimvallee.com/want-more-time-fix-bottleneck/"><![CDATA[<p>Like most people, you are probably rushing from morning to night.  You can accomplish a lot by determining what will be the focus of your day every morning, by sticking to what&#8217;s on your to-do list, and by limiting interruptions and other distractions. But it might not be enough. It is easy to forget about...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://kimvallee.com/want-more-time-fix-bottleneck/" title="Read more about Want less stress? Fix your bottleneck!">Read more &#187;</a></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com/want-more-time-fix-bottleneck/">Want less stress? Fix your bottleneck!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://kimvallee.com">Balancing Act by Kim Vallee</a>.</p>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>