<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="www.eugeniajongewaard.com">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="72cac36b9138f0461e1a727aa32f493b" url="http://www.eugeniajongewaard.com/2012/08/07/today-im-a-retro-gamer/"><![CDATA[Yesterday this videogame came to my mind so I wanted to post it. I used to play it when I was a little girl and it was a very good game. Great memories indeed! Did you play it too?
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7916ce276df4ee19a950b1d5d6b78255" url="http://www.eugeniajongewaard.com/2012/09/19/zendesk-maximizes-its-effectiveness-and-usability/"><![CDATA[It&#8217;s a great pleasure to announce one of the most important launches that Zendesk.com &#8211; where I work &#8211; has done so far, not only for the new look and feel of the application but also for the usability and interaction improvement that it has. &#8220;The new Zendesk provides customer service agents with rich information [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5bbbbef0892f6b5c06f109c10e317a3c" url="http://www.eugeniajongewaard.com/2012/12/05/officially-starting-with-javascript/"><![CDATA[I have been reading about javascript all this years but I&#8217;ve never studied it officially like I&#8217;m going to do now. So for you starter like me who is searching for a good video tutorial I recomend you this awesome course: Codeschool Any other to recommend me?
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5cb6df291f03c093029149f4719fbca0" url="http://www.eugeniajongewaard.com/2013/02/01/portfolio-update-sublime-text/"><![CDATA[Yay! Finally my portfolio website has been updated with my latest work. What you will see here is mainly my work as a UI Designer and Accessibility/Usability consultant. Hopefully I will also be uploading my amateur photography work really soon but in the meantime you can see my Photos on Flickr. So here it is [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ca9a8cd50cd3786baefaef0234b166dc" url="http://www.eugeniajongewaard.com/2013/02/19/3doodler-no-more-paper/"><![CDATA[This is awesome: the world&#8217;s first 3D printing pen
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c182e02a8cad1d9b04255281ca0ad566" url="http://www.eugeniajongewaard.com/2013/05/30/5-principles-of-successful-lean-product-teams/"><![CDATA[Lean production is an assembly-line methodology developed originally for Toyota and the manufacturing of automobiles. It is also known as the Toyota Production System or just-in-time production. Many industries, including software development, have adopted the principles of lean production. And these are the 5 Principles of Successful Lean Product Teams that I like the most: [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8b3a822cef035ae5d0d87f44aed692c2" url="http://www.eugeniajongewaard.com/2013/06/06/my-new-coffee-maker/"><![CDATA[Last week I bought my first expresso machine, the Oster Prima Latte. I have been testing it for a while and I can say that the gadget is really great! This little espresso machine allows you to customize the amount of milk you wish to add to your Cappuccino or Latte. It has an automatic [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9e6a8b9eafab1c010112bf0a4576a406" url="http://www.eugeniajongewaard.com/2013/06/27/how-to-fold-a-zendesk-t-shirt-in-5-seconds/"><![CDATA[
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e9c9f8ff6581b83383b8ea48742a0b56" url="http://www.eugeniajongewaard.com/2013/10/01/verbling-talking-with-native-speakers/"><![CDATA[Recently I have discovered this e-learning website called: Verbling. And when I see something I really like I love to talk about it so I thought it would deserve this post! Verbling is an awesome website that helps you learn or improve a new language by connecting you in timed video chats with other language [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e5d6165fe2abcee52fe906683f6679de" url="http://www.eugeniajongewaard.com/2013/10/17/what-is-really-google-web-designer/"><![CDATA[Everybody is talking about this new app from Google called: &#8220;Google Web Designer&#8221; but is it really a web designer tool? to clarify: Google Web Designer is primarily a tool for creating CSS3 animations on HTML5-based adverts. The company launched the free HTML5 development application at the start of October 2013. Google Web Designer includes [...]
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>