<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="jonizuka.wordpress.com">
	<documents count="7">
		<document id="ab1c0c5c3539ee3413145a0997cd174b" url="http://jonizuka.wordpress.com/2009/10/19/better-late-than-never/"><![CDATA[Since the start of my fifth fall term at the University of Oregon, I&#8217;ve been contemplating my inevitable plunge into the social media spectrum. Now, three weeks into it, I&#8217;ve decided to take a dive into my first unnerving task: the blog. The public relations scene has developed into an online frenzy of activity with [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=jonizuka.wordpress.com&#038;blog=9936429&#038;post=15&#038;subd=jonizuka&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c9ca149208a27d91b07c79191edc0b99" url="http://jonizuka.wordpress.com/2009/10/28/friend-of-the-family-with-malicious-intent/"><![CDATA[Over the weekend, the remnants of what was Washington Mutual officially switched over to a new title. Last year, WaMu went bankrupt and was sold the monstrosity that is JPMorgan Chase. Before Washington Mutual&#8217;s eventual buyout by Chase, their motto was &#8220;friend of the family,&#8221; and in my experiences, they lived up to it. Apparently, [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=jonizuka.wordpress.com&#038;blog=9936429&#038;post=29&#038;subd=jonizuka&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="22f386dfb8b058f9ebb59df2881575ff" url="http://jonizuka.wordpress.com/2009/11/01/celebrity-pr-how-much-is-too-much-information/"><![CDATA[Have you ever felt as if some celebrity gossip was just too much information? For individuals under constant public scrutiny, it is important that simple interviews and public statements do not include information that can damage their reputation. As a avid scourer of the daily headlines, I am curious as to why some celebrities feel [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=jonizuka.wordpress.com&#038;blog=9936429&#038;post=40&#038;subd=jonizuka&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f7c6a5ff21c8cc364e0b79652b64a80e" url="http://jonizuka.wordpress.com/2009/11/24/campaigning-for-better-credit/"><![CDATA[In Athens, Ga., a couple of weeks ago, I noticed a television commercial by the Advertising Council and the U.S. Treasury. The advertisement&#8217;s purpose was to encourage better credit practices for young Americans. This campaign is a beneficial way to make the public more knowledgeable of better spending habits, especially in a time serious national [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=jonizuka.wordpress.com&#038;blog=9936429&#038;post=112&#038;subd=jonizuka&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2364dd165d199db4ea0a42905d7bd525" url="http://jonizuka.wordpress.com/2010/06/01/back-off-bully/"><![CDATA[After the six-month hiatus I took from updating my PR blog, I can&#8217;t help but comment on the &#8220;That&#8217;s Not Cool&#8221; campaign that has blasted itself into my periphery. I check Google news multiple times per day, just to keep updated on certain stories, worldly news&#8230; whatnot. I&#8217;ve noticed an increase in stories covering teen bullying, [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=jonizuka.wordpress.com&#038;blog=9936429&#038;post=136&#038;subd=jonizuka&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6c35608d5d2fba93db599fda8ae3b793" url="http://jonizuka.wordpress.com/2010/07/27/handling-the-social-media-burnout/"><![CDATA[I just came across an e-release with 7 Tips for Avoiding the Social Media Burnout. I was able to relate to this article because finding time to maintain my social media sites is sometimes difficult. The world of social media is fast-paced and it&#8217;s important to stay focused so that &#8220;burnouts&#8221; don&#8217;t happen. The article lists seven [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=jonizuka.wordpress.com&#038;blog=9936429&#038;post=158&#038;subd=jonizuka&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="22c35975d816eede38eb8d00a740a07" url="http://jonizuka.wordpress.com/2013/04/22/carnival-cruises-travel-at-your-own-risk/"><![CDATA[In light of the string of Carnival Cruise Line catastrophes, Carnival declared it will spend up to $700 million to prevent further blackouts and fires on its ships. Over the past couple years, Carnival has had a cumbersome time with it’s fleet, given the constant engineering casualties, and now, its failed health inspections. From a public relations perspective, [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=jonizuka.wordpress.com&#038;blog=9936429&#038;post=171&#038;subd=jonizuka&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>