<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="www.dragonflyreiki.net">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="348417f4b1059a1a65993f31339b7868" url="http://www.dragonflyreiki.net/2013/06/perfect-just-as-you-are/"><![CDATA[Over the years, I&#8217;ve received spiritual teachings in dreams, and the one I had earlier this year was no exception. It has stayed with me, and I wanted to share it. I was facilitating a life coaching workshop for approximately 10 people. As part of the workshop, I was leading the participants through a series [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4512edce534337fe4cd9f72d9303352f" url="http://www.dragonflyreiki.net/2013/06/reiki-level-i-training-in-birmingham-al-sept-28/"><![CDATA[Why learn Reiki? Are you interested in taking better care of yourself and loved ones? Would you like to feel happier, healthier and more balanced? Register now to learn Komyo Reiki, a healing art and practice from Japan that combines hands-on treatment, practices and meditations for improved health and well-being. Komyo Reiki is true Japanese-style Usui [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="dc76e3d466dbe35721fa709b7f97d296" url="http://www.dragonflyreiki.net/2013/07/reiki-healing-at-team-decatur-get-active-event/"><![CDATA[Reiki Teacher Dana Young and Reiki Practitioner Christine Peck joined other local health and fitness organizations to offer information about and samples of Reiki healing to participants at the Team Decatur Get Active kick-off event on July 22, 2013. According to their  website, &#8220;Team Decatur is a group of City of Decatur residents, employees, and friends who [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="69136e84ac1929669ebda5f714278f67" url="http://www.dragonflyreiki.net/2013/08/healing-the-reintegration-of-self-and-source/"><![CDATA[I often receive emails or phone calls from people who want to know how quickly Reiki is going to heal them from their disease or issue. We are conditioned by a culture used to instant gratification, including pills to pop for a myriad of aches, pains or dysfunctions. We also don&#8217;t want to suffer either, [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4ac8469028c5fbe47e0b1c3978e6de35" url="http://www.dragonflyreiki.net/2013/09/embracing-your-belovedness-workshop-nov-23/"><![CDATA[Self-rejection is the greatest enemy of the spiritual life because it contradicts the sacred voice that calls us the “Beloved”. Being the Beloved expresses the core truth of our existence.” – Henri Nouwen In a world where there is so much self-doubt, pain and wounding, what does it mean to be beloved? To be beloved [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3c77d93bfc7ea62adc2bc3924b8d224e" url="http://www.dragonflyreiki.net/2013/09/healing-transformation-for-an-abundant-life/"><![CDATA[Are you&#8230; &#8230;committed to making important changes in your life for personal growth, but not sure where to begin? &#8230;seeking simple, sustainable ways to create more balance and clarity in your everyday life? &#8230;in need of one-on-one guidance for improved health and well-being? If so, I can help! I offer personalized spiritually-based coaching, combined with [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="46d462c257d67f55afd96862874f309e" url="http://www.dragonflyreiki.net/2013/10/hyakuten-inamoto-to-give-public-talk-on-reiki-history-on-nov-1/"><![CDATA[Komyo Reiki Kai founder Hyakuten Inamoto will be visiting in Atlanta at the beginning of November to offer his Komyo Reiki Kai Immersion Weekend training for qualified Reiki practitioners. On Friday, November 1, Mr. Inamoto is giving a public talk on the history of Reiki. An internationally known authority on Reiki, Mr. Inamoto will offer [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="727db0f3cebbe983753884d808a81472" url="http://www.dragonflyreiki.net/2013/12/dragonfly-reiki-awarded-best-of-2013-on-kudzu/"><![CDATA[Voted by the Kudzu Community as a Top Decatur Alternative Medicine Business! [Atlanta, GA] – December 10, 2013 – Dragonfly Reiki was named a Best of 2013 winner for Decatur Alternative Medicine on Kudzu.com, a leading source for local business information and consumer reviews. Over 5 million local businesses competed across a wide range of [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2fc944ae9908515644b4f5fc374c889b" url="http://www.dragonflyreiki.net/2013/12/reiki-fundraiser-team-in-training-jan18/"><![CDATA[My friend Andrew Johnston has been living with Chronic Myelogenous Leukemia for nearly 10 years. A former professional cyclist in Europe, Andrew is now a holistic personal trainer, author of Holistic Strength Training for Triathalon, and the first leukemia survivor to qualify for and finish an Ironman. He is happily married and his son goes [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ffc0d453fd0ecec36474a4c110fbbd80" url="http://www.dragonflyreiki.net/2014/01/5-tips-to-create-happier-healthier-life/"><![CDATA[Make meaningful changes for transformation and personal growth We are accompanied this New Year by the energies of the New Moon, symbolizing new beginnings and the release of old thoughts, feelings or patterns that no longer serve our highest good. This is a wonderful opportunity to move beyond the stale “to-do” list of resolutions and [...]
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>