<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="richfithappy.com/category/blog">
	<documents count="9">
		<document id="13f460292b4f62402e302529d6045c93" url="http://richfithappy.com/11-ways-to-detox-your-body-naturally/"><![CDATA[In this post we&#8217;re going to talk about 11 Ways To Detox Your Body Naturally! There&#8217;s a ton of supplement pushers out there who only want to sell you the next best thing when it comes to detoxing, but really what you need is products that are going to detox your body naturally.  There are 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a991dbb20bfdd78226f4000779a0ba12" url="http://richfithappy.com/eat-your-way-to-a-beautiful-you/"><![CDATA[By Alana Gold, Registered Dietitian Do you want to get rid of those bags under your eyes? Would you like your skin to have a healthy, natural glow? Of course you do! Instead of spending money on expensive beauty products to help you look rested, brighter and more youthful, why not take a trip to 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="aa8e2934556a1fde19416c3167c1f5e1" url="http://richfithappy.com/health-benefits-of-coconut-oil/"><![CDATA[It is anti-fungal, anti-bacterial and has healing properties. The benefits of coconut oil are plenty. It is the toast of the oil kingdom as it has the lowest fat content amongst all the vegetable oils. It is easily available and very cheap. Why Coconut Oil Is Beneficial? There is a scientific explanation as to what 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="97c3c22fde38b0232b888b94b71d8f9a" url="http://richfithappy.com/health-benefits-of-digestive-enzymes/"><![CDATA[Have you ever wondered about the role of enzymes in our body? Not only do they stimulate our brains but also they provide energy to the cells to repair tissues and digesting our food. The last action is done by digestive enzymes. Research claims that all diseases are a result of imbalance in the enzymes 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e7ce9233476c9b2b05fc6d51b095cb16" url="http://richfithappy.com/health-benefits-of-rooibos-tea/"><![CDATA[There are not many people who have heard of Rooibos tea. There is a plant, Rooibos or Red bush, found in South Africa. The tea is made with leaves of this plant that have been oxidized.  There are numerous benefits of Rooibos tea and that is why it is gaining popularity all over the world. 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5966e6204060ceedc869060d76850a60" url="http://richfithappy.com/health-benefits-of-super-fruits/"><![CDATA[If a balanced and nutritious diet is what you are looking for, you cannot avoid fruits. Different fruits are rich in various minerals and nutrients that benefit the body greatly. On the other hand, if fruits are good for your body, super fruits are even better. The benefits of Super fruits are well known across 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b8f5b49921dce51385ddc789818e4d73" url="http://richfithappy.com/raw-foods-are-they-beneficial-video/"><![CDATA[Ditch the Processed Foods for Raw Foods. While living in Pennsylvania I found it a bit difficult to eat raw organic foods all the time.  The reason being is that there were hardly any health food stores near by.  I find that is the number one excuse as to why people do not have a 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4d1daba9455fe7703be415377b9f3066" url="http://richfithappy.com/the-health-benefits-of-raw-food/"><![CDATA[Most people believe that there are many benefits of raw food diet. It is a diet that primarily consists of eating fruits and vegetables and other food products in their raw or uncooked form. People all over the world follow this diet as a method to detoxify their systems or as a way of life. In normal 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bd8d9f4d21a9cbb16f65df53fbfa5d76" url="http://richfithappy.com/vitamix-review/"><![CDATA[Are you seriously thinking of getting the Vitamix blender and you need to read through an unbiased Vitamix review in order to know that you are making a good investment? Well, keep reading! In this Vitamix review, I will simply point out the features that make this blender worth every single penny! Agreed, you cannot group Vitamix 
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>