<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="www.blogawardsireland.com/category/blog">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="4636fbc612145d64bba6fe5e42d3bb23" url="http://www.blogawardsireland.com/agriland-sponsors-best-outdoors-blog/"><![CDATA[As an enthusiastic farming blogger, I really wanted to add a farming category to the blog awards this year, particularly as the number of farming and gardening blogs are increasing. [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6301a6215cde8108ed8fe1622f1a0e0d" url="http://www.blogawardsireland.com/ahain-group-sponsors-best-corporate-blog/"><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve known many of the Ahain Group team for a number of  years now since I started blogging for Tweak Your Biz. We&#8217;re delighted that the relatively new Ahain Group [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4b5a7076dd5e77fe93ce4f5a1e332994" url="http://www.blogawardsireland.com/and-the-winners-are/"><![CDATA[&#160; 1. Best Great Outdoors Greenside Up 2. Best Music Blog Dublin Concerts 3. Best Popculture Blog Brand New Retro 4. Best Food / Drink Blog One Man&#8217;s Meat 5. [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="343bfce5d9d53b8f37e0f9d28a2558c0" url="http://www.blogawardsireland.com/best-overall-blog-2013/"><![CDATA[The Best Blog is being sponsored by The Digital Hub. This award goes to the highest scoring winner from the thirty categories &#8211; it will be the last award to [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="808e2a0e102011c53ac627ce5a0c943d" url="http://www.blogawardsireland.com/blog-awards-ireland-finalist-list-is-published/"><![CDATA[The Finalists are Published We would like to thank all the judges who judged the shortlist round &#8211; with thirty categories, we needed a lot of judges.  The finalists in [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b1aff7a553e9b84718fc50bcd54bba73" url="http://www.blogawardsireland.com/esb-ecars-sponsors-best-eco-green-blog/"><![CDATA[With the move to reducing our carbon footprint and reducing emissions, it is great to read more about how the ESB e-cars actually work.  There are a variety of ambassadors [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a593bb33f612a044cce3263f7352a680" url="http://www.blogawardsireland.com/lloyds-online-doctor-sponsors-best-health-wellbeing-blog/"><![CDATA[We&#8217;re bringing you some more background to Lloyds Online Doctor today, an online medical service that can have so many advantages. Lloyds Online are sponsoring Best Health &#38; Wellbeing blog. [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1fde9d88d49697d958030a04370b1b9" url="http://www.blogawardsireland.com/mcwilliamtweets-at-blog-awards-ireland/"><![CDATA[McWilliam Park Hotel has generously provided us with 3 vouchers for a stay at their hotel to give away tomorrow night at the Blog Awards! Below is an interview which [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="26f7e92c6ae44803f4583dbbd876bbcc" url="http://www.blogawardsireland.com/parcel-motel-sponsors-best-technology-blog/"><![CDATA[Have you ever gone to order something abroad and discovered they didn&#8217;t deliver to Ireland?  Or that the cost of sending it to Ireland is double that of sending it [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3fea6d75d9e5e947dc0975e5818fc249" url="http://www.blogawardsireland.com/the-digital-hub-sponsors-best-blog-in-the-2013-blog-awards/"><![CDATA[I first came across The Digital Hub when they contacted me to feature my previous business as a case study. I&#8217;ve always found them to be incredibly friendly and helpful [...]
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>