<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="www.alisonzarrella.com">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="b670a32e297c1a9d9683fae1a1abe8b7" url="http://www.alisonzarrella.com/5-tips-for-surviving-black-friday.html"><![CDATA[It&#8217;s almost here! The biggest shopping day of the year is nearly upon us. Are you ready? Here are my five tips for scoring great deals without sacrificing your sanity. With over a decade of Black Friday experience, I&#8217;ve learned how to make the most of this morning, taking advantage of everything from smartphone apps [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bb97e1df28c6f34224f12d5beb00e90e" url="http://www.alisonzarrella.com/back-to-school-ad-awesomeness.html"><![CDATA[It&#8217;s that time of year again! And while I&#8217;ve been out of school for a few years now, fall is still my all-time favorite season. I still participate in some of the back-to-school rituals, particularly shopping. Even without the 3 month summer break, fall seems like the time to start fresh. And of course, advertisers [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ab8c7457ca077b43c86a5cac31654f70" url="http://www.alisonzarrella.com/facebook-now-notifies-you-once-scheduled-posts-are-live.html"><![CDATA[Facebook wants your content, and they want it bad. As they continue to improve the post scheduling module, they appear to have rolled out a new feature starting today. Now, in addition to reminding you how many posts you have scheduled in the Activity Log, Facebook has added a Notification alert once your scheduled post [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d01094ef17f180ac1dd69c9f19a5e21f" url="http://www.alisonzarrella.com/getting-in-the-holiday-spirit.html"><![CDATA[&#8216;Tis the season&#8230;to start shopping. This holiday, retailers are upping their game with all sorts of new promotions. One that stuck out for me? Pinterest, asking people to help them create content for a Holiday Gift Guide.

The catch? It&#8217;s not even a contest! No prize, just the chance to be featured and maybe gain some [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4bfc9bdd8c11f08262f7977cc7fc5a87" url="http://www.alisonzarrella.com/pinterest-to-purchase-how-it-works.html"><![CDATA[Remember when Pinterest first launched, and people thought it was for wedding planning and not much else? It&#8217;s safe to say that Pinterest has proved itself in the business world. First they added price tagging to pins, then business listings. Now Pinterest sends reminders to users when pinned items go on sale, driving tons of [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="42e8519fef8c8a040bc8f7eeb048882a" url="http://www.alisonzarrella.com/psa-fact-check-before-you-facebook.html"><![CDATA[It&#8217;s inevitable. As more people and pages pop up on Facebook, information spreads more and more quickly. And as any journalist will tell you, if it bleeds it leads. So every Facebook login is an assault on your sensibilities, a barrage of world-ending, soul-crushing alerts about new predators and corporate corruption. 
Except, not really. I [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ae2adbfaaff329e755309528ac6ce078" url="http://www.alisonzarrella.com/pull-marketing-done-right.html"><![CDATA[As an avid online shopper (it&#8217;s research!) I see all kinds of marketing, from good to bad to—you guessed it—downright ugly. But this little email reminder option from DSW is genius. And so simple! They send an email in the morning about a sale, trying to spark your interest. When you open it, they acknowledge [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1671afe1c0820c9b49da46e002be00e5" url="http://www.alisonzarrella.com/remembering.html"><![CDATA[When I think back to September 11, 2011, I can remember vividly the moment I heard about the attacks. The edges of that day are blurry, but those first few moments remain. I was a high school junior in the second week of school. I was heading to lunch from French class. We had middle [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="eec44205676b428d85b13746940835dd" url="http://www.alisonzarrella.com/what-a-brand-should-be-in-social-media.html"><![CDATA[I saw this reply from Zappos on their Facebook page and thought it was too good to share. This is what a brand should be in social media, always.

Their reply is just perfect. They must get tons of off-topic questions not directly related to the buying experience. And there&#8217;s really no great way to answer [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8221f31f6b039156e3122cf426297ca9" url="http://www.alisonzarrella.com/why-black-thursday-is-not-the-end-of-family.html"><![CDATA[When Macy&#8217;s announced they would be open on Thanksgiving Day, it was the press release heard round the world. Or at least the US. Consumer outrage was expected and predictable, calling upon family values and questioning a greedy retailers need to be open an extra day. But what&#8217;s the real story?
Let&#8217;s talk about those &#8220;poor [...]
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>