<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="seattlesota.com">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="e1f0c1c2ada7200cdf2b1b5572fb3e12" url="http://seattlesota.com/2011/april-fools-and-social-media/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=april-fools-and-social-media"><![CDATA[Have you devised your April Fools Day pranks yet? It is on Friday! I&#8217;ve pranked people in the past but nothing too memorable so I&#8217;ve certainly been thinking about clever ways to do so this year. Now that I&#8217;m really involved in social media and a tweetaholic as many would say (yes, I&#8217;ll admit it), &#8230; <p><a class="more-link" href="http://seattlesota.com/2011/april-fools-and-social-media/">Read more &#187;</a></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="dd85b287dffc2954ee08093b0d0c632" url="http://seattlesota.com/2011/charlie-sheens-social-media-intern-april-fools/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=charlie-sheens-social-media-intern-april-fools"><![CDATA[April Fools! Yes, I fooled you. Well, some of you. A lot of you actually. I wasn&#8217;t expecting my prank to go as far as it did so I had some fun with it, perhaps too much fun. But hey, I DID warn all of you with my April Fools and Social Media post two &#8230; <p><a class="more-link" href="http://seattlesota.com/2011/charlie-sheens-social-media-intern-april-fools/">Read more &#187;</a></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="da7116839b8c6e2acbf6e9dc90a22f1a" url="http://seattlesota.com/2011/minnesota-to-seattle-roadtrip-day-three/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=minnesota-to-seattle-roadtrip-day-three"><![CDATA[Day three of our #seattlebound adventure started off with a nice continental breakfast and, of course, a stop at Starbucks. I ordered a venti-iced coffee with hazelnut to hold me over for the long road ahead. It tasted better than ever after drinking below par coffee for days! The day was off to a great &#8230; <p><a class="more-link" href="http://seattlesota.com/2011/minnesota-to-seattle-roadtrip-day-three/">Read more &#187;</a></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f3ef358923245e7d4d58140968756a76" url="http://seattlesota.com/2011/minnesota-to-seattle-roadtrip-day-two/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=minnesota-to-seattle-roadtrip-day-two"><![CDATA[&#160; We woke up at 6:30 am sharp ready to tackle day two of our #seattlebound adventure. It was raining (of course) and I knew as we departed our barn style motel in the Badlands of North Dakota that there wasn&#8217;t decent coffee anywhere near by. About an hour later on the road we saw &#8230; <p><a class="more-link" href="http://seattlesota.com/2011/minnesota-to-seattle-roadtrip-day-two/">Read more &#187;</a></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e7d2625ea655991477777adf3c105f64" url="http://seattlesota.com/2011/minnesota-to-seattle-roadtrip-final-day/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=minnesota-to-seattle-roadtrip-final-day"><![CDATA[It has taken me far too long to report on the final day of the infamous #seattlebound roadtrip. In case you are wondering, yes, we DID make it! I&#8217;ve been enjoying all that Seattle offers for about a week and life has been pretty crazy. The final leg of the drive was definitely exhilarating, but &#8230; <p><a class="more-link" href="http://seattlesota.com/2011/minnesota-to-seattle-roadtrip-final-day/">Read more &#187;</a></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b611a478d38f890992fb36e4ffd51891" url="http://seattlesota.com/2011/minnesota-twins-baseball-season/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=minnesota-twins-baseball-season"><![CDATA[One of my favorite weekends is here: Minnesota Twins Home Opener Weekend! WOO HOO! I am beyond excited as I am an avid baseball fan. I have always been a big fan and grew up going to games with my dad. Baseball is one thing that has always brought my Dad and I together. There &#8230; <p><a class="more-link" href="http://seattlesota.com/2011/minnesota-twins-baseball-season/">Read more &#187;</a></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ff95c47b63f40c18dfb6b935942ba5fb" url="http://seattlesota.com/2011/moving-to-seattle/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=moving-to-seattle"><![CDATA[I&#8217;m moving to Seattle! Finally. It has been a dream of mine since the fall and I&#8217;m so excited it is finally happening. I started this blog seattlesota not knowing when I would make the move from Minnesota to Seattle. My Seattle Twitter Story is definitely one I love to share to because it reminds me &#8230; <p><a class="more-link" href="http://seattlesota.com/2011/moving-to-seattle/">Read more &#187;</a></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="df5e1fa13d9afef80017d4d8d632b76c" url="http://seattlesota.com/2011/my-life-in-seattle/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=my-life-in-seattle"><![CDATA[All I can say is WOW. The past three weeks of my life have been absolutely bustling, challenging exciting, and restless. This post is way overdue and for those of you in Seattle, you know why. I have been so busy and I literally have spent only one or two nights at home. My life &#8230; <p><a class="more-link" href="http://seattlesota.com/2011/my-life-in-seattle/">Read more &#187;</a></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e01fc9402a0cc48f0c5d1eff3f49248d" url="http://seattlesota.com/2011/seattle-to-minnesota-roadtrip-day-one/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=seattle-to-minnesota-roadtrip-day-one"><![CDATA[The big day finally arrived! May 9. Nine is my favorite number for many reasons. My birthday is March 9, my soccer number was number nine and Mia Hamm&#8217;s number was nine. Good things always seem to happen to me on the 9th. Today was no exception! My journey to Seattle began! I woke up &#8230; <p><a class="more-link" href="http://seattlesota.com/2011/seattle-to-minnesota-roadtrip-day-one/">Read more &#187;</a></p>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b3a937f40f6bcc006b7fc0e24720ac60" url="http://seattlesota.com/2011/twitter-cartoons/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=twitter-cartoons"><![CDATA[It is a Monday morning and after waking up early I wanted a good laugh. Who doesn&#8217;t? I found some fun Twitter cartoons I thought you might like to get your week started. Enjoy! (click on them to enlarge) &#160; Have you found any funny social media cartoons? Please share with me! Happy Monday!
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>
