<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="decelerator.blogspot.com.es">
	<documents count="25">
		<document id="d11ffc47e0d5059c2231809beb23a20f" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/0W8wrLnynPU/d-mesons-flipping.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="mobile-photo"><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="300" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5849980059191528162" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-JZ_NlLU2qU8/US9N3os6yuI/AAAAAAAAAa4/WO6d5I44CHA/s400/lhcb_magnet-722650.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">The magnet at the LHCb detector</td></tr></tbody></table></div><br />A <a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1211.1230" target="_blank">result today from the LHCb</a> had me humming: <br />"On the 18th day of shut-down, my true love sent to me: D mesons flipping". <br /><br />To put this in English, the Large Hadron Collider's <a href="http://lhcb-public.web.cern.ch/lhcb-public/Welcome.html" target="_blank">LHCb detector</a> has <a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1211.1230" target="_blank">published</a> highly significant results indicating that they have detected particles called <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/D_meson" target="_blank">D mesons</a>, oscillating from matter into antimatter. The results come 18 days after the LHC shut down for maintenance.<br /><br /><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1211.1230" target="_blank">Their paper</a>, pre-published on <a href="http://arxiv.org/" target="_blank">arXiv</a>, outlines how the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/D_meson" target="_blank">D mesons</a>, the last of the four types of mesons to be 'observed' undergoing this oscillation, were detected to a five-sigma level of certainty.<br /><br />As <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-21594357" target="_blank">science writer Jason Palmer</a> puts it:<br />"In the complicated zoo of subatomic physics, particles routinely decay into other particles, or spontaneously change from a matter type to their antimatter counterparts. This "oscillation" forms an important part of the theory that attempts to tame the zoo - the Standard Model. Mesons are part of a large family of particles made up of the fundamental particles known as quarks. The protons and neutrons at the centres of the atoms of matter we know well are each made up of three such quarks. <br />Mesons, on the other hand, are made of just two - specifically one quark and one antimatter quark. Theory holds that four members of the meson family can undergo the matter-antimatter oscillation - the matter and antimatter quarks both flip to their opposites."<br /><br />The <a href="http://lhcb-public.web.cern.ch/lhcb-public/Welcome.html" target="_blank">LHCb</a>, which has had a series of <a href="http://decelerator.blogspot.fr/2012/11/your-move-theorists.html" target="_blank">stunning results with B mesons</a>, had observed two types of B mesons and a K meson oscillating between matter and antimatter before.&nbsp; But with this new paper, the team provide evidence that the last of the four types of particles, D mesons, has now been detected undertaking the same type of oscillation.<br /><br />As Chris Parkes, LHC researcher from University of Manchester <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-21594357" target="_blank">said</a>:<br />"This is a nice moment, it's a sort of completeness.”<br /><br />It is striking to note that <a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1211.1230" target="_blank">the abstract on arXiv</a> lists <i><b>60</b></i> authors, with another <i><b>550</b></i> not cited, due to lack of space. This really underscores the collaborative nature of physics at the Large Hadron Collider.<br /><br />The results are significant because the <a href="http://lhcb-public.web.cern.ch/lhcb-public/Welcome.html" target="_blank">LHCb</a> is investigating the unsolved question of <a href="http://lhcb-public.web.cern.ch/lhcb-public/en/Physics/Antimatter-en.html" target="_blank">why there is more matter than antimatter in the Universe</a>. According to the Standard Model, particles of matter and antimatter come in pairs, and matter and antimatter should obey the same laws.&nbsp; Therefore, we ought to expect an equal amount of both.&nbsp; So the question, "where's all the antimatter?" has had physicists scratching their heads for some time. The team at the <a href="http://lhcb-public.web.cern.ch/lhcb-public/Welcome.html" target="_blank">LHCb</a>, are undertaking some of the most significant and fundamental work to try and answer this question.<br /><br /><a href="http://lhcb-public.web.cern.ch/lhcb-public/Welcome.html" target="_blank">LHCb</a>'s result comes through two and half weeks after the LHC was shut-down for a lengthy period of maintenance.&nbsp; But it emphasises just how much science will be carrying on whilst the main detectors are serviced and upgraded. The data collected by researchers during the first phase of collisions will be pored over for years to come, and we should expect more fascinating results like these, in the coming months.<br /><br />Source: <a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1211.1230">http://arxiv.org/abs/1211.1230</a><br /><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-21594357">http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-21594357</a></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/0W8wrLnynPU" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bb6c9e617cbe2dab5367e8b13e29f564" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/3AuePOOpYXU/new-zealand-recognised-as-major.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-orbujmdSgyY/URDHS7sclWI/AAAAAAAAAX0/lG69L0L2_dw/s1600/bolton_stanley-791439.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="343" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5841387844775220578" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-orbujmdSgyY/URDHS7sclWI/AAAAAAAAAX0/lG69L0L2_dw/s400/bolton_stanley-791439.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">John Bolton (left) and New Zealander Gordan Stanley (centre), pictured with Jow Pawsey</td></tr></tbody></table><div>New Zealand has claimed its place in radio astronomy history.&nbsp;As <a href="http://decelerator.blogspot.co.uk/2012/01/remnants-of-cosmic-noise-in-new-zealand.html" target="_blank">reported here a year ago</a>, New Zealand has significant scientific heritage in the field of radio astronomy, and has begun to explore and celebrate this history.</div><div><br /></div><div>Last week, some of the biggest names in the field gathered for <a href="http://www.irasr.aut.ac.nz/conferences/new-zealand-and-the-beginnings-of-radio-astronomy-a-process-of-discovery/programme" target="_blank">an  international conference</a> which  marked New Zealand's role in helping to kick-start radio astronomy  research in the 1940s.&nbsp; Attended by the doyenne of the field,<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jocelyn_Bell_Burnell" target="_blank">  Jocelyn Bell Burnell</a>, and researchers and historians from New Zealand,  Australia and the UK, the conference explored the work of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Gatenby_Bolton" target="_blank">John Bolton</a>  and New Zealander,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.atnf.csiro.au/news/newsletter/feb02/Vale_Gordon_Stanley.htm" target="_blank">Gordon Stanley</a>, who detected radio waves from outside the solar  system in August 1948 from sites in Pakiri and Piha  in the North Island of New Zealand.<br /><br /></div><div><br /><table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-z09tB3_blOg/UREcgdfzo5I/AAAAAAAAAYU/E3PAMpPfcd8/s1600/elis.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-z09tB3_blOg/UREcgdfzo5I/AAAAAAAAAYU/E3PAMpPfcd8/s400/elis.jpg" width="312" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Elizabeth Alexander</td></tr></tbody></table>The conference also commemorated the pioneering work of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elizabeth_Alexander_(astronomer)" target="_blank">Elizabeth  Alexander,</a> often referred to as the first female radio astronomer, who  helped helped establish some of the early foundations of solar radio  astronomy in 1946. Alexander studied sources of interference  effecting radar stations in New Zealand established during World War II.&nbsp; During  March-April 1945, solar radio emission was detected at 200 MHz by  operators of a Royal New Zealand Air Force radar unit located on  Norfolk Island.</div><div>The emissions became known as the <a href="http://norfolkislandmuseum.blogspot.co.uk/2011/02/norfolk-island-effect.html" target="_blank">"Norfolk Island effect"</a>. Alexander, then based at the Department of  Scientific and Industrial Research in Wellington, heading up the  Operational Research Section of the Radio Development Laboratory,  carried out the most significant early work on the effect throughout  1945. In 1946. she published a paper in the journal, Radio &amp;  Electronics describing the emissions, and in doing so, furthered the fledgling  field of radio astronomy.</div><div><br /></div><div><a href="http://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007%2F1-4020-3724-4_5?LI=true" target="_blank">Wayne Orchiston, writing in "The New Astronomy"</a>,  has noted that Alexander's research also led to further solar radio  astronomy projects in New Zealand in the immediate post-war year, and  in part was responsible for the launch of the radio astronomy program  at the CSIRO, in Australia."<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-IHPaLhWAPFs/UREdLQcDG_I/AAAAAAAAAYc/JX5k-75mR_s/s1600/orchiston2.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="242" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-IHPaLhWAPFs/UREdLQcDG_I/AAAAAAAAAYc/JX5k-75mR_s/s400/orchiston2.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Radar Station (Whangaroa) - one of five involved in New Zealand's investigation of solar radio emission.&nbsp;Image courtesy of Wayne Orchiston.</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div>Astronomer Miller Goss, from the National Astronomy Observatory  in New Mexico, <a href="http://www.piha.co.nz/on-the-trail-of-cosmic-noise-at-piha/" target="_blank">puts it</a>:</div><div>"Bolton and Stanley's discovery revolutionised twentieth  century astronomy."</div><div><br /></div><div>Following their pioneering discoveries, Bolton went on to become  a major figure in Australian radio astronomy, helping found the famous  Parkes radio telescope, becoming director of the Australian National  Radio Astronomy Observatory and winning the the inaugural Jansky Prize  in 1966 (so named after the father of radio astronomy, Karl  Jansky).</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-pkEE5Qpna_E/URDHT81-pWI/AAAAAAAAAYA/ZIuH7l8mPPg/s1600/AFK_4862-795242.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="266" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5841387862263506274" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-pkEE5Qpna_E/URDHT81-pWI/AAAAAAAAAYA/ZIuH7l8mPPg/s400/AFK_4862-795242.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Sergei Gulyaev</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div>&nbsp;The conference was organised by the extraordinary <a href="http://www.aut.ac.nz/profiles/computing-mathematical-sciences/professors/sergei-gulyaev" target="_blank">Sergei Gulyaev</a>, who has revitalised radio astronomy in  New Zealand, spearheading the nation's participation in the <a href="http://decelerator.blogspot.co.uk/2011/04/jodrell-bank-selected-as-square.html" target="_blank">SKA</a>, amongst many other efforts.</div><div><br /></div><div>Source:  <a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/auckland/local-news/rodney-times/8250497/Stars-align-for-conference">http://www.stuff.co.nz/auckland/local-news/rodney-times/8250497/Stars-align-for-conference</a></div></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/3AuePOOpYXU" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d681f9aab46f51c778b1ea6c076ecf73" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/3vF2nfBZfE4/there-but-invisible.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-FCldM8LpOto/UsK9bYqe2vI/AAAAAAAAAj0/6FhP0Pdipvk/s1600/swell-788820.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="266" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5963537134766709490" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-FCldM8LpOto/UsK9bYqe2vI/AAAAAAAAAj0/6FhP0Pdipvk/s400/swell-788820.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><i>Swell</i> by Anthony McCall. Commissioned by AV Festival 2006.</td></tr></tbody></table><br />In physics, the darkness is the most illuminating place to look, if you want to understand the Universe right now. This year, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planck_(spacecraft)#2013_data_release" target="_blank">Planck</a> told us that <a href="http://www.nature.com/news/planck-telescope-peers-into-primordial-universe-1.12658" target="_blank">26.8% of all matter is dark</a>. Thanks to the earlier work of Brian Schmidt, Saul Perlmutter and Eric Riess, cosmologists also have to deal with the fact that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accelerating_expansion_of_the_Universe" target="_blank">the Universe is expanding at an ever increasing rate</a>, and that the energy responsible for that - <a href="http://www.darkenergysurvey.org/" target="_blank">dark energy</a> - accounts for 68.3% of all energy. <br /><br />So we now know that nearly 96% of the Universe is dark. It is <a href="http://is.gd/thereinvisible" target="_blank">there; but invisible</a>.<br /><br />But what this means is that we live in some of the most exciting times imaginable.<br />Because <a href="http://www.nobelprize.org/nobel_prizes/physics/laureates/2011/press.html" target="_blank">we live in a Universe that is to a large extent unknown to science</a>, and therefore the systems that govern all but 4% of the Universe are yet to be discovered. <br /><br /><i><a href="http://decelerator.blogspot.co.uk/2013/07/and-everything-is-possible-again.html" target="_blank">"And, everything is possible again."</a></i><br /><br />I'll be taking that thought into 2014.<br /><br />Honor Harger<br />31 December 2013<br /><div><br /></div></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/3vF2nfBZfE4" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e2f3286e164a228d60347ba11985bfe7" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/4m2SLc5rS3Y/listening-to-aurora.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="mobile-photo">&nbsp;<a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-I4Y77jYMn74/T_tTWmlvHoI/AAAAAAAAAPE/YLUfXl9fa1M/s1600/aurora1_wikipedia-738202.jpg"><img alt="" border="0" height="300" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5763291795931733634" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-I4Y77jYMn74/T_tTWmlvHoI/AAAAAAAAAPE/YLUfXl9fa1M/s400/aurora1_wikipedia-738202.jpg" width="400" /></a></div>For centuries, <a href="http://www.environmentandsociety.org/arcadia/sounds-sky-listening-aurora-borealis-fort-chipewyan">folklore has reported that people have been able to&nbsp;hear, as well as see, the Northern Lights</a>, or the aurora borealis.&nbsp;For the first time, researchers in Finland have been able to provide<br />evidence of what these historical listeners may have been detecting. <br /><br />The "auroral sounds" are formed about 70 meters above the ground&nbsp;level, <a href="http://www.aalto.fi/en/current//news/view/2012-07-09/">according to a team from Aalto University in Finland</a>. They report&nbsp;that "researchers located the sound sources by installing three&nbsp;separate microphones in an observation site where the auroral sounds&nbsp;were recorded. They then compared sounds captured by the microphones&nbsp;and determined the location of the sound source. The aurora borealis&nbsp;was seen at the observation site. The simultaneous measurements of&nbsp;the geomagnetic disturbances, made by the Finnish Meteorological&nbsp;Institute, showed a typical pattern of the northern lights episodes."<br /><br /><a href="http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2012/07/120709093048.htm">Science Daily&nbsp;noted&nbsp;that</a>:&nbsp;"Details about how the auroral sounds are created are still a&nbsp;mystery. The sounds do not occur regularly when the northern lights&nbsp;are seen. The recorded, unamplified sounds can be similar to crackles&nbsp;or muffled bangs which last for only a short period of time. Other&nbsp;people who have heard the auroral sounds have described them as&nbsp;distant noise and sputter. Because of these different descriptions,&nbsp;researchers suspect that there are several mechanisms behind the&nbsp;formation of these auroral sounds. These sounds are so soft that one&nbsp;has to listen very carefully to hear them and to distinguish them&nbsp;from the ambient noise."<br /><br />Professor <a href="http://www.aalto.fi/en/current//news/view/2012-07-09/">Unto Laine from Aalto University commented</a>, "our&nbsp;research proved that, during the occurrence of the northern lights,&nbsp;people can hear natural auroral sounds related to what they see. In&nbsp;the past, researchers thought that the aurora borealis was too far&nbsp;away for people to hear the sounds it made. This is true. However,&nbsp;our research proves that the source of the sounds that are associated&nbsp;with the aurora borealis we see is likely caused by the same&nbsp;energetic particles from the sun that create the northern lights far&nbsp;away in the sky. These particles or the geomagnetic disturbance&nbsp;produced by them seem to create sound much closer to the ground."<br /><br />Source: <a href="http://www.aalto.fi/en/current//news/view/2012-07-09/">http://www.aalto.fi/en/current//news/view/2012-07-09/</a><br />Listen: <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NRZfKqhs6rM">http://www.youtube.com</a></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/4m2SLc5rS3Y" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="cbd45e0c77fb9c103c6db4df4a3b1f8e" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/aPUraazdqvY/plants-doing-quantum-physics.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="mobile-photo"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hTpCrzO9lkY/UcR7CHGKmGI/AAAAAAAAAdg/DEpcpUnGUpk/s1600/57977_web-747551.jpg"><img alt="" border="0" height="280" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5891969488702314594" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hTpCrzO9lkY/UcR7CHGKmGI/AAAAAAAAAdg/DEpcpUnGUpk/s400/57977_web-747551.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><div><br />This week the fledgling field of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantum_biology" target="_blank">quantum biology</a> took a major step  forward with the publication of a significant study in <a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/content/340/6139/1448.full?rss=1" target="_blank">Science</a>.</div><div><br /></div><div>In the study, scientist, Niek van Hulst, and colleagues at <a href="http://www.icfo.eu/" target="_blank">the  Institute of Photonic Sciences</a> in Castelldefels  in Spain, outlined a extensive set of experiments which give the most  concrete evidence yet of quantum principles being involved with the  process of photosynthesis in plants.&nbsp;</div><div>The study, whilst not the first to suggest that quantum processes  are involved in photosynthesis, is important, as until now, no one had  directly observed the impact of this kind of quantum mechanism at  work, at room temperature. </div><div><br /></div><div>As <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-22996054" target="_blank">Jason Palmer writes</a>: "Plants gather packets of light called photons, shuttling  them deep into their cells where their energy is converted with  extraordinary efficiency. [?] An effect called a "coherence"  helps determine the most efficient path for the photons. [....] The  new study has been done painstakingly, aiming lasers at single  molecules of the light-harvesting machinery to show how light is  funnelled to the so-called reaction centres within plants where light  energy is converted into chemical energy."</div><div><br /></div><div>Quantum mechanics tends to be observed at very small, subatomic  scales and at extremely cold temperatures. Organisms as large, wet and  warm as plants have largely been understood using the principles of  "classical physics".&nbsp; But, the field of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantum_biology" target="_blank">quantum biology</a> has for some years now  been suggesting a far deeper entanglement between large complex  biological organisms and quantum mechanics.&nbsp; Various research  groups have shown that efficient energy transport in plants is  connected to a quantum-mechanical phenomenon. In 2007, Berkeley Lab  and the University of California published <a href="http://www.lbl.gov/Science-Articles/Archive/PBD-quantum-secrets.html" target="_blank">a paper in Nature that  suggested that electronic quantum coherence played a role in  photosynthesis</a>.</div><div><br /></div><div><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-YHZ_D9O4Qyc/UcR7CXj_fnI/AAAAAAAAAds/MoS6q6fB51s/s1600/plant-749445.jpg"><img alt="" border="0" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5891969493122383474" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-YHZ_D9O4Qyc/UcR7CXj_fnI/AAAAAAAAAds/MoS6q6fB51s/s320/plant-749445.jpg" /></a></div><div><br /></div><div>This week's <a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/content/340/6139/1448.full?rss=1" target="_blank">paper</a> by the  <a href="http://www.icfo.eu/newsroom/news2.php?id_news=1990&amp;subsection=home" target="_blank">Institute of Photonic Sciences</a>'&nbsp;underscores this, and provides compelling evidence. As  Rienk van Grondelle of the Free University Amsterdam noted in <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-22996054" target="_blank">an  interview with the BBC</a>, it is,  "a very nice proof that the ideas that existed about these  coherences are actually correct".</div><div><br /></div><div>The research paves the way for far closer links between two  fields of science - quantum physics and biology - often considered,  with some humour, as polar opposites.&nbsp; Greater collaborations  between quantum physicists and biologists is likely to lead to  important new insights in the coming years.&nbsp; It is hoped by many  scientists that understanding how quantum processes are involved in  how plants harness energy could be applied to the development of, for  example, <a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm?id=quantum-entanglement-and-photo" target="_blank">more efficient solar cells, something which has been  discussed for a few years now</a>.</div><div><br /></div><div>The field of quantum biology may just be coming of age.</div><div><br />Sources:<br /><a href="http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2013/06/130620142932.htm">http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2013/06/130620142932.htm</a><br /><a href="http://www.scienceworldreport.com/articles/7673/20130621/quantum-mechanical-secret-revealed-photosynthesis-future-solar-energy.htm">http://www.scienceworldreport.com/</a></div><div><a href="http://www.icfo.eu/newsroom/news2.php?id_news=1990&amp;subsection=home">http://www.icfo.eu/</a></div></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/aPUraazdqvY" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3d4d65e446b8c66f50dce753c9275385" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/bIbWy-mH1tw/archeologists-of-sky.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="mobile-photo"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ybVAueJBn7g/UHq5D75U5vI/AAAAAAAAASQ/s1yWDP3RdUw/s1600/ASKAP1-746463.jpg"><img alt="" border="0" height="195" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5799150947461818098" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ybVAueJBn7g/UHq5D75U5vI/AAAAAAAAASQ/s1yWDP3RdUw/s400/ASKAP1-746463.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><div><br />This week I have been spending a lot of time thinking about the  artwork of <a href="http://www.lighthouse.org.uk/programme/trevor-paglen-geographies-of-seeing" target="_blank">Trevor Paglen</a>, which is currently featuring in an exhibition I  co-curated at <a href="http://www.lighthouse.org.uk/" target="_blank">Lighthouse</a> in Brighton,  UK called <a href="http://www.lighthouse.org.uk/programme/trevor-paglen-geographies-of-seeing" target="_blank"><i>Geographies of Seeing</i></a>. Paglen describes his practice as "experimental geography". He is interested in illuminating the "black world"  of clandestine military operations carried out in orbit and here on earth.<br /><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-eBgEsNZU07Y/UHq5EU0LQLI/AAAAAAAAASc/IGfKAQ0VM8c/s1600/ASKAP_Paglen_moon-748971.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="300" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5799150954151100594" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-eBgEsNZU07Y/UHq5EU0LQLI/AAAAAAAAASc/IGfKAQ0VM8c/s400/ASKAP_Paglen_moon-748971.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><i>They Watch the Moon</i>, 2010, C-print © Trevor Paglen</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br />To do so, <a href="http://bampfa.berkeley.edu/press/release/TXT0226" target="_blank">one writer has noted</a>, "Paglen looks  upwards to the night sky, one of the oldest laboratories of rational  thought".<br /><br />This quote prompted <a href="https://twitter.com/marksimpkins/status/257103814694404096" target="_blank">Mark Simpkins to note  that</a>, "astronomy is archaeology of the sky", something that  resonated strongly with me. It prompted me to check in on the progress  of the 21st century's grandest sky archaeology project - <a href="http://decelerator.blogspot.co.uk/2011/04/jodrell-bank-selected-as-square.html" target="_blank">the Square Kilometre Array, or SKA</a>.</div><div><br /></div><div>As <a href="http://decelerator.blogspot.co.uk/2011/04/jodrell-bank-selected-as-square.html">we reported in April last year</a>, the <a href="http://www.skatelescope.org/" target="_blank">SKA</a> will be the world's largest and most  sensitive radio telescope.&nbsp; Rather than being a huge single radio  dish, it will be made up of thousands of smaller ones, which are  distributed across vast geographical areas.</div><div><br />In May this year <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/science/2012/may/25/africa-australasia-square-kilometre-array" target="_blank">it was announced</a> that the <a href="http://www.skatelescope.org/" target="_blank">SKA</a>  would be jointly hosted in  Southern Africa and Australia and New Zealand, a decision that  prompted some controversy, as the two geographical areas had been in  direct competition to host the array.&nbsp; But controversies aside,  this month, the <a href="http://www.skatelescope.org/" target="_blank">SKA</a>  took a major step forward with the launch of  Australia's <a href="http://www.askap.org/" target="_blank">ASKAP</a> - or Australian Square  Kilometre Array Pathfinder.</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-fdFSPjZNvGA/UHq5E1GbWPI/AAAAAAAAASo/8oui06vIcmA/s1600/ASKAP_DRAGONFLY-750979.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="266" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5799150962817587442" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-fdFSPjZNvGA/UHq5E1GbWPI/AAAAAAAAASo/8oui06vIcmA/s400/ASKAP_DRAGONFLY-750979.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Australian Square  Kilometre Array Pathfinder (ASKAP). Image courtesy of CSIRO.</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br /><a href="http://www.askap.org/" target="_blank">ASKAP</a> is located in remote Western Australia, and is operated by  the <a href="http://www.astro.uwa.edu.au/ska/mro">Murchison Radio Astronomy Observatory</a>. It is made up of 36 identical  antennas, each 12 metres in diameter, working together as a single  instrument, using the technique of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Astronomical_interferometer" target="_blank">interferometry</a>.&nbsp; As  well as being a significant radio telescope in its own right, <a href="http://www.askap.org/" target="_blank">ASKAP</a> is  an important testbed for the <a href="http://www.skatelescope.org/" target="_blank">SKA</a> .</div><div><br />A new receiver technology called a "phased array feed" means<a href="http://www.askap.org/" target="_blank"> ASKAP</a> will be able scan the sky much more rapidly than existing radio  telescopes, prompting claims it is the fastest radio telescope in the  world today.</div><div>The sky archaeologists at <a href="http://www.askap.org/" target="_blank">ASKAP</a> are focusing on some of the major  fundamental issues within cosmology and astronomy.&nbsp; <a href="http://www.askap.org/" target="_blank">ASKAP</a> is  expected to make advances in understanding galaxy formation, dark  energy the evolution of the Universe. Some of the initial research  will include a census of all galaxies within two billion light years.  This may shed light on how our own galaxy, the Milky Way, was  formed.</div><div><br />Brian Boyle, the director of <a href="http://www.askap.org/" target="_blank">ASKAP</a> for <a href="http://www.csiro.au/" target="_blank">CSIRO</a>,  Australia's national scientific research organisation, explained why  radio astronomy is such a powerful tool in the arsenal of modern  science:</div><div>"Radio waves tell us unique things about the cosmos, about  the gas from which stars were formed, and about exotic objects,  pulsars and quasars, that really push the boundaries of our knowledge  of the physical laws in the universe".</div><div><br /></div><div><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-GRfrzyAyl84/UHq5FeFqMRI/AAAAAAAAAS0/cF_zCa6846c/s1600/ASKAP_good-753245.jpg"><img alt="" border="0" height="287" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5799150973820219666" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-GRfrzyAyl84/UHq5FeFqMRI/AAAAAAAAAS0/cF_zCa6846c/s400/ASKAP_good-753245.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><div><br />Writer, <a href="http://www.cosmosmagazine.com/news/6044/worlds-fastest-radio-telescope-starts-australian-outback" target="_blank">Rebekah Kebede notes </a>that <a href="http://www.askap.org/" target="_blank">ASKAP</a> is located in remote  Murchison, "an area of 50,000 square kms, or the size of Costa  Rica, with barely 120 people."<br /><br />The location is ideal for radio astronomy because it is "radio  quiet" - it lacks man-made radio signals that interfere with  antennas designed to detect celestial signals.&nbsp; The area is the  home of <a href="http://www.ymac.org.au/go/about-us" target="_blank">the Yamatji Marlpa people</a>, who are the traditional owners  of the land on which the observatory is cited.</div><div><br /></div><div><a href="http://www.askap.org/" target="_blank">ASKAP</a> opened on 5 October 2012. Australia will build  another 60 antennas for the <a href="http://www.skatelescope.org/" target="_blank">SKA</a>, which begins construction in  2016.</div><div><br /></div><div>Huffington Post writer, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/alex-cherney/" target="_blank">Alex Cherney</a> has put together a  stunning time-lapse video showing <a href="http://www.askap.org/" target="_blank">ASKAP</a> in motion. The two night-sky  images of <a href="http://www.askap.org/" target="_blank">ASKAP</a> used in this post are from him.<br /><br /></div><div><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/FDoDk4D2RAw" width="560"></iframe> </div><br />Sources:<br /><a href="http://phys.org/news/2012-10-askap-dish-australian-telescope-array.html">http://phys.org/news/2012-10-askap-dish-australian-telescope-array.html</a><br /><a href="http://www.universetoday.com/97688/36-dish-australian-telescope-array-opens-for-business/">http://www.universetoday.com/97688/36-dish-australian-telescope-array-opens-for-business/</a><br /><a href="http://www.cosmosmagazine.com/news/6044/worlds-fastest-radio-telescope-starts-australian-outback" target="_blank">http://www.cosmosmagazine.com/news/6044/worlds-fastest-radio-telescope-starts-australian-outback</a></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/bIbWy-mH1tw" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="cd34f9e2aeb2ca43c8f69c42eea04a28" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/BivFz3VlLoE/dark-matter-remains-dark-for-now.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-jLSSOzVwC98/UXAv8eTsEJI/AAAAAAAAAcg/LIp4OACyxUk/s1600/CDMS-Bauer-s-700870.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="228" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5868243030438056082" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-jLSSOzVwC98/UXAv8eTsEJI/AAAAAAAAAcg/LIp4OACyxUk/s400/CDMS-Bauer-s-700870.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">CDMS detector. Courtesy of Fermilab.</td></tr></tbody></table><div><br />For the past month and a bit, the biggest story in physics has  undoubtedly been dark matter.</div><div><br /></div><div>When <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samuel_C._C._Ting" target="_blank">Sam Ting</a>,  the charismatic Nobel Prize winning director of the <a href="http://press.web.cern.ch/backgrounders/first-result-ams-experiment)" target="_blank">AMS project</a>,  announced in February that the team who monitor his orbiting Alpha  Magnetic Spectrometer, latched to the ISS, would be announcing  'significant results' in the search for dark matter, the whole physics  community held its breath.&nbsp; Somewhat skeptically.</div><div>The <a href="http://www.interactions.org/cms/?pid=1032740" target="_blank">results</a>, when  they were announced on 30 March at CERN, seemed to add weight to the  measurements made by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Payload_for_Antimatter_Matter_Exploration_and_Light-nuclei_Astrophysics#Results" target="_blank">PAMELA</a>, in 2008, and were  certainly of significant interest.</div><div><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Wfw9bRXWMSE/UXAwamH7naI/AAAAAAAAAco/hMty7O1M108/s1600/ams_on_iss.jpeg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="265" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Wfw9bRXWMSE/UXAwamH7naI/AAAAAAAAAco/hMty7O1M108/s400/ams_on_iss.jpeg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">AMS-02 on ISS. Courtesy of CERN</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div>But they perhaps fell short of what many were hoping for. As  theoretical physicist, <a href="http://www.ph.unimelb.edu.au/~kmack/" target="_blank">Katie Mack</a> put it on 5 April in <a href="http://physicsfocus.org/katie-mack-space-station-ams-detector-has-not-found-dark-matter-despite-what-some-media-reports-say/" target="_blank">Physics  Focus </a>-  somewhat bluntly, it should be said, "the AMS-02 detector on the  International Space Station has not detected dark matter. It hasn't  found 'indications' of dark matter, or even 'hints'. It certainly is  not providing the 'best evidence yet' of dark matter's  existence."</div><div><br /></div><div>She did, however, <a href="http://physicsfocus.org/katie-mack-space-station-ams-detector-has-not-found-dark-matter-despite-what-some-media-reports-say/" target="_blank">acknowledge</a> the important measurements the AMS-02  detector<i> has</i> made:</div><div>"What AMS has done is measure, to very high accuracy, the  amount of antimatter the galaxy is bombarding us with. [....]. The AMS  experiment detects cosmic rays - protons, electrons, and the  antimatter counterparts of each, antiprotons and positrons. Before the  experiment ran, we had predictions of how the matter/antimatter  fraction should vary with the energy of the particles. AMS tells us our predictions were wrong. The antiprotons look about  right, but there's a huge excess of high-energy positrons over what  astrophysical models predict, and a bump in the electron flux at high  energies. All of these results were actually seen by earlier  experiments <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Payload_for_Antimatter_Matter_Exploration_and_Light-nuclei_Astrophysics" target="_blank">PAMELA</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fermi_Gamma-ray_Space_Telescope" target="_blank">Fermi</a>, but  AMS confirms them to higher precision and higher energies. There's  more antimatter than we thought; now we have to figure out  why."</div><div><br /></div><div>This is a concise explanation of the so-called 'positron-excess',  which is one of the key indicators that dark matter - whatever it is -  exists.&nbsp; Mack <a href="http://physicsfocus.org/katie-mack-space-station-ams-detector-has-not-found-dark-matter-despite-what-some-media-reports-say/" target="_blank">goes on to explain</a>, that the radio astronomers'  favourite phenomenon, pulsars, are thought by many astrophysicists to  be the cause of the positron excess.</div><div>"Pulsars [...] can use their extreme magnetic fields to  accelerate particles and create electron-positron pairs. The fact that  pulsars do this is solidly in the realm of known physics, and  theoretical models can easily fit the signals seen in the cosmic ray  experiments."</div><div><br /></div><div>This is far from an accepted theory of the origin of dark matter, but it is a fascinating one  nonetheless.&nbsp; But where else might we look to find out about the  origins of dark matter? The answer is: <b>the mines</b>.</div><div><br /></div><div>Far beneath the surface of the earth, some of the most significant searches for  dark matter have been underway for years. This week, one of the  most notable of these, the <a href="http://cdms.berkeley.edu/" target="_blank">CDMS experiment (the Cryogenic Dark Matter  Search)</a> in the Soudan mine in Minnesota,  posted some extremely interesting results. Graduate student, Kevin  McCarthy, reported at the <a href="http://www.aps.org/meetings/april/" target="_blank">American Physical Society meeting in Denver  on 13 April </a>that CDMS has found  "three promising clues" of dark matter. The their silicon  detectors had picked up possible signs of three weakly interacting  massive particles (or 'WIMPs', as physicists call them).&nbsp; Their  evidence is verifiable to a level of three-sigma.</div><div><br /></div><div>As <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-22155222" target="_blank">Jason Palmer explains,</a> particle  physics has an accepted definition for a "discovery": a  five-sigma level of certainty. "The number of standard  deviations, or sigmas, is a measure of how unlikely it is that an  experimental result is simply down to chance, in the absence of a real  effect Similarly, tossing a coin and getting a number of heads in a  row may just be chance, rather than a sign of a "loaded"  coin The "three sigma" level represents about the same  likelihood of tossing nine heads in a row. Five sigma, on the other  hand, would correspond to tossing more than 21 in a row. With  independent confirmation by other experiments, five-sigma findings  become accepted discoveries."</div><div><br /></div><div>So CDMS' three-sigma result falls short of this, but it most  certainly counts as a 'tantalising hint'.</div><div><br /></div><div>As science writer <a href="http://www.newscientist.com/article/dn23389-tentative-dark-matter-hits-fit-with-shadow-dark-sector.html" target="_blank">Valerie Jamieson notes</a>, the CDMS dark matter  signal fits with recent theories that suggest dark matter is, "not a single entity, but a 'dark sector of particles' that could  include dark antimatter".</div><div><br /></div><div>"This may be the start of a very big deal" observes dark  matter theorist <a href="http://home.fnal.gov/~dhooper/" target="_blank">Dan Hooper,</a> of  Fermilab, who manage CDMS.</div><div><br /></div><div>So whilst dark matter remains enigmatic, and most certainly dark,  for now, there's some hope we may be closing in on its secrets.</div><div><br /></div><div>Sources:</div><div><a href="http://www.aps.org/meetings/april/">http://www.aps.org/meetings/april/</a></div><div><a href="http://is.gd/coldwater">http://is.gd/coldwater</a></div><div><a href="http://cdms.berkeley.edu/">http://cdms.berkeley.edu/</a></div><div><br /></div><div><br /></div></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/BivFz3VlLoE" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c0fcbb74aeb7f7526e02de7022fc9172" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/GYd1NtZMu54/your-move-theorists.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="352" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5812133175458669762" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kvcaTt7Zhfs/UKjYVD56JMI/AAAAAAAAAVY/E7l0AQzQwP4/s400/bmeson-708335.gif" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">B-mesons' decay products</td></tr></tbody></table><div><br /><a href="http://public.web.cern.ch/public/en/people/Experimentalists-en.html" target="_blank">Physicists rather enjoy the friendly rivalry between theorists and experimentalists</a>, and this week has been a fascinating week for both. Results presented at the <a href="http://www.icepp.s.u-tokyo.ac.jp/hcp2012/" target="_blank">Hadron Collider Physics symposium</a> in Kyoto this  week have proved a triumph for experimentalists working with the most  powerful tool at their disposal - the LHC. But theorists have been  left scratching their heads, as one of the most prominent theories of  "new physics" took a major hit. Since the search for physics beyond <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Standard_Model" target="_blank">the Standard Model</a> is a leading priority in  particle physics, this is highly significant for everyone.</div><div><br />Unsurprisingly, the hot topic of discussion at the <a href="http://www.icepp.s.u-tokyo.ac.jp/hcp2012/" target="_blank">Hadron Collider Physics symposium</a> was the LHC's <a href="http://decelerator.blogspot.co.uk/2012/07/science-history-is-made.html" target="_blank">incendiary boson results from earlier this year</a>.<br /><br />Both the teams from the <a href="http://cms.web.cern.ch/" target="_blank">CMS</a> detector and the <a href="http://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/Collaboration/" target="_blank"> ATLAS</a> detector  presented <a href="http://www.nature.com/news/new-higgs-results-bring-relief-and-disappointment-1.11837" target="_blank">new analyses of the observations</a> which led them to  announce the discovery of a Higgs-like boson in July.&nbsp; What's  striking about the new data is that is backs up initial suspicions  that the boson discovered at the LHC appears to be behaving precisely  as the Standard Model predicted it would. As Tommaso Dorigo noted in <a href="http://www.science20.com/quantum_diaries_survivor/higgs_new_atlas_and_cms_results-96412" target="_blank">Quantum Diaries</a>, the new measurements, "confirm the  standard model interpretation of the new found object."&nbsp;  Philip Gibbs at <a href="http://blog.vixra.org/2012/11/14/higgs-at-hcp2011" target="_blank">viXra</a> provides some further technical analysis of the  results <a href="http://blog.vixra.org/2012/11/14/higgs-at-hcp2011" target="_blank">here</a>.</div><br /><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="230" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5812133192734208866" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-bUfIh-TI5ZE/UKjYWEQt82I/AAAAAAAAAVk/ghQ2gy1J71k/s400/lhcb_collaboration-711816.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">The LHCb Experiment. Photo courtesy of CERN. </td></tr></tbody></table></div><br /><div>But perhaps more sensational was the new results presented by  their colleagues over at <a href="http://lhcb-public.web.cern.ch/lhcb-public/" target="_blank">the LHCb Experiment</a>. Johannes Albrecht  reported that the LHCb team have observed one of the rarest particle  decay events in physics, <a href="http://www.quantumdiaries.org/2012/11/14/huge-impact-from-a-tiny-decay/" target="_blank">a Bs meson decaying into 2 muons</a>. These events are so rare that the Standard Model  predicts they should only occur about once in 300 million  collisions.<br /><br />That <a href="http://lhcb-public.web.cern.ch/lhcb-public/" target="_blank">LHCb</a> has observed one of these events at all is a stunning  achievement for the experimentalists working on the detector. But the  fact that their results suggest the the Bs meson decay is every bit as  rare as the Standard Model predicted it should be, is a serious blow  for one of the leading theories of new physics - <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supersymmetry" target="_blank">supersymmetry</a>.<br /><br />The theory of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supersymmetry" target="_blank">supersymmetry</a>, often referred to by its  shortened nickname, SUSY, states that every fundamental matter particle  should have a more massive, or 'super' force carrier particle, and  every force carrier should have a 'super' matter particle.&nbsp; These  particles are often referred to as 'sparticles' (supersymmetric  particles). <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supersymmetry" target="_blank">Supersymmetry</a>. has been championed by theorists such as  Savas Dimopoulos and Gordon Kane, who memorably described the theory  as a <a href="http://www.nature.com/news/2011/110228/full/471013a.html" target="_blank">"wonderful, beautiful and unique"</a> solution  for the problems in our understanding of the subatomic world.<br /><br />However, the <a href="http://lhcb-public.web.cern.ch/lhcb-public/" target="_blank">LHCb</a>  results have cast serious doubt on the viability of  supersymmetry as a theory. Supersymmetry predicts that if  superparticles exist the Bs meson decay to a pair of muons should  occur far more often than one in 300 million.&nbsp; The work the <a href="http://lhcb-public.web.cern.ch/lhcb-public/" target="_blank">LHCb</a>   team were doing has long been considered the most important  experimental test for supersymmetry.&nbsp; Whilst the <a href="http://lhcb-public.web.cern.ch/lhcb-public/" target="_blank">LHCb</a>  results,  which prove the rarity of the decay, don't rule supersymmetry out all  together, the parameters for superparticles have narrowed  dramatically, making the theory a much less likely explanation for the  mysteries in our subatomic world, than many had hoped.</div><br /><div>Why is this significant? Well, all physicists know that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Standard_Model" target="_blank">the Standard Model</a>, despite its elegance, does not function as a complete  explanation for the forces which govern our universe. It provides  little explanation for gravity, and it noticeably fails to explain  either dark energy or dark matter. Given that it is believed that dark  matter may constitute up to 84% of all matter in the universe, and  dark energy up to 73% of all the known energy in the universe, a  theory which explains neither is clearly inadequate.</div><div><br />The science community at large had been hoping that the experiments  running at the LHC would start to uncover evidence for "new  physics" beyond <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Standard_Model" target="_blank">the Standard Model</a>, which would begin to explain  these puzzling features of the universe.&nbsp; But so far, not only  have the main results not done so, they've simply provided  ever-strengthening evidence for the veracity of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Standard_Model" target="_blank">the Standard Model</a>.&nbsp;</div><div><br />As Marc-Olivier Bettler from LHCb <a href="http://sciencemuseumdiscovery.com/blogs/insight/supersymmetry-in-a-spin/" target="_blank">noted this week</a>, "if new physics is present then it is hiding very  well behind the Standard Model".</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="290" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5812133202175370578" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-SBqF8kiIwUU/UKjYWnbqpVI/AAAAAAAAAVw/WsGXJu0ds_0/s400/gg-run177878-evt188723900-3d-nologo-713944.gif" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">A typical candidate event for the Higgs boson measured in the CMS electromagnetic calorimeter. Image courtesy of CERN</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br />The fact that <a href="http://cms.web.cern.ch/" target="_blank">CMS</a> and <a href="http://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/Collaboration/" target="_blank"> ATLAS</a>  this week seemed to be describing a  Higgs boson which looks awfully like the one predicted by the Standard  Model, is compounding theoretical concern. Expressing this eloquently  this week, <a href="http://www.newscientist.com/article/mg21628901.500-particle-headache-why-the-higgs-could-spell-disaster.html?full=true" target="_blank">Guido Altarelli from CERN stated</a> that a Standard Model  Higgs was, "a toy model to make the theory match the data, a  crutch to allow the Standard Model to walk a bit further until  something better comes along."<br /><br />As <a href="http://www.newscientist.com/article/mg21628901.500-particle-headache-why-the-higgs-could-spell-disaster.html?full=true" target="_blank">Matthew Chalmers noted in an article</a> which  starkly set out the challenges the experimental results are raising, a  Higgs boson at 125 GeV (the measurements both <a href="http://cms.web.cern.ch/" target="_blank">CMS</a> and <a href="http://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/Collaboration/" target="_blank"> ATLAS</a> have provided further evidence for this week) not only has a mass "vastly less than it  should be, it is also about as small as it can possibly be without  dragging the universe into another catastrophic transition. If it were  just a few GeV lighter, the strength of the Higgs interactions would  change in such a way that the lowest energy state of the vacuum would  dip below zero. The universe could then at some surprise moment  "tunnel" into this bizarre state, again instantly changing  the entire configuration of the particles and forces and obliterating  structures such as atoms."<br />He dramatically intoned, "as things stand, the universe is seemingly teetering on the cusp  of eternal stability and total ruin."<br /><br />All of this is to say that whilst results presented by <a href="http://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/Collaboration/" target="_blank">ATLAS</a>, <a href="http://cms.web.cern.ch/" target="_blank">CMS</a>, and the <a href="http://lhcb-public.web.cern.ch/lhcb-public/" target="_blank">LHCb</a> are bringing relief in some quarters, as they certainly prove how  exceptional the LHC is as a tool of discovery, they are causing some deep  unease amongst theorists.<br /><br />These are exciting times.<br /><br />As particle physicist <a href="http://decelerator.blogspot.co.uk/2012/02/chasing-ghosts-those-elusive-neutrinos.html" target="_blank">Ben Still observed earlier this year,</a> "until theorists can come up with  ways we can test their theories, they are just dealing with works of  fiction."<br /><br />So after some cracking moves this week in which the experimentalists  have put pay to some of the most treasured literary works of physics  theory, the ball is now back in the court of the theorists. They need  to dream up new theories which help make sense of these results, and  suggest new routes forward.<br /><br />Sources:<br /><a href="http://www.nature.com/news/new-higgs-results-bring-relief-and-disappointment-1.11837">http://www.nature.com/</a><br /><a href="http://www.quantumdiaries.org/2012/11/14/huge-impact-from-a-tiny-decay/">http://www.quantumdiaries.org/</a></div><div><a href="http://profmattstrassler.com/2012/11/12/first-news-from-kyoto-conference/">http://profmattstrassler.com/</a></div></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/GYd1NtZMu54" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f8bdc5f43a5b0e13baf15c7c15d5e970" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/iTEtbInPyeM/neutrinos-back-in-spotlight.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="mobile-photo"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-SzDE8Qgvf5Y/UWGlAiHIVVI/AAAAAAAAAbU/OqQhEi_AzoI/s1600/NOvA-3D-2-mr-730311.jpg"><img alt="" border="0" height="400" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5864149618388391250" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-SzDE8Qgvf5Y/UWGlAiHIVVI/AAAAAAAAAbU/OqQhEi_AzoI/s400/NOvA-3D-2-mr-730311.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><div><br />It's been a big couple of weeks for neutrinos. First, the <a href="http://www.infn.it/news/newsen.php?id=663">OPERA  experiment in Italy revealed</a> that they had detected the  transformation of a muon neutrino to a tau neutrino for only the third  time in their history. Soon after, <a href="http://www-nova.fnal.gov/">Fermilab's NOvA neutrino detector</a>  in the States published their first three-dimensional images of the elusive  particles (<a href="https://www.fnal.gov/pub/presspass/press_releases/2013/NOvA-201303-images.html">pictured above</a>).&nbsp; All this followed hard on the heels of one of the  most discussed and celebrated science results of the year so far - <a href="http://www.esa.int/Our_Activities/Space_Science/Planck/Planck_reveals_an_almost_perfect_Universe">the  new Planck measurement of the cosmic microwave background</a> - which has interesting  implications for neutrino physics.</div><div><br /></div><div>Neutrinos are among the more mysterious and slippery inhabitants  of the fundamental particle zoo. They can be created by certain types of radioactive decay, or nuclear reactions like those that take place in stars, or when cosmic rays hit atoms. They have barely any mass and therefore rarely  interact with other types of matter.&nbsp; This makes them fiendishly  difficult to observe.&nbsp; But they are a fascinating area of study  for physicists.&nbsp; Many of the neutrinos around today are thought  to have originated in the Big Bang, so understanding their properties  will give us important new insights into what the universe was like  13.7 billion years ago, and how it operates on a fundamental level  now.</div><div><br /></div><div>Neutrinos come in three different types, called  "flavours": electron, muon and tau.&nbsp; Forty years ago  physicists posited that these particles may occasionally be able to  change from flavour to flavour - for instance starting out as a muon  neutrino and ending up as a tau neutrino. This transformation could  explain one of the great puzzles of neutrino physics.&nbsp;  Theoretical models imply there should be far more neutrinos raining down on the Earth from nuclear reactions in the Sun, than there actually are.&nbsp;  So the mystery of the 'missing neutrinos' has been bothering  physicists for over a generation. If it could be proven that the  missing particles are actually neutrinos which have changed flavour as  they move through space, then this mystery could be solved.</div><div><br /></div><div>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OPERA_experiment">OPERA experiment in Gran Sasso, Italy</a> was set up  specifically for this purpose. It is designed to detect and analyse  exactly these kinds of transformations.&nbsp; But spotting them is no  easy matter. On 26 March 2013, OPERA announced that it had observed  this exceptionally rare act of 'shape-shifting' for just the third  time.&nbsp; A muon-type neutrino produced at CERN in Geneva arrived at  the Gran Sasso laboratory as a tau neutrino. This has only been  observed only twice before, once in 2010 and again last year.</div><div><br /></div><div>OPERA works by studying <a href="http://public.web.cern.ch/public/en/spotlight/SpotlightCNGS-en.html">beams of neutrinos produced at CERN </a> in Switzerland, which travel 732km to the underground laboratory at  the Gran Sasso facility, where they can be studied by physicists  working on the OPERA detector.&nbsp;&nbsp; As <a href="http://www.symmetrymagazine.org/article/march-2013/opera-snags-third-tau-neutrino">Kathryn Jepsen, writing  in Symmetry, puts it</a>, "the OPERA experiment is a fast-moving,  long-distance game of catch, with CERN laboratory at the border of  France and Switzerland pitching a concentrated beam of neutrinos  toward the 1250-ton OPERA detector. The neutrino is a difficult ball  to snag; it interacts so rarely with matter that it can zip  unflinchingly through an entire planet."</div><div><br /></div><div>The neutrinos which leave CERN are muon neutrinos. OPERA is  configured to detect tau neutrinos. If it spots one, it can deduce  that a 'change of flavour' has occurred en-route.&nbsp; Detecting such  a flavour oscillation, as the team did this March, is significant.&nbsp;  Not only is it, "an important confirmation of the two previous  observations", as the the head of OPERA's international research  team, <a href="http://www.infn.it/news/newsen.php?id=663">Giovanni De Lellis, has said</a>; it also provides more evidence  that flavour oscillation may indeed be the reason why the flux of  neutrinos from the Sun and Earth's atmosphere is so much smaller than  what theorists predict it should be.</div><div><br /></div><div>Over on the other side of the Atlantic, <a href="http://www.fnal.gov/">Fermilab</a> are in the process of establishing the <a href="http://www-nova.fnal.gov/">NOvA</a>  experiment as the most powerful neutrino  detector in the States. They recently took a significant step towards  this goal, by <a href="http://www.fnal.gov/pub/presspass/press_releases/2013/NOvA-20130328.html">releasing their first three-dimensional images of  particles</a> analysed in the under-construction detector.</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/--gZXmDXY9q8/UWGlBGIbLzI/AAAAAAAAAbg/rMT-QT8FWYc/s1600/nova-731777.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="265" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5864149628057497394" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/--gZXmDXY9q8/UWGlBGIbLzI/AAAAAAAAAbg/rMT-QT8FWYc/s400/nova-731777.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">NOvA detector in construction - near Ash River, USA, photographed in 2012. Image courtesy NOvA collaboration.</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br /></div><div><a href="http://www-nova.fnal.gov/">NOvA</a> is a collaboration of 180 scientists,  technicians and students from 20 universities and laboratories in the  U.S and another 14 institutions around the world.&nbsp; Later this  year, the <a href="http://www-nova.fnal.gov/">NOvA</a> detector at Ash River, near the Canadian border will  start receiving beams of neutrinos sent from Fermilab, the US  equivalent of CERN, which is based near Chicago. The beams of  neutrinos will travel 500km from Fermilab to <a href="http://www-nova.fnal.gov/">NOvA</a>.&nbsp; As <a href="http://www.fnal.gov/pub/presspass/press_releases/2013/NOvA-20130328.html">they say</a>, "when a neutrino interacts with the detector, the  particles it produces leave trails of light in their wake. The  detector records these streams of light, enabling physicists to  identify the original neutrino and measure the amount of energy it  had."</div><div><br /></div><div>Using the first completed section of the <a href="http://www-nova.fnal.gov/">NOvA</a> detector,  physicists have begun collecting data from cosmic rays - the particles  produced by a constant stream of atomic nuclei falling on the  Earth's atmosphere from space. The 3D particle images they have  produced as a result of this work are helping the physicists fine-tune  the instrument. When cosmic rays pass through the NOvA detector, they  leave straight tracks and well-understood energy signatures. As <a href="http://www.fnal.gov/pub/presspass/press_releases/2013/NOvA-20130328.html">Mat  Muether, a Fermilab researcher, notes</a>, "they are great for calibration. Everybody loves  cosmic rays for this reason. They are simple and abundant and a  perfect tool for tuning up a new detector."</div><div><br /></div><div><a href="http://www.fnal.gov/pub/presspass/press_releases/2013/NOvA-20130328.html">Fermilab state</a>, "the detector at its current size catches more  than 1000 cosmic rays per second. Naturally occurring neutrinos from  cosmic rays, supernovae and the sun stream through the detector at the  same time. But the flood of more visible cosmic-ray data makes it  difficult to pick them out. Once the upgraded Fermilab neutrino beam  starts, the NOvA detector will take data every 1.3 seconds to  synchronize with the Fermilab accelerator. Inside this short time  window, the burst of neutrinos from Fermilab will be much easier to  spot."</div><div><br /></div><div>And this is important. As <a href="http://www.fnal.gov/pub/presspass/press_releases/2013/NOvA-20130328.html">Gary Feldman of Harvard University  says</a>, "the more we know about neutrinos, the more we know about  the early universe and about how our world works at its most basic  level".</div><div><br /></div><div>The most <a href="http://www.esa.int/Our_Activities/Space_Science/Planck/Planck_reveals_an_almost_perfect_Universe">headline-stealing physics result of the year so far</a> has given us breathtaking new  insights into the early universe and our world at it's most basic  level. On the 21 March 2013, scientists working with the Planck Space  Telescope unveiled the most <a href="http://www.esa.int/Our_Activities/Space_Science/Planck/Planck_reveals_an_almost_perfect_Universe">detailed map ever created of the cosmic  microwave background (CMB)</a> - the leftover radiation from the Big  Bang.&nbsp; Whilst the Planck measurement of the CMB hasn't given us  that many clues as to what the fundamental properties of neutrinos  are, it may have helped us learn what they are not. In recent times,  physicists have begun to speculate that there may be a fourth type of  neutrino flavour - the <a href="http://www.nature.com/news/2010/100317/full/464334a.html">sterile neutrino</a>, so called  because it is not effected by the weak nuclear force, and therefore  interacts even less with other particles than it's shy and retiring,  tau, muon and electron neutrino cousins.&nbsp; But as <a href="http://in-space.info/en/news/cosmos-study-dashes-hope-new-neutrino">John Matson  writing in Scientific American has noted</a>,  Planck's findings suggest that physicists hoping for experimental  proof of the sterile neutrino are going to have to look harder or  rethink altogether.</div><div><br /></div><div>All and all, these are fascinating times for neutrino physics,  and we shouldn't be surprised if these ghostly little particles take  their share of the limelight in the coming year.</div><div><br /></div><div>Sources:</div><div><a href="http://www.fnal.gov/pub/presspass/press_releases/2013/NOvA-20130328.html">http://www.fnal.gov/</a></div><div><a href="http://www.infn.it/news/newsen.php?id=663">http://www.infn.it/news/newsen.php?id=663</a></div><div><a href="http://www.symmetrymagazine.org/article/march-2013/opera-snags-third-tau-neutrino">http://www.symmetrymagazine.org/</a></div></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/iTEtbInPyeM" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="93b4ae5c01194cde18efe7b590b08ad" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/jiRIRwd6VM8/did-einstein-discover-dark-energy.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="mobile-photo"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-1jFEu3vcE5Q/ULuNukOIq4I/AAAAAAAAAWg/kjii0Xzr4EQ/s1600/20110504_dark_energy-794357.jpg"><img alt="" border="0" height="400" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5817399174815591298" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-1jFEu3vcE5Q/ULuNukOIq4I/AAAAAAAAAWg/kjii0Xzr4EQ/s400/20110504_dark_energy-794357.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><br />One of the more interesting things that popped up on <a href="http://arxiv.org/" target="_blank">arXiv</a> this week was the quirkily titled abstract, <a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1211.6338" target="_blank"><i>How Einstein Discovered Dark Energy</i></a>,<i> </i>submitted by Alex Harvey, Visiting Scholar at New York University on 22 November. <br /><br />It bears repeating in its entirety: <br /><br />"In 1917 Einstein published his Cosmological Considerations Concerning the General Theory of Relativity. In it was the first use of the cosmological constant. Shortly thereafter Schrodinger presented a note providing a solution to these same equations with the cosmological constant term transposed to the right hand side thus making it part of the stress-energy tensor. Einstein commented that if Schrodinger had something more than a mere mathematical convenience in mind he should describe its properties. Then Einstein detailed what some of these properties might be. In so doing, he gave the first description of Dark Energy. We present a translation of Schrodinger's paper and Einstein's response."<br />The <a href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1211.6338v1.pdf" target="_blank">full paper and references are downloadable here</a>.  <br /><br /><br />It will be interesting to hear what the responses are to this. <br /><br />Source: <a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1211.6338">http://arxiv.org/abs/1211.6338</a></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/jiRIRwd6VM8" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="772038e6f7aadb79e377ad5060545d43" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/jQG3NOt-_PE/the-rise-of-algorithms.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="mobile-photo"><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="202" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5815443634396866738" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-hfSXH5Dk7XM/ULSbLIeIKLI/AAAAAAAAAWI/WLmAjEH0rRM/s400/theknife-783959.png" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">The Knife - a financial trading algorithm </td></tr></tbody></table></div><div class="mobile-photo"><br /></div>This week <a href="http://www.tarletongillespie.org/" target="_blank">Tarleton Gillespie</a> was the latest critical commentator to analyse the role that algorithms play in contemporary life. His detailed insightful and urgent essay, <a href="http://culturedigitally.org/2012/11/the-relevance-of-algorithms/" target="_blank"><i>The Relevance of Algorithms</i></a> was published on the <a href="http://culturedigitally.org/" target="_blank">Culture Digitally blog</a> this week, ahead of it's forthcoming publication in the MIT book, "Media Technologies".<br /><br /><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ZpUy4zPoEiw" width="560"></iframe> <br /><br />Picking up where Kevin Slavin's excoriating Lift talk, <a href="http://videos.liftconference.com/video/1177435/kevin-slavin-those-algorithms" target="_blank">"Those algorithms that govern our lives" </a>(later <a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/kevin_slavin_how_algorithms_shape_our_world.html" target="_blank">reprised for TED</a>) left off, Gillespie conducts a thorough investigation into how algorithms provide the basis for a great deal of our individual and societal choices. That we understand their impact on our daily lives so poorly is cause for great concern, Gillespie argues. He notes a particular anxiety with the way that algorithms are starting to influence how we find and interpret information, and points to the obvious impact this will have on politics: <br /><br />"Algorithms not only help us find information, they provide a means to know what there is to know and how to know it, to participate in social and political discourse." <br /><br />This has strong and relevant echoes back to the set of concerns raised by both designers and artists working with technology, as <a href="http://decelerator.blogspot.co.uk/2012/11/a-drones-eye-view-revealing-killing.html" target="_blank">alluded to in a previous post.</a> Artists Julian Oliver, Danja Vasiliev and Gordan Savicic have developed a&nbsp;discourse they refer to as "<a href="http://criticalengineering.org/" target="_blank">critical engineering</a>", which aims to expose the systems, mechanisms, languages and logics which make up our engineered world. This is urgent, political work, they argue, as the encroachment of engineering into our lives, is matched only by its increasing invisibility. If we lose our ability to perceive this technological infrastructure, we lose agency.<br /><br />As <a href="http://rhizome.org/editorial/2012/sep/5/artist-profile-julian-oliver/" target="_blank">Oliver wrote</a> recently:<br />"As thinkers with technical abilities in several areas, we want to take on our built and increasingly automated environment [...]  If there's ever a time to be doing that, it's now, especially with opaque and hidden infrastructure  in the telecommunications space deeply impacting diplomatic relations and civil liberties world wide. [...] Our inability to describe and understand technological infrastructure reduces our critical reach, leaving us both disempowered and, quite often, vulnerable." - <a href="http://rhizome.org/editorial/2012/sep/5/artist-profile-julian-oliver/" target="_blank">Julian Oliver</a>&nbsp;<a href="http://rhizome.org/editorial/2012/sep/5/artist-profile-julian-oliver/" target="_blank">(September 2012</a>)<br /><br />These thoughts are echoed almost precisely by designer, writer and publisher, <a href="http://www.aeonmagazine.com/world-views/will-wiles-technology-new-aesthetic/" target="_blank">James Bridle</a>&nbsp;(<a href="http://decelerator.blogspot.co.uk/2012/11/a-drones-eye-view-revealing-killing.html" target="_blank">who's work in this area was referenced here recently</a>), who&nbsp;notes:<br />"By legibility I mean our own ability to read these systems, how much they can affect the way we see and act in the world, and the differing positions of power we have in the world based on how legible those systems are. [...] Programmers have a huge amount of agency in the world, because they can deconstruct, reverse engineer and write and construct and create these systems. People who can't, don't, and they have less power in the world because of it." - <a href="http://www.aeonmagazine.com/world-views/will-wiles-technology-new-aesthetic/" target="_blank">James Bridle (September 2012)</a>.&nbsp;He <a href="http://booktwo.org/notebook/drone-shadows/" target="_blank">later wrote</a>:<br />"Those who cannot perceive the network cannot act effectively within it, and are powerless. The job, then, is to make such things visible." <br /><br />Gillespie's essay operates very much within this spirit, insisting on the need to be able to perceive and understand the way that algorithms are becoming part of our lived environment. He writes: <br />"What we need is an interrogation of algorithms as a key feature of our information ecosystem, and of the cultural forms emerging in their shadows, with a close attention to where and in what ways the introduction of algorithms into human knowledge practices may have political ramifications." <br /><br />His <a href="http://culturedigitally.org/2012/11/the-relevance-of-algorithms/" target="_blank">essay</a> then seeks to do just that, providing an excellent map for this emerging terrain.&nbsp; His perspective is not technological, but rather sociological, an analysis which he insists "must not conceive of algorithms as abstract, technical achievements, but must unpack the warm human and institutional choices that lie behind these cold mechanisms."<br /><br />His <a href="http://culturedigitally.org/2012/11/the-relevance-of-algorithms/" target="_blank">essay</a> is a vital insight into these choices.&nbsp; Resonating with the worlds of both Oliver and Bridle, he concludes:<br />"In many ways, algorithms remain outside our grasp, and they are designed to be. This is not to say that we should not aspire to illuminate their workings and impact. We should. But we may also need to prepare ourselves for more and more encounters with the unexpected and ineffable associations they will sometimes draw for us, the fundamental uncertainty about who we are speaking to or hearing, and the palpable but opaque undercurrents that move quietly beneath knowledge when it is managed by algorithms.<br /><br />Sources: <br /><a href="http://culturedigitally.org/2012/11/the-relevance-of-algorithms/">http://culturedigitally.org/2012/11/the-relevance-of-algorithms/</a><br /><a href="http://www.tarletongillespie.org/essays/Gillespie%20-%20The%20Relevance%20of%20Algorithms.pdf" target="_blank">http://www.tarletongillespie.org/</a></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/jQG3NOt-_PE" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="58f5bd06b184736f2de7d3c3315d3ec6" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/jx3CUQe6a6M/tuning-universe.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/honor-harger/tuning-into-the-universe_b_2737168.html" target="_blank"><img alt="" border="0" height="400" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-817vWZ2l2Bg/USiGna5-GRI/AAAAAAAAAZc/kgW_tuoQIlM/s400/huff.jpg" title="" width="366" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><br /><br />This weekend, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/honor-harger/tuning-into-the-universe_b_2737168.html" target="_blank">Huffington Post</a> have published my piece, <i><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/honor-harger/tuning-into-the-universe_b_2737168.html" target="_blank">Tuning the Universe</a></i>, which contextualses my <a href="http:// decelerator.blogspot.com/2011/06/history-of-universe-in-sound.html" target="_blank">TED talk</a>, which they are featuring as part of <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tedweekends/" target="_blank">TED Weekends</a>.<br /><br />The piece provides some background into the audified radio waves which I played  during my talk. Here's the gist of the article:<br /><div><br />"We have been surrounded by stunning portrayals of our own solar  system and beyond for generations, in books, on film and on  television. But in popular culture, we have no sense of what space  sounds like.&nbsp; And indeed, most people associate space with  silence.<br />There are, of course, perfectly valid scientific reasons for assuming  so. Space is a vacuum. Sounds cannot propagate in a vacuum.&nbsp; But  through the intervention of radio, it is possible for us to listen to  the Sun's fizzling solar flares, the roaring waves and spitting fire  of Jupiter's stormy interactions with its moon <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Io_(moon)" target="_blank">Io</a>, pulsars' metronomic beats,  or the eerie melodic shimmer of a whistler in the  magnetosphere."<br /><br /></div><div>My talk, and my work in this area, emerges from the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radio_astronomy" target="_blank">science of  radio astronomy</a>.</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-NyaJ2wAgWXI/USiC3Aqd8DI/AAAAAAAAAZA/204ecY-wphg/s1600/rt16_treetops-small-736080.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="300" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5848067997723127858" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-NyaJ2wAgWXI/USiC3Aqd8DI/AAAAAAAAAZA/204ecY-wphg/s400/rt16_treetops-small-736080.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><br />RT16 at the Ventspils International Radio Astronomy Centre. Latvia</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div>Whilst optical astronomers use telescopes to look at the visible  light emitted by stars, radio astronomers use radio telescopes, or  antennae, to detect radio waves. By combining radio astronomy with  radio and sound engineering, we can hear as well as see the stars, and  thus greatly expand our sensory perception of our cosmos.</div><div><br /></div><div>It is important to remember that stars and planets are not  directly audible. The recordings I played in my talk are radio waves  which have been converted into sound waves using radio receives and  amplifiers.&nbsp; This is a process I refer to as <i>audification</i>.  Huffington Post have also published two companion pieces which respond  to the talk, the first of which emphasises this point.&nbsp;<i>  <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/seth-shostak/sound-in-space_b_2736005.html" target="_blank">Celestial Sound Effects</a></i><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/seth-shostak/sound-in-space_b_2736005.html" target="_blank"> by Seth Shostak</a>&nbsp;notes correctly that, "they're electromagnetic  noise, converted by electronic devices ... into signals that - when  played through a loudspeaker - become the atmospheric pressure waves  we call sound."</div><div><br /></div><div>The second piece is<i> <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/seth-shostak/sound-in-space_b_2736005.html" target="_blank">What Is the Color of the Universe?</a></i><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/seth-shostak/sound-in-space_b_2736005.html" target="_blank"> by  Mario Livio</a>, which uses Karl Glazebrook and Ivan Baldry survey of  more than 200,000 galaxies (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2dF_Galaxy_Redshift_Survey)" target="_blank">the 2dF Galaxy Redshift Survey</a>) as a basis  for examining the colour of the universe.</div><div><br />Thanks to <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/honor-harger/tuning-into-the-universe_b_2737168.html" target="_blank">Huffington Post</a> and Janet Lee at TED for publishing the  piece.</div><div><br /></div><div>And here's the talk in full:</div><div><br /></div><div><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" mozallowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" src="http://embed.ted.com/talks/honor_harger_a_history_of_the_universe_in_sound.html" webkitallowfullscreen="" width="560"></iframe></div><div><br /><br />Source:&nbsp;  <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/honor-harger/tuning-into-the-universe_b_2737168.html">http://www.huffingtonpost.com/honor-harger/tuning-into-the-universe_b_2737168.html</a></div></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/jx3CUQe6a6M" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fdd1f3e8adebd7ea0c7f617cf864d2de" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/K0lU9r6D8Ik/the-beam-of-darkness.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="mobile-photo"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-lycDjfs1wqc/Uq3UeXjghtI/AAAAAAAAAjg/rYu6aJNH_6g/s1600/light-in-the-dark-732896.jpg"><img alt="" border="0" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5957651500265146066" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-lycDjfs1wqc/Uq3UeXjghtI/AAAAAAAAAjg/rYu6aJNH_6g/s320/light-in-the-dark-732896.jpg" /></a></div><br />This week, <a href="http://www.ece.nus.edu.sg/" target="_blank">engineers from Singapore</a> released details of a fascinating prototype which takes a radically different approach to the creation of an invisibility cloak.<br /><br />Whilst still popularly considered the realm of science fiction, <a href="http://www.physics.org/article-questions.asp?id=69" target="_blank">many working prototypes for 'invisibility cloaks' have been demonstrated</a> in the past few years, most using <a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/0909.0076" target="_blank">metamaterials</a>, and some using <a href="http://phys.org/news/2013-11-thin-invisibility-cloak.html" target="_blank">tiny antennae</a>.<br /><br />Using a principle, referred to as "anti-resolution", the Singaporean researchers have <a href="https://medium.com/p/fd5386e20aee" target="_blank">taken a completely different approach</a>, and have built a "darkness beam" that bathes objects in the absence of light.<br /><br />Using special lenses, optical engineer Chao Wan and his colleagues, have effectively created a region of space where the intensity of light is close to zero. As <a href="http://www.extremetech.com/extreme/172797-anti-resolution-darkness-ray-can-make-objects-invisible-from-a-distance" target="_blank">Sebastian Anthony points out</a>, "if there’s no light, nothing can be resolved. &nbsp;They have created an empty light capsule of invisibility."<br /><br />The <a href="https://medium.com/p/fd5386e20aee" target="_blank">arXiv blog explains further</a>:<br />"Optical engineers generally build imaging systems with the best possible resolving power. The basic idea is that an imaging system focuses light into a pattern known as a point spreading function. This consists of a central region of high intensity surrounded by a concentric lobe of lower intensity light. The trick to improving resolution is narrowing and intensifying this central region while suppressing the outer lobe. Now [the Singaporean] optical engineers have turned this approach on its head by suppressing the central region so that the field intensity here is zero while intensifying the lobe. The result is a three-dimensional beam of darkness that hides any object inside it."<br /><br />The researchers describe their technique in detail in <a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1312.0057" target="_blank">a paper on arXiv</a>:<br /><br /><i>"We theoretically and experimentally demonstrate the focusing of macroscopic 3D darkness surrounded by all light in free space. The object staying in the darkness is similar to staying in an empty light capsule because light just bypasses it by resorting to destructive interference."</i><br /><br /><a href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1312.0057v2.pdf" target="_blank">In their full paper</a>, the team conclude that the applications for such technology are manifold. And somewhat chilling:<br /><br /><i>"This new &nbsp;scheme of maneuvering light creates a plethora of possibilities for optical imaging systems, superb surveillance by seeing things behind for the military use, or cloaking the object surrounded by high field intensity."</i><br /><br /><br />Sources: <br /><a href="https://medium.com/p/fd5386e20aee">https://medium.com/p/fd5386e20aee</a><br /><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1312.0057">http://arxiv.org/abs/1312.0057</a></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/K0lU9r6D8Ik" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="90c542b5eb1a166b9778fc92bb8c7f91" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/Mh3sG5tbfLU/on-edges-of-possible-radiative-decay.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Vh5OHZYm98k/UEM5G3g-a1I/AAAAAAAAAP8/GEdlIQO6WDs/s1600/black-rain-1-711637.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="220" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5783529136618105682" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Vh5OHZYm98k/UEM5G3g-a1I/AAAAAAAAAP8/GEdlIQO6WDs/s400/black-rain-1-711637.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Solar flare, as depicted in <i>Black Rain</i> by Semiconductor</td></tr></tbody></table><br />A fascinating <a href="http://wavewatching.net/2012/09/01/from-the-annals-of-the-impossible-experimental-physics-edition/">post&nbsp;in Henning Dekant's excellent Wavewatching blog</a> this week, adds some&nbsp;depth to <a href="http://www.astronomynow.com/news/n1208/15solarflares">August's stories</a>&nbsp;suggesting&nbsp;scientists had found a way to predict solar storms.<br /><br />Jere Jenkins and Ephraim Fischbach of <a href="http://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/releases/2012/Q3/new-system-could-predict-solar-flares,-give-advance-warning.html">Purdue University</a>&nbsp;published a paper in <a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0927650512001442">Astroparticle Physics</a>&nbsp;which showed evidence that the rate of the breakdown of radioactive&nbsp;materials changes in advance of solar flares.  They believe this&nbsp;fluctuation should be able to be used to create an early-warning&nbsp;system for potentially destructive solar storms.<br /><br />The astrophysics community met this with surprise, skepticism and&nbsp;even alarm in some quarters, as whilst an early-warning system for solar flares is something of a holy grail within space&nbsp;engineering, Jenkins and Fischbach did appear to be challenging our&nbsp;fundamental understanding of radioactive decay.<br /><br />Their latest work builds on earlier research, including <a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/0808.3283">a paper four&nbsp;years ago</a>, which presented&nbsp;surprising evidence of a correlation between nuclear decay rates and&nbsp;Earth-Sun distance.<br /><br />So why is all of this weird?  Radioactive elements are unstable and&nbsp;break down over time. As they do this they release energy in the form&nbsp;of radiation. As <a href="http://wavewatching.net/2012/09/01/from-the-annals-of-the-impossible-experimental-physics-edition/">Dekant notes</a>,"radioactive decay is supposed to be&nbsp;the ultimate random process, immutably governed by an element's half&nbsp;life and nothing else. There is no way to determine when a single&nbsp;radioactive atom will decay, nor any way to speed-up or slow down the&nbsp;process." He emphasises this is considered to be an "iron clad&nbsp;certainty".<br /><br />Therefore the absolute last thing you'd be expecting reputable&nbsp;scientists to report is results which show "a discernible pattern in&nbsp;the decay rate of a radioactive element" or "any correlation with&nbsp;outside events". That's precisely what Jenkins and Fischbach have&nbsp;presented in their latest paper. Beyond the practical implications&nbsp;for an early-warning system for solar storms, this has far-reaching&nbsp;implications for our understanding of radiation in general.<br /><br />Jenkins' research was inspired by what <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-19276003">Jonathan Ball</a>&nbsp;describes&nbsp;as a chance event. Jenkins "was watching television coverage of&nbsp;astronauts spacewalking at the International Space Station. A solar&nbsp;flare erupted and was thought to pose a risk to the astronauts. On&nbsp;checking equipment in his laboratory, he was surprised to discover&nbsp;that the rate of radioactive decay changed before the solar flare."<br /><br />This lead to Jenkins, and colleagues, developing a<a href="http://www.blogger.com/goog_1332816413"> hypothesis that</a>&nbsp;<a href="http://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/releases/2012/Q3/new-system-could-predict-solar-flares,-give-advance-warning.html">radioactive decay rates are influenced by solar activity</a>, possibly&nbsp;streams of subatomic particles called solar neutrinos. This influence&nbsp;can wax and wane due to seasonal changes in the Earth's distance from&nbsp;the sun and also during solar flares.  The <a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0927650512001442">latest paper in&nbsp;Astroparticle Physics</a> provides the evidence for this hypothesis, and as&nbsp;<a href="http://wavewatching.net/2012/09/01/from-the-annals-of-the-impossible-experimental-physics-edition/">Dekant notes</a>, "the evidence for the reality of this effect is&nbsp;surprisingly good, and that is rather shocking".<br /><br />Shocking, because: <br />"It does not fit into any established theory at this time." <br /><br />Sources: <br /><a href="http://wavewatching.net/">http://wavewatching.net/</a><br /><a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0927650512001442">Astroparticle Physics</a><br /><a href="http://www.astronomynow.com/news/n1208/15solarflares/">http://www.astronomynow.com/news/n1208/15solarflares/</a><br /><br />Thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/hondanhon">Dan Hon</a>&nbsp;for directing me to this.</div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/Mh3sG5tbfLU" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c0a585fce05d1c033a29b6251ac1fdbb" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/OcJ-Da7G96s/a-drones-eye-view-revealing-killing.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="mobile-photo"><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-YGO_KRDGXr0/UJ53rSA6ybI/AAAAAAAAAUE/idFuMlSr0ek/s1600/drones-704461.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="400" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5809212154808289714" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-YGO_KRDGXr0/UJ53rSA6ybI/AAAAAAAAAUE/idFuMlSr0ek/s400/drones-704461.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Jaar, Yemen, October 18 2012 / 7-9 killed. Image from Dronestagram by James Bridle</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br />The unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV), or drone, has become one of  the most potent weapons of contemporary warfare. Remotely controlled by  operators thousands of miles away from the theatre of war, drones  carry out aerial attacks which <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Drone_attacks_in_Pakistan" target="_blank">leave hundreds of people dead</a>. The  increasing amount of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Collateral_damage" target="_blank">'collateral damage'</a> from US drone strikes  on the Pakistan-Afghanistan border recently lead prominent politician,  <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/commentisfree/2012/oct/28/detention-imran-khan-drones" target="_blank">Imran Khan, to lead a high-profile protest against their use</a>.</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Gb9bRFbrXpA/UJ53r0hnb2I/AAAAAAAAAUQ/LuZjqxl5B-A/s1600/trevor_paglen_2010_dronevision-706941.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="307" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5809212164072238946" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Gb9bRFbrXpA/UJ53r0hnb2I/AAAAAAAAAUQ/LuZjqxl5B-A/s400/trevor_paglen_2010_dronevision-706941.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Drone Vision by Trevor Paglen</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br /></div><div>Artists have been actively documenting the impact of the use of  drones in warfare for some years now.&nbsp;&nbsp; <b>Trevor Paglen</b>'s <a href="http://vimeo.com/47723379" target="_blank"><i>Drone Vision</i></a>, recently on show at <a href="http://www.lighthouse.org.uk/programme/trevor-paglen-geographies-of-seeing" target="_blank"> Lighthouse</a> in Brighton, provides us with a chilling  "drones-eye-view" of a landscape, enabling us to see what  drone-operators see.</div><div><br /></div><div><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="225" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5809212175708170466" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-OXFvFDu_XQE/UJ53sf31qOI/AAAAAAAAAUc/pCKJ0BJ1uiY/s400/fast-709017.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Five Thousand Feet is the Best by Omer Fast </td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br />The utterly compelling and disturbing film installation, <a href="http://vimeo.com/34050994" target="_blank"><i>Five Thousand Feet is the Best</i></a>  by Israeli artist <b>Omer Fast </b>tells the story of a former Predator drone  operator, recalling his experience of using drones to fire at  civilians and militia in Afghanistan and Pakistan.&nbsp; At one stage  of the film, he describes the use of what marines refer to as  "the light of god", the laser targeting marker, which is  used to direct hellfire missiles to their intended target.</div><div><br /></div><div>"We call it in, and we're given all the clearances that are  necessary, all the approvals and everything else, and then we do  something called the Light of God - the Marines like to call it the  Light of God. It's a laser targeting marker. We just send out a beam  of laser and when the troops put on their night vision goggles  they'll just see this light that looks like it's coming from heaven.  Right on the spot, coming out of nowhere, from the sky. It's quite  beautiful." (quoted from <a href="http://vimeo.com/34050994" target="_blank"><i>Five Thousand Feet is the Best</i></a>).</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="300" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5809212186928233186" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-kNaP8dx92v8/UJ53tJq6OuI/AAAAAAAAAUo/8L_STUgmkO4/s400/light-of-god-712038.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">The Light of God by James Bridle</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br />Writer, publisher, web developer and artist, <a href="http://shorttermmemoryloss.com/" target="_blank">James Bridle</a> responded to this by creating his  own work, <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/stml/8122855101/" target="_blank"><i>The Light of God</i></a>.</div><div><br /></div><div>Sharing Paglen and Fast's concern with the use of drones in  warfare, Bridle has crated a series of projects which attempt to  reveal their presence in the landscape.&nbsp; His <a href="http://booktwo.org/notebook/drone-shadows/" target="_blank"><i>Drone Shadow</i> </a>interventions are  one-to-one representations of the MQ-1 Predator Unmanned Aerial  Vehicle (UAV) drawn to scale within urban landscapes. The first was  <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/stml/sets/72157629467854567/" target="_blank">drawn in London this February</a> (in collaboration with Einar Sneve  Martinussen), and the  <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/stml/sets/72157631741955211/" target="_blank">second in Turkey this  October </a>as part of the Istanbul Design Biennial. </div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-S4irTBkvNSA/UJ53ttg4D9I/AAAAAAAAAU0/rMGguC5_VJo/s1600/84_drone-port-2-714356.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="298" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5809212196549824466" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-S4irTBkvNSA/UJ53ttg4D9I/AAAAAAAAAU0/rMGguC5_VJo/s400/84_drone-port-2-714356.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Drone Shadow 002 by James Bridle</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br />Like Paglen and Fast, Bridle's work stems from a deep concern  with increasingly invisible and seamless military technologies that  are creating the context for "secret, unaccountable, endless  wars".<br /><br /><a href="http://booktwo.org/notebook/drone-shadows" target="_blank">Bridle writes</a>, "the drone also, for  me, stands in part for the network itself: an invisible, inherently  connected technology allowing sight and action at a distance. Us and  the digital, acting together, a medium and an exchange. But the  non-human components of the network are not moral actors, and the same  technology that permits civilian technological wonder, the wide-eyed  futurism of the New Aesthetic and the unevenly-distributed joy of  living now, also produces obscurantist "security" culture,  ubiquitous surveillance, and robotic killing machines. [....] We all live under the shadow of the drone, although most of us  are lucky enough not to live under its direct fire. But the attitude  they represent - of technology used for obscuration and violence; of  the obfuscation of morality and culpability; of the illusion of  omniscience and omnipotence; of the lesser value of other peoples  lives; of, frankly, endless war - should concern us all."</div><div><br /></div><div>His latest work, released yesterday, is <a href="http://booktwo.org/notebook/dronestagram-drones-eye-view/" target="_blank"><i>Dronestagram</i></a>. Bridle  has been collecting images of the locations of drone strikes, and  sharing these photographs on the photo-sharing site Instagram. His  intention is to make these locations more visible, bringing them  closer to us, and in the process perhaps making the reality of the  daily occurrence of deadly drone strikes more tangible.</div><div><br /></div><div>He utilises public records from the <a href="http://www.thebureauinvestigates.com/" target="_blank">Bureau of Investigative  Journalism</a> who document strikes as they happen in Pakistan, Yemen  or Somalia. After confirming the location of a strike, he then uses  Google Maps to create a satellite image of the targeted location.&nbsp;  The image, accompanied by a description of the site, and the  death-toll, if known, is uploaded to Instagram.</div><div><br /></div><div><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-IU7IPmpkPWY/UJ53ucwnuLI/AAAAAAAAAVA/migjw6xsbnE/s1600/yemen-716862.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="400" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5809212209232328882" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-IU7IPmpkPWY/UJ53ucwnuLI/AAAAAAAAAVA/migjw6xsbnE/s400/yemen-716862.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Wadi Abu Jabara, Yemen, 28 October 2012. 3 killed. Image from Dronestagram by James Bridle</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br />The images of deserted, barren landscapes and abandoned buildings  have a sobering potency juxtaposed with with the banal pictures of  pets and parties that populate Instagram. But it is what we don't see  that gives these images such an emotional power. The mortality.</div><div><br /></div><div><a href="http://booktwo.org/notebook/dronestagram-drones-eye-view/" target="_blank">Bridle writes</a>, "drones are just the latest in a long line of  military technologies augmenting the process of death-dealing, but  they are among the most efficient, the most distancing, the most  invisible. These qualities allow them to do what they do unseen [...].  Whether you think these killings are immoral or not, most of them are  by any international standard illegal."</div><div><br /></div><div>The work of artists such as Trevor Paglen, Omer Fast, and James Bridle exists within  a long tradition of artists bearing witness to events that our  governments and military would prefer we didn't see.<br /><br />But  Bridle's work is also part of an ongoing collective effort from both  artists and engineers to reveal the technological infrastructures that  enable events like drone-strikes to occur. As technology becomes more  ubiquitous, and our relationship with our devices becomes ever more  seamless, our technical infrastructure is becoming ever more  invisible. When our environment becomes opaque or invisible, it  becomes difficult to interpret it, and act within it.&nbsp; As artist  and critical engineer, <a href="http://julianoliver.com/" target="_blank">Julian Oliver</a>  <a href="http://rhizome.org/editorial/2012/sep/5/artist-profile-julian-oliver/" target="_blank">recently noted,</a> "our inability to describe and understand  technological infrastructure reduces our critical reach, leaving us  both disempowered and, quite often, vulnerable." </div><div><br /></div><div>Or as <a href="http://booktwo.org/notebook/drone-shadows/" target="_blank">Bridle puts it</a>, "those who cannot perceive the  network cannot act effectively within it, and are powerless. The job,  then, is to make such things visible." </div><div><br /></div><div><br /></div><div>Sources:</div><div><a href="http://vimeo.com/47723379">http://vimeo.com/47723379</a></div><div><a href="http://vimeo.com/34050994">http://vimeo.com/34050994</a></div><div><a href="http://booktwo.org/notebook/drone-shadows/">http://booktwo.org/notebook/drone-shadows/</a></div><div><a href="http://booktwo.org/notebook/dronestagram-drones-eye-view/">http://booktwo.org/notebook/dronestagram-drones-eye-view/</a></div><div><a href="http://rhizome.org/editorial/2012/sep/5/artist-profile-julian-oliver/">http://rhizome.org/editorial/2012/sep/5/artist-profile-julian-oliver/</a></div><div><br /></div></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/OcJ-Da7G96s" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="cf8e31fb93b6ea08c65c4e73139dbd0d" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/PLsi-6KrMPA/storifying-critical-citizen-science.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-TD3FfKLdnHM/UWGsx4jKf5I/AAAAAAAAAb0/nKKOjk9rICc/s1600/madlab-718170.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="267" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5864158162806538130" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-TD3FfKLdnHM/UWGsx4jKf5I/AAAAAAAAAb0/nKKOjk9rICc/s400/madlab-718170.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">MadLab Scientists investigating food products. Image (cc) MadLabUK, 2013.</td></tr></tbody></table><div><a href="http://www.sussex.ac.uk/spru/people/peoplelists/person/312399" target="_blank">Alice Bell</a>  recently <a href="https://twitter.com/alicebell/status/317331109555892224" target="_blank">drew my attention</a> to a  fascinating piece of writing by the Goldsmiths academic, <a href="http://www.internetartizans.co.uk/">Dan McQuillan</a>. The piece entitled,<i> <a href="http://storify.com/danmcquillan/what-is-critical-citizen-science-a-dialogue/" target="_blank">What is  Critical Citizen Science? (A Dialogue)</a></i>, is a meditation on the emerging field of citizen  science. It takes the form of a fictional dialogue between 'nomad',  the apotheosis of a free-thinking scientist-cum-hacker, and  'royalist', a caricature of an antediluvian traditionalist academic.  Through the voices of these archetypes, <a href="http://storify.com/danmcquillan/what-is-critical-citizen-science-a-dialogue/" target="_blank">McQuillan sets out</a> what he  refers to as 'critical citizen science', a bottom-up,  participative scientific movement.</div><div><br /></div><div><a href="http://storify.com/danmcquillan/what-is-critical-citizen-science-a-dialogue/" target="_blank">The piece</a> is published on <a href="http://storify.com/" target="_blank">Storify</a>, the  social media service that lets users create stories using elements  from other platforms such as Twitter, YouTube or Instagram.&nbsp;  Users build a story from video, images, and quotations from various  places, using their own words to formulate a narrative.</div><div><br /></div><div>Through a combination of well-chosen references, polemics and  poetry, a sense of what 'critical citizen science' might be, gradually  emerges from McQuillan's text. The dialogic format inevitably  calls to mind the conversations between Achilles and the tortoise in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zeno%27s_paradoxes#Achilles_and_the_tortoise"> Zeno</a>, <a href="http://www.ditext.com/carroll/tortoise.html">Carroll</a>,  and perhaps most fittingly, Hofstadter's <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/G%C3%B6del,_Escher,_Bach" target="_blank"><i>Gödel, Escher, Bach</i></a>. In  <a href="http://storify.com/danmcquillan/what-is-critical-citizen-science-a-dialogue/" target="_blank">McQuillan's work too</a>, the medium of dialogue lends itself well to an  inquiry into the complex ethics, aesthetics and politics that  'critical citizen science' might be engaged with.</div><div><br /></div><div>Intriguingly, over the course of the dialogue, McQuillan  correlates emerging community science and technology practices,  exemplified by crowdmapping initiatives like <a href="http://harassmap.org/en/" target="_blank">Harassmap</a>, hackerspaces such as <a href="http://madlab.org.uk/" target="_blank">MadLab</a>, and open hardware projects such as <a href="http://blog.safecast.org/about/" target="_blank">Safecast</a> and <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1JqRmFpkdY8&amp;feature=player_embedded" target="_blank">Water Hack</a>, with an analysis of radical media art practice of the late  20th century, particularly <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electronic_Disturbance_Theater" target="_blank">the Electronic Disturbance Theater</a>.<br /><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="228" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5864158180966888578" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-FO9ROOdnUe0/UWGsy8M7dII/AAAAAAAAAcA/VctnnXUH9PA/s400/dominguez-interview-front-722506.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><span class="st">Ricardo Dominguez, Electronic Disturbance Theater</span></td></tr></tbody></table></div><div>As  someone <a href="http://www.tacticalmediafiles.net/netcongestion/html/individual_contributions/honorhargeradamhyde.html" target="_blank">very</a> <a href="http://www.tacticalmediafiles.net/netcongestion/html/programme.html" target="_blank">much</a> <a href="http://radioqualia.va.com.au/tool_fair/" target="_blank"> engaged</a> with the wider context of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tactical_media" target="_blank">tactical media</a> as a cultural strategy  in the 1990s, and now equally fascinated by  emerging forms of  participatory science, I found <a href="http://www.internetartizans.co.uk/">McQuillan</a>'s juxtaposition of  these two discrete  areas, deeply compelling.<br /><br />Here's a short extract, where we listen in on nomad and royalist,  discussing new sites of scientific learning:</div><div><br /></div><div><i>nomad: there is already an emerging set of learning spaces for  critical citizen science; hackerspaces, makerspaces and  fablabs...</i></div><div><i>royalist: what nonsense. these aren't labs, they're garages; and  it's not science, merely an obsessive meddling with hardware.</i></div><div><i>nomad: popularly known as hacking. i refer you to early  hacktivists the Electronic Disturbance Theater and their 'science of  the oppressed" - "...alternative social forms of life and  art that fall between the known and unknown, between fiction and the  real, between clean science and dirty science - each a part of a long  history of an epistemology of social production which privileges the  standpoint of the proletariat, the multitude, the open hacks of the  DIY moments, and of autonomous investigators who stage test zones of  cognitive styles... concrete practices as speculation and speculation  as concrete practices - at the speed of dreams."</i></div><div><br /></div><div>This is not a manifesto for 'critical citizen science' (or  perhaps just as accurately, 'tactical citizen science'?). It's more of  a persuasive suggestion.&nbsp; But one can't help but recall another  grass-roots movement which argues for a similarly critically engaged  approach to science and technology. In October 2011, Julian Oliver,  Gordan Savicic and Danja Vasiliev published the <a href="http://criticalengineering.org/" target="_blank">Critical  Engineering Manifesto</a>.&nbsp; It  begins by stating:</div><div><br /></div><div>"The Critical Engineer considers Engineering to be the most  transformative language of our time, shaping the way we move,  communicate and think. It is the work of the Critical Engineer to  study and exploit this language, exposing its influence."</div><div><br /></div><div>As co-author, <a href="http://rhizome.org/editorial/2012/sep/5/artist-profile-julian-oliver/" target="_blank">Oliver noted in an interview in 2012</a>, "as thinkers with technical abilities in  several areas, we want to take on our built and increasingly automated  environment by the terms in which it's given, opening it up for  post-utilitarian conversation, for play and interrogation. If there's  ever a time to be doing that, it's now, especially with opaque and  hidden infrastructure in the telecommunications space deeply impacting  diplomatic relations and civil liberties world wide."</div><div><br /></div><div>The manifesto provides an analytical framework for artistic  practice which exposes the technological and scientific systems which  unpin much of society. By making these infrastructures and systems  visible, the 'critical engineer' reveals the political and power  structures at play, instigates critical discussion, and questions who  has agency within these systems.</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-IlpOkufXrdM/UWGszvjmhkI/AAAAAAAAAcQ/hm6leC0v4hY/s1600/grenade_660-725783.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="266" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5864158194752194114" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-IlpOkufXrdM/UWGszvjmhkI/AAAAAAAAAcQ/hm6leC0v4hY/s400/grenade_660-725783.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><i>Transparency Grenade</i> (2011) by Julian Oliver</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div>Projects such as Oliver's<i> <a href="http://transparencygrenade.com/" target="_blank">Transparency Grenade</a></i> (2011) and Oliver and Vasiliev's<i> <a href="http://newstweek.com/" target="_blank"> Newstweek</a></i> (2011) are designed as both  functional tools, which both reveal and disrupt the invisible  information and communication networks that surround us, and  conversation-starters about our unquestioning reliance on  technological systems we often don't understand.&nbsp; Their intention  is to expose the deep reach that science and technology have in our  lives, and to try and encourage more active forms of intervention and  agency.&nbsp; As Oliver (2012) <a href="http://rhizome.org/editorial/2012/sep/5/artist-profile-julian-oliver/" target="_blank">has noted</a>, we all "think through tools both before and while we  use them and the more we depend upon a tool the more we are changed by  it."</div><div><br /></div><div>McQuillan's speculations on critical citizen science seem  to originate from a similar desire to question the power structures and  politics of scientific practice. He insinuates an anxiety about  popular citizen-science efforts such as Galaxy Zoo and LHC@Home, which  harness the labour of users, without deeply engaging them in the  scientific process.&nbsp; To frame that concern, he cites Tiziana  Terranova's critique of user-generated content outlined in her  text,<i> <a href="https://www.zotero.org/groups/web_2.0/items/itemKey/JUUP24VJ" target="_blank">Free Labor: Producing Culture for the Digital Economy</a></i>  (2000).</div><div><br /></div><div>His text also conveys an unease with the exponential hype  surrounding 'big data' and 'open data':</div><div><br /></div><div><i>royalist: [...]&nbsp; The networks you rely on for your  delocalised tinkering have already given birth to a new science; and  it's name is Data Science; and its Data shall be Big.</i></div><div><i>nomad: [...] As our data is always ambiguous, we shall Glitch;  becoming the discontinuities and unexpected artefacts in the big data  you crave.</i></div><div><br /></div><div>Later, McQuillan points to the value of critical citizen scientists in  bearing witness to events which governments and bureaucracies would  prefer citizens not to see, let alone intervene into:</div><div><br /></div><div><i>nomad: [....] Why not look to the example of white coated  citizens weapons inspectors for responsible empiricism. In a horsemeat  crisis, the critical citizen scientist packs their DIY bio and  flashmobs the nearest Lidl. This isn't an idle fantasy; only recently,  Madlab testers set up shop as the Deptford Market DNA FoodLab.</i></div><div><br /></div><div>Elsewhere the piece, McQuillan muses whether 'critical citizen  science' could be the site at which the Internet of Things becomes the  "Parliament of Things" as described by Bruno Latour in his  1991 book,<i> <a href="http://www.blogger.com/goog_813993852">We Have Never Been Modern</a></i><a href="http://www.amazon.com/We-Have-Never-Been-Modern/dp/0674948394">.</a> By  this, Latour was referring to a kind of symmetry between people and  what he calls "non-human entities" (or "things").  He argues that our society is comprised of people assembled around  "things". Latour dismantles the barrier between culture and  nature, between subject and object, proposing more subtle relations  between humans and "things", in which the latter are granted  the same amount of agency as we are. McQuillan spiritedly picks this  up, in the voice of nomad, contending:</div><div><br /></div><div><i>"Through citizen science, the Parliament of Things will  become the Occupy of Objects."</i></div><div><br /></div><div>Whilst I was originally drawn to the subject of the piece - its  evocation of radical tactical art media practices, entwined with new  community science efforts, and echoing (perhaps inadvertently) the  philosophy of the critical engineering movement - the methodology of  the story construction is also worthy of note.&nbsp; When I first read  the piece and started thinking about it, I opined to the science  policy researcher, <a href="http://justinpickard.net/">Justin Pickard</a>, that  such evocative material deserved to be written up in a more formal  manner.&nbsp; He responded by saying:</div><div><br /></div><div>"This *is* it written up properly. Storify-native STS. Look  how reliant it is on the video clips, images, and  hyperlinks."</div><div><br /></div><div>So, tools like Storify enable writers and makers to build  layered, interwoven narratives around science and technology research  and ideas. These tools provide us with a different vector to be able  to express heterogeneous, emerging and often conflicting ideas.&nbsp;  As such, they have the potential to develop into an intriguing and  valuable alternative platforms for science communication, and the  analysis of scientific research.</div><div><br /></div><div>Source:</div><div><a href="http://storify.com/danmcquillan/what-is-critical-citizen-science-a-dialogue/">http://storify.com/danmcquillan/what-is-critical-citizen-science-a-dialogue/</a></div><div><br /></div></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/PLsi-6KrMPA" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6d81663035f2f61588702bef678fde87" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/PqIqsk3AqSU/lhc-as-cathedral.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="mobile-photo"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ncVx_gn0sQ0/T_6GtTha3mI/AAAAAAAAAPU/18XzMRAeRDs/s1600/cern1-792959.jpg"><img alt="" border="0" height="245" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5764192685973495394" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ncVx_gn0sQ0/T_6GtTha3mI/AAAAAAAAAPU/18XzMRAeRDs/s400/cern1-792959.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><br />Much has been written about <a href="http://www.cosmosmagazine.com/node/1125">the&nbsp;cathedral-like&nbsp;qualities</a> of the LHC detectors,&nbsp;<a href="http://cms.web.cern.ch/">CMS</a> and&nbsp;<a href="http://atlas.web.cern.ch/">ATLAS</a>.<br />A new set of images published on the blog,&nbsp;<a href="http://butdoesitfloat.com/Well-what-are-you-Are-you-some-kind-of-diffuse-consciousness-that-is">Does&nbsp;It Float</a> beautifully communicates the site's&nbsp;visual grandeur.<br /><br /><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-NBEwvZYGDOw/T_6IMAJ-ieI/AAAAAAAAAPo/dExxk1HFJ-M/s1600/cern3.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="271" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-NBEwvZYGDOw/T_6IMAJ-ieI/AAAAAAAAAPo/dExxk1HFJ-M/s400/cern3.jpg" style="cursor: move;" width="400" /></a><br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-s6Z7jCUdClI/T_6ICFF2EVI/AAAAAAAAAPc/Wkt0YIOLueo/s1600/cern2.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="253" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-s6Z7jCUdClI/T_6ICFF2EVI/AAAAAAAAAPc/Wkt0YIOLueo/s400/cern2.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br />All Images © CERN.<br /><br />Source:&nbsp;<a href="http://butdoesitfloat.com/Well-what-are-you-Are-you-some-kind-of-diffuse-consciousness-that-is">Does&nbsp;It Float</a>&nbsp;</div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/PqIqsk3AqSU" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1361c2c1d30e45c5872efaa4ca881914" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/ps5XKEpTM88/ensonifying-space.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div style="text-align: left;"></div><div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-XnRzwtQP30o/UStCzkBZPRI/AAAAAAAAAag/SfCjXc--xG0/s1600/rt32.jpg" imageanchor="0" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-XnRzwtQP30o/UStCzkBZPRI/AAAAAAAAAag/SfCjXc--xG0/s400/rt32.jpg" width="358" /></a></div><div></div><br />It is very heartening and interesting to read <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tedweekends/" target="_blank">so many fascinating  articles</a>, emerging from my<i> <a href="http://decelerator.blogspot.co.uk/2013/02/tuning-universe.html" target="_blank">Tuning into the Universe</a></i>&nbsp;piece  for Huffington Post this weekend.</div><div><br /></div><div>Scientists and journalists from <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tedweekends" target="_blank">Huffington Post community have  published a range of pieces</a> on everything from data  sonification, to astereoseismology, to the reminiscences of a former  astronaut. Together these articles greatly expand the field of general  knowledge around the physics of radio astronomy, and our capacity to  sensorially experience it.</div><div><br /></div><div>One of the pieces draws on an interview with radio astronomer,  and the co-founder of the SETI Institute, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jill_Tarter" target="_blank">Jill Tarter</a>. Amplifying the central  message of<i>&nbsp;</i><i>&nbsp;<a href="http://decelerator.blogspot.co.uk/2013/02/tuning-universe.html" target="_blank">Tuning into the Universe</a></i>, Tarter <a href="http://www.npr.org/2011/02/20/133914639/tuning-in-space-noise-for-sounds-of-life" target="_blank">notes&nbsp;that</a>: </div><div>"when SETI listens to the cosmos, the institute is actually  receiving electromagnetic radiation. And then, just the way your radio  does, that energy can be used to make audible sound."</div><div><br /></div><div>The pieces published in response to the article extend, expand  and<i> ensonify</i> this notion.&nbsp; Some of my favourites  include:</div><div><br /></div><div><i><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/dr-tyler-nordgren/the-sound-of-the-deep-sea_b_2736359.html" target="_blank">The Sound of the Deep Sea of Spac</a>e</i> by radio astronomer,  Dr. Tyler Nordgren&nbsp;equates the universe with a vast ocean,  echoing Carl Sagan's famous analogy from his series, <i><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cosmos:_A_Personal_Voyage" target="_blank">Cosmos</a></i>. He  poetically maps out the methods of astronomical observation available  to modern astronomers, beyond the detection of visible light.&nbsp;He notes: "as a young radio astronomer I learned early  on that every time human beings have explored the world with new  senses we have discovered new and amazing phenomena".<br /><br /><div><div style="margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;"><i><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/anna-leahy/voyager-golden-record_b_2749806.html" target="_blank">Voices Carry</a></i>&nbsp;by Anna Leahy and Douglas Dechow&nbsp;explores the sonic signature of our own planet:</div></div><div><div style="margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;">"The sound of the Earth's inherent dynamics -- the movement of atmosphere and oceans -- produces a steady drone as well. Lightning produces crackling, which scientists call sferics."</div></div></div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DBoFuyYfCLg/USs-7YXygRI/AAAAAAAAAaA/zeWMkEr3tgQ/s1600/golden_record_cover-753598.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="366" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5848837730946154770" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DBoFuyYfCLg/USs-7YXygRI/AAAAAAAAAaA/zeWMkEr3tgQ/s400/golden_record_cover-753598.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Voyager Golden Record</td></tr></tbody></table>The article includes a memorable passage about the <a href="http://voyager.jpl.nasa.gov/spacecraft/goldenrec.html" target="_blank">Voyager Golden  Record</a>, which  contains 'greetings in 56 languages, natural sounds like thunder and  crickets chirping, and music from around the world', encoded in audio  and now travelling towards the outer reaches of our solar system on  board Voyager.</div><div><br /></div><div>In<i> <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jim-bell/solar-system-sounds_b_2736114.html" target="_blank">An Audible Tour of the Solar System? Sign Me Up!</a>,</i>&nbsp;astronomer and planetary scientist, Jim Bell&nbsp;analyses our celestial neighbourhood, exploring the  potential for acoustic sound on each of our nearest planets.&nbsp;<i><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jerry-l-ross/spacewalking_b_2744797.html" target="_blank">The Perfect Quiet of Space</a></i>&nbsp;by legendary astronaut, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jerry_L._Ross" target="_blank">Jerry L. Ros</a>s, is the extraordinary  account of his nine spacewalks, undertaken during his seven missions  into space.</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-GZ8GZsSWzhY/USs-8CEcUXI/AAAAAAAAAaM/4wGXOsVFD7w/s1600/ross-756530.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="231" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5848837742139298162" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-GZ8GZsSWzhY/USs-8CEcUXI/AAAAAAAAAaM/4wGXOsVFD7w/s400/ross-756530.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Jerry L. Ross n one of his nine spacewalks.</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br />He writes eloquently about the silence which astronauts  experience, when outside the International Space Station:</div><div>"Without the sophisticated listening devices scientists use  on earth to hear the whispers of the universe, to an astronaut space  is infinite quiet, a place where we bring the only sounds that break  the silence."</div><div><br /></div><div><i><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mark-ballora/sound-the-music-universe_b_2745188.html" target="_blank">Sound: The Music of the Universe</a></i> by Mark Ballora and  George Smoot III&nbsp;is an excellent overview of the practice of  data sonification, which takes in in the brilliant work of the <a href="http://spdf.gsfc.nasa.gov/research/sonification/sonification_software.html" target="_blank">xSonify</a>  team, who are making sonification applications for blind  scientists. The article also refers to the emerging science of  astereoseismology and exoseismology, which I talked about last Friday  in <a href="http://2013.sonicacts.com/events/honor-harger-the-dark-arts" target="_blank">my Sonic Acts talk</a>.</div><div><br /></div><div>They clearly explain why data sonification methods can  be useful:</div><div>"Symbolic renderings create other perspectives. Literal  renderings are not always compatible with the capabilities of our  auditory system. When data points are treated as audio samples and  played back at audio rates (typically at 44100 values/second) quick  changes are lost to us, as we can't hear fluctuations discretely at  the millisecond level. If, instead, we treat the data points  symbolically, for example as pitches, we are better able to  "magnify" what we are listening to."</div><div><br /></div><div>In<i> <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ayodele-faiyetole/understanding-the-sound-space_b_2736478.html" target="_blank">Understanding the Sound of Space</a></i>, Ayodele Faiyetole&nbsp;notes that sound is under used in  science.&nbsp; He draws on an interview with cosmologist, Yuko  Takahashi, who believes there's a great value in presenting scientific  results in a totally different dimensions, such as sound:</div><div>"Maps of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cosmic_microwave_background_radiation" target="_blank">CMB anisotropy </a>can be converted to sound as a telescope sweeps across the sky to give  the audience a better appreciation of the fluctuations."</div><div><br /></div><div>As <a href="http://www.blogger.com/(http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mark-ballora/sound-the-music-universe_b_2745188.html" target="_blank">Ballora and Smoot</a> put it, "if the universe is, at some  level, music, then it seems only natural that we should study it with  musical tools of thinking."</div><div><br /></div><div>Source: <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tedweekends/">http://www.huffingtonpost.com/tedweekends/</a></div></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/ps5XKEpTM88" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="36e6d76127847114b7a7532b2baa110f" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/pXQib9_pxPE/kepler-conference-in-need-of-new-home.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-SPwQk3MBuDw/UlHMuXlkfdI/AAAAAAAAAh8/TOaJizvmKWc/s1600/Telescope-KeplerSpacecraft-20130103-717260main_pia11824-full-737299.jpg"><img alt="" border="0" height="245" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5931747281201298898" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-SPwQk3MBuDw/UlHMuXlkfdI/AAAAAAAAAh8/TOaJizvmKWc/s400/Telescope-KeplerSpacecraft-20130103-717260main_pia11824-full-737299.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div>This week a scandal rocked the astronomy community, relating to a exo-planet conference which will discuss results from the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kepler_(spacecraft)" target="_blank">Kepler Space Telescope</a>. The Kepler Science Conference II is scheduled to take place at<a href="http://nexsci.caltech.edu/conferences/KeplerII/" target="_blank"> NASA Ames' research facility next month</a>.<br /><br />However, US government laws have made it impossible for the organisers to welcome colleagues from countries such as China to the conference. &nbsp;As <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/science/2013/oct/05/us-scientists-boycott-nasa-china-ban" target="_blank">Ian Sample reported this week</a>, all Chinese nationals are prohibited from setting foot on NASA property by law. &nbsp;Consequently, the conference has had to exclude scientists from China, as well as scientists from nations such as, Burma, Eritrea, Iran, North Korea, Saudi Arabia, Sudan and Uzbekistan, from the event. This has sparked major controversy, and a campaign to boycott the event. <br /><br />As&nbsp;<a href="http://www.economist.com/blogs/babbage/2013/10/america-china-and-space-science" target="_blank">Tim Cross noted in the Economist</a>, "it is hard to fathom what secrets any supposed Chinese spies would have been able to pilfer at a conference devoted to alien planets."<br /><br />A group of scientists are now trying to arrange an alternative venue for the conference so that any scientist registered to attend - no matter what nationality they are - is able to share their research with their colleagues. <a href="http://is.gd/saveopenscience" target="_blank">Lucianne Walkowicz</a>, a scientist who worked on the Kepler mission, <a href="http://is.gd/saveopenscience" target="_blank">has called for help to find an alternative space for the conference</a>.<br /><br />The very principles of open science are at stake here. &nbsp;As astronomer, Chris Lintott, <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/science/2013/oct/05/us-scientists-boycott-nasa-china-ban" target="_blank">has said</a>:<br /><br /><i>"I'm shocked and upset by the way this policy has been applied. Science is supposed to be open to all and restricting those who can attend by nationality goes against years of practice, going right back to cold war conferences of Russian and western physicists."</i><br /><br /><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geoffrey_Marcy" target="_blank">Geoff Marcy</a>, known for discovering more extrasolar planets than anyone else, and tipped as a future Nobelist, has put it more strongly calling the exclusion of scientists from the banned nations, "completely shameful and unethical." <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/science/2013/oct/05/us-scientists-boycott-nasa-china-ban" target="_blank">He said</a>:<br /><br /><i>"In good conscience, I cannot attend a meeting that discriminates in this way. The meeting is about planets located trillions of miles away, with no national security implications."</i><br /><br />Those of us with good networks and contacts may be able to help.<br /><br />Finding a venue that can accommodate 400 people, between November 4-8, 2013, in the Bay Area in California is going to be very challenging, but surely not impossible. &nbsp;If you are aware of venues that can accommodate up to 400 people, <a href="mailto:L.M.Walkowicz@gmail.com" target="_blank">please reach out to Lucianne and let her know</a>. &nbsp;There are many obstacles that would need to be addressed before the conference could be shifted, but locating some possible alternatives spaces is the first step.<br /><br /></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/pXQib9_pxPE" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ddd6a0030bc7bbf5ddee0be241ba10a8" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/Q0CAFqDV0mQ/here-at-last.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="mobile-photo"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-YC9VM5YF7yc/UlQMKplcd8I/AAAAAAAAAiM/EMKL7dUEbKc/s1600/higgs-750222.png"><img alt="" border="0" height="216" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5932379986254919618" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-YC9VM5YF7yc/UlQMKplcd8I/AAAAAAAAAiM/EMKL7dUEbKc/s400/higgs-750222.png" width="400" /></a></div><div class="mobile-photo"><br /></div><div class="mobile-photo">"Here at last ..."</div><div class="mobile-photo"><br /></div><div class="mobile-photo">With those words the Nobel Committee awarded the <a href="http://www.nobelprize.org/nobel_prizes/physics/laureates/2013/press.pdf)" target="_blank">2013 Nobel Prize for Physics</a> to Francois Englert (left) and&nbsp;Peter Higgs (right) for their work in discovering the theoretical basis for what we now refer to as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Higgs_mechanism" target="_blank">the Higgs mechanism</a>.</div><div class="mobile-photo"><br /></div><div class="mobile-photo">Speculation about the 2013 prize had <a href="http://www.mnn.com/green-tech/research-innovations/stories/should-the-higgs-boson-win-the-2013-nobel-prize" target="_blank">reached fever pitch</a> ahead of this year's announcement. &nbsp;Most <a href="http://blog.vixra.org/2013/10/07/nobel-anticipation/" target="_blank">commentators in the physics community</a> expected that this would be the year that the scientists who ushered in our understanding of how subatomic particles obtained mass, would be honoured by the Nobel committee.&nbsp;</div><div class="mobile-photo">The question was, which scientists?</div><div class="mobile-photo"><br /></div><div class="mobile-photo">Nobel science prizes can traditionally only be awarded to a maximum of three recipients, all of whom must be living. &nbsp;The theoretical work on the Higgs mechanism, and the prediction of the existence of the Higgs boson, was undertaken by at least six physicists in 1964: Robert Brout (sadly deceased) and Francois Englert; Peter Higgs; and Gerald Guralnik, C. R. Hagen, and Tom Kibble.</div><div class="mobile-photo"><br /></div><div class="mobile-photo">Further complicating matters was the strong belief amongst many that the extraordinary experimental work, undertaken by the CMS and ATLAS teams at CERN, ought to be acknowledged. &nbsp;</div><div class="mobile-photo"><br /></div><div class="mobile-photo">Who can forget <a href="http://decelerator.blogspot.co.uk/2012/07/science-history-is-made.html" target="_blank">that emotional day, 4 July 2012</a>, when Joe Incandela and Fabiola Gianotti broke the news that both CMS and ATLAS had found experimental evidence of the Higgs boson?&nbsp;</div><div class="mobile-photo"><br /></div><div class="mobile-photo">The pundits focused on whether this would be the year that the Nobel committee broke with tradition and awarded the prize to more than three recipients. Would they be bold enough the recognise the efforts of an institution for the first time, by including CERN in the award? &nbsp;Would the theoretical work of Guralnik, Hagen and Kibble, be acknowledged alongside the work of Higgs and Englert? &nbsp;</div><div class="mobile-photo"><br /></div><div class="mobile-photo">Science writer and ATLAS team member, Jon Butterworth, summed up the feelings of many when <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/science/2013/oct/08/nobel-prize-in-physics-live-blog" target="_blank">he wrote</a>:</div><div class="mobile-photo"><br /></div><div class="mobile-photo"><i>"It should be Higgs, Englert and Cern. Nobel prizes are for discovery, Higgs and Englert discovered the theory, Cern (many people) discovered the reality."</i></div><div class="mobile-photo"><br /></div><div class="mobile-photo">This morning's announcement, delayed by an hour for unspecified reasons, reveled that tradition is intact. Englert and Higgs <a href="http://www.nobelprize.org/nobel_prizes/physics/laureates/2013/press.pdf" target="_blank">share the prize for</a> "the theoretical discovery of a mechanism that contributes to our understanding of the origin of mass of subatomic particles, and which recently was confirmed through the discovery of the predicted fundamental particle, by the ATLAS and CMS experiments at CERN’s Large Hadron Collider."</div><div class="mobile-photo"><br /></div><div class="mobile-photo">The news <a href="https://twitter.com/CERN/status/387532837991104512/photo/1" target="_blank">triggered celebrations at CERN</a> and in physics labs the world over, but also some <a href="http://is.gd/higgstory" target="_blank">quieter reflection</a> from those close to the news.</div><div class="mobile-photo"><br /></div><div class="mobile-photo">As Matt Strassler has noted, in <a href="http://is.gd/higgstory" target="_blank">his excellent analysis of the history of the discovery</a>, it is important to acknowledge the longer, more complex story involved in the discovery of this vital constituent of the Standard Model of particle physics. Over-simplifications of what is involved in doing science can lead to dangerous misconceptions. &nbsp;He writes:</div><div class="mobile-photo"><br /></div><div class="mobile-photo"><i>"History in general, and history of science in particular, is always vastly more complex than the simple stories we tell ourselves and our descendants."</i></div><div class="mobile-photo"><br /></div><div class="mobile-photo">Jon Butterworth made a further plea for the collaborative nature of science to be properly recognised, in <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/science/life-and-physics/2013/oct/08/nobel-higgs-boson-experimenters" target="_blank">his response to the news</a>:</div><div class="mobile-photo"><br /></div><div class="mobile-photo"><i>"While lone geniuses and breakthroughs do occur, incremental progress and collaboration are more important in increasing our understanding of nature. Even the theory breakthrough behind this prize required a body of incrementally acquired knowledge to which many contributed.</i></div><div class="mobile-photo"><i>The discovery of a Higgs boson, showing that the theoretical ideas are manifested in the real world, was thanks to the work of many thousands. There are 3,000 or so people on Atlas, a similar number on CMS, and hundreds who worked on the LHC. While the citation gives handsome credit for all this, part of me still wishes the prizes could have acknowledged it too."</i></div><div class="mobile-photo"><br /></div><div class="mobile-photo">Whilst there is no question that Higgs and Englert richly deserve this accolade, spare a thought for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gerald_Guralnik" target="_blank">Guralnik</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C._R._Hagen" target="_blank">Hagen</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tom_W._B._Kibble" target="_blank">Kibble</a>, as well as the thousands of experimentalists at CERN.</div><div><br /></div></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/Q0CAFqDV0mQ" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="14cdf6282e2988f71bcdb660b9b1b0c3" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/qy4awUOqkZ4/reifying-quantum-mechanics.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="197" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5804337603904939298" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-T3PzzZFubXQ/UI0mTE0yJSI/AAAAAAAAATM/tlxjv-YgJFU/s400/berkley_2011-759517.png" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><i>Berkeley</i> (2011) by Alejandro Guijarro</td></tr></tbody></table><div>The interface between the outer reaches of theoretical physics  and conceptual art is becoming ever closer, it seems.&nbsp; This year  the the work of Austrian physicist, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anton_Zeilinger" target="_blank">Anton Zeilinger</a> was shown alongside  works by major conceptual artist, Lawrence Weiner, and contemporary  artists, such as Thomas Bayrle, at <a href="http://d13.documenta.de/#/participants/participants/anton-zeilinger/" target="_blank">Documenta</a>  - the contemporary artworld's premier shop window.</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="270" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5804337616382609234" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-pdPSh2jzSc0/UI0mTzTsR1I/AAAAAAAAATY/mXejgjJLeGE/s400/anton-zeilinger-4-763413.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><i>Quantum Now</i> by Anton Zeilinger (2012) at dOCUMENTA  13</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br /></div><div>And this month, a new exhibition has opened at the <a href="http://www.tristanhoare.co.uk/exhibitions_Alejandro_Guijarro.htm" target="_blank">Wilmotte</a> art  gallery in  London, which exhibits the working surfaces of some of the world's  leading quantum mechanics labs.</div><div><br /></div><div><i>Momentum</i> by Spanish artist <a href="http://www.alejandroguijarro.com/" target="_blank">Alejandro Guijarro</a>, brings together a collection of  large-format photographs of chalkboards taken at the quantum mechanics  departments of Oxford and Cambridge universities in the UK, Berkeley  and SLAC (the National Accelerator Laboratory) in the States, CERN in  Switzerland, and the Instituto de Física Corpuscular in Spain.&nbsp;  </div><div><br /></div><div>The blackboard has long been the iconic visual symbol of the  physics lab, an ever-shifting collaborative canvas, exhibiting the  abstract mental processes of those working there.&nbsp; Seemingly  impenetrable to the lay-eye, they possess an enigmatic aesthetic  quality.</div><div><br /></div><div><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-wJZ2y-4ZynA/UI0mUuCcsuI/AAAAAAAAATk/FAWeA0XcmGU/s1600/7_13-766044.jpg"><img alt="" border="0" height="222" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5804337632147976930" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-wJZ2y-4ZynA/UI0mUuCcsuI/AAAAAAAAATk/FAWeA0XcmGU/s400/7_13-766044.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><div><br />As <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2012/10/the-beautiful-blackboards-at-quantum-physics-labs/264166/" target="_blank">Megan Garber notes in The Atlantic</a>, "in an age  of dry-erase whiteboards and write-on wall paint - an age that has  produced surfaces and markers that allow writings to be undone with  the ruthless efficiency of a single swipe - blackboards have taken on  the wistfulness of the outmoded technology. And the semi-erased  chalkboard, in particular - its darkness swirled with the detritus of  unknown decisions and revisions - compounds the nostalgia. Its  spectral insights mingle in the bright dust of calcium  carbonate."</div><div><br /></div><div>The exhibition displays the images of blackboards life-size,  allowing us to scrutinise the equations and begin to appreciate them,  not only for their symbolic value, but their line and form.&nbsp;  Guijarro notes, "the images in this series do not purport to be  documents holding an objective truth. They function purely as  suggestions. They are fragmented pieces of ideas, thoughts or  explanations from which arises a level of randomness. They are an  attempt to portray the space of a flat surface and of a given frame.  They are arbitrary moments in the restless life of an object in  constant motion."</div><div><br /></div><div>The <a href="http://www.tristanhoare.co.uk/exhibitions_Alejandro_Guijarro.htm" target="_blank">curatorial text</a> of the exhibition also emphasises the art  historical lineage of Guijarro's photographs:</div><div>"The colourful equations remind us of Basquiat's formulaic  language and the white chalk evokes Cy Twombly's later canvases.  Each line and smudge has its own history and meaning, produced by a  scientist unaware of their artistic merit."</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="161" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5804337645228615682" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3HFPfXFkuJ0/UI0mVexHaAI/AAAAAAAAATw/1F4vVLoBjgM/s400/untititled_2011-769163.png" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><i>Untitled</i> (2011) by Alejandro Guijarro</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br /></div><div><br /></div><div>At a time where developments such as the <a href="http://decelerator.blogspot.co.uk/2012/07/science-history-is-made.html" target="">LHC at CERN</a> have brought  both experimental and theoretical physics to the wider attention of  the public, one is tempted to wonder if these exhibitions are an  attempt by the artworld to aestheticise, or even reify, the seemingly  abstract field of quantum mechanics.</div><div><br /></div><div><i>Momentum</i> is on show at the <a href="http://www.tristanhoare.co.uk/exhibitions_Alejandro_Guijarro.htm" target="_blank">Wilmotte gallery </a> until the 9th November 2012.</div><div><br /></div><div>Sources:</div><div><a href="http://www.alejandroguijarro.com/ongoing/blackboards/">http://www.alejandroguijarro.com/ongoing/blackboards/</a></div><div><a href="http://www.tristanhoare.co.uk/exhibitions_Alejandro_Guijarro.htm">http://www.tristanhoare.co.uk/exhibitions_Alejandro_Guijarro.htm</a></div><div><br /></div></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/qy4awUOqkZ4" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6d06aa79a856bb8e8e1c35cf11499140" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/rnIzFRcdPWY/and-everything-is-possible-again.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-NjJD9rz20Dk/Udl-lksmszI/AAAAAAAAAeE/cjirV9mlL2c/s1600/Scifoo2013_alumini-713411.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="165" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5897884370989396786" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-NjJD9rz20Dk/Udl-lksmszI/AAAAAAAAAeE/cjirV9mlL2c/s400/Scifoo2013_alumini-713411.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">&nbsp;The SciFoo 2013 alumini, photographed at Google, June 2013.</td></tr></tbody></table><div><br />This year I was fortunate enough to be invited to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Science_Foo_Camp" target="_blank">Science Foo Camp</a>, or <i>SciFoo</i> in  California. Its exactly two weeks since it all came to an end, and its  time to write up what stands as one of the more transformational  experiences I've had in some time.</div><div><br /></div><div><a href="http://www.digital-science.com/sciencefoo/" target="_blank">SciFoo</a> is the  brainchild of O'Reilly, Nature publishing group and Google. It takes  place every year at Google's Mountain View headquarters in Silicon  Valley, California, where around 200 of the world's preeminent  scientists gather together. Nobel Laureates rub shoulders with rocket  engineers, roboticists, angel investors, science writers and the odd  science celebrity.</div><div><br /></div><div>This year's <a href="http://www.digital-science.com/sciencefoo/" target="_blank">SciFoo</a> took place from 21 -23 June.&nbsp; O'Reilly's  famed FOO ("Friends Of O'Reilly") camps are unconferences.&nbsp; The  boundary between audience and participant is dismantled. All attendees  are encouraged to organise sessions, speak and actively contribute to  others' sessions. On the evening of Friday 21 June, we all gathered at  the glittering <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Googleplex" target="_blank">Googleplex</a> to meet each other, sample Google's famed  hospitality and devise the schedule for the next few days. </div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="311" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5897884381204730434" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Trja9fSLVK0/Udl-mKwIUkI/AAAAAAAAAeM/wRAn-GY36C4/s400/SummerSolstice_SciFoo_Googleplex_MountainViewCA_June2013_zps839e74c7-716419.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Summer solstice moon over the Googleplex; Mountain View, June  2013.&nbsp; Image courtesy of Christopher Reiger</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br /></div><div>Over the next two days an extraordinary 108 hour-long sessions  unfolded on topics as diverse as citizen science, the future of human  space exploration, personal genomics, cognitive enhancement, synthetic  biology, precision cosmology, drones, the ethics of lab animal  research, sentient robots, wearable computing and DNA as data  storage.&nbsp; At any one moment, ten sessions were operating in  parallel, meaning the most challenging aspect of being there, was  choosing which of the unmissable sessions to go along to.<br /><br />On the first evening, I got together with<b> <a href="http://tangledfields.com/" target="_blank">Lucianne  Walkowicz</a></b>, one of the astrophysicists  who works on NASA's Kepler mission. We both have a keen interest in  sonification, and how sound can help us understand scientific data in  new and interesting ways. So we proposed a session on Sound in  Science. Artist and design researcher,<b> <a href="http://sarahendren.net/about/" target="_blank">Sara Hendron</a></b> proposed a session on Art and Science,  and invited me to take part. So there was a bit of preparation to do  before the sessions got underway on Saturday.</div><div><br /></div><div><br /></div><div><b>Neuroscience: Where will we be in 2063?</b></div><div><br /></div><div>My SciFoo started with a session on the future of neuroscience,  led by cognitive scientist,<b> Gary Marcus</b>, Google's director of  research,<b> Peter Norvig</b>, and one of the giants of genomic  science,<b> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_M._Church" target="_blank">George Church</a></b>.<br /><br /><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="266" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5897884389646139250" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-3IrOMKUqU8U/Udl-mqMt_3I/AAAAAAAAAec/dHqiiofT3tY/s400/George_Church-718196.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><div>George Church, photographed at SciFoo, Google, June 2013.  Photograph courtesy of Edge.</div></td></tr></tbody></table></div><br />It was titled,  "Where will we be in 2063?", and was extremely well attended,  which was hardly a surprise given Church's presence. It was populated by  a diverse group of brain researchers, chemists, investors,  philosophers and physicists, ensuring extremely lively conversations  about how neuroscience could and should evolve over the next fifty  years. The catalyst for the session was the dawn of the era of Big  Neuroscience. Two major initiatives are happening on both sides of the  Atlantic:<b> </b>Henry Markram's one billion euro <a href="http://bluebrain.epfl.ch/page-56882-en.html" target="_blank">Blue Brain project,  based at EPFL in Switzerland</a>, and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BRAIN_Initiative" target="_blank"> BRAIN Initiative</a>, a US$100 million brain-mapping project. Both initiatives  promise to revolutionise our understanding of the brain. <a href="http://bluebrain.epfl.ch/page-56882-en.html" target="_blank">Blue Brain</a>'s  plan is to create a synthetic brain by reverse-engineering the  mammalian brain down to the molecular level. The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BRAIN_Initiative" target="_blank">BRAIN Initiative</a>  plans to map the activity of every neuron in the human brain.</div><div><br />The session revealed strongly contrasting approaches to how we might  best undertake brain research, with pointed criticisms of Markram's  plans. I was sitting next to the influential chemist,<b> <a href="http://www.chem.gla.ac.uk/cronin/" target="_blank">Lee  Cronin</a></b>, who insisted the best  way to understand the brain was to build one from scratch using basic  biochemical materials. There were heated debates about what we could  possibly learn from models of the brain, which are decoupled from the  brain's essential interactions with the rest of the body, and its  environment. Some speculated that top-down computer modelling  approaches would be useless in explaining some of the hard problems  within neuroscience, such as the long-standing 'what is  consciousness?' question. This was less of an issue for the chemists,  who's line on that was simply: "that's not a hard problem.  Consciousness doesn't exist." (Cronin).<br /><br />The session ended  with the obligatory conversation about artificial intelligence, with  many pondering the ethics of striving towards hard AI. There could  have been a whole session devoted just to that, and the extent of the  divisions within the room were starkly revealed, just before the end.  One of the conveners of the session, stated, "No one doubts  strong AI is possible", to which theoretical physicist<b> Lee  Smolin</b> retorted, "I doubt! I don't know what you're talking  about!"</div><div><br /></div><div><b>Quantum Jumps and Weirdness</b></div><div><br />Next up for me was <a href="http://www.cqc2t.org/biography/102" target="_blank"><b>Andrea Morello</b></a>'s  session, where he promised to show us quantum jumps, and use this as a  catalyst to discuss the "weirdness" inherent within quantum  mechanics.&nbsp; As Morello put it: "you often hear that quantum  mechanics is weird, counterintuitive, and if you don't think so, you  didn't understand it." Morello proposed to "show us  something that eminent people (Erwin Schroedinger, for one) thought  impossible to see until not long ago: the quantum jumps of a single  atomic nucleus, before our eyes. The collapse of the wavefunction live  on camera." And that's exactly what he did.<br /><br />We were not allowed to take  photos in any of the SciFoo sessions, which was such a pity. I would  loved to have documented not only Morello's video footage of quantum  jumps in action, but also the compelling visualisation of the process  developed by students at Sydney's College of Fine Arts.&nbsp; I'll see  if I can get Andrea to send over some footage of both, and add it in  if I can.</div><div><br /></div><div>The footage was a trigger to discuss how what we are exposed to  in daily life determines our perception of science, and to dig into the  notion of "weirdness". The ensuing discussion was  fascinating, with several of the scientists in the room failing to  understand what was "weird' about Morello's demo.&nbsp; As<b>  Dave Gallo</b>, oceanographer and director of Special Projects at  Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute, noted the video footage we were  looking at showed us an oscilloscope visualising an electrical signal  switching on and off. "What's weird about that?" he asked.  Bioinformatics expert,<b> Nick Goldman</b> (of <a href="http://www.wired.com/wiredscience/2013/01/dna-data-storage-2/" target="_blank">DNA as data storage  fame</a>),  concurred: "this is like closing your eyes and hearing that there  are cars passing by the window. Until you look around you can't be  sure if you will see a car in your eyeline or not. I want the picture  of cars and not cars". We were very close to getting into a deep  discussion about quantum computing, with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daniel_Lidar" target="_blank">David Lidar</a>, director  of the Center for Quantum Information Science and Technology at UCS,  tantalisingly opening his laptop and cueing up some data to show us,  but sadly, we ran out time.</div><div><br /><b>Redesigning National Security</b></div><div><br /></div><div>SciFoo took place right at the moment where the Edward Snowden  saga was at the forefront of everyone's minds, with the revelations of  the existence of PRISM and the possible role of technology companies  in supplying data to the NSA, causing widespread anger and mistrust.  So the last thing I really expected to be doing was taking part in  discussion about redesigning national security, post-PRISM. At Google.  Lead by two national security analysts.&nbsp; The session, "How  can citizens lead and redesign 21st century national security?"  was lead by<b> </b><a href="http://ise.gov/users/david-bray" target="_blank"><b>David Bray</b></a>, Senior Executive with the U.S.  Government, and<b> Jean-Louis Tiernan</b>, Director-general of the  academic outreach program of the Canadian Security Intelligence  Service.&nbsp;&nbsp; Bray's set-up for the session was: "your  smartphone is equivalent to a military supercomputer from the early  1980s. We've already seen citizen-led endeavours assist with crisis  response. Maybe the same can be done for "natural security".  What information would you be willing to share at a public event as  collected from your smartphone, if it meant you were part of a  citizen-led endeavour to ensure collective security at an event (eg.  next year's Boston marathon?)."</div><div><br />The session was well attended, by a large number of Google employees,  physicists, bioinformatics experts and others, and as you'd expect,  the discussion was at times heated.&nbsp; The notion of 'computational  justice' was debated at length, with one contributor, who will remain  anonymous admitting, "I've worked within the intelligence  community most of my life. I've been both a perpetrator and a victim  of computational excess."<b> <a href="http://www.sanger.ac.uk/research/faculty/thubbard/" target="_blank">Tim Hubbard</a></b>, one of the key  members of the UK's Human Genome Project, contributed some extremely  welcome interjections about the ethics of the security industry  engaging in large-scale acts of invasions of privacy. A highlight of  the session was the comic intervention from<b> <a href="http://www.shuttleworthfoundation.org/fellows/francois-grey/" target="_blank">Francois Grey</a></b>  (coordinator of the Citizen Cyberscience Centre at CERN and Citizen  Science Advisor at Tsinghua University in Beijing), who at a strategic  point close to the end stood up and said, "I work in Beijing and  therefore here I represent China, and I'd like to give you both these  Chinese USB keys to plug into your computers", and handed both  security analysts a USB stick, to much mirth and giggles.</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="284" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5897884399252310658" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-n5M0BYKo2A0/Udl-nN_AioI/AAAAAAAAAeo/E1uKECNrDM0/s400/blackrain-720668.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><i>Black  Rain</i> by Semiconductor, discussed in the Art and Science  session, SciFoo, June 2013. Image © Semiconductor.</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br /></div><div><b>Art and Science</b></div><div><br /></div><div>Next up was our Art and Science session, led by <a href="http://sarahendren.net/about/" target="_blank"><b>Sara Hendron</b></a>, who's a fellow at the  MetaLAB at Harvard, and manager of the <a href="http://ablersite.org/" target="_blank">Abler</a> website.&nbsp; Sara wanted us to consider what artists  and designers have to offer to scientific researchers, and vice  versa.&nbsp; The intention was to explore models for collaborative  research that go beyond buzzwords like "design thinking" and  beyond the "artist-in-residence," short-term-affiliation  model.</div><div><br /></div><div>The session began with a presentation from<b> Selene Foster</b>  and<b> Christopher Reiger</b>, about <a href="http://www.baasics.com/" target="_blank">BAASICS</a> (Bay Area Art &amp;  Science Interdisciplinary Collaborative Sessions), a non-profit organisation that brings  together regional visual artists, scientists, choreographers, and  composers in performances, which explore themes such as mental  disorder and human-animal interactions.</div><div><br /></div><div>I then gave a short talk about the notion of <i>Science As Culture</i>,  emphasising the point that the most successful art and science  projects cultivate a positive feedback loop, in which works of art  lead to new scientific experiments, which lead to new works of art,  etc.&nbsp; I presented a series of projects that my organisation,<b> <a href="http://www.lighthouse.org.uk/" target="_blank"> Lighthouse</a></b> has been involved with,  including work by Brighton-based artists,<b> Semiconductor</b>, who  make stunning digital films and installations, which utilise research  and data from facilities like NASA's Space Sciences Lab, or the  orbiting STEREO satellite.<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><object class="BLOGGER-youtube-video" classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0" data-thumbnail-src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/XxBRKfU2DEM/0.jpg" height="266" width="320"><param name="movie" value="http://youtube.googleapis.com/v/XxBRKfU2DEM&source=uds" /><param name="bgcolor" value="#FFFFFF" /><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><embed width="320" height="266"  src="http://youtube.googleapis.com/v/XxBRKfU2DEM&source=uds" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></div></div><div></div><div><br />I focused on <a href="http://www.lighthouse.org.uk/programme/semiconductor-20-hz" target="_blank"><i>20Hz</i></a>, which  Lighthouse co-commissioned, a depiction of a magnetic storm happening  in the Earth's upper atmosphere, caused by the Sun's interaction  with our ionosphere.&nbsp; The sound you hear is VLF waves, captured  by a Canadian facility called CARISMA, and converted into audio.&nbsp;  Semiconductor have visualised this sound as vibrating particles. So we  can hear and see the Sun interacting with Earth.</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="266" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5897884408032484802" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-JbbGvTygzAI/Udl-nusXXcI/AAAAAAAAAe0/Uay8FsN7Ud0/s400/lablife-722527.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><i>Laboratory  Life</i> at Lighthouse, February 2011 (from left, Janine Fenton,  Margaret Walsh, Kuai Shen). Image courtesy of Lighthouse.</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br /></div><div>I talked a bit about<i> <a href="http://www.lighthouse.org.uk/programme/laboratory-life" target="_blank">Laboratory Life</a></i>, for which we  transformed our arts venue into a biotech laboratory, populated by 21  doctors, engineers and artists, who worked in collaborative teams for  two weeks. The teams cultivated bacteria in giant agar dishes, bred  fruit-flies for astrobiological purposes, and attempted to tattoo DNA.  The public could visit the lab and watch the work happen. Science in  action had become a cultural process.</div><div><br />I also showed<b> Conrad Shawcross</b>' gorgeous kinetic evocation  of string theory,<i> Loop System Quartet</i>:</div><div><br /></div><div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><object class="BLOGGER-youtube-video" classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0" data-thumbnail-src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/wcR-WMuC7Zo/0.jpg" height="266" width="320"><param name="movie" value="http://youtube.googleapis.com/v/wcR-WMuC7Zo&source=uds" /><param name="bgcolor" value="#FFFFFF" /><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><embed width="320" height="266"  src="http://youtube.googleapis.com/v/wcR-WMuC7Zo&source=uds" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></div><br /></div><div><br /></div><div>And finished with a series of works by UK-artist,<b> <a href="http://www.katiepaterson.org/" target="_blank">Katie  Paterson</a></b>, including<i> Ancient  Darkness TV</i>. Working with astronomers from the Mauna Kea  Observatory in Hawaii, Paterson sourced an image of 'ancient  darkness' and transmitted it on New York television station for one  minute in 2009. It revealed darkness from the furthest point of the  observed universe, 13.2 billion years ago, not too long after the Big  Bang, and long, long before Earth existed.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-CzAvauf3Z-g/UdmDBaakVaI/AAAAAAAAAgs/vQ_ixeflSas/s1600/ancientdarkness.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="303" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-CzAvauf3Z-g/UdmDBaakVaI/AAAAAAAAAgs/vQ_ixeflSas/s400/ancientdarkness.jpg" title="" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><i>Ancient Darkness TV</i> by Katie Paterson. Image © the artist. </td></tr></tbody></table><br />Paterson's work  expresses a fascination with how we can look back in time through  telescopes, to a point before the earth existed. She is intrigued  by the fact that there is never a way to directly observe what is  going on in the deep universe right now this moment. We can only look  into the past.</div><div><br />The discussion after the presentation was extremely engaged, lively  and thoughtful. I was particularly grateful for the contributions from <b> Lee Smolin</b>, who knows Katie's work well, and <b><a href="http://www.projectnoah.org/users/Yasser" target="_blank">Yasser Ansari</a></b> (founder of  Project Noah), who made some  inspiring remarks about the transformative potential of art, within  the session. Sara Hendron has also <a href="http://ablersite.org/2013/07/05/bodies-at-work/" target="_blank">written the session up beautifully over  at her blog</a>.</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="300" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5897884416337839202" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/--ZLiK_ofkCY/Udl-oNohBGI/AAAAAAAAAfA/Z0rhmMJ0pNw/s400/BNbI96uCYAA8Fgb-724402.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Michael  Chorost, trying out Google Glass, SciFoo, June 2013. Image courtesy of  Chorost</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><b><br /></b></div><div><b>Living with a Cochlear Implant</b></div><div><br /><a href="http://www.michaelchorost.com/" target="_blank"><b>Michael Chorost</b> </a>led a great session on what it is like to live  with a cochlear implant. This has been nicely reviewed by angel  investor,<b> Esther Dyson</b>, over at <a href="http://www.edge.org/event/ask-a-scifoo-question" target="_blank">the Edge</a>, so I'll let her  words sum it up:<br />"The most wonderful session I attended - and  the most meaningful experience overall - was Michael Chorost talking  about his own cochlear implant. He told us how it worked, played  recordings so we could get some sense of how things sound to people  who have an implant.&nbsp; He passed some samples around the room for  us to touch and examine. We talked about learning to hear - and how  there's a point in childhood after which it gets harder and harder to  learn. We got an understanding of the technology, and also of how the  technology changes both individual lives and cultural norms-such as  sign language, which may become the language of the poor deaf as the  rich deaf start using cochlear implants."</div><div><br /><br /><b>And everything is possible again</b></div><div><br />We then moved swiftly on to the first of SciFoo's string of utterly  brilliant cosmology sessions.&nbsp; SciFoo this year was attended by  not one, but two, of the 2011 Nobel Physics Laureates -<b> <a href="http://www.mso.anu.edu.au/~brian/" target="_blank">Brian  Schmidt</a></b>, head of the Supernova  Search Team at ANU in Australia, and<b> <a href="http://panisse.lbl.gov/public/sauldir/saulhome.html" target="_blank">Saul Perlmutter</a></b><a href="http://panisse.lbl.gov/public/sauldir/saulhome.html" target="_blank">,</a> head of the  Supernova Cosmology Project at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory.  Studying several dozen supernovae, they discovered that the Universe  is expanding at an ever-accelerating rate, a discovery which came as a  complete surprise, even to the Laureates themselves. In one of the  more poetic Nobel statements of recent years, the Nobel Committee  concluded <a href="http://www.nobelprize.org/nobel_prizes/physics/laureates/2011/press.html" target="_blank">their announcement of the award</a> by noting:<i>&nbsp;</i><br /><br /><i>"The findings of the 2011 Nobel Laureates in Physics have  helped to unveil a Universe that to a large extent is unknown to  science. And everything is possible again."</i></div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="268" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5897884425489688178" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-MfIoAA88C6c/Udl-ovufJnI/AAAAAAAAAfI/BNFv_bRQcP8/s400/CosmicSparring-SaulBrian-CosVariance-726718.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><div>Brian Schmidt (left) and Saul Perlmutter (right) - Photo courtesy of  MIT</div></td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br /></div><div>Schmidt and Perlmutter teamed up again for SciFoo, and brought in  fellow cosmologists,<b> <a href="http://excursionset.com/" target="_blank">Richard Easther</a></b>, a fellow kiwi, who's head of Physics at  the University of Auckland in New Zealand, and<b> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_J._Steinhardt" target="_blank">Paul Steinhardt</a></b>, Albert Einstein  Professor of Science at Princeton University, to lead a 'state of  play' session on cosmology. The atmosphere in the room was electric.  The attendees included several major names within cosmology and  physics, including<b> Paul Davies, Lee Smolin</b> and<b> Caleb  Scharf</b>, and well as many non-specialists, including biochemist and  fellow Nobelist,<b> Kary Mullis</b>.<br /><br />Schmidt and Perlmutter led a  well-paced narrative explaining recent developments of cosmological  theory, starting with the consensus view that the universe began some  13.8 billion years ago with the Big Bang, and thanks to their work, is  now found to be expanding at an ever-accelerating rate, presumably due  to what we now refer to as dark energy. Easther then contributed an  excellent, clear explanation of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inflation_%28cosmology%29" target="_blank">the theory of inflation</a>, which  provides an explanation for the homogeneity and geometry of the  universe and the origin of galaxies.<br /><br />It's not often one is in a position to hear someone say,  "and we have one of the major contributors to the theory of  inflation in the room with us today", but that's SciFoo in a  nutshell.&nbsp; Thus Easther introduced<b> </b><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_J._Steinhardt" target="_blank">Paul Steinhardt</a> who  established his reputation in physics working on the theory of  inflation in the 1980s.&nbsp; As such, within the physics community,  it has caused quite some controversy that it is Steinhardt himself who  is now one of the most vocal critics of the theory.&nbsp; He gave a  lucid account of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inflation_%28cosmology%29#Criticisms" target="_blank">the unresolved issues  </a>that inflation gives rise to, and the conundrums which physicists have  yet to be able to explain, most particularly <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiverse" target="_blank">the multiverse problem</a>. Steinhardt in the past has  described the multiverse as, <a href="http://seedmagazine.com/content/article/the_multiverse_problem/" target="_blank">"a dangerous idea that I am simply  unwilling to contemplate"</a>.</div><div><br />One of my nicest SciFoo moments was being able to ask Steinhardt to  introduce his explanation for how the universe originated, which does  away with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiverse" target="_blank">the multiverse problem</a>. This of course leads us squarely to  the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ekpyrotic_universe" target="_blank">ekpyrotic</a>, or cyclic, models of cosmology, for which Steinhardt is  one of the leading advocates. The cyclic theory of the universe is a  radical extension of Big Bang cosmology, in which the evolution of the  universe is periodic and the key events shaping the large scale  structure of the universe occur before the Big Bang. Steinhardt set  out the cyclic theory, paying particular attention to one of my  favourite variants, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Bounce" target="_blank">the Big Bounce</a>.<br /><br />Having basic cosmology explained by the people who actually wrote it  was pretty special.<br />&nbsp; </div><div><b>Noise, Strings and Glissandi</b></div><div><br />After dinner it was time for my <b>Sound in Science</b> session.&nbsp; In  this, I asked how can hearing a star, a quark, or even the Higgs boson  might help us understand these phenomena better? What can listening to  scientific data tell us that looking can not? Can experiencing  scientific events as sound give us a more intuitive understanding of  the data? The session proposed to explore the way that both scientists  and artists are working in hand in hand to give us auditory encounters  with some of the most fascinating scientific research being undertaken  today, Just as the cartographers of the past worked hand-in-hand with  artists who illustrated and interpreted the new worlds they  discovered, our Universe, on the smallest and largest scales, is being  visualised and sonified by artists and musicians today. As the Nobel  Physics Laureate, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mark-ballora/sound-the-music-universe_b_2745188.html" target="_blank">George Smoot III has said, if</a> - as Kepler and  Pythagorus - suggested, "the universe is, at some level, music, then  it seems only natural that we should study it with musical tools of  thinking." Spanning radio astronomy, helioseismology, and  nanotechnology, this session featured everything from the real music  of the spheres, to the sounds of the charismatic mini-fauna of the  quantum world.<br /><br />I began by giving an overview about how we can sonify radio signals  from astronomical sources to effectively 'listen to space', something  I've spoken about before:<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><object class="BLOGGER-youtube-video" classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0" data-thumbnail-src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/mAAxykQH0Wo/0.jpg" height="266" width="320"><param name="movie" value="http://youtube.googleapis.com/v/mAAxykQH0Wo&source=uds" /><param name="bgcolor" value="#FFFFFF" /><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><embed width="320" height="266"  src="http://youtube.googleapis.com/v/mAAxykQH0Wo&source=uds" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></div></div><div><br />I also talked about UK artists,<b> <a href="http://www.devine.co.uk/linernotes/5-minute-oscillations-of-the-sun" target="_blank">Caroline Devine</a></b>, who's recent work,<i> 5  Minute Oscillations of the Sun</i>  uses the sound waves we can detect through helioseismology, a field of  astrophysics that which studies the sound waves which resonate through  the blazing hot gases of the Sun. Devine worked with a research  facility called <a href="http://bison.ph.bham.ac.uk/index.php?page=bison" target="_blank">BiSON</a> based at the School of Physics and Astronomy at  the University of Birmingham. BiSON operates a network of six remote  solar observatories which generate data which Devine used within her  work. Devine took the data and "sped up" the frequencies one  million times so that they corresponded with the human hearing  frequency range. She made tones at those frequencies with a tone  generator. All the overtones that can be heard within the piece relate  to natural resonances present within the sun's interior.</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="300" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5897884430931166946" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-7U5BYHBYcNg/Udl-pD_1huI/AAAAAAAAAfU/MNmLGVER5tk/s400/lucianne-727918.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Lucianne Walkowicz</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br /></div><div>Astrophysicist,<b> <a href="http://tangledfields.com/" target="_blank">Lucianne Walkowicz</a></b>, then outlined a slightly different, but  related, approach to listening to stars. Walkowicz is a member of  NASA's Kepler Mission, which <a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/news/national/nasa-kepler-telescope-malfunctions-threatening-space-mission-article-1.1345087" target="_blank">until it's recent troubles</a>, was the  astronomical community's key planet-hunting tool.&nbsp; But Walkowicz  is also an artist, and uses the data she collects from the Kepler  satellite to create compositions. She takes data and searches for  which frequencies are present at different times, then scales them to  frequencies the human ear can hear, using a sine-wave generator. She  then creates tones that change with time to represent how the  frequencies in the star are changing.&nbsp; She explains her process  in detail, and presents samples of her compositions in this piece  here, for <a href="http://blog.ted.com/2013/03/08/rhythms-of-starlight-melodies-of-astrophysics-fellows-friday-with-lucianne-walkowicz/" target="_blank">TED</a>.</div><div><br /></div><div>One of the magical things about SciFoo is the conversations that  happen serendipitously during breaks, or on the Google bus that took  us from the hotel to the Googleplex. I had one such discussion  with<b> <a href="http://www.its.caltech.edu/~jnawroth/" target="_blank">Janna Nawroth</a></b>, the  creator of this extraordinary nano-scale, jellyfish:</div><div><br /></div><div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><object class="BLOGGER-youtube-video" classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0" data-thumbnail-src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/2spbFpzyiJ0/0.jpg" height="266" width="320"><param name="movie" value="http://youtube.googleapis.com/v/2spbFpzyiJ0&source=uds" /><param name="bgcolor" value="#FFFFFF" /><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><embed width="320" height="266"  src="http://youtube.googleapis.com/v/2spbFpzyiJ0&source=uds" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></div><br /></div><div><br /></div><div>She spoke about the role of sound in neuroscience research. It  was such a fascinating tale that I asked her to recount for our  session. Here it is again, in her own words.</div><div><br />"Audio monitoring can be used in intracellular recordings within neuroscience.  Here, a researcher attempts to penetrate, or break via suction, a  nerve cell within a tissue using a microelectrode, so that the  transmembrane voltage (voltage difference between inside and outside  of cell) can be measured. Rapid changes of the transmembrane voltage  are known as action potentials or neuronal firing and serve for  signalling information in the brain. It is a major challenge to both  get the electrode near/into the cell and make sure the cell is  healthy. Both can be aided by the nature of current or voltage signals  measured between electrode tip and a reference electrode in the tissue  bath. The amplitude of the electrical signal depends on tissue  resistance and varies as the tip approaches a cell (which represents  high electrical resistance). Thus, by converting signal amplitude into  an audio pitch, the investigator can hear when a cell is approached.  The signal changes again when the cell is penetrated or when the  electrode connects to it via a membrane seal. Once continuous with the  intracellular compartment, the electrode will register action  potentials, which can be heard as a "click" sound. Frequency  and distribution of those spikes can be used as indicators for cell  type, health and physiological state."&nbsp; <br /><br />"Audio can also assist  *extracellular recordings*. Here, basically a wire is stuck into the  tissue to pick up action potentials generated in the surrounding of  the wire. Oftentimes signals from several neurons&nbsp; can be picked  up, giving an idea of global neuronal activity in the tissue. These  signals are much weaker than those recorded from inside a cell and  don't allow for the same degree of analysis; however, they allow to  see more than one cell at a time. These signals can be converted into  audible clicks. During the session we listened to the click sounds of  extracellular recordings of the brain. They were artificially  modulated in pitch to indicate the firing of individual  neurons."<br /><br />Nawroth also showed how neuronal activity can be <a href="http://cns.iaf.cnrs-gif.fr/alain_music.html" target="_blank">sonified through  music</a>.&nbsp; It was a  fascinating contrast with the work Lucianne and I presented.<br /><br />Last up was <b><a href="http://www.nano.biu.ac.il/index.aspx?id=3400&amp;itemID=5532" target="_blank">Ido Bachelet</a></b> from the Institute for Nanotechnology  and Advanced Materials, Bar-Ilan University in Israel. As well as  working in biotech, Bachelet describes himself as "a composer of  music for piano and molecules". He gave a remarkable account of  how DNA sequences could be used to generate music. This TEDMED talk  gives a great overview of his work and his approach to working with  nano-materials:</div><div><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><object class="BLOGGER-youtube-video" classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0" data-thumbnail-src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/-5KLTonB3Pg/0.jpg" height="266" width="320"><param name="movie" value="http://youtube.googleapis.com/v/-5KLTonB3Pg&source=uds" /><param name="bgcolor" value="#FFFFFF" /><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><embed width="320" height="266"  src="http://youtube.googleapis.com/v/-5KLTonB3Pg&source=uds" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object></div></div><div><br />After an an amazing evening of conversations, and a brief sleep, it  was straight back into the fray the following day.</div><div><br /><b>Temporal Naturalism</b><br /><br />My day started with two fascinating cosmology and philosophy  sessions, both of which explored the nature of time.&nbsp; The first  was entitled 'Temporal Naturalism', and was lead by theoretical  physicist,<b> <a href="http://leesmolin.com/" target="_blank">Lee Smolin</a></b>, who has  recently published the controversial book,<i> <a href="http://leesmolin.com/writings/time-reborn/" target="_blank">Time Reborn</a></i>.</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="266" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5897884440969588610" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-NcrCcJTJ72s/Udl-ppZLr4I/AAAAAAAAAfk/8ywXOqGlCGs/s400/Lee_Smolin-730180.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><div>Lee Smolin, photographed at SciFoo, Google, June 2013. Photograph  courtesy of Edge.</div></td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br /></div><div>He was joined by philosophers,<b> Adina Roskies</b> and<b> Fiery  Cushman</b>, for a session which attempted to build a somewhat  unlikely bridge between between cosmological theories of time and the  philosophy of mind.&nbsp; Smolin's introduction to the session asked,  "can we have a temporal naturalism in which laws evolve and the  future is to some extent open? Does naturalism commit us to the strong  AI hypothesis or could we come to understand qualia as real and the  brain as a physical system that is, however, not isomorphic to a  digital computer running an algorithm?"</div><div><br /></div><div>My early academic training was in philosophy of mind, so I was  fascinated to see <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Qualia" target="_blank">qualia</a> - a term which refers to individual instances  of subjective, conscious experience, the "what it's like"  of, for example, redness or pain - pop up in this context. I was  intrigued to understand how qualia could possibly relate to notions of  cosmological time, so I attended this session with great interest.&nbsp;  As did physicists<b> Paul Steinhardt</b>,<b> Saul Perlmutter</b>,  and<b> Andrea Morello</b>, as well as a smattering of others.&nbsp;  Smolin began by setting out the philosophical framework by which we  could discuss this unusual idea, and outlined two conceptions of  time:<br /><br />i) Timeless Naturalism<br />This is the orthodox view within physics, whereby the experience of  time is an illusion. As Einstein noted, "the distinction between  the past, present and future is only a stubbornly persistent  illusion." The fundamental description of the world is in the  subatomic world, and as Andrea Morello notes, "quantum mechanics  is completely deterministic. Up until the measurement".&nbsp; As  quantum mechanics is deterministic, the future is entirely  predictable, and therefore the notion of time is redundant. If you  know the laws of physics, you can understand history, and to a certain  extent, predict the future.&nbsp; The problem as Smolin sees it, is  that the present moment, qualia, and free will, have trouble fitting  into this conception of the world. So Smolin proposes an  alternative:<br /><br />ii) Temporal naturalism<br />In this view, what is real is the present moment. Some things persist,  but what is really real, exists in the present. There is no place for  laws of nature that contradict the notion of the present. Among the  things which exist in the present are records of past observations.  The past is a sequence of 'present moments'. He asked:<br />- is it cogent to have a naturalism that is 'presentist'?<br />- does this make it possible for a philosophy of mind where <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Qualia" target="_blank">qualia</a> are  properly real, as argued by philosophers, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thomas_Nagel" target="_blank">Thomas Nagel</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galen_Strawson" target="_blank">Galen Strawson</a>?<br />- can there be a view of naturalism where <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Qualia" target="_blank">qualia</a> are as real as  electrons?</div><div><br />And so ensued a fascinating discussion which immediately began  with expressions of skepticism by the assembled physicists, who  couldn't understand how qualia could possibly pose such a major  problem.<br /><br />The two standard arguments which are used by  philosophers to try and convey the problem of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Qualia" target="_blank">qualia</a> are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Qualia#The_zombie_argument" target="_blank">the zombie  argument </a> and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge_argument" target="_blank">Knowledge argument, </a>developed by Frank Jackson.&nbsp; Adina Roskies did  her best to try and convince the physicists with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Qualia#The_zombie_argument" target="_blank">the zombie  argument </a>,  but to be honest, I think we probably needed to deploy the famous  <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge_argument#Thought_experiment" target="_blank">thought experiment from the Knowledge argument</a>.  My artistic group, <a href="http://radioqualia.va.com.au/illata/" target="_blank">r a d i o q u a l i a, did a project about this in 1998</a>, so I'm quite fond of it.<br /><br />To  further the Knowledge argument, Jackson <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knowledge_argument#Thought_experiment" target="_blank">invented a fictitious  character called "Mary"</a>, a colour scientist who was  imprisoned in a black and white room.&nbsp; Raised from birth in the  black and white room, Mary lacks any knowledge of 'what it is like' to  have experiences of colour. But she is a brilliant colour scientist  who knows everything there is to know about the science of colour. She  has just never experienced it. Once she leaves her black and white  room, and experiences colour for the first time, does she learn  anything new?&nbsp; Does her first encounter with "redness"  give her any new information about red? If it does, then there is some  knowledge about human colour vision she did not have prior to her  experience of it, and therefore, not all knowledge is physical  knowledge.&nbsp; The thought experiment, was conceived to elucidate  the Knowledge Argument, a rebuttal against 'physicalism', the  philosophical view that all factual knowledge can be formulated as a  statement about physical objects and activities. The Knowledge  argument states that physicalism is false on the ground that there  exist facts that cannot be known solely in virtue of knowing all the  physical facts. That is, experiences of colour, pain or happiness  (qualia), can not be known simply by possessing physical facts about  these properties.</div><div><br /></div><div>Even if an adequate explanation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Qualia" target="_blank">qualia</a> been provided,  Steinhardt and Perlmutter weren't having any of it. Steinhardt took  the traditional skeptical view that the problem of qualia will be  solved when we obtain more knowledge of the processes which occur in  the brain.&nbsp; The standard physicalist rebuttal is that <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Qualia" target="_blank">qualia</a>  don't pose a deep philosophical problem; we just lack adequate  explanatory data at the moment. Steinhardt went as far as saying that  qualia are "a parochial problem of biology that can't possibly  effect the laws of nature."</div><div><br />A debate about how this could relate to cosmological time ensued, in  which Smolin frequently expressed astonishment that his colleagues  from physics found it so hard to accept that qualia create a  fundamental challenge to the traditional view in physics that time,  inseparable from space, doesn't exist as an independent aspect of  reality.&nbsp; I think Smolin's view is that if <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Qualia" target="_blank">qualia</a> are really  real, they reveal a fundamental truth about time, which is that there  is a present. And if there's a present, then time exists as a  fundamental aspect of reality, independent of space.&nbsp; This is an  idea, Smolin writes about at length in <i><a href="http://leesmolin.com/writings/time-reborn/" target="_blank">Time Reborn</a></i>, and an idea we  returned to in the next session.<br /><br /></div><div><b>Time Before the Big Bang</b></div><div><br /></div><div>In the "Time Before the Big Bang" session,<b>  Smolin</b> and<b> Steinhardt</b> set aside their differences to delve  deeper into the ideas Steinhardt introduced in the previous day's  cosmology session.</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="266" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5897884450807071410" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-dzPqw2-eEtY/Udl-qOCnwrI/AAAAAAAAAfw/kUork2DMRfM/s400/Paul_Steinhardt-732252.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><div>Paul Steinhardt, photographed at SciFoo, Google, June 2013.  Photograph courtesy of Edge.</div></td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br /></div><div>Once again, the room was packed with a combination of experts,  including<b> Paul Davies</b> and<b> Richard Easther</b>, and curious  onlookers. Steinhardt began by further explaining why he's currently  advocating for a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Bounce" target="_blank">Big Bounce cosmology</a>, in which 'bangs' happens  cyclically, and therefore time exists before what we have come to  refer to as the Big Bang.&nbsp; He started out by outlining that  present orthodox views of the universe, including <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inflation_%28cosmology%29" target="_blank">the theory of inflation</a> lead to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiverse" target="_blank">the multiverse problem</a>. He contended that there  are three basic responses from the cosmology community to the  multiverse problem:</div><div><br />i) I don't care<br />ii) Something will come along to solve it<br />iii) There's flaw with our models, and we need to look at other  ideas<br /><br />Steinhardt places himself in the third category. The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Bounce" target="_blank">Big Bounce</a> theory  enables for the flattening and smoothing of spacetime, which we see in  observational data, to occur over time periods far greater than Big  Bang cosmology. He reminded us that the Big Bang is of course a  radical idea, because it is a violation of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unitarity_%28physics%29" target="_blank">unitarity</a>.&nbsp; The Big  Bounce enables us to connect the late history of the universe with its  early history.&nbsp; In the Big Bounce, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dark_energy">dark energy</a> plays a key role  in setting up the cycles. It drives each bounce, and then decays.&nbsp;  It is reminiscent of the idea of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eternal_inflation" target="_blank">Eternal Inflation</a>. But for a theory to  work, it must be <a href="http://is.gd/geodesiccompleteness" target="_blank">'geodesically complete'.</a> To put it simply, it has to have  a beginning as well as an end. Steinhardt contends that inflation is  'geodesically incomplete' because it doesn't adequately describe a  beginning.&nbsp; <b>Paul Davies</b> noted that the Big Bounce Theory seems  remarkably like the old <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steady_State_theory" target="_blank">Steady State Theory</a>, the prevalent view  before evidence of the Big Bang was discovered in 1964. Steinhardt  (somewhat surprisingly) agreed that it is an articulated and evolved theory that builds on the  Steady State Theory and takes it in new directions.<br /><br />Smolin picked up this by reminding the room that there are thirty  parameters in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Standard_Model" target="_blank">the Standard Model</a> - our best explanation  for the formation of matter in the universe - which have been added  "by hand" so that theory agrees with experiment.&nbsp; This,  Smolin contends, is suggestive of fundamental flaws in the model.&nbsp;  It should be noted that most physicists would contend that, as Richard  Easther puts it, "the parameters are not added 'by hand'  - they are things like the masses of fundamental particles, which  typically have finite, non-zero values. So the numbers exist if the  particles exist."&nbsp; But back to the session: Smolin contended that<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/String_theory" target="_blank"> string theory</a> has failed  because of its infinite variations, so we now need a new theory which  explains what happened, which is testable.&nbsp; So far, so  familiar.</div><div><br />Smolin then outlined his radical theory of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lee_Smolin#Cosmological_natural_selection" target="_blank">Cosmological natural  selection</a>. Can we use the notion of natural selection - Darwin's big  idea - in cosmology?&nbsp; Is a process analogous to biological natural  selection occurring at larger scales?&nbsp; And if so, could the laws  of physics themselves by subject to evolution? Have the laws of  physics evolved over time? There's no evidence that there's been any  evolution in the laws of physics since the Big Bang. So, if evolution  has taken place, it must have done so in time before the Big Bang.&nbsp;  Smolin then deepened the analogy with population biology, by stating  that "reproduction" on a cosmological scale takes place  through the Big Bounces Steinhardt had outlined.<br /><br />Smolin's theory  - outlined in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Life_of_the_Cosmos" target="_blank"><i>The Life of the Cosmos</i></a>, states that new  universes are born when black holes forms in our universe. A  collapsing black hole causes the emergence of a new universe on the  "other side". Each universe thus gives rise to as many new  universes as it has black holes. The genes within cosmological natural  selection, are the types of matter explained in the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Standard_Model" target="_blank">Standard Model</a>.<br /><br />This line of thinking provoked heated discussion within the room, and some visible  discomfort from some of the physicists, notably, Easther. It is an unease,  which it should be said, is probably widely shared.&nbsp; Whilst there  was no resolution by the time we got to the end of the hour, it was a  thoroughly stimulating discussion.</div><div><br />One of the attendees of the cosmology sessions, and perhaps one of the  most popular SciFoo campers, was former CIA analyst,<b> <a href="http://www.deloitte.com/view/en_US/us/Industries/US-federal-government/b5a98204b7085310VgnVCM1000001a56f00aRCRD.htm" target="_blank">Carmen  Medina</a></b>. She noted afterwards, "<a href="https://twitter.com/milouness/status/349375273243918336" target="_blank">one thing I found quite  reassuring at SciFoo was the general cheerfulness of the  cosmologists</a>".&nbsp;  Publicly, this was very true. The cosmologists were genial, cheery and  warm. But privately, several of them intimated their deep concerns  about the state of play, the enormity of the challenges, and extent of  divisions within the field.&nbsp; One noted, after the Time Before the  Big Bang session, that it may be another hundred years before we  arrive at the next paradigm-changing breakthrough in cosmology.</div><div><br /><br /><b>Serendipity</b><br /><br />It is these kinds of conversations which are the real currency of  SciFoo, and some of the best experiences I had during those intense  three days were in the social sessions, or over dinner and lunch.&nbsp;  Particularly memorable were wonderful discussions with, among others:  futurist, <a href="http://www.saffo.com/" target="_blank">Paul Saffo</a>, NASA rocket scientist, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harold_Sonny_White_%28NASA_Scientist%29" target="_blank">Harold White</a>,&nbsp;  co-founder of the amazing DIYBio lab, <a href="http://biocurious.org/" target="_blank">BioCurious</a>, Raymond McCauley, AI  researcher, <a href="http://ai.stanford.edu/~yonid/" target="_blank">Yoni Donner</a>, and <a href="http://www2.mrc-lmb.cam.ac.uk/group-leaders/n-to-s/john-sutherland/" target="_blank">John Sutherland</a>, who studies the chemical  origins of life.  I also loved spending time with some of the people that I've already  mentioned, including <a href="http://www.astro.princeton.edu/~lucianne/" target="_blank">Lucianne Walkowicz</a>, <a href="http://www.chem.gla.ac.uk/cronin/" target="_blank">Lee Cronin</a>, <a href="http://www.its.caltech.edu/~jnawroth/" target="_blank">Janna Nawroth</a>,  <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/yassera" target="_blank">Yasser Ansari</a>, <a href="http://www.nano.biu.ac.il/index.aspx?id=3400&amp;itemID=5532" target="_blank">Ido Bachelet</a>, and <a href="http://www.sanger.ac.uk/research/faculty/thubbard/" target="_blank">Tim Hubbard</a>. I'm indebted to the  cosmologists, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brian_Schmidt" target="_blank">Brian Schmidt</a>, <a href="http://cosmology.auckland.ac.nz/" target="_blank">Richard Easther</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lee_Smolin" target="_blank">Lee Smolin,</a> for being  so generous with their time, and so open to curious questions from the  laity.</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="300" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5897884457712477010" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-M5VvzI7onRQ/Udl-qnw_41I/AAAAAAAAAf8/FKY3F6_nKu0/s400/digital_science_team-734767.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><div>Some of the folks from Digital Science, co-organisers of SciFoo  2013.</div></td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br /></div><div>Huge kudos too goes to the <a href="http://www.digital-science.com/" target="_blank">Digital Science</a> crew, especially <b>Alan  Hyndman </b>and <b>Jean Liu</b>, for doing such a brilliant job of making sure  the social time that we had together was as fabulous as possible.  Seeing a bunch of immanent scientists enthusiastically tackling 'Hey  Jude' well past midnight at a local dive bar in Sunnyvale was quite  something, and entirely down to Alan and Jean.<b>&nbsp;</b><br /><br /><b>The Googleplex</b></div><div><b><br /></b></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="300" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5897884472280451682" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Vb0jJJdV8A8/Udl-reCRimI/AAAAAAAAAgE/H2-1ODr-Orw/s400/photo%2B68-737273.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Google, SciFoo, June 2013.</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br /></div><div>The environment in which all of this was happening, Google,  obviously deserves to be mentioned. This has been written about at  length by others, notably <a href="http://excursionset.com/blog/2013/6/29/blog-foo" target="_blank">Richard Easther at his blog</a> and <a href="http://blogs.scientificamerican.com/a-blog-around-the-clock/2013/07/04/scifoo-in-pictures/" target="_blank">Bora Zivkovic at  his</a>, so I'll let them articulate just how  strange and wonderful it was to be at the Googleplex.</div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="400" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5897884474756009682" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zO6msDEFQ-M/Udl-rnQfjtI/AAAAAAAAAgQ/9C8bWr9uA3s/s400/sergei-738768.jpg" width="375" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><div>Sergey Brin in Glass, SciFoo, June 2013.</div></td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br /></div><div>I would add that it was distinctly odd being in the same space as so  many people wearing <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Glass" target="_blank">Google Glass</a>. Chief amongst these was<b> Sergey  Brin</b>, co-founder of Google, and inventor of Glass (pictured  above). But there were many Google researchers who wore Glass  continuously throughout SciFoo. Having tackled Google chairman, Eric  Schmidt on the privacy implications of Glass earlier this year on  <a href="http://honorharger.wordpress.com/2013/05/26/starting-the-week-in-the-digital-age/" target="_blank">BBC's Start the Week</a>, it was interesting being in a context where I  got to see the devices being used so widely.&nbsp; I have to say,  seeing people wearing Glass up close didn't make me feel personally  any less queasy about the potential the device has to disrupt and  shape social interactions, something <a href="http://creativegood.com/blog/the-google-glass-feature-no-one-is-talking-about/" target="_blank">Mark Hurst has written cogently  about</a>. It was striking that whilst photography was  banned within the sessions, the Glass-wearers did not remove their  Glasses, nor asked the participants if it was OK that they wore  them, at least during the sessions I attended. There are uncomfortable questions  about what constitutes acceptable social behaviour of the wearers of  Glass, and how they interact with the rest of us, which need to be  debated and discussed before I'd feel relaxed about having this device  widely used within society.<br /><br />But that aside, it should be  stressed that generally-speaking, Google were amazing hosts, offering  us generous hospitality at every turn. All of the Google staff I met  were welcoming, and all had fascinating stories to tell of their own  work and research.</div><div><br /><br /><b>A dozen conferences in one ...</b></div><div><br /></div><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="300" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5897884485619751922" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-TqUMSZs2zUY/Udl-sPunG_I/AAAAAAAAAgg/pFLLtU8_zsE/s400/scifoosession-740137.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">SciFoo session, June 2013.</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><br /></div><div>At the closing session of SciFoo, a handful of volunteers  reported back on their favourite SciFoo experiences. I felt I'd been  to one of the best conference I'd ever been to in my sessions, but in  the reporting back, it became clear that there had been at least ten  parallel conferences taking place, which were all equally compelling.&nbsp;  One of the senior scientists who reported back summed up the mood in  the room, by stating that SciFoo had been the best professional  experience of his entire career.&nbsp; That rang true for many of  us.<br /><br />Huge thanks to <a href="http://www.digital-science.com/" target="_blank">Digital Science</a>, <a href="http://www.nature.com/" target="_blank"> Nature</a>, O'<a href="http://oreilly.com/" target="_blank">Reilly</a> and  Google for their hospitality and for designing such a vivid,  hypnagogic, intellectual ride.</div><br /><div>And everything is possible again.<br /><br /></div><br /><br /><div><br /></div></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/rnIzFRcdPWY" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8f48d3205ff750320b279ca5b97d7dda" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/t3z3eKVJhpI/sea-above-sky-below.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="mobile-photo"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-rZ1j0RjclTw/UHF-Rux2DvI/AAAAAAAAAQY/5omoN-RLLHc/s1600/skybelow-773125.jpg"><img alt="" border="0" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5796553038482509554" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-rZ1j0RjclTw/UHF-Rux2DvI/AAAAAAAAAQY/5omoN-RLLHc/s1600/skybelow-773125.jpg" /></a></div><div><br /><i><b>Sea above, sky below</b></i>.&nbsp; The phrase is seemingly a  contradiction and a mental paradox.&nbsp; Yet recent research into  cosmology, astronomy and oceanography suggests that this riddle is  perhaps not as irreconcilable as what it may first appear. Recalling  <a href="http://www.bartleby.com/4/407.html" target="_blank">Milton's evocation of the empty heavens as a kind of ocean</a>, the  inversion of sea and sky is taking place all around us, in physics and  in oceanography. <br /><br />The most important advances in scientific thought about the  origins and structure of the universe now suggest that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiverse">our world may  be just one amongst</a> many, floating in a <a href="http://ned.ipac.caltech.edu/level5/Jakobsen/Jak4.html" target="_blank">cosmological sea</a>. The space  probe <a href="http://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/cassini/main/index.html" target="_blank">Cassini</a> has revealed that even in the heavens above, <a href="http://science.nasa.gov/science-news/science-at-nasa/2011/26jan_fizzyocean/" target="_blank">oceans may  in fact, be commonplace.</a>&nbsp; Radio astronomers describe the noise storms of  Jupiter and its moon Io as sounding like <a href="http://radiojove.gsfc.nasa.gov/help/faq1.htm#B2" target="_blank">ocean waves breaking up on  the beach</a>. And here on the firmament we are increasingly turning to  the oceans in order to better understand the skies. <br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.almaobservatory.org/"><img alt="" border="0" height="211" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5796553043684944962" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-SPu3e0zwvoU/UHF-SCKM7EI/AAAAAAAAAQk/ZPBo4OHrOGw/s400/alma-775656.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.almaobservatory.org/">ALMA (the Atacama Large Millimetre/submillimetre Array)</a></td></tr></tbody></table><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><br />After recently watching the documentary, <i><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/iplayer/episode/b013pnv4/Horizon_20112012_Seeing_Stars" target="_blank">Seeing Stars</a></i>, which  analyses the new generation of telescopes that enable scientists and  engineers to do 'extreme astronomy', I was prompted to revisit some  of the unusual techniques which are currently being used to probe the  edges of our universe, which I first starting looking into a few years  ago.<br />The documentary, by the way, is well worth  watching:<br /><br /><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/iDsIGkQvAIw" width="560"></iframe> <br /><div><br />The infant branch of astronomy, known as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neutrino_astronomy" target="_blank">"neutrino  astronomy"</a> is motivated by the possibility of observing  phenomena, such as cosmic neutrinos, that are inaccessible to optical  telescopes.&nbsp; Cosmic neutrinos, which are believed to be produced  by cosmic rays, are very difficult to detect. By building arrays deep  under water, astronomers can make sure that most of the particles they  detect are actually produced by cosmic sources. These detectors look  down through the Earth to see the universe, using the whole planet as  a shield to absorb the riffraff of particles from the  atmosphere.</div><div><br /></div><div><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-XMkO4_rN6SY/UHF-So5kz5I/AAAAAAAAAQw/Fi42mIZGTgo/s1600/pascale-778322.jpg"><img alt="" border="0" height="216" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5796553054084190098" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-XMkO4_rN6SY/UHF-So5kz5I/AAAAAAAAAQw/Fi42mIZGTgo/s400/pascale-778322.jpg" width="400" /></a><br /><br />One of the leading voices within oceanic neutrino science is <b>Dr  Paschal Coyle</b> (pictured), who is based in Marseille in France.&nbsp; His 2007 Journal of Physics paper, <a href="http://www.iop.org/EJ/article/1742-6596/60/1/007/jpconf7_60_007.pdf?request-id=4e5329ee-aaba-44d4-ab77-f5c7502b5cc6" target="_blank"><i>Neutrinos Out of the (Deep) Blue</i></a> remains a  valuable reference in surveying the various approaches to underwater  neutrino observation.<br /><br />He is a key researcher with the <a href="http://antares.in2p3.fr/Overview/index.html" target="_blank">ANTARES</a> observatory, which is situated under  the Mediterranean Sea, 42km off the coast of Toulon. His team set out to monitor their below-sea telescope in the brilliantly named research vessel, <i>Pourquoi Pas?</i>.</div><div><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="257" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5796553063245931266" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-J3sFjzMzScY/UHF-TLB54wI/AAAAAAAAAQ8/cbnor8ThvRY/s400/pourquois1-779829.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">ANTARES research vessel, <i>Pourquois Pas?</i></td></tr></tbody></table><br /></div><div><a href="http://antares.in2p3.fr/Overview/index.html" target="_blank">ANTARES</a> stands for <b>"A</b>stronomy with a <b>N</b>eutrino <b>T</b>elescope and <b>A</b>byss  environmental <b>RES</b>each project", a rather clunkily assembled acronym,  but one that figuratively at least, situates one of our most  charismatic stars - <b>Antares</b> - deep under the sea.</div><div><br /></div><div>The <a href="http://antares.in2p3.fr/Overview/index.html" target="_blank">ANTARES</a> detector comprises a total of 900 optical modules  distributed over 12 flexible lines, each comprising 25 storeys.&nbsp;  They are anchored at the bottom of the sea at a depth of about 2.5 km,  approximately 70 meters apart from each other.</div><br /><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="266" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5796553072998373490" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-OKryBdMeZGM/UHF-TvXEWHI/AAAAAAAAARI/6OZz_sc2mI8/s400/antares_array-781963.jpg" width="400" /></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Design visualisation of the ANTARES underwater detector modules</td></tr></tbody></table></div><br /><div><a href="http://antares.in2p3.fr/Overview/index.html" target="_blank">ANTARES</a> is designed to detect neutrinos from space, coming from the direction of  the Southern Hemisphere of Earth.&nbsp; As neutrinos have no mass  and no charge, they fly through matter as if it wasn't there, and are  therefore fiendishly difficult to detect.&nbsp; If a cosmic neutrino  collided with Earth in the Southern Hemisphere, say for example in Australia, it would fly through the Earth and exit through the  Mediterranean sea off southern France on it's way back out to space. <a href="http://antares.in2p3.fr/Overview/index.html" target="_blank">ANTARES</a> is constructed with the specific intention of detecting those  elusive neutrinos on their ghostly and perpetual journey.&nbsp;  Occasionally, on its journey, a <a href="http://hyperphysics.phy-astr.gsu.edu/hbase/particles/neutrino2.html#c2" target="_blank">muon neutrino</a> will interact with the water in the Mediterranean. When  this happens, it will produce a high energy muon.</div><div>&nbsp;<a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-b-uLxAqRHaY/UHF-UF9_ONI/AAAAAAAAARU/GXmAq0XZSIM/s1600/Cherenkov-783829.jpg"><img alt="" border="0" height="317" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5796553079067195602" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-b-uLxAqRHaY/UHF-UF9_ONI/AAAAAAAAARU/GXmAq0XZSIM/s400/Cherenkov-783829.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><div><br /><a href="http://antares.in2p3.fr/Overview/index.html" target="_blank">ANTARES</a> works by detecting <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cherenkov_radiation" target="_blank">Cherenkov radiation</a> (pictured) emitted as the muon passes through the water.&nbsp; So <a href="http://antares.in2p3.fr/Overview/index.html" target="_blank">ANTARES</a> is a highly  sensitive optical instrument designed to detect the uncanny blue glow  of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cherenkov_radiation" target="_blank">Cherenkov radiation</a> caused by one of the rarest phenomena in  existence.</div><div><br /><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Vjduh52Sr2I/UHF-UqSbrnI/AAAAAAAAARg/wpu4U4PLVSY/s1600/pourquois3-785831.jpg"><img alt="" border="0" height="255" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5796553088816623218" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Vjduh52Sr2I/UHF-UqSbrnI/AAAAAAAAARg/wpu4U4PLVSY/s400/pourquois3-785831.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><div>Over the past four years, Paschal Coyle and his team, have made many  expeditions to the underwater detector hunting for neutrinos.&nbsp; Whilst they  have detected many neutrinos - consistent with what might be found in the Earth's atmosphere at any one time - they haven't found a single cosmic neutrino. <br /><br />To put it more formally, as the team did in <a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1205.2173" target="_blank">their  May 2012 abstract</a>, "no significant neutrino signal in excess of  that expected from atmospheric background has been found".&nbsp; The team submitted a <a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1207.3105" target="_blank">further  paper to the Astrophysical Journal in July</a>, and in it they emphasised, "no statistically significant signal has been found and upper  limits on the neutrino flux have been obtained." </div><br /><div>Despite this, the search goes on, and <a href="http://antares.in2p3.fr/Overview/index.html" target="_blank">ANTARES</a> has more than one  function. As well as looking for particles of cosmic origin, and thus  being an important part of the astrophysics community, <a href="http://antares.in2p3.fr/Overview/index.html" target="_blank">ANTARES</a> is also  at the forefront of particle physics research, taking part in the  search for <b>dark matter</b>. It complements the dark matter searches  performed by experiments such as Fermilab's <a href="http://ppd.fnal.gov/experiments/cdms/" target="_blank">CDMS</a>, and at <a href="http://dev-press.web.cern.ch/backgrounders/dark-matter" target="_blank">CERN's dark matter work  at the LHC</a>.</div><br /><div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-cTqnHgOr9io/UHF-VfY8MrI/AAAAAAAAARs/9l7UQY-VfRM/s1600/antares_instruments-789376.jpg" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="210" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5796553103070999218" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-cTqnHgOr9io/UHF-VfY8MrI/AAAAAAAAARs/9l7UQY-VfRM/s400/antares_instruments-789376.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">ANTARES instrument panel aboard <i>Pourquois Pas?</i></td></tr></tbody></table></div><br /><div><a href="http://antares.in2p3.fr/Overview/index.html" target="_blank">ANTARES'</a> contribution to the field is to attempt to detect a  hypothetical phenomena known as <i>"neutralino annihilation"</i>,  which is thought to take place in the Sun, or the centre of our galaxy.&nbsp; The  theoretical particle, the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neutralino" target="_blank">neutralino</a>, is considered a good  candidate for the substance of the universe's <b>cold dark matter</b>. To  confirm its existence, neutrino telescopes, such as <a href="http://antares.in2p3.fr/Overview/index.html" target="_blank">ANTARES</a>, look for  evidence of the annihilation of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neutralino" target="_blank">neutralinos</a> in regions of high dark  matter density such as the centres of stars or galaxies.&nbsp; If <a href="http://antares.in2p3.fr/Overview/index.html" target="_blank">ANTARES</a> was able to detect this speculative phenomena, it would be a major  breakthrough in our understanding of the universe.</div><br /><div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.cosmic-ray.org/"><img alt="" border="0" height="163" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5796553111153743042" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-1yVSZAvkQj8/UHF-V9gBFMI/AAAAAAAAAR4/B6dI1GdrD0U/s400/hires_black_rock_best-790989.jpg" width="400" /></a></div></div><div><br />A new generation of telescopes are analysing our skies in ever  more novel ways: from <a href="http://www.almaobservatory.org/en/about-alma" target="_blank">vast radio arrays in arid desert mountains</a>, to <a href="http://www.nasa.gov/sofia" target="_blank">telescopes strapped  to aircraft soaring into the stratosphere</a>,  to futuristic <a href="http://www.cosmic-ray.org/" target="_blank">Air Fluorescence telescopes looking for high-energy  cosmic rays</a>. At the forefront of these  techniques are telescopes built underwater, searching our skies from  the depths of our oceans.<br /><br />As it looks through the earth to detect neutrinos from space, <a href="http://antares.in2p3.fr/Overview/index.html" target="_blank">ANTARES</a>  is peering at the sky below, from the sea above.<br /><br /><b>Dedication:</b><br /><br /><i>Sea Above, Sky Below</i> is the title of a song by <b>Dirty Three</b>, which  appears on the 1995 album, <i>Ocean Songs</i>. This post is dedicated to Peter Kirk.<br /><br /><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/z6mkjocat84" width="420"></iframe> <br /><br /><b>Sources:</b><br /><a href="http://antares.in2p3.fr/Overview/index.html">http://antares.in2p3.fr/Overview/index.html</a><br /><a href="http://www.iop.org/EJ/article/1742-6596/60/1/007/jpconf7_60_007.pdf?request-id=4e5329ee-aaba-44d4-ab77-f5c7502b5cc6">http://www.iop.org/</a><br /><a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1207.3105">http://arxiv.org/abs/1207.3105</a><br /><br /><br /></div><div><br /></div></div></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/t3z3eKVJhpI" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="dedcbfc6c6df4f376ae1911063c3aece" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/WEnNsbMR7mM/can-particle-physics-transform-our.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="mobile-photo"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-NaB6xxhofgs/UPwdREBSNtI/AAAAAAAAAXc/z219DDt2mO0/s1600/network-743881.jpg"><img alt="" border="0" height="316" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5835571396139431634" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-NaB6xxhofgs/UPwdREBSNtI/AAAAAAAAAXc/z219DDt2mO0/s400/network-743881.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><div class="mobile-photo"><br /></div><br />One of the more intriguing papers we've happened upon early this year is some research from the <a href="http://physics.unifr.ch/" target="_blank">University of Fribourg</a> which suggests that particle physics can improve the technology behind recommendation systems.<br /><br /><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Recommender_system" target="_blank">Recommendation systems</a> are software which websites such as Amazon and Facebook use to tailor information for users. &nbsp;When Amazon, somewhat eerily, suggests that you check out a book by a writer you've been just been thinking about, that's a recommendation system, or "engine", in action. Recommendation engines are at the heart of online business, as the good ones are known to generate profits. &nbsp;Improving them is a key goal for retailers and software companies alike.<br /><br />But what on earth does particle physics have to do with software like that? &nbsp;Well, a group of researchers at the at the <a href="http://physics.unifr.ch/fr/page/91" target="_blank">University of Fribourg in Switzerland</a> believe that the physics which governs the behaviour of photons and electrons may also be used to optimise recommendation engines.<br /><br />Stanislao Gualdi, Matus Medo, and Yi-Cheng Zhang this month published <a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1301.1887" target="_blank">an abstract</a> on <a href="http://arxiv.org/" target="_blank">arXiv</a> entitled, <a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1301.1887" target="_blank">"Crowd Avoidance and Diversity in Socio-Economic Systems and Recommendation"</a>. &nbsp;The paper's key insight is that the problem with recommendation engines is that they can lead to 'overcrowding' around a specific product or service, which can be detrimental to the experience users have with it. &nbsp;Surges in demand can be sometimes advantageous, but if the value of a resource diminishes as more people use it, then this creates a problem. &nbsp;A good example would be a service like Netflix recommending the same movie to too many of its users, thereby creating long waiting times for everyone. Another good example, would be a travel website recommending a beach or a picnic spot because it is quiet. As <a href="http://www.technologyreview.com/view/509861/how-particle-physics-is-improving-recommendation-engines/" target="_blank">Technology Review noted</a> "this can end up destroying the peace that gives it value. Similarly, restaurant recommendations can lead to overcrowding or difficulty getting a table which again makes the dining experience unpleasant."<br /><br />These examples show how over-stimulated demand can reduce the value of a resource. Gualdi, Medo and Zhang set about to tackle this issue. &nbsp;They applied the logic employed in particle physics, where particles tend to occupy the most energetically favourable states.&nbsp;<a href="http://www.technologyreview.com/view/509861/how-particle-physics-is-improving-recommendation-engines/" target="_blank">Technology Review</a>&nbsp;explain:<br />"If the particles are bosons, such as photons, there is no limit to the number that can occupy a given state. But if they are fermions, like electrons, their physical properties dictate that no two can occupy the same state. Clearly the resulting distribution of these different types of particles is entirely different.The analogy here is with goods that any number of people can share or that only one person can have."<br /><br />The latter case - products or experiences that are best experienced by small groups, or even individuals - provides a dilemma for recommendation engines. In order for these things to retain their value, they need to remain available only to limited umbers of people.&nbsp;Gualdi, Medo and Zhang&nbsp;insist that the principle of 'crowd avoidance' needs to be employed to avoid oversubscription, crowding and disappointment.<br /><br />They provide evidence in their paper that building crowd avoidance into the recommendation process can increase the accuracy of the recommendation, and therefore the potential profitability of the recommendation engine. As they put it:<br />"We use real data to show that contrary to expectations, the introduction of these constraints enhances recommendation accuracy and diversity even in systems where overcrowding is not detrimental. The observed accuracy improvements are explained in terms of removing potential bias of the recommendation method."<br /><br />It's a fascinating and quirky approach, and if they are right, and their technique is employed by the software developers who design and build our online world, it might just transform what is recommended to us, and when, and how we experience it.<br /><br />Source: <a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1301.1887">http://arxiv.org/abs/1301.1887</a><br /><br /></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/WEnNsbMR7mM" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="47f4c9411b20246ba4abdb9deea22dee" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/particledecelerator/~3/XSOmP4AUP2w/its-full-of-stars.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="mobile-photo"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-4DBgpjgro2U/UPwC1tlCvEI/AAAAAAAAAXE/ZUFhZdC_3Rs/s1600/milkyway-778222.jpg"><img alt="" border="0" height="310" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5835542338956606530" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-4DBgpjgro2U/UPwC1tlCvEI/AAAAAAAAAXE/ZUFhZdC_3Rs/s640/milkyway-778222.jpg" width="640" /></a></div><br />This week the noted photographer and optics&nbsp;engineer, <a href="http://sguisard.astrosurf.com/" target="_blank">Stéphane Guisard</a>&nbsp;posted<a href="http://sguisard.astrosurf.com/Pagim/GC.html" target="_blank"> a stunning</a>&nbsp;<a href="http://sguisard.astrosurf.com/Pagim/GC.html" target="_blank">mosaic image of the Milky Way</a>&nbsp;captured at ESO's Paranal Observatory in Chile.<br /><br />The mosaic is constructed from 52 fields, shot&nbsp;over 29 nights, and consists of 1200 separate&nbsp;photos and 1 billion pixels.&nbsp;The image transports us to the centre of the&nbsp;Milky Way, giving us a scalable and zoomable&nbsp;encounter with  literally millions of stars.<br /><br />As&nbsp;<a href="http://sguisard.astrosurf.com/" target="_blank">Guisard</a>&nbsp;notes, "it shows the region spanning&nbsp;from Sagittarius (with the Milky Way center and&nbsp;M8/M20 area on the left) to Scorpius (with&nbsp;colorful Antares and Rho Ophiuchus region on the&nbsp;right) and Cat Paw nebula (red nebula at the&nbsp;bottom)."<br /><br />This is the galaxy in extreme fidelity. Enjoy getting lost in the detail. <br /><br />Source: <a href="http://sguisard.astrosurf.com/Pagim/GC.html">http://sguisard.astrosurf.com/Pagim/GC.html</a></div><div class="blogger-post-footer">http://decelerator.blogspot.com/</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/particledecelerator/~4/XSOmP4AUP2w" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>