<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="labtomarket.wordpress.com">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="7270bf4848e24e65701b97b1af91414d" url="http://labtomarket.wordpress.com/2013/04/29/measuring-user-engagement/"><![CDATA[Measuring User Engagement Together with Heather O&#8217;Brien and Elad Yom-Tov, we will be giving a tutorial at the International World-Wide Web Conference (WWW), 13-17 May 2013, Rio de Janeiro. Here is a description of our tutorial. We will add slides and a bibliography soon. Introduction and Motivations In the online world, user engagement refers to [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=labtomarket.wordpress.com&#038;blog=51295330&#038;post=166&#038;subd=labtomarket&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d561d2739d4eb64c2371433377a9c603" url="http://labtomarket.wordpress.com/2013/05/08/measuring-user-engagement-tutorial-slides/"><![CDATA[Together with Heather O’Brien and Elad Yom-Tov, we will be giving a tutorial at the International World-Wide Web Conference (WWW), 13-17 May 2013, Rio de Janeiro. The slides are now available on Slideshare. You can also access the two-slides per page format (PDF) here: MeasuringUserEngagement or one-slide per page format (PDF) here. The references can be found here: References_Tutorial. We [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=labtomarket.wordpress.com&#038;blog=51295330&#038;post=191&#038;subd=labtomarket&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="81a6903697d0f1119aed2456e4513c02" url="http://labtomarket.wordpress.com/2013/05/12/measuring-user-engagement-final-set-of-slides-for-www-2013/"><![CDATA[Together with Heather O’Brien and Elad Yom-Tov, we will be giving a tutorial at the International World-Wide Web Conference (WWW), 13 May 2013, Rio de Janeiro, at 8.30am. Here is the final set of slides (some typos and few other changes) and reduced. We hope to present most of the work described in the slides: MeasuringUserEngagement_Presented. Feedback and comments [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=labtomarket.wordpress.com&#038;blog=51295330&#038;post=206&#038;subd=labtomarket&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f89b81b40e641f9ba02bfb90cfcc96d2" url="http://labtomarket.wordpress.com/2013/06/04/user-engagement-follows-various-patterns/"><![CDATA[We need a taxonomy of web user engagement There are lots lots and lots of metrics that can be used to assess how users engage with a website. Widely used ones by the web-analytics community are click-through rates, number of page views, time spent on a website, how often users return to a site, number [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=labtomarket.wordpress.com&#038;blog=51295330&#038;post=224&#038;subd=labtomarket&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4e9caa88d74345e62fc46e8564575c73" url="http://labtomarket.wordpress.com/2013/06/13/absence-time-as-an-engagement-metric/"><![CDATA[What can absence time tell about user engagement? Two widely employed engagement metrics are click-through rate and dwell time. These are particularly used for services where user engagement is about clicking, for example in the context of search where presumably users click on relevant results, and/or spending time on a site, for example consuming content [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=labtomarket.wordpress.com&#038;blog=51295330&#038;post=336&#038;subd=labtomarket&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="66a68fb02e810d6746164be708921c57" url="http://labtomarket.wordpress.com/2013/06/19/to-be-or-not-be-engaged-what-are-the-questions-to-ask/"><![CDATA[Today I am giving a keynote at the 18th International Conference on Application of Natural Language to Information Systems (NLDB2013), which is held at MediaCityUK, Salford. I have now started to think at what are the questions to ask when evaluating user engagement. In the talk, I discuss these questions through five studies we did. Also [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=labtomarket.wordpress.com&#038;blog=51295330&#038;post=449&#038;subd=labtomarket&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8eaa94f4fefa6b2bdf7c41e595006dcf" url="http://labtomarket.wordpress.com/2013/06/25/transient-news-crowds-in-social-media/"><![CDATA[Hey Twitter crowd &#8230; What else is there? Original and shorter post at Crowdsearch.org. Twitter is a powerful tool for journalists at multiple stages of the news production process: to detect newsworthy events, interpret them, or verify their factual veracity. In 2011, a poll on 478 journalists from 15 countries found that 47% of them used Twitter as a source [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=labtomarket.wordpress.com&#038;blog=51295330&#038;post=418&#038;subd=labtomarket&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c200cb6d82b01651192b65907cfbac18" url="http://labtomarket.wordpress.com/2013/06/28/engagement-for-the-average/"><![CDATA[Measuring user engagement for the &#8220;average&#8221; users and experiences: Can psychophysiological measurement help? I recently attended the Input-Output conference in Brighton, UK. The theme of the conference was &#8220;Interdisciplinary approaches to Causality in Engagement, Immersion, and Presence in Performance and Human-Computer Interaction”. I wanted to learn about  psychophysiological measurement. I am myself on a quest: understand what is [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=labtomarket.wordpress.com&#038;blog=51295330&#038;post=466&#038;subd=labtomarket&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5b77a7ecffed86dd05269eaa39040c8a" url="http://labtomarket.wordpress.com/2013/10/01/how-engaged-are-wikipedia-users/"><![CDATA[How engaged are Wikipedia users? Recently, we were asked: “How engaged are Wikipedia users?” To answer this question, we visited Alexa, a Web Analytics site, and learned that Wikipedia is one of the most visited sites in the world (ranked 6th), that users spend on average around 4:35 minutes per day on Wikipedia, and that [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=labtomarket.wordpress.com&#038;blog=51295330&#038;post=570&#038;subd=labtomarket&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="460b357d9e1fa50beed29bf6c196ba86" url="http://labtomarket.wordpress.com/2013/10/10/online-users-multitask/"><![CDATA[Online, users multitask We often access several sites within an online session. We may perform one main task (when we plan a holiday, we often compare offers from different travel sites, go to a review site to check hotels), or several totally unrelated tasks in parallel (responding to an email while reading news). Both are what we call online [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=labtomarket.wordpress.com&#038;blog=51295330&#038;post=667&#038;subd=labtomarket&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>