<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="bouldersuz.wordpress.com">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="caed26d69307bbf9214dbc94391d4cad" url="http://bouldersuz.wordpress.com/2012/04/11/win-win-economy-roars-to-life/"><![CDATA[Amy Hoak of Marketwatch writes that there is a bit more confidence this year. Others, too, have noticed what Realtors noticed months ago. There is a sudden and surprising strong interest in real estate right now. The pace of existing housing sales were up 11.4 percent nationally in February. Could it be a coincidence that [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=bouldersuz.wordpress.com&#038;blog=9866074&#038;post=908&#038;subd=bouldersuz&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6bbdc92afa545935e665cb5f68d4502c" url="http://bouldersuz.wordpress.com/2012/04/14/some-obvious-and-not-so-obvious-tips/"><![CDATA[Yahoo put a crack team on finding common turn-offs for buyers. They found 10 they ranked. You would be right in thinking that these are common sense guides. But these are good reminders and I added my own take. A home seller is competing with a lot of foreclosures in this market. And, while the [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=bouldersuz.wordpress.com&#038;blog=9866074&#038;post=920&#038;subd=bouldersuz&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="379d83fafeda3147e356dcc617b09f35" url="http://bouldersuz.wordpress.com/2012/05/26/are-you-landlord-material/"><![CDATA[One-fifth of all home sales came available through foreclosure. If it&#8217;s not surprising to you that nationwide home values have been falling as rents rise, you may already be considering what it would be like to go into the landlord game. Here in Boulder County, CO, foreclosures are slowing to a trickle as rental units [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=bouldersuz.wordpress.com&#038;blog=9866074&#038;post=944&#038;subd=bouldersuz&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1f7de8bcc45b632935f8f26e244666f0" url="http://bouldersuz.wordpress.com/2012/06/30/972/"><![CDATA[CNNMoney.com carried a story in June 2010 asking if a housing shortage could be on the way. Others have joined in pondering the conditions that are now pointing to a serious shortfall in available units. Here in Boulder County, Colorado, which has 30 construction projects on tap for the next two years, a crisis-level shortage [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=bouldersuz.wordpress.com&#038;blog=9866074&#038;post=972&#038;subd=bouldersuz&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f542e65fd71e79c24ce5e71318b3b153" url="http://bouldersuz.wordpress.com/2013/03/17/keeping-a-sidewalk-in-good-repair/"><![CDATA[Oh, those unsightly lines. Have those wrinkles got you worried? &#8230; the ones on the sidewalk. The city of Longmont will repair cracks if they meet city criteria. Fill out the form at the city of Longmont web site and they will take a look and even schedule a repair. For your driveway and walkup, you [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=bouldersuz.wordpress.com&#038;blog=9866074&#038;post=979&#038;subd=bouldersuz&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="16694898697a9c484e24a69b261885b8" url="http://bouldersuz.wordpress.com/2013/04/19/analysis-the-housing-apocalypse-that-never-came/"><![CDATA[By Raymond Alvarez Contributing Writer  A strange thing happened on the way to the real estate apocalypse. It didn&#8217;t happen. Pundit and journalist alike had everyone looking the wrong way. But, who can blame them? How can you ignore the plethora of foreclosure signs on the way into the office? It turns out they weren&#8217;t [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=bouldersuz.wordpress.com&#038;blog=9866074&#038;post=983&#038;subd=bouldersuz&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f2ab13dc069cf6175596f06a57f3cca0" url="http://bouldersuz.wordpress.com/2013/05/12/boulder-still-the-media-darling/"><![CDATA[Boulder often finds itself in media &#8211; especially articles like this one. A city for outdoor enthusiasts, athletes and cyclists, Boulder is hip. A world-class university keeps it in the press, too. Nobel Prize winners work there. Esoteric research of all kinds is going on there. Got any small inventions in mind? A few years [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=bouldersuz.wordpress.com&#038;blog=9866074&#038;post=1010&#038;subd=bouldersuz&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="cf7713354562ead0ecd02b60c4559de3" url="http://bouldersuz.wordpress.com/2013/05/25/the-case-for-flipping-now/"><![CDATA[You can say that conditions have improved significantly and maybe dramatically for restoration. There is at least one group that never stops restoring properties. Some people believe that historic structures are better built. This hardcore group enjoys the styles that are reminiscent of days gone by. There were others that left us shaking our heads [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=bouldersuz.wordpress.com&#038;blog=9866074&#038;post=1016&#038;subd=bouldersuz&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="731f42d7cfafb66da29b0356b2a3fdf7" url="http://bouldersuz.wordpress.com/2013/06/03/longmont-a-legacy/"><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; Few argue that Longmont is a great small city &#8211; more than 85,000 and growing. The local newspaper and various media are full of activities and there are many amenities &#8211; like golf, skateboard parks, ice rinks and health clubs. Longmont is our kind of town. Suz Real Estate / PML 720.810.0683 https://www.facebook.com/SuzRealEstate<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=bouldersuz.wordpress.com&#038;blog=9866074&#038;post=1023&#038;subd=bouldersuz&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="df6931245f07f4be4e48696dfc2f6137" url="http://bouldersuz.wordpress.com/2013/06/16/longmont-where-legacy-resides/"><![CDATA[&#160; Discover Longmont, one of the pearls in a string along the Front Range. Townsfolk have long appreciated its history, having named one of its city parks for President Theodore Roosevelt. Roosevelt used his executive power to establish the first national parks. Congress also got into the act, but Roosevelt is the reason we have this abundance [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=bouldersuz.wordpress.com&#038;blog=9866074&#038;post=1026&#038;subd=bouldersuz&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>