<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="www.innovativeseo.net">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="55a4130031d2a6a0701069c35609d036" url="http://www.innovativeseo.net/2012/01/google-plus-seo-impact/"><![CDATA[Innovative SEO : Learn &#38; Share All About SEO Hello Friends, In continuation to my previous post on Google Plus : Bitter or Better , this post is more about the impact of Google+ SERP on SEO. In last post, I have share that, how Google reads individual search pattern, track &#38; analyze the data [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7405aba98d65efeed5d947c237d8553" url="http://www.innovativeseo.net/2012/02/track-pdf-in-google-analytics/"><![CDATA[Innovative SEO : Learn &#38; Share All About SEO Hello Friends, Recently, I have come across a real time challenge to track a really important data in Google Analytics. One of my client has a website which offers Online Application From in PDF Format &#38; One has to download it, fill it &#38; send back [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c40b9932b0fe727a1024d913d272d955" url="http://www.innovativeseo.net/2012/03/seo-pagination-google/"><![CDATA[Innovative SEO : Learn &#38; Share All About SEO Hello Friends, This post is all about Paging issues most of you have faced when it comes to SEO. As we all know that Google crawler faces difficulty in crawling, indexing &#38; ranking content having pagination. Why ? Here are the reasons, But recently, Google has [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="afdc44433dd037bb0a8e91c434543648" url="http://www.innovativeseo.net/2012/10/google-tag-manager/"><![CDATA[Innovative SEO : Learn &#38; Share All About SEO Hello Friends, Its been long time since my last post. Well, but here I am back with some really interesting updates by Google. Well, Its not about Panda or Penguin or nothing you need to worry about, but in fact this news will bring some smiles [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="56ab074d81551f4c2e1a7de608e09bc4" url="http://www.innovativeseo.net/2013/01/death-of-seo/"><![CDATA[Innovative SEO : Now An Inbound Marketer Hello Friends, Wish you all a very happy near year Well, Yes, New Year greeting message does not go well with the Title, but then it’s the reality Since you are reading this blog that means that some way you are connected with SEO Industry and you might [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="acfd59dc94024712a2366fcca8918e97" url="http://www.innovativeseo.net/2013/01/inbound-marketing/"><![CDATA[Innovative SEO : Learn &#38; Share All About Inbound Marketing Hello Friends, In connection with my previous post, here goes an Interesting Presentation on Inbound marketing. The presentation includes the basic concept of What is Inbound Marketing, Why there is a need of Inbound marketing, 5 steps to implement Inbound marketing in your company &#38; [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ebdb98279060b11d9d897a5825d1f776" url="http://www.innovativeseo.net/2013/02/improve-online-identity/"><![CDATA[Innovative SEO : Learn &#38; Share all about Inbound Marketing Hello Friends, Recently, I was reading a beautiful article on Online Branding Tools &#38; thought to share some insights of the article with all of you. Just came across an awesome post by Anna Runyan on Classycareergirl.com. She has shared some notes from Shama Kabani&#8217;s [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fd43a04a9ec86b55e7c287c0c8331a7a" url="http://www.innovativeseo.net/2013/02/seo-project-management-1/"><![CDATA[Innovative SEO : Learn &#38; Share All About Inbound Marketing Hello Friends, With this post, I am starting a blog series namely &#8220;Project Inception&#8220; Why : Few days back, I got a couple of questions on Facebook from industry colleagues on SEO Project Management &#38; managing SEO clients. So, I thought to share my experience [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5d26a85a555930abaa7270dfa8f64944" url="http://www.innovativeseo.net/2013/02/seo-project-management-2/"><![CDATA[Innovative SEO : Learn &#38; Share All About Inbound Marketing Hello Friends, We are continuing with “SEO Project Inception” series. This is the 2nd part in the series ( you can check out SEO Project Management Part-1 as well) where I am trying to find out the cause of the query raised by my friends [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e2f72a4d423a113708d223f8ef974277" url="http://www.innovativeseo.net/2013/09/google-analytics-basics/"><![CDATA[Innovative SEO : Learn &#38; Share All About Inbound Marketing Hello Friends, Its been a long time since my last post on SEO. Well, couple of things changed since then, but basics are still the same. In this post, we will review the Google Analytics Basics for all those who are still new to Google [...]
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>