<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="domesticfuel.com/author/joanna">
	<documents count="30">
		<document id="99c13133cc76b51fb427de53d024a527" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/1jcbydAFhYQ/"><![CDATA[Biodiesel maker Imperium Renewables has inked a six-month deal to keep its Washington State plant in canola oil as a feedstock for the green fuel. Legumex Walker Inc.&#8217;s Pacific Coast Canola (PCC) subsidiary will deliver by truck its super degummed &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/17/imperium-gets-canola-deal-for-biodiesel/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c68fe96a6800b37ccdf53958b6d0c730" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/4REnTS5-c14/"><![CDATA[VoteVets has expanded its television campaign in support of the Renewable Fuel Standard (RFS). The ads began in Iowa earlier this month and have now expanded into Nebraska. The ads are also airing in Washington, D.C. The ad airing in &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/17/votevets-expands-rfs-ad-campaign/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="14424168ef0b1ace17f33c3b8f25e62c" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/50S_elXJ_94/"><![CDATA[This morning Joe Jobe, CEO, National Biodiesel Board, rallied his troops at the National Biodiesel Conference in San Diego. He told attendees that the petroleum industry is misleading Americans about fuel policy and called on President Barack Obama to stand &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/21/joe-jobe-exposes-renewable-energy-reality/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fe88d0b91a163cb541d6de0486ee7642" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/686sghCnxZs/"><![CDATA[Iowa Governor Terry Branstad, Lt. Governor Kim Reynolds, Iowa Secretary of Agriculture Bill Northey, the Iowa Senate, and the Iowa House of Representatives along with Iowa’s entire Congressional Delegation are unanimously standing together to pass a resolution in support of &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/17/bioenergy-bytes-149/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ae11a49fe22a619f8977191459c3d675" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/6_vn387maxE/"><![CDATA[Researchers at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) have found a new way to get more out of harvesting solar energy. This article from the school says they&#8217;re using the sun to heat a high-temperature material whose infrared radiation would &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/21/mit-finds-new-way-to-get-more-out-of-solar/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e5410095e4fdcf17df1b538d677576ae" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/8E0f0EXIKI4/"><![CDATA[A bi-partisan group of lawmakers is calling on the government to end its proposal to reduce the amount of ethanol and biodiesel that will be blended into the Nation&#8217;s fuel supply. Led by Democratic Congresswoman Cheri Bustos (IL-17) and Republican &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/21/bi-partisan-group-protests-epa-biofuels-reductions/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="17a025d08dc9180a5be99a52b3c5438f" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/bejBZnItQtk/"><![CDATA[According to a new study, that compared the greenhouse gas emission reductions of corn ethanol and those of crude oil production and fracking, corn ethanol&#8217;s carbon intensity is declining while the carbon intensity of petroleum is increasing. The study was &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/16/new-study-corn-ethanol-reduces-ghg-emissions/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4966a8a4a0cc5ef4e49e738af449b849" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/cDggBmIUWMM/"><![CDATA[Some folks north of the border might call it the little yellow plant that could. But this article from the Toronto Globe and Mail says canola, one of the key feedstocks in Canada&#8217;s biodiesel industry, has really taken off from &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/21/biodiesel-part-of-canadas-canola-success-story/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bfcce48f09ad5e884ecb7ded08b1d7ee" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/cpE-I8TaNJ8/"><![CDATA[A German chemical company has introduced a new liquid stabilizer for biodiesel. This news release posted on NewswireToday.com says LANXESS is now offering Baynox Extra, an easy-to-meter additive that prolongs biodiesel&#8217;s shelf life and doesn&#8217;t crystallize, even at 10 below &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/20/lanxess-biodiesel-stabilizer-introduced/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d998ca54e177b46adcc5a320decba980" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/CY_tFtE2X9c/"><![CDATA[A Renewable Fuel Standard (RFS) road show is kicking off in Iowa on Tuesday, January 21, 2014 to highlight the importance of Iowa&#8217;s renewable fuels industry. Iowa Secretary of Agriculture Bill Northey will be encouraging Iowans to comment on a &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/17/rfs-road-show-kicks-off-in-iowa/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="da8869752b4f0d1ae80b834d5fff4a69" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/egleHniaAZs/"><![CDATA[Officials in a central Virginia city have unanimously approved the conversion of an old petroleum site into a storage and distribution facility for gas, biodiesel and ethanol. This article from the Fredericksburg (VA) Free Lance-Star says they&#8217;re allowing the Lincoln &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/17/virginia-city-greenlights-biodiesel-ethanol-terminal/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b3fa186514ebbedd04fa4c3eb7cc39b9" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/eyW_WP4JJRc/"><![CDATA[This years Biodiesel and Ethanol Marketing Awards went to Russ and Barb Danielsen from Southern Iowa Oil and Jason Stauffer from STAR Energy. The 2014 winners were announced by Iowa Secretary of Agriculture Bill Northey. “Both winners have gone to &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/16/iowa-renewable-fuel-awards-go-to/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6fb4cf45dcefa4fad7b7a56f10155bdf" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/hHnVSLaopF8/"><![CDATA[It&#8217;s that time. The 2014 National Biodiesel Conference is next week. I&#8217;ll be on location once again and working as the Biodiesel Blogger on the NBB Conference Blog. Things will get going late Monday and through Wednesday. You can find &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/17/biodiesel-blogging-again/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="eeb5c39338eead1cbce6d2d7a1df1f03" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/hhWc-m1dQbA/"><![CDATA[The first of this year&#8217;s Eye on Biodiesel Awards was presented this morning for Innovation. It was presented to General Motors and the B20-Approved Chevrolet Cruze. General Motors continues to be a leading biodiesel supporter among OEM&#8217;s. This year the &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/21/innovation-award-to-chevy-cruze/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d05e45ae16e0971a623437c711107199" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/I3Oar2AeXPk/"><![CDATA[Gov. Terry Branstad and Lt. Gov. Kim Reynolds are leading a group of senior state officials from Iowa and the Midwest to organize and host a public hearing allowing citizens outside of Washington, D.C., the opportunity to testify about the &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/17/hearing-in-the-heartland-supporting-the-rfs/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4e0a8d0a6d35004ffcf0989bd0f39213" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/Ip8094Tl6t0/"><![CDATA[An update to a story we told you about last week&#8230; an offshore wind energy project in Maine has received a key approval from state regulators. This article from CompositesWorld.com says the Maine Public Utilities Commission gave the go-ahead for &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/21/maine-wind-project-gains-key-approval/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2e01cf96c20c5264603f04e6407d7c9b" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/j6ITGgtXlk4/"><![CDATA[Led Zepplin 2 will be performing at the 19th Annual Ethanol Conference (NEC) on Tuesday, February 18, 2014 in Orlando Florida. The cover band includes Paul Kamp, an active participant in the biofuels industry. The band recently toured in New &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/22/led-zeppelin-2-to-perform-at-nec/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="cbab736c6b1cbfb22f0d53f25c70bc81" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/jIs-855XCBw/"><![CDATA[Patriot Renewable Fuels is delivering the message of the benefits of American made products with their new LED sign on Interstate 80 that was installed on December 20, 2013. The biorefinery is located just off I-80 and drivers can see &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/17/american-made-message-delivered-to-drivers-on-i-80/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ca5464d310f2b2458fce2ba38e53fac0" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/LZ7Q74PZrWI/"><![CDATA[Cutting back on your sugar intake? Than consider using it to create a battery. Not really but doesn&#8217;t it sound cool? A Virgina Tech research team did just this and has developed a battery that runs on sugar. The research &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/22/sugar-bringing-in-the-new-age-of-batteries/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="962e90c65199306d101ff46d676d51a0" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/m6H5H5QLXgg/"><![CDATA[A big announcement for the availability with consumers this week with the announcement that MAPCO Express, one of the country&#8217;s largest retail chains, they will begin offering E15 to consumers. MAPCO has set a goal of offering E15 at all &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/16/mapco-to-sell-e15/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="24f90a233be3fa70ac82363148deb303" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/p5HIglJqyos/"><![CDATA[The 2014 National Biodiesel Conference is underway in San Diego. This evening attendees got together for a welcome reception at the San Diego Convention Center. It looks like we&#8217;re going to have an even larger crowd than was first thought! &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/20/2014-national-biodiesel-conference-underway/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6601bc3233570d3851ca4f4141d524b4" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/Rr1gbySczqs/"><![CDATA[Aircraft manufacturing giant Boeing wants the government to approve its plan of using renewable or &#8220;green&#8221; diesel. This story from TriplePundit.com says the company is appealing to the U.S. Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) and other stakeholders to get permission to &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/22/boeing-looks-to-get-renewable-diesel-approval/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ef46f78d955dd2ed168a131cee68d0f9" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/S4qcjZPGEnk/"><![CDATA[A Missouri biodiesel maker says it has opened the world&#8217;s most advanced biodiesel plant. This news release from Blue Sun Energy says the 30-million-gallon-per-year plant in St. Joseph uses enzymatic biodiesel processing technology. “We have fully commercialized the enzymatic process &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/20/blue-sun-opens-most-advanced-biodiesel-plant/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3c3d657749433c1ff72c39f9e12b9d70" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/vp25UjGIweE/"><![CDATA[The federal government continues to go after the few bad actors who are trying to defraud the incentive system for biodiesel production. The Department of Justice announced the indictment of James Jariv, 63, of Las Vegas, and Nathan Stoliar, 64, &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/22/feds-continue-crackdown-on-biodiesel-rin-fraud/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9411e0f3e23bb6bee82cb3b56c7d9300" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/WbFIIrrUsqg/"><![CDATA[As the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) considers its proposal that would, in effect, slash the amount of ethanol and biodiesel to be blended into the Nation&#8217;s fuel supply, the American Farm Bureau Federation (AFBF) is telling the government to &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/17/farm-bureau-lends-support-to-keeping-rfs/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f47304be4a92489eef6f6e8b14ee2f53" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/Wd8luqzuQBE/"><![CDATA[The UI GreenMetric World University Ranking has ranked the University of California, Davis in the top 10 for campus sustainability and environment-friendly management. In Universitas Indonesia’s fourth annual GreenMetric rankings, for 2013, UC Davis is ninth overall (up from 17th &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/22/bioenergy-bytes-150/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="989b34a432d65ae4b771e8366f73dc82" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/xjVcgidmvbk/"><![CDATA[The 8th Annual Iowa Renewable Fuels Summit and Trade Show is just around the corner (January 28, 2014) and the list of experts keeps on a comin. The event&#8217;s host, the Iowa Renewable Fuels Association (IRFA), has announced a new &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/16/and-the-experts-keep-on-a-comin/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c24a2a19af9c1aab160f701b625f1c98" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/xkSO_Z5ozjQ/"><![CDATA[Researchers at the University of Wisconsin-Madison have found a way to get more ethanol out of sugars used in the refining process. This university article says they&#8217;re using a plant-derived chemical, gamma valerolactone, or GVL. “With the sugar platform, you &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/21/wisconsin-resarchers-find-better-biofuels-chemical/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ff7ecf112de773b5d9a8241c71c6063" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/ZHPl_sAuaP4/"><![CDATA[A research center dedicated to advancing the study and development of ethanol is expanding its research staff. This news release from the National Corn-to-Ethanol Research Center (NCERC) at Southern Illinois University-Edwardsville (SIUE) has added Dr. Arun Athmanathan, a postdoctoral fellow &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/21/southern-illinois-expands-ethanol-research-team/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1ae98f504b19bdc7a3c1be2c159fecb" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DomesticFuel/~3/_cIxbTzBT2M/"><![CDATA[The current situation with the RFS has pitted the big petroleum industry against an industry that has made great strides in developing renewable and clean energy. Attendees at the National Biodiesel Conference today got some motivation and inspiration from Jim &#8230; <a href="http://domesticfuel.com/2014/01/21/winning-teamwork-needed-by-biodiesel-industry/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>