<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="scientopia.org/blogs/whizbang">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="78a1c94fb13d75312423497258861b3f" url="http://scientopia.org/blogs/whizbang/2013/11/28/happy-black-friday-eve/"><![CDATA[We used to go shopping on the day after Thanksgiving, before it became Black Friday. It was crowded, and there were good sales. It felt happy and chaotic and special. Then stores picked up on it and made it into "A Thing." Now it starts on Thanksgiving Day and has become something of which I [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="372bf9ee4d865dd99d139d69e2932c7f" url="http://scientopia.org/blogs/whizbang/2013/12/03/nutcracker-musings/"><![CDATA[December has arrived, bringing chilly weather and thoughts of nutcrackers... No, not this practical kind. Not even this decorative kind. More like the dancing kind! Did you know that there is another kind of nutcracker? A kidney kind of nutcracker? Click here to read about this unusual condition, the nutcracker syndrome, at my other home [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="654325e8cb02430537839480abb1a3af" url="http://scientopia.org/blogs/whizbang/2013/12/09/not-ready-for-prime-time-23andme/"><![CDATA[In case you spent the last few weeks on a desert island, you may have missed the love letters flowing between the FDA and 23andMe, resulting in this disclaimer that must be signed before accessing the direct-to-consumer genotyper's website: I understand that 23andMe only sells ancestry reports and raw genetic data at this time. I [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9ae16161e2df0a11b0915ffc9be65b5c" url="http://scientopia.org/blogs/whizbang/2013/12/13/thoughts-on-medical-care/"><![CDATA[I have been fighting the latest viral infection and seeing outpatients all week. Over that period, I have come up with several suggestions to improve healthcare, perhaps even making it more affordable. In no particular order, here they are: If you have an appointment, show up and ON TIME. If you cannot make your appointment, [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3dbafb36be81996b3bf63e19364a94df" url="http://scientopia.org/blogs/whizbang/2013/12/18/a-holiday-tradition/"><![CDATA[Here I sit, waiting for patients that seem to be not showing up or being extremely late for their appointments. Lucky for me I can do this in my administrative office; the clinic computers will not let me blog! This will be my last week at work this year. Next week I will be working [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c5dddf6f2aa9e12ee7c52cd73d896480" url="http://scientopia.org/blogs/whizbang/2013/12/20/end-of-the-year-meme/"><![CDATA[A couple of years ago, someone (DrugMonkey?) posted the title and first sentence or so of the first blog post of each month for the year. Here is my version for 2013: Watching Football? You Need Chili! Jan 02 2013 On New Year's Day, I settle in with the first bowl game and barely move [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fad82c31f8cf41da244225bbb0732894" url="http://scientopia.org/blogs/whizbang/2013/12/21/what-i-am-reading-autism-spectrum-edition/"><![CDATA[&#160; On a trip this autumn, I finished my novels and began scouring Amazon for something else to keep me entertained and sane in airports. Their algorhythm suggested The Rosie Project; once again, an on-target suggestion that did the job. The book begins with an introduction to Don Tillman, a professor of genetics with a [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6b74dbe96a93b8cf2c5be5d544b084a9" url="http://scientopia.org/blogs/whizbang/2013/12/24/celebrate/"><![CDATA[Every year I end up with some Christmas song stuck in my brain, a festive ear worm to end the year. Here is this year's lucky song. Enjoy and have a happy holiday, whatever you celebrate.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="278dc47cccf46fc2b3c3a839456bf3a8" url="http://scientopia.org/blogs/whizbang/2014/01/02/holidays-done-football-continues/"><![CDATA[Tonight the Oklahoma Sooners face Alabama in the Sugar Bowl. I understand what my colleagues feel today: As I said when my Missouri Tigers faced The Crimson Tide last year, it's like watching your child in the Hunger Games; you're hoping for the best, but you know the likely outcome won't be pretty. Speaking of [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2260262b4ccb832ba2415812dcd9389" url="http://scientopia.org/blogs/whizbang/2014/01/08/twenty-fourteen-travel-begins/"><![CDATA[Just one week into the new year, and I am already on the road. As I write this post, I await the first leg of my trip to San Antonio for the alumnae group of the Executive Leadership in Academic Medicine for Women. This every-other-year get-together will give me a chance to learn new stuff, [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>