<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="aidanmoher.com/blog">
	<documents count="15">
		<document id="e2d70a9554ef1169da23be0859f4e7a3" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/aidanmoher/eiaU/~3/6d0cxjiWgWA/"><![CDATA[Every once in a while, an artist nails the artwork from the book they are covering. Marc Simonetti does it on an alarmingly regular basis. This artwork, created by Simonetti for the Brazilian edition of Brandon Sanderson&#8217;s Mistborn: The Final Empire, is gorgeous, and the most accurate to imagery that I had in my mind&#8217;s...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://aidanmoher.com/blog/2013/12/art/cover-art/marc-simonettis-mistborn/" title="ReadMarc Simonetti&#8217;s <em>Mistborn</em>">Read more &#187;</a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b9848ab23205d272e0433191fdbd2c0b" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/aidanmoher/eiaU/~3/B8teYxEPbF0/"><![CDATA[Brian McClellan turned a lot of heads earlier this year with the release of Promise of Blood, the first book in The Powder Mage Trilogy, a flintlock fantasy that SciFi Now called, &#8220;a historically influenced fantastical romp filled with machismo, intrigue and magic.&#8221; Machismo aside, (that&#8217;s a virtue in a novel?) McClellan&#8217;s debut has been...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://aidanmoher.com/blog/2013/12/asides/brian-mcclellan-announces-delay-for-the-crimson-campaign/" title="ReadBrian McClellan announces delay for <em>The Crimson Campaign</em>">Read more &#187;</a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="73c6bc02af1604e5b2939aa143c0112c" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/aidanmoher/eiaU/~3/bOPKJ2u4dYw/"><![CDATA[Joe Abercrombie confirmed Monday that the first draft of his next novel, Half a King is, for all intents and purposes, done. The &#8220;kind of YA kind of crossover whatever the hell it is&#8221; has completed its copyedits and is ready for its publication on &#8220;July 8th 2014 from Del Rey in the US, and...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://aidanmoher.com/blog/2013/12/asides/an-abercrombie-update-half-a-king-finished-the-first-law-on-the-horizon/" title="ReadAn Abercrombie update: <em>Half a King</em> finished, <em>The First Law</em> on the Horizon">Read more &#187;</a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c2d4a7fc3c5aacf61e8d728b59abb115" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/aidanmoher/eiaU/~3/Eg1LWpXiVYM/"><![CDATA[Lightning in a Bottle, an unfilmable story. Last year, after a decade of speculation, failed starts and mountains of expectation, Peter Jackson released The Hobbit: An Unexpected Journey, the first in a trilogy of films adapting J.R.R. Tolkien&#8217;s classic fantasy novel, The Hobbit, for the big screen. Following in the footsteps of its bigger brother,...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://aidanmoher.com/blog/2013/12/reviews/the-desolation-of-tolkien-a-review-of-the-desolation-of-smaug/" title="ReadThe Desolation of Tolkien: A review of <em>The Desolation of Smaug</em>">Read more &#187;</a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4e978e47318f7247242d7618f2c3b9fa" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/aidanmoher/eiaU/~3/iKS9t-wDW0U/"><![CDATA[Note: This article was originally published as part of Smugglivus, a year-end celebration of all things books over at The Book Smugglers. Check out the rest of the fun! To begin the year, I set myself a challenge: read a perfect split balance of male:female authors in 2013. It was a personal challenge, and I...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://aidanmoher.com/blog/featured-article/2013/12/best-of-13-my-favourite-books-by-women/" title="ReadBest of &#8217;13 — My Favourite Books by Women">Read more &#187;</a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9f4e25ed17e7b2375ebed6b766c3c49b" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/aidanmoher/eiaU/~3/KuVjp7F7Fd4/"><![CDATA[Full of Pratchett’s trademark wit and humor, Raising Steam is a tour de force of comedic fantasy and proves that despite recent health issues and uncertainty about his future as a novelist, Terry Pratchett is still a wordsmith and storyteller at the top of his game. Steam power has come to Discworld and caught in...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://aidanmoher.com/blog/review/2014/01/review-of-raising-steam-by-terry-pratchett/" title="ReadReview of <em>Raising Steam</em> by Terry Pratchett">Read more &#187;</a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="95707686de19002e3a78ddf6ba223e69" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/aidanmoher/eiaU/~3/Ky0b89SDgl4/"><![CDATA[Ending several weeks of speculation (and a couple of years of wishful thinking and fervent hoping among fans), Atlus announced Persona 5, the latest installation in the long-running Japanese RPG series. &#8220;Persona 5 will launch for PlayStation 3 in Japan during winter 2014,&#8221; reports Polygon, followed by &#8216;three spin-off titles coming for various platforms.&#8217; At...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://aidanmoher.com/blog/2013/11/asides/persona-5-announced-for-2014-release/" title="Read<em>Persona 5</em> Announced for 2014 Release">Read more &#187;</a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="440d78ca8420a8e7301ee714760177f0" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/aidanmoher/eiaU/~3/mP5GZjHNJIo/"><![CDATA[For many readers, escaping into a good fantasy or science fiction novel is a way to leave the ordinary world behind, to enter into a land of wonder, where anything can happen and things of magical beauty and indescribably evil can coexist and clash for supremacy. But, ask anyone who has examined our own world,...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://aidanmoher.com/blog/2013/12/asides/fantasy-on-earth-kowloons-walled-city/" title="ReadFantasy on Earth: Kowloon&#8217;s Walled City">Read more &#187;</a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b5bb8e7e2ba669400ff73e49f6e2649e" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/aidanmoher/eiaU/~3/MukfYYeiNZU/"><![CDATA[Well, boys and girls, mark your calendars. We&#8217;ve got a (tentative, vague) date for the next volume of Scott Lynch&#8217;s Gentlemen Bastards sequence, The Thorn of Emberlain. The Thorn of Emberlain &#8220;ought to be out in the fall of 2014,&#8221; said Lynch in an interview with Fantastical Imaginations. While some guarded skepticism is natural, Adam...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://aidanmoher.com/blog/2013/12/asides/scott-lynch-reveals-2014-release-date-for-the-thorn-of-emberlain/" title="ReadScott Lynch reveals 2014 release date for <em>The Thorn of Emberlain</em>">Read more &#187;</a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2ba2bc72fa6b474cf48134a7e18e81a7" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/aidanmoher/eiaU/~3/OHYloU-7_Xc/"><![CDATA[Remember back in your younger days when the hours would fly by as you dug through your bin of LEGO, bounded only by the limits of your imagination? Grown now, Alice Finch and David Frank have taken that concept to another level with their enormous recreation of Rivendell, The Last Homely House west of the...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://aidanmoher.com/blog/2013/12/art/tolkiens-rivendell-recreated-with-200000-lego-bricks/" title="ReadTolkien&#8217;s Rivendell recreated with 200,000 LEGO bricks">Read more &#187;</a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e383625566f482639f355b27cb112aad" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/aidanmoher/eiaU/~3/upVsQbmbUIE/"><![CDATA[Last month, I reported on a rumoured videogame adaptation of Game of Thrones by Adventure Game-kings Telltale Games. The developer, through CEO Dan Connors, confirmed the adaptation this week, indicating that it will be a &#8220;multi-year, multi-title partnership&#8221; with Martin and HBO. The game(s) will be based on Game of Thrones, the television adaptation of...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://aidanmoher.com/blog/2013/12/asides/telltale-games-announces-multi-year-multi-title-partnership-with-george-r-r-martin-and-game-of-thrones/" title="ReadTelltale Games announces &#8216;multi-year, multi-title partnership&#8217; with George R.R. Martin and <em>Game of Thrones</em>">Read more &#187;</a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f081266544f253eccf6af5151c5a81eb" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/aidanmoher/eiaU/~3/WeNlYgQ0lUQ/"><![CDATA[Ken Liu, World Fantasy Award-winning author of The Paper Menagerie, announced yesterday the sale of his first novel, The Chrysanthemum and the Dandelion, and its sequels. The Chrysanthemum and the Dandelion is the first volume of The Dandelion Dynasty. A full synopsis of the series was provided on io9: The Dandelion Dynasty follows Kuni Garu,...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://aidanmoher.com/blog/2013/11/asides/ken-liu-award-winning-short-story-writer-announces-his-first-novel-the-chrysanthemum-and-the-dandelion/" title="ReadKen Liu, award-winning short story writer, announces his first novel, <em>The Chrysanthemum and the Dandelion</em>">Read more &#187;</a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="16cc4c91d6121bbff81fee2b67e5b199" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/aidanmoher/eiaU/~3/YPRGobYqu3g/"><![CDATA[If there&#8217;s one takeaway from the first film in Peter Jackson&#8217;s film adaptation of The Hobbit, it&#8217;s that the writer/director&#8217;s tinkering with Tolkien&#8217;s lore, ostensibly for the sake of making a more bloated exciting theatre-going experience, was less than successful. The additions of Azog, Radagast&#8217;s plight against the Necromancer, the absurdity in the hall of...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://aidanmoher.com/blog/2013/12/asides/so-about-those-elves-peter-jackson-discusses-the-desolation-of-smaug/" title="ReadSo&#8230; about those elves. Peter Jackson discusses <em>The Desolation of Smaug</em>">Read more &#187;</a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fabb7a1088865625109495fe4541385d" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/aidanmoher/eiaU/~3/ZDzJ0QtycBY/"><![CDATA[Why did Shakespeare write fantasies? Why not mainstream topics, such as histories and romantic comedies? Before we examine this question, let us examine a few others first: Fantasies are fun! Why doesn’t everybody read them? What is mainstream? Why is a story about ordinary life considered mainstream, while an equally charming fantasy is relegated to...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://aidanmoher.com/blog/featured-article/2013/12/from-the-ghetto-to-literary-old-town-exploring-shakespeares-magic-by-l-jagi-lamplighter/" title="Read&#8220;From the Ghetto to Literary Old Town: Exploring Shakespeare&#8217;s Magic&#8221; by L. Jagi Lamplighter">Read more &#187;</a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2484350b2551fe88113c4762f8f8c2ce" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/aidanmoher/eiaU/~3/_69eUj99iJ4/"><![CDATA[It&#8217;s no secret the Hayao Miyazaki is one of the most masterful and celebrated film makers of the past century. The Japanese writer/director&#8217;s studio, Studio Ghibli, author to contemporary classic like My Neighbour Totoro, Spirited Away, and Princess Mononoke, has helped introduce countless young (and old) people to the beautiful Japanese legends and myths that...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://aidanmoher.com/blog/2013/12/art/what-if-gorgeous-concept-art-for-hayao-miyazakis-pippi-longstocking-the-strongest-girl-in-the-world/" title="ReadWhat If: Gorgeous concept art for Hayao Miyazaki&#8217;s <em> Pippi Longstocking, The Strongest Girl in the World</em>">Read more &#187;</a>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>