<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="ablawg.ca/author/jwhamilton">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="3402371fda8e154671372973de4cfeb4" url="http://ablawg.ca/2013/05/10/consequences-of-being-an-opca-litigant/"><![CDATA[PDF version: Consequences of being an OPCA Litigant? Case commented on: ANB v Hancock, 2013 ABQB 97. ANB v Hancock is Associate Chief Justice John D. Rooke’s second written judgment about an Organized Pseudolegal Commercial Argument (OPCA) litigant. As summarized &#8230; <a href="http://ablawg.ca/2013/05/10/consequences-of-being-an-opca-litigant/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6c41a837491c52c0e3a3c9a7ccec3622" url="http://ablawg.ca/2013/05/15/do-covenants-to-compensate-for-designation-as-an-historical-resource-run-with-the-land/"><![CDATA[PDF version: Do Covenants to Compensate for Designation as an Historical Resource Run with the Land? Case considered: Equitable Trust Company v Lougheed Block Inc, 2013 ABQB 209. The foreclosure proceedings taken with respect to the historic Lougheed Building at &#8230; <a href="http://ablawg.ca/2013/05/15/do-covenants-to-compensate-for-designation-as-an-historical-resource-run-with-the-land/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="414d75e93d56f8280c8ca2df00cad3b8" url="http://ablawg.ca/2013/06/05/roundtable-on-quebec-v-a-searching-for-clarity-on-equality/"><![CDATA[PDF version: Roundtable on Quebec v A: Searching for Clarity on Equality Decision considered: Quebec (Attorney General) v A, 2013 SCC 5 (case summary available here). On May 13, 2013, we led the Faculty of Law’s first roundtable discussion of the &#8230; <a href="http://ablawg.ca/2013/06/05/roundtable-on-quebec-v-a-searching-for-clarity-on-equality/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="204c6d2b61abb565c4ee5e319e330687" url="http://ablawg.ca/2013/07/08/adapting-and-using-the-law-in-the-recovery-from-a-natural-disaster/"><![CDATA[PDF version: Adapting and Using the Law in the Recovery from a Natural Disaster Law on the Edge panel discussion commented on: “Law at the Limits: A Canterbury Tale: Adapting and Using the Law in the Recovery from a Natural Disaster” The &#8230; <a href="http://ablawg.ca/2013/07/08/adapting-and-using-the-law-in-the-recovery-from-a-natural-disaster/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="81af561466f7be95b264494051f7e53b" url="http://ablawg.ca/2013/08/06/enforcing-albertas-restrictions-on-consumer-arbitration/"><![CDATA[PDF version: Enforcing Alberta’s Restrictions on Consumer Arbitration Case commented on: Young v National Money Mart Company, 2013 ABCA 264 (CanLII). This decision by the Alberta Court of Appeal is a welcome addition to the body of consumer arbitration case &#8230; <a href="http://ablawg.ca/2013/08/06/enforcing-albertas-restrictions-on-consumer-arbitration/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b0f0e760895c619256cd63b86bae873a" url="http://ablawg.ca/2013/08/26/is-a-lease-with-an-option-to-renew-a-subdivision/"><![CDATA[PDF Version: Is a Lease with an Option to Renew a Subdivision? Case commented on: Strathcona County v. Half Moon Lake Resort Ltd., 2013 ABQB 405 The main question in this case was whether an option to renew a lease &#8230; <a href="http://ablawg.ca/2013/08/26/is-a-lease-with-an-option-to-renew-a-subdivision/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4f30e4d7f1fe77922eafa81fdf32d0bf" url="http://ablawg.ca/2013/08/30/roundtable-on-ontario-v-criminal-lawyers-association-of-ontario/"><![CDATA[PDF Version: Roundtable on Ontario v Criminal Lawyers’ Association of Ontario Cases Considered: Ontario v Criminal Lawyers’ Association of Ontario, 2013 SCC 43 On August 13, 2013, Faculty of Law hosted its last Roundtable discussion of the summer. That discussion &#8230; <a href="http://ablawg.ca/2013/08/30/roundtable-on-ontario-v-criminal-lawyers-association-of-ontario/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f6f8a4410c4c46775f62cb3b61aa3b48" url="http://ablawg.ca/2013/09/18/enforcing-and-extending-vexatious-litigant-orders/"><![CDATA[PDF Version: Enforcing and Extending Vexatious Litigant Orders Case commented on: 1158997 Alberta Inc v Maple Trust Company, 2013 ABQB 483 This decision is interesting for two reasons. First, it illustrates a problem with the vexatious litigant provisions in Part &#8230; <a href="http://ablawg.ca/2013/09/18/enforcing-and-extending-vexatious-litigant-orders/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="cf5868e70a2ce106aad9571e3b41a0bb" url="http://ablawg.ca/2013/10/22/disclosure-of-foreign-assets-in-matrimonial-property-actions/"><![CDATA[PDF Version: Disclosure of Foreign Assets in Matrimonial Property Actions Case commented on: Chikonyora v Chikonyora, 2013 ABCA 320 Had the decision of the Court of Queen’s Bench been allowed to stand in this case, the division of matrimonial property &#8230; <a href="http://ablawg.ca/2013/10/22/disclosure-of-foreign-assets-in-matrimonial-property-actions/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="118445170a4d0e6f0a6236566e034e67" url="http://ablawg.ca/2013/12/18/the-difference-between-a-duplex-and-a-semi-detached-house/"><![CDATA[PDF Version: The Difference Between a Duplex and a Semi-Detached House Case commented on: Deagle v 1678452 Alberta Ltd., 2013 ABQB 708 Does permission to construct a semi-detached dwelling allow the building of a secondary suite? That was the essence &#8230; <a href="http://ablawg.ca/2013/12/18/the-difference-between-a-duplex-and-a-semi-detached-house/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>