<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="arhipov.blogspot.com">
	<documents count="25">
		<document id="a07cb80d0c09a57de25e1a8963159921" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/1wxKa_B5p_0/ide-project-files-in-version-contro-yes.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div style="text-align: justify;"><i style="text-align: left;"><b>NB!&nbsp;</b>This topic is mostly related to Java projects. The situation might be a little different in case of other technologies and IDEs.</i></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><i style="text-align: left;"><br /></i></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Just recently I had some discussions with the clients who were claiming that they keep IDE project files in version control system hence they avoid any changes to those files. For reference, those are Eclipse generated <b>.project</b> and <b>.classpath</b>. From my point of view it is a bad practice by all means, however I usually prefer to collect some information on the topic before I say it loudly. So I asked from my G+ and Twitter followers, <a href="https://twitter.com/antonarhipov/status/228395791423770624">IDE project files in version control - Yes/No?</a>&nbsp;Surprisingly, I've got quite a number of responses, so I decided to summarize the information as a blog post.</div><br />Basically, the answer to this question isn't binary, yes or no, but it also could be "yes, but... " or "no, if...". So there might be some argument why someone prefers one way or another.<br /><br />The vast majority of the answers is "No, no, noooooooo!! Never!". And just a couple of answers were "yes" with some weak arguments of why someone should keep those files in version control.<br /><br />Here are some yes answers first.<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-A0g7P4mL0Kg/UBGxkaSkkrI/AAAAAAAAQFk/lrzhMA_VjjQ/s1600/twitter-yes-1.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-A0g7P4mL0Kg/UBGxkaSkkrI/AAAAAAAAQFk/lrzhMA_VjjQ/s1600/twitter-yes-1.png" /></a></div><br />Bad stuff. Seems that the team isn't really competent with the tools. The project should be easy to setup and why on earth I should press 100500 buttons to setup a project. If this is the case, the first thing that team lead should do, is to simplify the project structure, setup and build process. No excuses there.<br /><br />Yeah, yeah, I can already hear some arguments like "but we have a complex project" or "this is the way our setup is done". Bullsh*t! <br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-IR6WvowUoM8/UBI5W7XqpLI/AAAAAAAAQIM/jxNwR7JkyHM/s1600/petr1.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-IR6WvowUoM8/UBI5W7XqpLI/AAAAAAAAQIM/jxNwR7JkyHM/s1600/petr1.png" /></a></div>OK, there is some optimization for the setup, IDE specific though. If all the team members use the same setup, it might even make sense for those who want to keep hands off the console.<br /><br />Here's another one:<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-dcz9E9geKAw/UBGzHMa3uUI/AAAAAAAAQFs/W3hZ9ypInlI/s1600/twitter-yes-2.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-dcz9E9geKAw/UBGzHMa3uUI/AAAAAAAAQFs/W3hZ9ypInlI/s1600/twitter-yes-2.png" /></a></div><br /><div style="text-align: justify;">"Specific Eclipse plugins" - yeah! that's is actually an argument for <b>not</b> keeping the files in version control! Eclipse plugins usually modify <b>.project</b> files as they add a "nature" or any other project specific settings to the configuration. And actually, IntelliJ does the same, but (let me bash to tools a bit) IntelliJ can suggest the settings as you open a project from scratch. And with Eclipse, you have to do that manually. What if your colleague uses some awesome eclipse plugin that makes modifications to <b>.project </b>file, and you hate that plugin and do not want to install it, and the<b> .project </b>file is in version control? Here's just a simple example that you could see while exporting a project with existing project files:</div><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-8XfAbM_6Sps/UBG2EX80gVI/AAAAAAAAQF0/4Y8GdLow54E/s1600/eclipse-example-error.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="52" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-8XfAbM_6Sps/UBG2EX80gVI/AAAAAAAAQF0/4Y8GdLow54E/s640/eclipse-example-error.png" width="640" /></a></div><br />This is so annoying to resolve this kind of problems. And all you want to do is just to open the project and proceed with your normal work.<br /><br />Here's more:<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9UXuYNNZdY4/UBG4l0qfY-I/AAAAAAAAQF8/Eeo2qg3ZOxo/s1600/twitter-yes-3.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9UXuYNNZdY4/UBG4l0qfY-I/AAAAAAAAQF8/Eeo2qg3ZOxo/s1600/twitter-yes-3.png" /></a></div><br /><div style="text-align: justify;">Currently, I use IntelliJ and the rest of the team uses Eclipse. And I absolutely do not care if they put the project files into version control, because I will import it into my IDE in two clicks anyway. So the assumption that <i>"absolutely yes, given that the team is working with the same IDEs"</i> is wrong, and no viable argument here as well.&nbsp;</div><br />However, here we have some much more interesting ideas:<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-e2WO1xc63pI/UBG5lFCrBfI/AAAAAAAAQGE/D_vS9pbsUss/s1600/twitter-yesno-1.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-e2WO1xc63pI/UBG5lFCrBfI/AAAAAAAAQGE/D_vS9pbsUss/s1600/twitter-yesno-1.png" /></a></div><br /><div style="text-align: justify;">Wow, this is really interesting one - "those that define formatting or source code". Indeed! In cases when you work on varions projects for different clients, the requirements and code styles might be quite different and it makes sense even to keep this kind of files in version control, so you can share it with the team and restore the code style settings if you lost them. Good point here!</div><br />However, you can probably see the vector of my post now.<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-dbMU8wR1prk/UBG7QpYkx9I/AAAAAAAAQGc/Uwf_UmkXoQ0/s1600/maven2.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-dbMU8wR1prk/UBG7QpYkx9I/AAAAAAAAQGc/Uwf_UmkXoQ0/s1600/maven2.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3UGbrrtNwbk/UBG7RLxvq1I/AAAAAAAAQGg/sWb_KuZIBrM/s1600/maven3.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3UGbrrtNwbk/UBG7RLxvq1I/AAAAAAAAQGg/sWb_KuZIBrM/s1600/maven3.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-G2Xtw3WZ8EI/UBG7Ox042iI/AAAAAAAAQGU/z0rEZUS94_A/s1600/maven1.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-G2Xtw3WZ8EI/UBG7Ox042iI/AAAAAAAAQGU/z0rEZUS94_A/s1600/maven1.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-43tQeUIZxig/UBG-1kzLYFI/AAAAAAAAQG8/YRzJqSa3qSA/s1600/maven4.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-43tQeUIZxig/UBG-1kzLYFI/AAAAAAAAQG8/YRzJqSa3qSA/s1600/maven4.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><br /><div style="text-align: justify;">So the point is, IDEs support Maven quite well, so why on earth I would need to keep the IDE settings in version control if we already have what we need: <b>pom.xml</b>. IntelliJ and NetBeans cope with that quite well, and Eclipse also, if you use <a href="http://www.jboss.org/tools/">JBoss Tools</a>.</div><br />But what if I'm a Maven hater? (I really am). Here's an interesting conversation:<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-ugMEYeGhIGU/UBG8piW4u_I/AAAAAAAAQG0/gjak2U8yxWk/s1600/maven-etc.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-ugMEYeGhIGU/UBG8piW4u_I/AAAAAAAAQG0/gjak2U8yxWk/s1600/maven-etc.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">Oh sure, Gradle that is! Well, the IDE support isn't there yet. Luckily, STS provides a nice Gradle plugin for Eclipse, but the support for IntelliJ and NetBeans isn't quite there yet.</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><div style="text-align: justify;"><span style="background-color: white;">However, my claim is that Maven or Gradle isn't the prerequisite to avoid the project files in version control. The real prerequisite is the simple setup of you project and a clean structure, so that importing the project is just a couple of clicks. Then you can cope with any kind of project, even if it doesn't contain pom.xml.</span></div></div><br />And here's what most of them say about the topic:<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-By8MgZlVC7A/UBG_lU444fI/AAAAAAAAQHE/gmtUs18YI2k/s1600/yes1.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-By8MgZlVC7A/UBG_lU444fI/AAAAAAAAQHE/gmtUs18YI2k/s1600/yes1.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-aQLwAA5rkIs/UBG_mLkzFlI/AAAAAAAAQHM/A2DxBwrIdTI/s1600/yes2.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-aQLwAA5rkIs/UBG_mLkzFlI/AAAAAAAAQHM/A2DxBwrIdTI/s1600/yes2.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-YExWA45cX48/UBG_nVws-_I/AAAAAAAAQHQ/-bak9eGwNmA/s1600/yes3.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-YExWA45cX48/UBG_nVws-_I/AAAAAAAAQHQ/-bak9eGwNmA/s1600/yes3.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-MEAN6YVzYzA/UBHX_y76kDI/AAAAAAAAQHc/KSe03CuIPiw/s1600/no1.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-MEAN6YVzYzA/UBHX_y76kDI/AAAAAAAAQHc/KSe03CuIPiw/s1600/no1.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-ovS65GXhIXI/UBHYA9t-G5I/AAAAAAAAQHk/j47d_tIKI-0/s1600/no2.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-ovS65GXhIXI/UBHYA9t-G5I/AAAAAAAAQHk/j47d_tIKI-0/s1600/no2.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-O4OFHgMDD4Q/UBHYBl0t8HI/AAAAAAAAQHo/fzsxgHfxvE4/s1600/no3.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-O4OFHgMDD4Q/UBHYBl0t8HI/AAAAAAAAQHo/fzsxgHfxvE4/s1600/no3.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hEFpTKJJfnM/UBHYCF6Q5kI/AAAAAAAAQHw/I5iZUqMv-pg/s1600/no4.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hEFpTKJJfnM/UBHYCF6Q5kI/AAAAAAAAQHw/I5iZUqMv-pg/s1600/no4.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-picue_uDPN4/UBHYDJqkB5I/AAAAAAAAQIE/n7OO5s4jo3g/s1600/no6.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-picue_uDPN4/UBHYDJqkB5I/AAAAAAAAQIE/n7OO5s4jo3g/s1600/no6.png" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><br /><div style="text-align: justify;">Myself, I have tried both ways - keeping the project files in version control and not checking them in, and my take is that under no circumstances it is a good idea to check the project files in. Again, a much better solution is to keep your project structure clean and simple, which might be harder than to check the files into version control, but much more beneficial on the long run.</div><br />Thanks everyone for the input! Take care...<br /><br /><br /></div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/1wxKa_B5p_0" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="933b677e9f54d2ddabd6e9b6ed334317" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/5sdIMuXXM_Y/do-you-really-get-classloaders.html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://jrebel.com">JRebel</a> team has produced a nice-looking <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/labs/rebel-labs-tutorial-do-you-really-get-classloaders/">PDF about Java classloaders</a>. This should be a very nice read for everyone who wants to know more about Java platform fundamentals. <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/5sdIMuXXM_Y" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="77d156a97f6480ae73eec11c50b03202" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/AqjB7LXXlVA/con-fess-2012-day-2.html"><![CDATA[<p>I had great fun speaking at Con-FESS today. Here are my <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/arhan/why-doesnt-java-has-instant-turnaround-confess-2012">slides</a> for the <i>Why Doesn't Java Have Instant Turnaround</i> talk. The internet connection was great so I even managed to make a <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/software/jrebel/remoting/">JRebel Remoting</a> demo with <a href="http://jelastic.com">Jelastic PaaS</a>.</p> <p>After that, we had a great time investigating <a href="https://github.com/griffon">Griffon</a> framework internals with <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/aalmiray">Andres Almiray</a>. Although it is quite tricky to update desktop applications on the fly, it seems it is still possible and Griffon will be able to leverage JRebel facilities.</p> <p><a href="https://twitter.com/#!/pniederw">Peter Niederwieser</a> talked about <a href="http://2012.con-fess.com/sessions/-/details/157/Gradle-in-the-Enterprise">Gradle in the enterprise</a>. Gradle is just about to go 1.0 which is great. The tooling is getting better and there are very nice features in Gradle that simplify build procedure and build script implementation - true incremental builds, autowiring, dsl extensions, etc. What is really missing at the moment is the stable way to migrate Maven projects to Gradle (there are some scripts, but these aren't quite stable) and the native release plugin. It is quite interesting that Gradle has implemented its own dependency management solution and isn't based on Ivy any more.</p> <p><a href="https://twitter.com/#!/darthvader42">Stefan Armbruster</a> talked about using Grails with Neo4j graph database. It seems that it doesn't integrate that smoothly yet - some minor glitches still exist, but nevertheless it was used for a production application.</p> <center><div style="width:425px" id="__ss_12846487"> <strong style="display:block;margin:12px 0 4px"><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/arhan/why-doesnt-java-has-instant-turnaround-confess-2012" title="Why Doesn&#39;t Java Have Instant Turnaround - Con-FESS 2012" target="_blank">Why Doesn&#39;t Java Has Instant Turnaround - Con-FESS 2012</a></strong> <iframe src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/12846487" width="425" height="355" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe> <div style="padding:5px 0 12px"> View more <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/thecroaker/death-by-powerpoint" target="_blank">PowerPoint</a> from <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/arhan" target="_blank">Anton Arhipov</a> </div> </div></center> The video recording of the talk is available at Con-FESS website: <a href="http://2012.con-fess.com/sessions/-/details/139/Why-doesnt-Java-have-instant-turnaround">http://2012.con-fess.com/sessions/-/details/139/Why-doesnt-Java-have-instant-turnaround</a><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/AqjB7LXXlVA" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e02110a9b390626d865a4e3b3a77e3be" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/bK6f-wM0BA0/java-build-tools-survey-results.html"><![CDATA[<p>Here come the results for the last week's Java build tools survey. 675 people responded - thanks everyone who contributed!</p> <p>The answers were not mutually exclusive and a good portion of responders selected several answers. I interpret that as "I use Maven at work and Gradle at home". Or maybe there are multiple projects that the guys are working on and the old projects aren't migrated from Ant to Maven/Gradle.</p> <p>Anyways, here are the results:</p> <center><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9PV4HGbZILY/Uf81KVbFc0I/AAAAAAAARXM/Iqi4spbk8WY/s1600/java-build-tools-results.png" /></center> <p>480 out of 675 people indicated that they use Maven, which makes 71.1% out of all responders. Actually this number somehow matches my personal assumption about Maven share. Jason actually confirmed that this should be in line with the previous similar surveys:</p>   <center><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p><a href="https://twitter.com/antonarhipov">@antonarhipov</a> That’s in line with other surveys for the last few years. The 60% is converging toward 85% Maven usage rate from Central.</p>&mdash; Jason van Zyl (@jvanzyl) <a href="https://twitter.com/jvanzyl/statuses/362911688452231168">August 1, 2013</a></blockquote><script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></center> <p>Gradle was used 235 people out of 675, which makes 34.8%. I was quite surprised by the number and I think this is due that the survey was mostly published via Twitter - I have some followers from Groovy/Gradle community. While I do believe that Gradle is getting momentum as a build tool, I really doubt that its share is high in Java enterprise/legacy projects. </p> <p>Ant (+Ivy) was mentioned by 114 responders and is at the third place with 16.9%. I think this number will be much much higher if we take only the legacy/enterprise projects.</p> <b>Maven vs Gradle vs Ant</b> <p>I think that there's no Maven vs Ant debate any more. Maven has won. Tooling support is (mostly) excellent and setting up a Maven projects in all major Java IDEs is (mostly) a no-brainer. There's definitely the Maven vs Gradle debate - there's plenty of details to debate about, which is better (at the moment of writing this post). But yet again, tooling support for Maven is the main argument why Maven is better. I think that <u>without good IDE support Gradle won't overtake the build tools' market share</u>, period.</p> <p><b>BTW</b>, I'll keep the <a href="http://arhipov.blogspot.com/2013/07/java-build-tools-survey.html"><b>survey</b></a> opened for some time - maybe it will get more responses.</p> <p><b>P.S.</b> There's a good summary about the build tools at <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/devprod-report-redux-build-tools-thoughts-for-2013-with-gradles-hans-dockter/#!/">Rebel Labs</a>, if you're interested.</p> <p><b>UPDATE:</b> SBT was the 4th in the standings. 2.8% of respondents have indicated that they use SBT.<p> <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/bK6f-wM0BA0" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3dd80e07df08eb51b9b9962196d3e5be" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/Fg5SQrvukGo/back-from-33rd-degree.html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://33degree.org/">33rd Degree</a> conference have changed location this year. This time the action took place in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Warsaw">Warsaw</a>. It seems that 33rd Degree has outgrown its venue in Krakow and the organizers decided to pursue the possibility to expand the conference.  <h1>The venue</h1> <p>I realized that the venue "configuration" counts a lot. This time the conference was located equally on 2 floors of the <a href="http://www.gromada.pl/">Gromada Airport</a> hotel. Actually it was a fair separation for both vendors and speakers, but there's a caveat. If the fancier sponsors are on the top floor and the most famous speakers are there as well, then the vendors who locate in the "bunker" should be worried. Actually the speakers who get to speak in the other floor should be worried as well. Literally, on the first day when I arrived, I could not wait in the line for a cup of tea at the top floor and at the same time it was dead empty at the bottom floor. This is just how the crowd moves, and it is very hard to fix it.</p> <h1>My talks</h1> <p>My first talk <i><b>Do you really get your IDE?</b></i> happened to take place at the bottom floor at the same time when a beer party was starting at the top floor. I was almost sure that noone will be interested in coming to the talk and my bet was that only 5-10 people would show up. I was totally wrong. The room was full. Very surprising. Since it was a BOF format and a lot time was consumed by conversations in the middle of the talk, I didn't really cover all the cool tricks that I wanted but I would count this talk pretty successful anyway - it was fun and entertaining. I hope I can "sharpen the saw" in delivering this talk a bit more since people really enjoy learning the tools.</p> <center><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-qJhHKvRiroE/UUekyJdNDGI/AAAAAAAAQtE/rKGobAakkjk/s1600/boromir_mem_intellij_ctrl_s.jpg" imageanchor="1" ><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-qJhHKvRiroE/UUekyJdNDGI/AAAAAAAAQtE/rKGobAakkjk/s320/boromir_mem_intellij_ctrl_s.jpg" /></a></center> <p>My second talk was about JRebel and how it can be used for updating Java applications. Not so many people came this time, probably because JRebel is a well known tool already and <a href="https://twitter.com/jbaruch">Baruch</a> has dragged all the attendees in his talk instead.</p> <h1>Other talks</h1> <p>I usually don't attend that many sessions at the conferences since I know a lot of speakers personally and can learn from them directly in off-line conversations. However, this time I decided to go and listen and learn some cool stuff at the sessions.</p> <p><b><i>Leading the technical change by Nathaniel Schutta</i></b>. The talk title and abstract did not fire up my curiosity. I just know that <a href="https://twitter.com/ntschutta">Nathaniel</a> has a style delivering the presentations and I wanted to go and learn from his performance. The idea is very simple actually: instead of bullet points Nathaniel creates a slide per bullet point and makes it look attractive so that when the next slides comes he can see it from his laptop screen and then he knows what and how he should say. That is why the delivery is so smooth, no matter which topic he presents. Of course Nathaniel didn't skip the book he co-authored, the <a href="http://presentationpatterns.com/">Presentation Patterns</a> - very useful book for everyone who wants to present at the conferences.</p> <p><b><i>Being Honest - Rethinking Enterprise Java by Adam Bien.</i></b> <a href="https://twitter.com/adambien">Adam</a> is a very energetic speaker and I actually like his presentations about Java EE very much. But this time the technical aspects of the presentation didn't do good. The large room was full, but the screen was way too small for everyone to see the code. Plus the mic wasn't really working and it was quite hard to listen, so I could help myself but leave the room for some other talk.</p> <center><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-_QC8VSeWdlU/UUeYcfHzNqI/AAAAAAAAQss/4IyeEt3d01A/s1600/33-adam-bien-talk.jpg" imageanchor="1" ><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-_QC8VSeWdlU/UUeYcfHzNqI/AAAAAAAAQss/4IyeEt3d01A/s320/33-adam-bien-talk.jpg" /></a></center> <p>So I made it to the talk about <b><i>Kotlin by Hadi Hariri</i></b>. Kotlin's ecosystem is doing great steps forward. Unfortunately I didn't see the whole talk. In the part that I grasped this time Hadi was talking about the features that allow creating DSLs and he presented his own development, <a href="https://github.com/hhariri/spek">Spek</a>, the specification framework for Kotlin.</p> <center><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-kYywnNUfPbQ/UUea0lQKOhI/AAAAAAAAQs0/hbrYcrheaL0/s1600/33-hadi-hariri-talk.jpg" imageanchor="1" ><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-kYywnNUfPbQ/UUea0lQKOhI/AAAAAAAAQs0/hbrYcrheaL0/s320/33-hadi-hariri-talk.jpg" /></a></center> <p><b><i>Scripted: Embracing Eclipse Orion by Martin Lippert</i></b>. This was very unfortunate. Very nice talk about very nice tool with almost empty room. I call it "bad marketing". <a href="https://twitter.com/martinlippert">Martin</a> is a good speaker and he talks about interesting topics, but it seems the title of the talk turned off the crowd. Who cares about Eclipse Orion at this kind of conference? Besides, nothing in the talk was really about Eclipse Orion. It was about <a href="https://github.com/scripted-editor/scripted/">Scripted</a> - a kick-ass browser based JavaScript editor, very interesting R&D project developed at SpringSource/VMWare.</p> <p><b><i>Programming with Lambda Expressions in Java by Venkat Subramaniam.</i></b> <a href="https://twitter.com/venkat_s">Venkat's</a> talks are so perfect it is hard to get a seat in the room. Attendees usually occupy the room in advance before the talk starts and those who are late steal the chairs from other rooms in order to get a seat. Nothing really advanced in the topic, but Venkat presents it with passion. Very entertaining.</p> <p><b><i>How we took our server-side application to the Cloud and liked what we got</i></b> by <a href="https://twitter.com/jbaruch">Baruch Sadogursky</a>. Very interesting talk for those who want to learn the basics of multy-tenancy and approaches in implementation for SaaS. Baruch talked about the solution <a href="http://www.jfrog.com/home/v_artifactory_opensource_overview">they</a> chose for the hosted version of <a href="http://www.jfrog.com/home/v_artifactorypro_overview">Artifactory</a> - what were the challenges and pitfalls. </p> <center><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ccl-SuuaITM/UUehoKhK3LI/AAAAAAAAQs8/RJsCjf-2LSw/s1600/33-baruch-talk.jpg" imageanchor="1" ><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ccl-SuuaITM/UUehoKhK3LI/AAAAAAAAQs8/RJsCjf-2LSw/s320/33-baruch-talk.jpg" /></a></center>  <h1>Overall</h1> <p>33rd Degree was definitely a success for the organizers but still there's plenty of details to improve: technical equipment would be the first on the list. Something needs to be done for managing the crowd - most of the time people are late for the sessions by a lot (with exception for the Venkat's talks). This is very distracting for the speakers, I think, even if they say it is not.</p> <p>The great thing about 33rd Degree is that <a href="https://twitter.com/grzegorzduda">Grzegorz</a> works super-hard to organize it all: get the great (NFJS) speakers, cool vendors (Atlassian, Plumbr, JetBrains, etc), and the venue, which is actually very nice: plenty of space, great food, very close to the airport. plus, the price for the conference is still very affordable.</p>    <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/Fg5SQrvukGo" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ee5fa7200adc848c2796c6ba61f545a8" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/FMtZodrTe7k/slides-mastering-java-bytecode.html"><![CDATA[<center><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/arhan/mastering-java-bytecode" title="Mastering Java Bytecode - JAX.de 2012" target="_blank">Mastering Java Bytecode - JAX.de 2012</a><br/><iframe src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/12595662" width="425" height="355" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></center><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/FMtZodrTe7k" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="dfb8ff18c072bf2fa09eb237d96023ee" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/HLEkkIYBadE/xpdays-kiev-continuous-delivery.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><a href="http://xpdays.com.ua/">XPDays in Kiev</a> was a success! Great crowd, interesting talks and fruitful discussions, socializing included.<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-XSEbIpwDYkc/UKlw02K6xMI/AAAAAAAAQTQ/jGGJFlE0F34/s1600/xpdays-badge.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-XSEbIpwDYkc/UKlw02K6xMI/AAAAAAAAQTQ/jGGJFlE0F34/s320/xpdays-badge.jpg" width="256" /></a>Embedded are the slides from by <b>import continuous.delivery.*</b> talk which was surprisingly well received and it seems a lot of people are looking for ways to release and deploy continuously, even in the large organizations.</div><br />There are numerous different tools that could be used to organize the continuous delivery pipeline. The pipeline that I've demonstrated was built with <a href="http://jenkins-ci.org/">Jenkins</a>, <a href="http://www.jfrog.com/home/v_artifactorypro_overview">Artifactory</a> (Pro) and <a href="http://liverebel.com/">LiveRebel</a>.<br /><br />I'm not super happy with the <a href="https://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/Build+Pipeline+Plugin">build pipeline plugin</a> in <b>Jenkins</b>. In the talk I had to spend time explaining why the flow is organized the way it is and why the build pipeline plugin behaves the way it behaves. It is just buggy... I should find time to fix it.<br /><br /><a href="http://www.jfrog.com/home/v_artifactorypro_overview">Arifactory's Pro</a> version was just primarily because of the fact that artifact promotion feature is a Pro version and some of the REST APIs that I wanted to use were under Pro license. There are alternatives, but with Artifactory it was just much easier to show the relevant stuff.<br /><br /><a href="http://liverebel.com/">LiveRebel</a> - well, there's no real alternative to it. The attendees were really impressed how easy it is to deploy via LiveRebel and oversee the target environment.<br /><br />The cool part is that all the tools integrate well via the REST API (or CLI) and you can build a very flexible pipeline if this kind of integration is available. What I also realized is that although everything can be automated in the pipeline, it shouldn't get on your way still - you should be able to go into any step and re-execute if needed.<br /><br />Another critical feature is the rollback functionality. It is not just that you select the previous version of the app if something goes wrong. There's more things you have to keep in mind when organizing the pipeline (I'm not revealing it now :P).<br /><br />Enjoy the slides! :)<br /><br /><center><table width="600"><tr><td><script async="async" class="speakerdeck-embed" data-id="5e58f3e01402013077d112313d1a82a3" data-ratio="1.2994923857868" src="//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js"></script></td></tr></table></center></div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/HLEkkIYBadE" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="876593e4dd84dca2d5f017e58ebe6a6" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/IvwAWWJXJnk/talking-at-33rd-degree-conference.html"><![CDATA[<p>Once again, I'm back to <a href="http://2013.33degree.org/">33rd Degree</a> conference, taking place in Warsaw on March 13-15.</p> <center><a href="http://2013.33degree.org/" imageanchor="1" ><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-3Lr1xpn6Rx4/UTtOcoBCgQI/AAAAAAAAQsc/Vo2iyZIDibs/s320/33degree2013.png" /></a></center> <p>I'm going to have 2 talks there:</p> <p><b><a href="http://2013.33degree.org/talk/show/56">Do you really get your IDE?</a></b>, which is actually a BOF. This is my first time experience in running a BOF, so I'm not really sure how it turns out. I want to discuss with the folks, how the IDEs are used and how are the developers using the IDEs. I will play a bit with the code in IntelliJ IDEA and probably jump into other IDEs as well.</p>   <p><b><a href="http://2013.33degree.org/talk/show/57">Reloading Java applications like a Pro.</a></b> At many conferences I've been talking about the very root of the turnaround problems in Java, the reasons and pitfalls. But this time I decided that it would be much more fun to showcase what JRebel can do for different types of Java applications. I plan to talk about the mechanics of the updates and what is happening inside Java application when JRebel is doing it work. Hopefully I can fit several demo scenarios into the talk: for Spring based application, for JavaEE, maybe something for non-conventional apps and desktop apps (e.g. JavaFX).</p> <p>I'm glad that 33rd Degree organizers allowed me to talk about JRebel directly. At many conferences the organizers are actually quite hesitant to accept any talks about commercial products. However, every time I give a talk on some technical topic, the attendees actually are eager to ask questions about JRebel rather than about the talk topic itself. It means that JRebel is more interesting, than, for instance, Java bytecode. So why bother about the commercial side of it?</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/IvwAWWJXJnk" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bf490eb9b3821241cad67c307e14132e" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/j0yrCxmSNng/automating-intellij-idea-plug-in.html"><![CDATA[<p>In the <a href="http://arhipov.blogspot.com/2013/10/managing-dependencies-for-intellij-idea.html">previous post</a> I wrote about managing the dependencies for IntelliJ IDEA plugin development and generating the project files. This was pretty simple and here's the full script:</p> <pre><br /><code><br />apply plugin: "java"<br />apply plugin: "idea"<br /><br />repositories {<br />    jcenter()<br />    maven {<br />        credentials {<br />            username 'username'<br />            password 'password'<br />        }<br />        url "http://my.repository.url<br />    }<br />}<br /><br />dependencies {<br />    compile('org.zeroturnaround:jr-sdk:5.4.1') {<br />        transitive = false<br />    }<br />    compile 'org.ow2.asm:asm-all:4.1'<br />    compile 'org.slf4j:slf4j-nop:1.6.3'<br />    compile 'org.apache.commons:commons-compress:1.2'<br />}<br /><br />defaultTasks 'setup'<br /><br />idea.project.ipr {<br />    beforeMerged { project -><br />        project.modulePaths.clear()<br />    }<br />}<br /><br />idea.module.iml {<br />    withXml {<br />        it.node.@type = "PLUGIN_MODULE"<br />    }<br />}<br /><br />task setup {<br />   description = "crete .idea based project structure"<br />   dependsOn ideaModule, ideaProject<br />   doLast {<br />     copy {<br />        from '.'<br />        into '.idea/'<br />        include '*.ipr'<br />        rename { "modules.xml" }<br />     }<br />     project.delete "${project.name}.ipr"<br />   }<br />}<br /><br />task wrapper(type: Wrapper) {<br />    gradleVersion = '1.8'<br />}<br /></code><br /></pre> <p>The script is only limited to <b>pulling down the dependencies</b> from binary repository and <b>generating the project files</b>. However, one really big thing is missing here, is the SDK setup. Adding the new SDK for plugin development is <a href="http://confluence.jetbrains.com/display/IDEADEV/Getting+Started+with+Plugin+Development">simple enough</a>, but I still have a good reason to automate that. In my plugin, there's a dependency on some SDK artifacts that are not included into SDK classpath by default. So adding the dependencies one by one into the SDK via the UI is a bit tedious and not really encouraging for the team work.</p> <p>It would be cool if the script could register the <b>IntelliJ Platform Plugin SDK</b> and add it into the project files. It turns out that it should be doable as the SDK definitions are stored in <b>options/jdk.table.xml</b> file in <a href="http://devnet.jetbrains.com/docs/DOC-181">IntelliJ IDEA's configuration directory</a>.</p> <p>It might be a bit brittle to go tinkering with the file directly, so maybe <a href="https://github.com/JetBrains/intellij-community/tree/master/jps">JPS API</a> could actually be used to add a new entry for the SDK. <i>(just an idea)</i></p> <p>Those would be the steps for automating the setup:</p><ol><li>Fetch dependencies and generate .idea directory based project</li><li>Generate Platform SDK entry to options/jdk.table.xml and add the reference to project *.iml file and .idea/misc.xml file</li><li>Optionally, add more dependencies to Platform SDK definition</li><li>The final step is the to add the build and release logic to the script</li></ol> <p><u>Now, a little bit of dreaming :-)</u></p> <p>In the ideal world, the steps could be described as properties in build.gradle file:</p><ol><li><b>idea.module.type="PLUGIN_MODULE"</b> - resolve as plugin module</li><li><b>idea.project.sdk=auto</b> (and <b>idea.module.sdk=auto</b>) - auto-generate the SDK entry (with good defaults) and add it to the project and module</li><li>The extra SDK dependencies are probably something that needs a special care. Don't know what could be the best workaround, but maybe something like this:<br/> <pre>idea.project.sdk.dependencies {<br />   lib1.jar<br />   lib2.jar<br />   lib3.jar<br />}</pre> </li><li>Build script would basically mimic the autogenerated the Ant file, and release step actually requires a bit more than just changing the version of the artifact: the version in META-INF/plugin.xml has to be updated as well.</li></ol> <p>Dreaming aside, I think that the steps described above could be automated with a reasonable effort. So I better go and <a href="https://github.com/gradle/gradle/tree/master/subprojects/ide">fork gradle idea plugin</a> now... stay tuned :)</p>           <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/j0yrCxmSNng" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="633d53252e64a3472a484f923438f5b5" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/kFT3c_MdVtM/im-speaking-at-javazone-again-this-year.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://jz12.java.no/news" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="181" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-kErGg9_SAPk/UAndesZYpYI/AAAAAAAAQFQ/bZBqokN2Jg8/s200/splashlogo.png" width="200" /></a></div>I'm <a href="http://javazone.no/incogito10/events/JavaZone%202012/sessions#f3b272f5-76a0-4588-80db-d426ad0e4934">speaking</a> at JavaZone again this year. Hope to give an overview of javaagent and Instrumentation API with some referrals to the interesting use cases.</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/kFT3c_MdVtM" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ab4f4079062c2e16943f8d22cc797f96" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/lzM1JKG-6WA/con-fess-2012-day-1.html"><![CDATA[<p>Although the <a href="http://2012.con-fess.com/">Con-FESS conference</a> attendance doesn't seem to be very high, around 200 people, it still was a good idea to come here. Look at this:</p><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-L1WUQi50GmY/T6gqAFgrPqI/AAAAAAAAPKs/4PeXP2OhXD4/s1600/IMAG0850.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="301" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-L1WUQi50GmY/T6gqAFgrPqI/AAAAAAAAPKs/4PeXP2OhXD4/s400/IMAG0850.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><p>Nice view, eh? :)</p> <p>First, I've attended to keynote talk by Jürgen Höller, <a href="http://2012.con-fess.com/sessions/-/details/153/Enterprise-Java-in-2012-and-Beyond---From-Java-EE-6-to-Cloud-Computing">Enterprise Java in 2012 and Beyond - From Java EE 6 to Cloud Computing</a>. The talk was about the current trends towards cloud platforms. Cloud is a hot topic for Java EE 7 these days. The term "cloud" spawns across quite different technologies, not just Java. For instance, alternative datastores are quite popular among quite providers as these allow for better scalability. As the implementations are so different it is quite hard to imagine any reasonable standardization in this area. And even for Java, the vendors agree just on some bits of the standard, like Servlets, for instance. To my mind, the diversity will only grow in the cloud era.</p> <p>Also, it will be interesting to see how to tooling will evolve in some time. I'm quite sure that <a href="http://www.jboss.org/tools">JBoss Tools</a> and <a href="http://www.springsource.com/developer/sts">STS</a>, as well as <a href="https://developers.google.com/eclipse/">Google Eclipse plugin</a> are aiming for this use case. With JRebel, it is now also <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/jrebel/remoting">possible</a> to update application code in the cloud. I'm quite sure, in near future we will see some new tooling specially designed for the cloud apps but as the diversity is quite high, these tools will most likely be PaaS-specific.</p> <p>Next, I've attended the talk about <a href="http://2012.con-fess.com/sessions/-/details/112/The-Groovy-Ecosystem">Groovy ecosystem</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/aalmiray">Andres Almiray</a>. It was an overview of the frameworks and libraries build with Groovy and for Groovy: Grails, Griffon, Gaelyk, Caelyf, Gradle, Gant, Codenark, GMetrics, Easyb. Not that much into the details, but a good overview.</p> <p>I learned a lot from <a href="http://2012.con-fess.com/sessions/-/details/130/CDI-for-Experts">Mark Struberg's talk about CDI</a> and it really terrifies me how complex it might get with all the annotation-based programming model that CDI offers. Especially with the CDI extensions. Especially if people will start use this extensively. It is fine if people could stick with the libraries like <a href="http://myfaces.apache.org/extensions/cdi/">CODI</a>, <a href="http://sfwk.org/Seam3">Seam3</a>, or <a href="http://wiki.apache.org/incubator/DeltaSpikeProposal">Apache DeltaSpike</a>, but the perspective that the annotations are scattered across the source code and the developer can't see the full view at once really frightens me.</p> <p>Mark covered the standardization pitfalls as well as the gotchas when writing a CDI-based apps - very informative! He warned us from using @ApplicationScope for the beans as it isn't quite clear how this should work and the application containers can interpret this a bit differently, either for a whole EAR deployment or just for WAR deployment boundaries. It seems he had a lot more information to tell and he didn't fit everything in this talk, but we also had an interesting discussion afterwards. Here's a <a href="http://twitpic.com/9ihqdt">rage comic</a> I came up with afterwards :)</p> <p>Last, I attended the talk about <a href="http://2012.con-fess.com/sessions/-/details/102/Next-Generation---Systems-Integration-in-the-Cloud-Era">systems integration of could-based services</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/KaiWaehner">Kai Wähner</a>. The presentation covered the introduction to Apache Camel and how it was used to integrate with Amazon Web Services and Google App Engine. </p> <p>The conference is hosted <a href="http://2012.con-fess.com/location">in Leogang, a small village not far from Salzburg, in Hotel Krallerhof</a>. Surrounded with mountains, this place is amazing!</p> <div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VW1UZBmdLds/T6g1elogFYI/AAAAAAAAPK8/fSp9yZqaQ7M/s1600/IMAG0849.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left:1em; margin-right:1em"><img border="0" height="301" width="400" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VW1UZBmdLds/T6g1elogFYI/AAAAAAAAPK8/fSp9yZqaQ7M/s400/IMAG0849.jpg" /></a></div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/lzM1JKG-6WA" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e5c528034599d6eb4a815b0c8b570b48" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/Mugxty4_Z-E/java-ee-8-coherence-is-key.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">Java EE 7 was released just recently. And now it seems to be the time of preparing to the design on Java EE 8.  There are already some whichlists published in the blogs:<br /><br /><ul style="text-align: left;"><li><a href="http://antoniogoncalves.org/2013/07/18/java-ee-8-whislist/">Antonio Goncalves' Java EE 8 wishlist</a>&nbsp;</li><li><a href="http://arjan-tijms.blogspot.de/2013/07/java-ee-8-wish-list.html">Arjan Tijms’ - Java EE 8 wish list</a>&nbsp;</li></ul>I might we wrong, but I don't remember seeing (or hearing) from anyone what is the <b>ultimate goal</b> of all these improvements. IMO, Java EE should take a look on Ruby-on-Rails or Play! and try to inspire from the coherent nature of those frameworks. Currently, my feeling is that Java EE looks like a collection of different specs that integrate with each other to a certain degree. But actually to be productive, one shouldn’t care about the names of the specs (CDI, JAX-RS, EJB, etc), but instead “just write” the code. Java EE could just really align itself better with RoR.</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/Mugxty4_Z-E" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bea2f2ad34c0a18c723208f1b92125a1" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/OxFVlABJgN0/geekout-2013-tallinn-june-12-14.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://geekout.ee/">GeekOUT</a> conference started in 2011 as a local Java event. In 2013 it will be the 3rd coming for GeekOUT and the conference agenda is quite outstanding!</p> <center><a href="http://geekout.ee/conference/schedule/" imageanchor="1" ><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-pu8-xnEruyI/UWcn_9t0B3I/AAAAAAAAQtc/OeRCVdPGAIU/s320/geekout-logo-large.png" /></a></center> <p>There are 3 things about the conference that stand out:<br/><br/><b>Agenda</b> - 15 carefully selected talks. It is all about Java, JVM and JVM programming languages and tooling. <br/><b>Workshops</b> - a dedicated day for hands-on workshops. <br/><b>DemoGrounds</b> - a number of very cool vendors will be exhibiting: Hazelcast, CloudBees, Atlassian and more! <br/></p> <p>However, one interesting thing about the conference is that it takes place in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tallinn">Tallinn</a>. I can tell you for sure - Tallinn is absolutely awesome in June! Well, it usually is :) So if you are a Java developer and haven't been to Tallinn yet - now you have a good reason to visit the city!</p>   <center><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-GexY4GbxOQc/UWcuahYJNVI/AAAAAAAAQts/qPO5R21OQNA/s320/tallinn.png" /></center> <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/OxFVlABJgN0" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a3dab2a61da5bd838ff48bd790cbde5e" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/OYn2pWqyqWk/managing-dependencies-for-intellij-idea.html"><![CDATA[<p>Probably the most painful part in developing plugins for IntelliJ IDEA is the dependency management of the libraries that your plugin might depend on. There is a multitude of problems that one may encounter:</p> <ul><li>IDEA binaries are not hosted publicly neither in Maven Central, JCenter, or any other repository.</li><li>Plugins cannot be built with the common tools like Maven or Gradle without setting up your hair on fire.</li></ul> <p>When your plugin depends on just a few external libraries, and the plugin build itself doesn't require customization, then everything is simple: put the dependencies into lib/ (or whatever) folder in the project and generate the Ant build script through <b>Build -&gt; Generate Ant Build...</b> action. Simple. Well, not really simple: the generated build script will require a few JARs from IDEA by pointing to the IDEA installation directory. So the simplest thing to do in this case is to extract the full IntelliJ IDEA distribution into some directory at the machine where the continuous integration server runs.</p>   <div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-IS-sGyjwLYI/Um2VkzMnVAI/AAAAAAAAUxI/-qE-zrc8gFE/s1600/generate-ant-script.png" /></div> <p>Simple, ugly, but works. Why not to make things a bit more kosher?</p> <p>In my world, any developer in the team should be able to clone the project, open it in the IDE(A), and ideally, launch the project without any additional tuning.</p> <p>So what could we do in case of IntelliJ IDEA plugins projects? Store the *.iml files in VCS so that when the project is opened by another developer he would automatically have all the dependencies attached to the module? <a href="http://arhipov.blogspot.com/2012/07/ide-project-files-in-version-contro-yes.html">Not kosher</a>.</p> <div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-IRjk2or6Amw/Um2VHpnnp5I/AAAAAAAAUxA/wn33dgsaBNY/s1600/boromir_project_files_in_vcs.jpg" /></div> <p>For me, clearly, the dependencies should be managed by dependency management tool. Options: Maven, Ivy, Gradle. IDEA provides a very good Maven support. But not for its own plugin modules. In fact, for plugin modules I wouldn't even try to use Maven as once IDEA recognizes it as a Maven project, it will erase the information about its plugin origin.</p> <p>Other options: Ivy and Gradle. Ivy is awesome. It works. There's also a nice plugin for IDEA that will automatically import the dependencies if it locates ivy.xml in the project directory. In that case you could still use the autogenerated Ant build script - just alter it a bit so that it would make a call to ivy task to get the dependencies and incorporate 'em into the build classpath.</p> <p>Sounds a bit too hardcore to me. There's a high chance that the project import will not be as smooth as you would like it to be. Especially if the project structure isn't very trivial.</p> <p><center><b>Gradle to the rescue!</b></center></p> <p>Gradle is awesome when it comes to non-trivial project structures. Its Ant-like flexibility along with nice Groovy syntax and all the Maven-like goodies is just awesome!</p> <p>First of all, managing dependencies is very easy. For instance:</p> <pre><br />  repositories {<br />    jcenter()<br />  }<br /><br />  dependencies {<br />    compile('org.zeroturnaround:jr-sdk:5.4.1') {<br />        transitive = false<br />    }<br />    compile 'org.ow2.asm:asm-all:4.1'<br />    compile 'org.slf4j:slf4j-nop:1.6.3'<br />    compile 'org.apache.commons:commons-compress:1.2'<br />  }<br /></pre> <p>The little cool part is that JetGradle (in IDEA 12) would also automatically resolve and add the dependencies into the project.</p> <div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ATwHlpxkIbs/Um2aVHhrXKI/AAAAAAAAUxY/WpDvxJ5wSe0/s1600/jetgradle-dependencies.png" /></div> <p>This is cool but it is not enough. First of all, JetGradle cannot import the project as an IDEA plugin module. Secondly, there's no JetGradle in IDEA 13 as Gradle integration is getting a major overhaul. OK, back to the drawing board.</p> <p>There's an <a href="http://www.gradle.org/docs/current/userguide/idea_plugin.html">'idea'</a> plugin for Gradle, how cool is that?</p> Just run <b>gradle idea</b> and it will generate the project files, incorporating the references to the required dependencies. Good. But the generated module type is a Java module. And I need <u>Plugin module</u>. Have no fear, Gradle's here! We can easily customize the build script to adjust the XML project descriptor to our requirements.</o>  <pre><br />  apply plugin: "idea"<br /><br />  repositories { ... }<br />  dependencies { ... }<br /><br />  idea.project.ipr {<br />    beforeMerged { project -><br />      project.modulePaths.clear()<br />    }<br />  }<br /><br />  idea.module.iml {<br />    withXml {<br />      it.node.@type = "PLUGIN_MODULE"<br />    }<br />  }<br /></pre> <p>The <b>withXml</b> hook makes the magic here - instead of the auto-generated 'JAVA_MODULE' the final descriptor will contain 'PLUGIN_MODULE' which will make IDEA think that the module is an IntelliJ IDEA plugin.</p> <p>Only little problem that bothered me: the generated project descriptor is an *.ipr file that is kind of deprecated. It would have been much better if the plugin generated a directory based project metadata. The <a href="http://issues.gradle.org/browse/GRADLE-1041">feature request was filed long ago</a> but still isn't resolved.</p> <p>After experimenting with the project descriptors for a bit, I actually found a simple workaround for this minor annoyance. The <b>.idea</b> directory structure requires only <b>modules.xml</b> file that is identical to the <b>*.ipr</b> file that idea plugin generates. So I could just use this simple task to create directory based structure:</p> <pre><br />  task setup {<br />     dependsOn ideaModule, ideaProject<br />     doLast {<br />       copy {<br />          from '.'<br />          into '.idea/'<br />          include '*.ipr'<br />          rename { "modules.xml" }<br />       }<br />       project.delete "${project.name}.ipr"<br />     }<br />  }<br /></pre> <b>[hate mode="on"]</b>Just writing <b>delete "*.ipr"</b> would not work. That's annoying.<b>[hate mode="off"]</b> </p>So now I could just execute <b>gradle setup</b> and it would generate the directory based project structure, with the correct references to the required dependencies and I could import the project into IDEA without any hassle.</p> <p>This is all good. However, this is not the end of the story! There's more to do and more issues to resolve:</p> <ul><li>Get the required IDEA internal artifacts to a local repository, so that these dependencies could also be downloaded via Gradle dependency manager.</li><li>Migrate auto-generated Ant build script into Gradle script.</li><li>Adopt the Gradle script to be able to manage the releases of the plugin.</li></ul> <p>However, <b>[hate mode="on"]</b>none of this hassle would be needed if IntelliJ IDEA provided a sane way of building the plugins and managing the dependencies.<b>[hate mode="off"]</b></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/OYn2pWqyqWk" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e60eaa0d8794fa9d2f8e1b2392aec9ee" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/p4eCSj-Z4lA/javaone-2013-apples-and-oranges.html"><![CDATA[<center><iframe type="text/html" width="420" height="290" mozallowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true" src="http://parleys.com/share.html#play/525418a2e4b0c4f11ec576da" frameborder="0">&lt;br /&gt;</iframe></center><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/p4eCSj-Z4lA" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ccd498fe21a24ae594e2b57c8faac70b" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/pfQBSjA43-M/do-you-really-get-your-ide.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">This is bit like a philosophical post. Just some thoughts regarding our perception of developer tooling.&nbsp; <br /><br />First - a question. Which IDE do you use? Eclipse? NetBeans? IntelliJ IDEA? Visual Studio? Vim? Emacs? Yeah, really - Vim counts as an IDE as long as you can configure it to behave like one. Or maybe Sublime Text, a really awesome text editor?<br /><br />Second question. Do you leverage the full power of your favourite IDE/editor?<br /><br />Mostly, people will say that the <b>just use</b> the IDE and I haven't really seen many people leveraging the power of refactorings, shortcuts, other awesome IDE features that are out there. Why? Lazy?&nbsp;Careless? Neglectful?<br /><br />I was reading a nice theory article <a href="http://osteele.com/posts/2004/11/ides">The IDE Divide</a>, which is already 8 years old. The point of the article is that it points out two extremes among the developers: <b>language mavens</b> and <b>tooling mavens</b>. Language mavens are those who case about the deepest nuances in the programming languages and don't really want to rely on tools (or just don't have time to explore the features of the tools). Tooling mavens are the ones who are obsessed with learning (and creating?) the tools and not spending as much time discovering the mysteries of language features. The article also mentioned that it is enormously hard to be both, the language maven and the tools maven at the same time, since the time for learning all this stuff is limited.<br /><br />But generally, I think, knowing the properties language and runtime is more important as it is the produced code that will eventually run on the system. The tools are just used to create the programs. However, I rather consider myself a "tooling maven" type of developer. Not that I don't care about the languages, no. It is just the interest shift towards tools for me.<br /><br />Despite the above, I noticed something (or it is just my perception). When a the new-born programmer starts, you will first try to reach the comfortable level of using the language. Once you're successful, there comes time for you to write the programs more effectively - faster, using shortcuts… click, click, click. This is where the tooling kicks in. Eventually, you start appreciate those nice features of your IDE that help you to write the code more effectively. The next stage is when you realize that actually you do not write code as much as you read it, and then you will start to appreciate the features that help you to navigate the code, analyze it, maybe refactor it. Language becomes a bit unimportant.<br /><br />I was chatting with <a href="http://jlaskowski.blogspot.com/">Jacek Laskowski</a> one day and he asked an interesting question: <i>"If you're given awesome tools/components/frameworks to work with, would you really care about which programming language to use?"</i>. Really good question. I wouldn't care, I guess. You will learn the language anyway. Or you will learn the tooling anyway once you're comfortable with the language of your choice, because normally you would like to be more effective (this is my perception of curious programmers, I hope you <i>are</i> a curious programmer).<br /><br />What do you feel when a colleague next to you just moves around the project like a pro and finds everything he needs just in fractions of a second, and types with shortcuts creating new statements with just a few strokes? And then you try to type: <i>'p' 'u' 'b' 'l' 'i' 'c' '_' 's' 't' 'a' 't' 'i' 'c' '_' 'v' 'o' 'i' 'd' '_' 'm' 'a' 'i' 'l'</i> [oooops! a typo!]. Frustrating…<br /><br />It is every so often I was keeping myself back from screaming at my colleague "just Ctrl+Shift+E !!!!" while the team mate was looking for the class in the project tree the name of which he did not remember.<br /><br />&nbsp;Modern IDEs have revolutionized the way in which we are able to work with the code. Sadly, most programmers are held back by some mysterious myth that if you learn the tools too much you're doomed as a programmer as you start depending on those tools. Don't be held back by such fears! Go <a href="http://arhipov.blogspot.com/2011/06/whats-cool-in-intellijidea-part-i.html">learn</a> <a href="http://arhipov.blogspot.com/2011/07/whats-cool-in-intellijidea-part-ii-live.html">some</a> <a href="http://arhipov.blogspot.com/2011/08/whats-cool-in-intellijidea-part-iii.html">tooling</a> <a href="http://arhipov.blogspot.com/2012/09/maven-support-in-intellij-idea.html">instead</a> - it will save you some time later!</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/pfQBSjA43-M" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="639c30bc80596246ebea117a86997dcf" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/pKm6wc6p05U/java-build-tools-survey.html"><![CDATA[Just curious, what could be the share of Java build tools. I will share the results as soon as there's enough answers for this survey to make sense.  <br/><div id="surveyMonkeyInfo"><div><script src="http://www.surveymonkey.com/jsEmbed.aspx?sm=WdSRIptzhD5_2f7N4pvYlwOg_3d_3d"> </script></div></div> <b>P.S.</b> If the browser doesn't display the embedded survey frame, here's the direct link: <a href="http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/WLGLW2K">http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/WLGLW2K</a><br/><b>P.S.2</b> BTW, I'm looking for volunteers to give the new JRebel Beta a try. If you're interested, please sign up <b><a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/software/jrebel/beta/">here</a></b> - we will start publishing the binaries soon.  <P><b>UPDATE:</b> I've published the results <a href="http://arhipov.blogspot.com/2013/08/java-build-tools-survey-results.html">here</a></P><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/pKm6wc6p05U" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bdea5ce77dd673794697711a64058e9b" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/QuZ0VLxcjGM/javazone-2012-taming-java-agents.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">At JavaZone I've presented a talk called <i><b>Taming Java Agents</b>. </i>It is not about the distributed computing or messaging as the title might imply. It is about the tools that exercise <b>-javaagent</b> JVM argument to hook into class loading process<i>&nbsp;</i>in order to perform some necessary evil to the bytecode. The tools can do amazing things to the application by rewriting the bytecode - <a href="http://appdynamics.com/">performance</a> &amp; <a href="http://plumbr.eu/">memory</a> monitoring, <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/software/jrebel/">class reloading</a>, <a href="http://www.jboss.org/byteman">tracing</a>, etc.&nbsp;I think this is an interesting topic in general - the tools do not exist for no reason.<br /><br />Here are the slides and the video from the talk:<br /><br /><center><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0" height="421" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/14260031" style="border-width: 1px 1px 0; border: 1px solid #CCC; margin-bottom: 5px;" width="512"> </iframe><br /><br /><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/49298212" width="600" height="337" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></center></div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/QuZ0VLxcjGM" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7b986a772083207ae58d440a2d866a13" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/RPhFGly0kXs/a-great-read-on-scala.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">A great article has been published at <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/blog/">ZeroTurnaround's blog</a>: <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/labs/scala-2013-a-pragmatic-guide-to-scala-adoption-in-your-java-organization/">Scala 2013: A Pragmatic Guide to Scala Adoption in Your Java Organization</a>. You can download it as a <a href="http://pages.zeroturnaround.com/Scala_Sept2013_scala-report.html">PDF</a> (which looks really cool!). The nice part is that it includes an interview with <a href="https://twitter.com/odersky">Martin Odersky</a> and quotes by <a href="https://twitter.com/jsuereth">Josh Suereth</a>. </div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/RPhFGly0kXs" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="30e41057d1d77020d38ae657e262dcfb" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/SEOOY5G8tp0/welcome-to-rebellabs.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on">In ZeroTurnaround we just launched a new page with awesome content collected in one place. <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/">RebelLabs</a> hosts very nicely designed documents with interesting content produced by <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/about-us/">ZT engineers</a>. <br /></div>My favorites so far are the reports on <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/devs/scala-2013-a-pragmatic-guide-to-scala-adoption-in-your-java-organization/">Scala adoption</a> and <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/devs/developer-productivity-report-2012/">Developers Productivity Report from 2012</a><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/SEOOY5G8tp0" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d5df42c272edae38497574fe76b5b82f" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/tji7GDSQ3CE/jrebel-60-beta-registration-started.html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been more than a year since <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/blog/jrebel-5-0/">JRebel 5</a> has been released. During the year there have been a few minor releases and a lot of things were improved – <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/software/jrebel/remoting/">remoting</a>, debugger integration, <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/software/jrebel/features/frameworks/">support for more frameworks</a>, IDE plugins, etc.</p> <p>Now, <b>JRebel 6</b> is on the horizon. There will be several big changes (not revealing yet), which I hope will improve the UX very much. JRebel will be able to do things that it wasn't able to do before - that's very cool!</p> <p>Since it is a major release and there are a lot of changes that we introduced to the product, I'm looking for volunteers to try out the new beta version on real-life Java projects.</p> <center><b>You can register for the beta program <a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/software/jrebel/beta/">here</a>.</b></center> <p>If all goes as planned the first builds will land late August / early September.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/tji7GDSQ3CE" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="69ce17a6455fed689907b089297dde36" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/XJ2qQgvC7-A/maven-support-in-intellij-idea.html"><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"><p>The screencast demonstrates Maven integration features available in IntelliJ IDEA. Apache Camel maven archetype is used to generate the application. The main features are: </p><ul><li>Project setup automation and automatic dependency resolution</li><li>Editor assistance and autocompletion</li><li>Refactorings</li><li>Dependency graph</li><li>Lifecycle management using the tooling window</li></ul>  <center><object data="http://tv.jetbrains.net/flowplayer/flowplayer-3.2.10.swf" height="600" id="_fp_0.04471339425072074" name="player" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="800">    <param value="true" name="allowfullscreen"/>    <param value="always" name="allowscriptaccess"/>    <param value="transparent" name="wmode"/>    <param value="high" name="quality"/>    <param name="movie" value="http://tv.jetbrains.net/flowplayer/flowplayer-3.2.10.swf" />    <param value="config=%7B%22playlist%22%3A%5B%7B%22autoPlay%22%3Afalse%2C%22baseUrl%22%3A%22http%3A//tv.jetbrains.net%22%2C%22autoBuffering%22%3Atrue%2C%22scaling%22%3A%22orig%22%2C%22url%22%3A%22http%3A//tv.jetbrains.net/sites/default/files/videos/converted/Maven-with-IntelliJ-IDEA.mp4%22%7D%5D%2C%22plugins%22%3A%7B%22controls%22%3A%7B%22callType%22%3A%22default%22%2C%22stop%22%3Atrue%2C%22url%22%3A%22http%3A//tv.jetbrains.net/flowplayer/flowplayer.controls-3.2.8.swf%22%7D%2C%22viral%22%3A%7B%22callType%22%3A%22default%22%2C%22share%22%3Afalse%2C%22url%22%3A%22http%3A//tv.jetbrains.net/flowplayer/flowplayer.viralvideos-3.2.9.swf%22%2C%22email%22%3Afalse%7D%2C%22dock%22%3A%7B%22right%22%3A15%2C%22horizontal%22%3Afalse%2C%22width%22%3A%227pct%22%2C%22autoHide%22%3Atrue%7D%7D%2C%22clip%22%3A%7B%22pageUrl%22%3A%22http%3A//tv.jetbrains.net/videocontent/maven-support-in-intellij-idea%22%2C%22autoPlay%22%3Afalse%2C%22baseUrl%22%3A%22http%3A//tv.jetbrains.net%22%2C%22autoBuffering%22%3Atrue%2C%22url%22%3A%22http%3A//tv.jetbrains.net/sites/default/files/videos/converted/Maven-with-IntelliJ-IDEA.mp4%22%2C%22scaling%22%3A%22orig%22%7D%7D" name="flashvars"/></object></center><br /></div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/XJ2qQgvC7-A" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bce453edb6b8d9f9a4f8f17eb95bc6cf" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/y91_Xv-wlss/speaking-at-javaone-sf-2013.html"><![CDATA[<p><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.oracle.com/javaone" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 2em; margin-right: 2em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-krRCkje0SCk/UclkZERI5cI/AAAAAAAARUY/agtxZjJO4fY/s1600/179481-j1-sf-imspeaking-200x200-1946267.jpg" /></a></div>I've got 4 talks to deliver at JavaOne SF this year: <ul><li><b><i><a href="https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2013/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=10388">UGF10388 - NetBeans Community Tools with JRebel, Jelastic and others.</a></i></b> I'll be talking about our NetBeans plugin for JRebel - how it's made and what it does.</li><li><b><i><a href="https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2013/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=2585">CON2585 - Embedding JVM Scripting Languages.</a></i></b> This talk has been brewing in my head for a long time now. It started at a time when I was investigating applicability business rule engines at my previous job. Amazingly, after some time I realized that in order to implement a BRMS, you actually have to have a very very very good reason. In most cases a rule engine can be as easy as a simple dynamic script that follows some conventions. Scripting languages on JVM allow just that! I'll be talking about embedding scripting into a Java app and assessing different options for the implementation. Will cover Groovy, JRuby and a bit of JavaScript too.</li><li><b><i><a href="https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2013/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=2578">CON2578 - Taming Java Agents.</a></i></b> Since JRebel is stands on the shoulders of Instrumentation API and bootstraps via <i>-javaagent</i> VM argument, there's good portion of interesting things that I could talk about. Thankfully, <a href="https://twitter.com/inikem">Nikita</a> will assist me as he's involved with <a href="http://plumbr.eu/">Plumbr</a>, which also based largely on Instrumentation API, however, it includes some native code as well. Combined, it will be an interesting overview of the underlying technology that enables us to develop awesome tools for Java platform.</li><li><b><i><a href="https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2013/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=3477">CON3477 - Apples and Oranges: The Highlights of Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA, and NetBeans IDE.</a></i></b></li> This will the showcase of all 3 major IDEs - NetBeans IDE, IntelliJ IDEA, and Eclipse (with JBoss Tools plugin). Geertjan suggested we do it together, so there will be 3 speakers, one for each IDE: <a href="http://twitter.com/GeertjanW">Geertjan</a> for NetBeans IDE, <a href="http://twitter.com/maxandersen">Max Andersen</a> for Eclipse, and myself for IntelliJ IDEA.</li></ul></p><center>See You At JavaOne!</center><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/y91_Xv-wlss" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="420100277aca84050292477d12a3a958" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/zb1wEjlJ5RQ/rebel-labs-java-8-lambdas-default.html"><![CDATA[<p>I've spent some time composing an <b><a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/java-8-revealed-lambdas-default-methods-and-bulk-data-operations/">overview of the new features in Java 8</a></b>. It includes the overview of lambda expressions in Java 8 and accompanying interesting features - default methods and bulk data operations for Java collections. I hope you will find the text interesting.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/zb1wEjlJ5RQ" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="473ce050474e465a63873acba712fcd2" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~3/zkkoMXlBhfk/java-ee-7-public-draft-was-published-i.html"><![CDATA[On December 20, 2012 a <a href="http://java.net/projects/javaee-spec/downloads">public draft of Java EE 7</a> has been uploaded. From the first sight, the new spec is rather an improvement of the subsequent specs in Java EE 6.  For instance, I really like the <a href="http://java.net/projects/javaee-spec/downloads/download/WebProfilePublicDraft.pdf">Web Profile</a> idea. But is is a shame that it wasn't a part of Java EE 6 Web Profile.  <blockquote>The Web Profile is targeted at developers of modern web applications</blockquote> IMO, most of the modern web applications make use of REST. Or at least this is my perception. In Rails world, AFAIK, violating REST principle is a subject for brutal prosecution by the colleagues :)  Luckily Java EE 7 fixes that mistake and JAX-RS specification is now a part of Web Profile.   <blockquote>Targeting “modern” web applications then implies offering a reasonably  complete stack, composed of standard APIs, and capable out-of-the-box of  addressing the needs of a large class of web applications.</blockquote><p>OK, now you can really develop "modern" web apps with Web Profile, but... </p><p><blockquote>In terms of completeness, the Web Profile offers a complete stack, with  technologies addressing presentation and state management.  (JavaServer Faces,  JavaServer Pages), core web container funtionality (Servlet), business logic  (Enterprise JavaBeans Lite), transactions (Java Transaction API), persistence  (Java Persistence API) and more.</blockquote></p><p>Sounds like redundancy to me. For instance, why would you need EJBs there? If CDI supported interceptors properly there wouldn't be a need for EJBs in that sense. Or, JSF? Well, I'm just not a fan of that.  </p><p>What I'm trying to say here is that since for compatibility reasons there wouldn't be possible to drop specs from Web Profile, maybe it is now time to create a "Light Profile"? A minimalistic set of Java EE specs that would be sufficient for building <b><i>modern</i></b> web applications. </p><p>Of course the term is a bit foggy - what should we consider a <i>modern web application</i>. These days it is a combination of a REST backend and UI technologies such as HTML5 and JavaScript. My logic says that since Java EE doesn't specify UI technology then the main specification that required is JAX-RS and the complementary specifications to support transactions (JTA/JTS), persistance (JPA), and dependency injection (CDI). Of course, there are some nice complementary specifications such as Bean Validation and Java API for JSON processing. But I would definitely drop JSF and EJBs for sure. </p><p>This would bring the containers like Tomcat and Jetty even closer to the spec and who knows maybe one day we will have a Java EE "Jetty Profile", why not :) </p>  <img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/AntonsBlog/~4/zkkoMXlBhfk" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>