<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="www.investigation.com/blog">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="cb19e1099d3a0b97479b917ea35d7ddf" url="http://www.investigation.com/blog/2013/03/21/the-getty-images-shakedown/"><![CDATA[Is Getty the mafia of the realm of digital images? It would appear that Getty has a penchant for sending cease and desist letters demanding exorbitant amounts of money for stock photography and images that they claim people are using without their consent. The letters, which Kessler has seen in the past, contain screen prints [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7cc0ae1cbe6d1121d25ee975ed5ca8f" url="http://www.investigation.com/blog/2013/04/08/association-of-legal-administrators-annual-conference-and-exposition-april-15-april-17-2013-2/"><![CDATA[We would like to remind everyone that Kessler International will be exhibiting at the upcoming Association of Legal Administrators Annual Conference and Exposition April 15 – April 17, 2013 at BOOTH 622. We are excited to share information about the forensic accounting, computer forensics, investigative and brand protection services that we provide with ALA members, [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1fdefc39a42609f7d0bf3fa4fb6a7975" url="http://www.investigation.com/blog/2013/04/24/join-us-at-the-inta-135th-annual-meeting-in-dallas-texas/"><![CDATA[Let Kessler put your cow chip tossing skills to the test at the INTA 135th Annual Meeting in Dallas, Texas.  We will be waiting for you at booths 601 and 603 where you will have your shot at cow chip tossing, with the added benefit of learning more about the full range of brand protection [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4f16d0f355dce0ca78b6fa3d06f1465" url="http://www.investigation.com/blog/2013/09/03/kessler-international-takes-second-acq-awards-title-in-forensic-accounting-firm-of-the-year-category/"><![CDATA[Kessler International was recently named the 2013 Forensic Accounting Firm of the Year at the ACQ Global Awards, having received 12% of the nominations in their category. This is Kessler’s second title in the category, having received the honor in 2011. Since 2008, the ACQ Global Awards have been celebrating achievement, innovation and brilliance in [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7027c40a8a6d575a8f09593e35f3315c" url="http://www.investigation.com/blog/2013/09/06/back-to-school-back-to-broke/"><![CDATA[It’s back-to-school time, which means new teachers, classrooms and the inevitable school supply list. With the ever-changing world of technology, parents no longer have to wait for the first day of school to receive these growing laundry lists of items. Supply lists can now be found on the websites of most school districts, and websites [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="da27d1e457d4bbadb45392e37e5b1082" url="http://www.investigation.com/blog/2013/09/16/maximum-buyers-remorse/"><![CDATA[A recent purchase by one of Kessler&#8217;s staff members from Office Max lead us to discover that the company misrepresented the product online as a brand name product, when in actuality what they are selling is a sub-par generic product.  The product in question, a package of BUNN 12 Cup Coffee Filters bulk was presented [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c558cc2096408e7aec174309fcedbb57" url="http://www.investigation.com/blog/2013/10/03/get-a-clue-about-clue-reports-your-insurance-policy-depends-on-it/"><![CDATA[While most people are familiar with a credit report, most have probably never heard of a CLUE report. These reports are generated from a database, known as the Comprehensive Loss Underwriting Exchange, or “CLUE,” and enable homeowner and automobile insurers to exchange information about claims for loss of property, or even inquiries about specific types [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="17fb5a4b4a63baa3970e20c40ff71f9c" url="http://www.investigation.com/blog/2013/10/18/private-investigators-with-a-private-agenda/"><![CDATA[ In the world of Private Investigators, there are a plethora of individuals and firms out there. But how do you know you’re choosing the right one? Deciding to hire a private investigator is more than just a business transaction. It is the formation of a relationship bound by trust, ethics, and integrity, or at least [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="45e06438c624335c806c29b3083ab25d" url="http://www.investigation.com/blog/2013/11/06/bumping-a-burglars-most-efficient-way-to-break-in/"><![CDATA[Most people think that when they lock their doors they are safely nestled within the walls of their home. But what if they weren’t? What if at any point, someone could break into your home with as little effort as it takes to unlock a door? Did you know, there is a technique called “bumping,” [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f2b455e88877ecce4b872fff5e359924" url="http://www.investigation.com/blog/2013/12/19/target-shoppers-become-the-target-of-data-breach/"><![CDATA[Target stores have undergone a massive breach of data, which is likely to have affected 40 million customer accounts. The breach is said to have taken place from Black Friday on November 27 through December 15. Customers who used only a credit card are said to be safe from the breach; however shoppers that used [...]
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>