<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="lovelymorning.com">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="5803b3209b067a5100a826e53c63bd69" url="http://lovelymorning.com/index.php/2013/07/forrest-is-one/"><![CDATA[His party is up on 100 Layer Cakelet for your viewing pleasure (along with a cute shoot we did for Ergo, if you can&#8217;t get enough of him), but here are a few photos after the party was cleaned up that evening. A nice bookend to the photos I posted of Dash the night before. [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f0ae208240ffb77aaa0da8bc9174a1c0" url="http://lovelymorning.com/index.php/2013/07/summer-yes/"><![CDATA[We&#8217;ve been having a good time this summer. That is for sure. I just dumped a bunch of photos into iPhoto off of my big camera so I can post Forrest&#8217;s birthday party over on Cakelet (did I mention he turned one?!), and I found these. From the night before when Dash was helping us [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="38e955b304b4be59fefa7ba40991843c" url="http://lovelymorning.com/index.php/2013/09/beet-popsicles/"><![CDATA[Kay so these? If you&#8217;re a crazy mom like me and measure your worth by the number of vegetables you can convince your children to eat, these are for you. Beets! In popsicle form! Imagine the vitamins. Plus they have organic greek yogurt for a nice protein boost. And they&#8217;re yummy. In kind of an [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bc4a9df1a6d0dd2edec68295836d6d84" url="http://lovelymorning.com/index.php/2013/11/a-fall-mobile/"><![CDATA[I love mobiles. We have one in the kids&#8217; room and one in our bedroom, and I love that they add just a teensy bit of whimsy to a space. The guys and I collected a bunch of things around the neighborhood during a few morning walks and Dash and I finally assembled our little [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f2c2db0699c06c9c65fef3f5df2ef32b" url="http://lovelymorning.com/index.php/2013/11/halloween-2013/"><![CDATA[Let&#8217;s just say it was a good year for mama. I&#8217;ve been waiting to make Forrest&#8217;s costume for three years, since Brock first sent me a link to something similar (as a joke), and then forbade me from making it for baby Dashiell. Which is clearly why you have a second baby. I&#8217;d say this [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="84ff8e6f5b2dbc3c77ebc53606fa0f43" url="http://lovelymorning.com/index.php/2013/11/welcome-fall/"><![CDATA[I love fall. I mean, I know *everybody* loves fall. But seriously, I think it&#8217;s my spirit season. We certainly have plenty of warm days ahead of us here in Southern California, yet I can&#8217;t help feeling slightly desperate to put away the sunscreen and popsicles (okay, probably not the popsicles) to enjoy sweaters, chilly [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a16e04a367c00d910f8ea1120d9fcd88" url="http://lovelymorning.com/index.php/2013/12/the-best-toffee-recipe/"><![CDATA[It really is, you guys. And I&#8217;ve had a lot of toffee. Now, I&#8217;ve never actually made another recipe so I might be a bit biased, but I&#8217;m telling you this one is perfection. And since there seems to be some interest in the recipe (according to this instagram photo), I thought I would repost [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7aef586574f71d823dca1b7d67a35442" url="http://lovelymorning.com/index.php/2013/12/tis-the-season-for-photo-albums-and-holiday-cards/"><![CDATA[I am usually about two weeks away from dealing with holiday cards at this point in the year. Which means our greetings normally arrive in their intended mailboxes around the second week of January. It&#8217;s kind of a problem. But this year I was determined to plan like a normal person would, and while I [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1c793748d4959a5ec9031f1372f31fcf" url="http://lovelymorning.com/index.php/2014/01/152/"><![CDATA[Last year I remember seeing lots of mamas I follow on the internets participating in a weekly project documenting their children every week for the entire year. I clicked around a bit over the weekend and finally traced it back to Jodi of Practicing Simplicity (I have been out of the blog loop for-ever!). So [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1e1992ed8d90a6b0ba2abf8febbb62ed" url="http://lovelymorning.com/index.php/2014/01/carrot-coconut-soup/"><![CDATA[I think it&#8217;s safe to say that this is a perfect lunch soup for the quiet, calm days of January. Possibly my favorite month of the year, or at least it feels like that when Christmas is finally packed up and we can get back to living. It&#8217;s from the November issue of Bon Appetit, [...]
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>