<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="65-XX" url="almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com">
	<documents count="25">
		<document id="4957c5a7b033729bc754b7aeac3a01e1" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2013/12/2014-will-be-good-year.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: large;">On January 2nd I plan to hit the ground running. By the end of the year, my single outstanding debt (other than my mortgage,which is just $500/month) will be paid off because I'm saving so much on my health insurance and I'll be free and clear to navigate. I'll have enough money in savings to compensate for the "famine" part of my "feast or famine" professional existence and a team of power partners (SEO guru, web designer, graphics expert, marketing/advertising/promotional items vendor, and copywriters who write in niches other than the ones I tackle) to make sure I have everything I need to serve business owners and entrepreneurs completely. <b><i><u>Full-service, one-stop shopping.</u></i></b></span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><b><i><u><br /></u></i></b></span><span style="font-size: large;">I plan to work as full-time as possible as a copywriter for the next two years, until I'm <b><i>eligible</i></b> to retire in early 2016, and then I'll <b><i>consider</i></b> retiring (but will still be writing copy for businesses and entrepreneurs, of course, since it's allowed now) <b><i>or</i></b> waiting until later to officially retire. (The longer I wait, the larger my Social Security check will be, which is good because it won't be much when/if I semi-retire in 2016).</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">So I just have one more year of this roller coaster existence before things should settle down and I'll be able to relax more. THEN I'll start writing for pleasure and to get the stuff out of my brain that still needs to come out before I croak or forget it all -- whichever comes first!&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Knowing this helps me feel better. I'll probably work one more year at the church to help pay off the outstanding debt I mentioned above and, after that, I can let that go, too and take off on more weekends instead of being tethered to home to that&nbsp;responsibility.</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;"><b><i>WOO HOO!</i></b></span>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fcf4a6eaa8c7faa0caa05fe26347b73a" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2013/12/b-b-b-baby-its-cold-outside.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: large;">This is the third day in a row that I've needed to carry hot water to the chickens so they have something to drink. And two of the hens (out of nine) are electing to remain in the hen house this morning under the heat lamp. What does that tell you? The outdoor thermometer reads 15 degrees but that's right next to the house, so it's likely colder farther away. Sure feels like it, anyway.</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">It's funny to see hens "walking in water" (over frozen-solid ice) to drink the hot stuff I poured in on top. Looks mighty odd. I should take a photo, I suppose. "Jesus Chickens" might go viral.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">But then, I'd rather have something less 'controversial"--or more substantial--go viral if my name is going to be on it.</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">You know, something like <b><i>Christmas goats</i></b>... a blast from the past...</span><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-DsuU75KZ0Xs/UqNFQb_RRoI/AAAAAAAAA2s/NiKJyUiuaqU/s1600/Christmas+Goats+%2311+Dec+23+2010.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="212" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-DsuU75KZ0Xs/UqNFQb_RRoI/AAAAAAAAA2s/NiKJyUiuaqU/s320/Christmas+Goats+%2311+Dec+23+2010.jpg" width="320" /></a></div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="425f0683fa793a167ffcb9f1032c431b" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2013/12/day-after-christmas-blues.html"><![CDATA[<div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-size: large;">In bygone years (before 2003) I always felt blue after Christmas, but not since then. These days I'm just <b><i>relieved when it's over</i></b>! Isn't that awful?</span><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;">I love Christmas to the core of my being because of its significance as a religious holy day, but because I can't afford much in the way of gifts (which is what Christmas includes for most of the people I know and love) and haven't been able to ever since I moved back to Washington in 2003, I get blue <b><i>before</i></b> Christmas and stay that way until it's over. It sucks not to be able to participate in the gift-giving aspects of it. I do a little (and I mean a little, because it's all I can do) but it never feels adequate, so I get depressed ahead of time and stay that way for weeks leading up to the big day. This year I wasn't sure I'd be able to participate at all but at the last possible second I received an unexpected windfall and spent it all (and a little bit more) on gift cards so I squeaked by... and still felt crappy. *sigh*</span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;">The good news is that, starting in less than one week thanks to Obamacare (the Affordable Care Act, which is living up to its actual name in <b><i>this</i></b> household &nbsp;by a landslide) my monthly health insurance bill will be less by over $300/month, so if I stay healthy and don't have to go see a doctor except for routine check-ups, I will be able to start saving money and by next Christmas things will be a lot better for me as long as I stay as busy as I am right now as a writer. I'll be wildly better off if I get busier than I am right now, which I anticipate will happen in 2014 because of my local networking efforts.&nbsp;</span><b style="font-size: x-large;"><i>Hallelujah!</i></b></div><div><b style="font-size: x-large;"><i><br /></i></b></div><div><b style="font-size: x-large;"><i><br /></i></b></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d1508c4d51e465d29a05c17d12bc7d6b" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2013/12/feast-or-famine-life-as-creative-is.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: large;">A few weeks ago I had clients in holding patterns, waiting to land as soon as I completed the project I was on.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">This week both of the clients who were scheduled to employ me have decided to wait until after the holidays have come and gone. <b><i>ACK!</i></b>&nbsp; So here I sit, praying for some unexpected drop-ins: former clients, new clients, some editing work, <b><i>anything!</i></b>&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Moral of the story: get down payments or retainer fees up front so that when (not if) clients decide to delay, it doesn't throw you into "OMG!" Mode, wondering how you're going to make ends meet. "<i style="font-weight: bold;">There goes my Christmas plans and packages. I'm dead in the water..." </i>T'is NOT the season to be a pauper. I can handle it any other time of the year, off and on (it's a way of life for most Creatives) but this time of year it makes me come across looking like a penny-pinching Scrooge when I'm feeling more like Bob Crachit--or Tiny Tim!&nbsp; &nbsp;Grrrr...</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Not that I'm sitting here twiddling my thumbs, mind you. When my schedule frees up unexpectedly, I start writing for myself, doing the marketing stuff that shows my wares and abilities on FB, Twitter, and LinkedIn.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">I also write complimentary copy, during these droughts, for power networking partners who have sent work my way this year. I just finished writing 4000 words of copy for Internet Earle (who is creating a complimentary website for a friend of his) to thank him for the number of times he has sent clients my way and saved my bacon this year, and for Lisa Taylor, who offers two services that lots of people need: computer tutoring for seniors here in the Tacoma &nbsp;area and other technophobes and custom WordPress sites. It makes me feel very, very good to be able to do this for them. Words are the only gifts I can afford to get them this year for Christmas, and it's a great gift--one that most people have to pay serious money to get. &nbsp;Oh! And I bathed my sister's two dogs yesterday, too... in my spare time. So I'm not twiddling my thumbs, by any stretch of the imagination!</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">But of course none of the above pays the mortgage; it just keeps me from stressing too much over something I can't control while blessing people who have been such blessings to me.</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">I'm watching the websites that offer writing jobs (usually for peanuts) to see if I spot anything that will carry me through this dry spell that I can bid on. That takes a lot of time out of every day, including weekends. &nbsp;I must spend 50-60 hours a week looking for writing work when I'm &nbsp;not engaged in writing projects. &nbsp;Very few people understand the enormous amount of time and attention it takes to make a living this way. But there's nothing else on earth I'd rather do than write, so here I am... writing for free when I can't write for pay!</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Please keep me in your prayers for a sudden, surprising upswing in business--sooner rather than later. (Now would be a good time!)&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">I appreciate it!</span>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="487522f917e8434a953d9dfd3820e1f5" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2013/12/five-ways-to-find-great-freelance.html"><![CDATA[<div align="center" class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: center;"><div style="text-align: left;"><b><o:p> </o:p></b></div><b></b><br /><b></b><br /><b></b><br /><b></b><br /><b><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt; text-align: center;"><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><span style="font-size: large;">5 Ways to Find a Great Freelance Copywriter<o:p></o:p></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span><span style="font-family: Calibri;">©2013 Kristine M. Smith</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; text-align: left;"><i style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;"><span style="color: #1f497d; line-height: 115%; mso-themecolor: text2;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><span style="font-size: large;"><span style="color: black;">Professional copywriters usually charge one to three dollars per word. Here’s how to get one for less—<u>without</u>sacrificing quality.<o:p></o:p></span></span></span></span></i></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; text-align: left;"><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><span style="font-size: large;">Every business and entrepreneur needs a professional writer now and then—for web content, a brochure, content marketing articles, you name it. Unfortunately, too many have fallen victim to tens of thousands of charlatans and wannabes who have hung their shingles at scores of online freelance websites and proclaimed themselves copywriting experts. (No certification or testing is required so <i style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;">anyone</i>can claim the title.)<o:p></o:p></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpFirst" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; mso-add-space: auto; mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-align: left; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><span style="line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Calibri; mso-bidi-theme-font: minor-latin;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">1.</span><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: normal;"><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </strong></span></span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><i style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;"><u><span style="line-height: 115%;">IF</span></u></i> you elect to use an online freelance website to look for copywriters (<u>not</u>recommended!) be sure to carefully review each candidate’s profile page, client history and feedback, certified test results, and portfolio. Most of the reputable copywriters have fled online freelance websites (or are fleeing as fast as they can) because the reputation of these sites has plummeted&nbsp;because&nbsp;of&nbsp;the overwhelming numbers of impostors and their resulting unhappy customers; few professionals want to be associated with them anymore. If you go this route, expect to spend hours (perhaps days) sorting through often-laughable sub-standard profiles and portfolios in search of the remaining reputable providers. Bottom line: <i style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;">Don’t settle for less than the best.</i> You’ll get what you pay for at these sites. Remember: you’ll need a result that you can be proud of, not sub-standard copy fit only for lining the bottom of a bird cage.<o:p></o:p></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; mso-add-space: auto; mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-align: left; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><span style="line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Calibri; mso-bidi-theme-font: minor-latin;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">2.</span><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: normal;"><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </strong></span></span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri;">If you want a local provider, do a search on “your town + copywriter” and see who pops up. Visit their websites and look at their histories, portfolios and client testimonials.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>(Note: no professional copywriter tackles all niches; only hacks and wannabes do that—and they usually do it poorly.) When you find ones that impress you, give them a call and make arrangements to meet them to discuss your needs.<o:p></o:p></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; mso-add-space: auto; mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-align: left; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><span style="line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Calibri; mso-bidi-theme-font: minor-latin;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">3.</span><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: normal;"><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </strong></span></span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri;">If the physical location of your copywriter isn’t an issue, run a search on the kind of copywriter you’re seeking (SEO copywriter, real estate copywriter, web content copywriter, content marketing copywriter, etc.) and check out the credentials and client reviews of the ones you find. I highly recommend that you hire a native professional copywriter from within your own country (wherever you are in the world) when your target audience is also where you are, since he or she will be well-versed in your nation’s idioms, culture and customs and won’t be making major mistakes because of cultural and language issues. If your target audience is in another country, hire a professional copywriter from the same country your target audience is in unless the copywriter can show you copy he has already written for that audience. Why? Because (for example) UK Englishmen speak, spell, and write differently than do Americans, Australians and Canadians; readers can be put off if they run across unfamiliar colloquialisms, spellings or cultural references that they don’t hear at home.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp;&nbsp; </span>A metaphor like “You hit that one out of the ball park!” resonates in the United States, where baseball is a national pastime; it’ll just raise eyebrows (and sometimes hackles) in other places.<o:p></o:p></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; mso-add-space: auto; mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-align: left; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">4.</span><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: normal;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri;">If you aren’t well-versed when it comes to spelling, grammar and punctuation or if you confuse words when you’re writing (there, their, they’re; its and it’s; accept, except; then and than, etc.) find someone else to help you select your copywriter. </span><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">It’s what you <i style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;">don’t </i>know about spelling, grammar, punctuation and other matters that can come back to bite you professionally unless you find an ally to help you choose a copywriter.<o:p></o:p></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; mso-add-space: auto; mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-align: left; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><span style="line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Calibri; mso-bidi-theme-font: minor-latin;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">5.</span><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: normal;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri;">Agree to pay a small fee to the copywriter you’re considering hiring. Have them write a short one-page/250-word sample web page, article or letter on your topic of choice (give them the source materials for this piece); or (ideally) have them edit and enhance a substandard one-page/250-word piece you already have on hand.<span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp; </span>Let them know you want the piece back in under an hour (unless they’re absolutely swamped with deadlines). If they can produce the piece to your satisfaction within this time frame, it’s likely you’re dealing with a professional candidate.<o:p></o:p></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; mso-add-space: auto; mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-align: left; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><span style="line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Calibri; mso-bidi-theme-font: minor-latin;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">6.</span><span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: normal;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="line-height: 115%;"><o:p><span style="font-family: Calibri;">&nbsp;</span></o:p></span></span><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><span style="font-size: large;">Using due diligence you can find an exemplary freelance copywriter to do your bidding, one who won’t charge you an arm and a leg for their services. But please note: if you aren’t able (or willing) to pay <i style="mso-bidi-font-style: normal;">at least</i> $100/hour for the services of a professional copywriter, wait until you are. No professional copywriter worth his or her salt is going to write for you while going backward financially. Consider a U.S. copywriter’s reality (which may mirror your own if you’re an American business person or entrepreneur)…<o:p></o:p></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; mso-add-space: auto; text-align: left;"><span style="line-height: 115%;"><o:p><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: large;">&nbsp;</span></o:p></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; mso-add-space: auto; text-align: left;"><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><span style="font-size: large;">Self-employed freelance copywriters in the USA...<o:p></o:p></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; mso-add-space: auto; text-align: left;"><span style="line-height: 115%;"><o:p><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: large;">&nbsp;</span></o:p></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; mso-add-space: auto; mso-list: l1 level1 lfo2; text-align: left; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><span style="font-family: Wingdings; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Wingdings; mso-fareast-font-family: Wingdings;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">Ø<span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: normal;">&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><span style="line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Arial;">don't get paid vacations </span><span style="line-height: 115%;"><o:p></o:p></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; mso-add-space: auto; mso-list: l1 level1 lfo2; text-align: left; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><span style="font-family: Wingdings; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Wingdings; mso-fareast-font-family: Wingdings;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">Ø<span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: normal;">&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><span style="line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Arial;">don't get paid sick days </span><span style="line-height: 115%;"><o:p></o:p></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; mso-add-space: auto; mso-list: l1 level1 lfo2; text-align: left; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><span style="font-family: Wingdings; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Wingdings; mso-fareast-font-family: Wingdings;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">Ø<span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: normal;">&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><span style="line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Arial;">rarely get bonuses for outstanding work </span><span style="line-height: 115%;"><o:p></o:p></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; mso-add-space: auto; mso-list: l1 level1 lfo2; text-align: left; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><span style="font-family: Wingdings; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Wingdings; mso-fareast-font-family: Wingdings;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">Ø<span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: normal;">&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><span style="line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Arial;">don't have employer-paid insurance plans </span><span style="line-height: 115%;"><o:p></o:p></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; mso-add-space: auto; mso-list: l1 level1 lfo2; text-align: left; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><span style="font-family: Wingdings; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Wingdings; mso-fareast-font-family: Wingdings;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">Ø<span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: normal;">&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><span style="line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Arial;">don't qualify for unemployment when work doesn’t materialize </span><span style="line-height: 115%;"><o:p></o:p></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; mso-add-space: auto; mso-list: l1 level1 lfo2; text-align: left; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><span style="font-family: Wingdings; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Wingdings; mso-fareast-font-family: Wingdings;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">Ø<span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: normal;">&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><span style="line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Arial;">have to take into account the time it requires to find and quote on projects</span><span style="line-height: 115%;"><o:p></o:p></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; mso-add-space: auto; mso-list: l1 level1 lfo2; text-align: left; text-indent: -0.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><span style="font-family: Wingdings; line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Wingdings; mso-fareast-font-family: Wingdings;"><span style="mso-list: Ignore;">Ø<span style="font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: normal;">&nbsp; </span></span></span><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><span style="line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Arial;">have to pay 100% of our Social Security, FICA, and other federally-mandated fees instead of just a portion of them </span><span style="line-height: 115%;"><o:p></o:p></span></span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; mso-add-space: auto; text-align: left;"><span style="line-height: 115%;"><o:p><span style="font-family: Calibri; font-size: large;">&nbsp;</span></o:p></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"> </span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpLast" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; mso-add-space: auto; text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><span style="font-size: large;"><span style="line-height: 115%; mso-bidi-font-family: Arial;">Although freelancers enjoy writing great copy...sadly....enjoyment doesn't pay the mortgage. <br /><br /></span><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="mso-spacerun: yes;">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </span>#<o:p></o:p></span></span></span></div><span style="font-size: large;"> </span><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in -4.5pt 10pt; text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;">Kristine M. Smith is a professional freelance copywriter and the author of seven books. To discover the kinds of projects she tackles and the ones she leaves to other professional writers, please email her at </span><a href="mailto:kristinemsmith@msn.com"><span style="color: blue; font-family: Calibri;">kristinemsmith@msn.com</span></a><span style="font-family: Calibri;">.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="margin: 0in 0in 10pt; text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Calibri;"><span style="font-size: large;"><span style="font-size: small;">Permission is hereby granted to reprint this article as long as the copyright notice and this byline is included wherever the reprint appears.</span> <o:p></o:p></span></span></div></b><br /></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="bebd3b7b2278f32f96c53b44e14c3a0d" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2013/12/go-with-god-nelson-mandela.html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/video/nbc-news/53749055?from=en-us_msnhp#53749055">http://www.nbcnews.com/video/nbc-news/53749055?from=en-us_msnhp#53749055</a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6b0e543ddbee11075ea1f4687dc099d" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2013/12/going-to-see-captain-phillips-again.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: large;">I'm going to see <b>Captain Phillips</b> again with friends (Lisa Twining Taylor and Edward Smith) before it leaves town for good. (It &nbsp;ought to be seen on the big screen, and they haven't seen it yet.)&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">If you haven't seen it yet, don't wait. It's a true story and the actors are all fabulous, including Tom Hanks and the Somalian actor who plays the lead heavy.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">And just a heads up (I just learned this recently): the last scene in the trauma/emergency room wasn't scripted (as far as the trauma nurse is concerned), which makes it even more amazing!! It&nbsp;</span><span style="font-size: large;">will make the skin covering your cranium crawl and you'll tear up, guaranteed. It's absolutely brilliant.&nbsp;</span><span style="font-size: large;">I'd say the nurse deserves an Oscar, <b><i>but she wasn't acting</i></b>--she was just directed to do what she'd normally do if a trauma patient came in displaying the symptoms Tom Hanks does... &nbsp;Fabulous! &nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">(Still, I consider it acting when you can do that in a mock-up, dramatic situation in front of lights, cameras and film crew, so maybe she <b><i>does</i></b> deserve an Oscar. Let me know what you think about that!)</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Go see <b>Captain Phillips</b>. Ten thumbs up!</span>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="92ba82be7360e923b426ca1e799d974d" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2013/12/how-nelson-mandela-affected-me-as.html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/video/meet-the-press/53772364/#53772364">http://www.nbcnews.com/video/meet-the-press/53772364/#53772364</a><br /><br /><span style="font-size: large;">I was a civil rights advocate from the moment I saw police dogs and fire hoses being loosed on African-Americans here in the US.</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">I remember reading HOUSE OF BONDAGE as a teenager or young adult--reading the words, gasping over the photos of privation and segregation (</span><span style="font-size: large;">apartheid)&nbsp;</span><span style="font-size: large;">in South Africa--and being utterly appalled. I never could understand how the color of another person's skin could create such travesties of justice. I &nbsp;loathed the sight of racially-motivated segregation and fear-mongering. &nbsp;None of it made any sense to me.</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">And when white people called Mandela and others "terrorists" I just laughed. Mandela was <b><i>fighting</i></b> terrorists; he was just pushing back against the culture of his times, as were the civil rights workers in America.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">I always asked people who were unsettled by black "uppity-ness" where they thought they would be if they were black and facing the policies that were allied against them getting a fair shake in the world. I'm afraid I wouldn't have been <b><i>as</i></b>&nbsp;patient, kind or forbearing as Mandela and ML King Jr; I'm afraid I would have been impatient, supremely angry, and explosive. &nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">It's bad enough being treated the way I've been treated as a "female" (as 'less worthy of consideration' when it comes to being heard as the men I worked with and for); I can't even imagine being held at arm's length because of race. I would be livid. I'm certainly not sure that peaceful, non-violent demonstrations would have been <b><u>my</u></b> <i>modus operandi</i> of choice. I was more hot-headed then; had plenty of extra energy to turn loose on injustice. &nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">I "get" Mandela, Gandhi and King now: I realize that their way was the only way to properly <i><b>shame</b></i> whites forward. Violence would have been met with violence, with so-called ( but entirely bogus) "righteous anger". &nbsp;I've seen far too many photos of lynchings. I know what black people were risking by standing up for equal rights. I lived in the deep south for a while during the early 70's and the racism there was <b><i>still</i></b> palpable...</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Nelson Mandela is justifiably being celebrated today as a giant among men. He deserves every accolade being bestowed on him. He never deserved anything less.</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">May God rest his soul and endorse the cause of freedom-loving people everywhere. &nbsp;Love is all we need. Love is all there is. The rest is just static, pain and fear fighting to ward off what is perceived as potential pain and fear. It has to stop before we extinguish ourselves as a species.</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><br /><br /><br /><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ed4578ffc37a58293c8ae644e7d8c8c" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2013/12/kristine-m-smiths-word-whisperer-logo.html"><![CDATA[<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-5G8kkDLsvx0/Ur4x9QeeKJI/AAAAAAAAA38/t_OfWkDBi84/s1600/KMS+logo+CMYK+sm.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="275" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-5G8kkDLsvx0/Ur4x9QeeKJI/AAAAAAAAA38/t_OfWkDBi84/s320/KMS+logo+CMYK+sm.jpg" width="320" /></a></div><div style="text-align: center;"><b>Registered Trademark</b></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9efffe22f8cc127339b37293f8932479" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2013/12/my-newest-websites-are-underway.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: large;">I'm excited. In not much more than a week (unless I get slammed with work) I'll be able to launch <a href="http://wordwhisperer.net/">wordwhisperer.net</a>, my professional copy writing website on WordPress. <b><i>Woo hoo!</i></b></span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">I'll have another one not much later, <a href="http://wordwhisperer.me/">wordwhisperer.me</a>, which will feature the books I've written and the ones I'll be writing.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Both sites will have blogs to keep me busy "in my spare time" (HAH!) so this blog will probably go by the wayside&nbsp;<b><i>unless</i></b> it becomes an eclectic, diary-type thing. Let me know what <b><i><u>you</u></i></b> want to see happening here. I may export some of the copy writing and book-centered blog posts from here to the new ones and leave this one for mostly Kelley-related stuff. It's aptly-named to be a Kelley-based site, for sure!</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">My webmaster, Lisa Twining Taylor, is busy building the WP innards that will take me wherever I want to go. I've been a little strait-jacketed with one of my other professional sites (<a href="http://copywriter-copywriting.net/">copywriter-copywriting.net</a>) because I can't &nbsp;update it regularly without inconveniencing its very busy webmaster so, although it ranks well, it just isn't useful enough. And it isn't responsive, either (the pages don't adapt between desktops, laptops, and other mobile devices); the two new ones <b><i>will</i></b> be responsive, a huge plus. Nor is there a blog on it or on my <a href="http://kristinemsmith.biz/">kristinemsmith.biz</a> site, so they're static sites -- and that's no way to boost them to the top of search engines! &nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Of course, typing in "Kristine M. Smith" will get you to me surely enough, but unless you remember to include the M between Kristine and Smith you're just as likely to get another writer with stellar Star Trek credits, or well-known veterinarians and others. So it's important to get the new sites up so I'm totally in charge of updating them.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Best of all,&nbsp;<a href="http://wordwhisperer.net/">Wordwhisperer.net</a> will help me get off the freelance websites that have become nightmarish places for providers and buyers both. I'll be viewed as the pro I am instead of a pawn in the online race to the bottom for the 'cheapest adequate' (as opposed to the 'best stellar') provider.&nbsp;</span><span style="font-size: large;">In this business, as in most others, you get what you pay for. Start-up business owners and entrepreneurs need to know this.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Among my first tasks will be educating start-up businesses and entrepreneurs so they understand the immense, long-term, evergreen&nbsp;<b><u>value</u></b> of enlisting a professional copywriter... SEO guru ... web designer ...branding expert ... promotional pro ... and the like. I know and have worked with a bunch of great people and plan to extol their virtues every bit as much as they've been extolling mine! In 2014 we're going to be helping each other get to the next level and beyond.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><br /><div style="text-align: center;"><b><i><span style="color: white; font-size: x-large;">Working together, we'll get 'er done! &nbsp;</span></i></b></div><div style="text-align: center;"><b><i><span style="color: white; font-size: x-large;">2014 is the year!</span></i></b></div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ff66a2654e19df301a2916b4f98fb7b2" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2013/12/new-article-i-wrote-for-living-without.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: large;">New article I wrote last night ("Where is Love?") is up now at Life Without Family Network. Check it out if/when you have time or the interest--and feel free to Like and Share!!</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;"><a href="http://www.lwfnetwork.com/">http://www.lwfnetwork.com/</a></span>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b365e0fc301a3cfc133b89fdb6b1e60c" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2013/12/new-website-for-cannon-beach-conference.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: large;">The new Cannon Beach Conference Center website is being built as I write this. I wrote all of the copy for it. Not all of the copy has been loaded yet, but whatever has been loaded that you can see already is all mine!&nbsp;</span><br /><b><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></b><a href="http://retreatcenter.net/"><b><span style="font-size: large;">http://retreatcenter.net/</span></b></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8b9cb9ed24eaea6fe8dc693e838a6724" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2013/12/newest-review-from-local-tacoma-area.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: large;">A primary reason why I love doing what I do is that I get the most enthusiastic client feedback. And although money is important (it allows me to stay in business as a copywriter) the kudos I get from clients mean far more to me!</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><b><i>Kris:</i></b><br /><div><b><i><br /></i></b></div><div><b><i>You <u>are</u> the word whisperer.  Nicely done.  You are a gifted writer and very thorough while delivering the final project in a short period of time. </i></b></div><div><b><i><br /></i></b></div><div><span style="orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><b><i>John B. Merz, Administrator</i></b></span></div><div><div style="word-wrap: break-word;"><div style="word-wrap: break-word;"><div><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><b><i>Memory Haven Sumner</i></b></span></span></span></div><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><b><i></i></b></span></span></span><br /><div><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><b><i>Memory Care Cottages</i></b></span></span></span><br /><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><b><i>5107 Parker Road E.</i></b></span></span></span><br /><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><b><i>Sumner, WA  98390</i></b></span></span></span><br /><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><b><i><br /></i></b>(Copy written to SEO keywords <u>without</u> talking points provided)</span></span></span><br /><div style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div align="center" class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large; text-align: center;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span style="font-family: &quot;Berlin Sans FB&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 18.0pt;">Links to pages I've written<o:p></o:p></span></span></span></span></div><div align="center" class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large; text-align: center;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span style="font-family: &quot;Berlin Sans FB&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 14.0pt;">(Clients gave me permission to disclose that I wrote their copy for them.)<o:p></o:p></span></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span style="font-family: &quot;Berlin Sans FB&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 14.0pt;"><a href="http://www.autorepairseattle.com/">http://www.autorepairseattle.com/</a><o:p></o:p></span></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span style="font-size: small;">(Copy written to SEO keywords&nbsp;</span><u style="font-size: medium;">without</u><span style="font-size: small;">&nbsp;talking points provided)</span></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span style="font-family: &quot;Berlin Sans FB&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 14.0pt;"><a href="http://partsrv.net/">http://partsrv.net/</a><o:p></o:p></span></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span style="font-size: small;">(Copy written to SEO keywords&nbsp;</span><u style="font-size: medium;">without</u><span style="font-size: small;">&nbsp;talking points provided)</span></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span style="color: yellow; font-family: &quot;Berlin Sans FB&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 14pt;"><a href="http://www.furnacefilterscanada.com/">http://www.furnacefilterscanada.com/</a></span><span style="font-family: &quot;Berlin Sans FB&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;;"><span style="color: yellow;"> (I wrote the home page and the English Language version of the video at this site.)</span></span></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; color: yellow;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span style="font-family: 'Segoe UI', sans-serif; font-size: 10.5pt;"><b><i style="background-color: #990000;">The script is amazing.<o:p></o:p></i></b></span></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="background-color: #990000; border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span style="font-family: 'Segoe UI', sans-serif; font-size: 10.5pt;"><b><i style="background-color: #990000;">Thank you again,<o:p></o:p></i></b></span></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="background-color: #990000; border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span style="background-color: #990000; font-family: 'Segoe UI', sans-serif; font-size: 10.5pt;"><b><i>Jean</i></b><o:p></o:p></span></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="background-color: #990000; border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span style="background-color: #990000; font-family: 'Segoe UI', sans-serif; font-size: 14pt;"><a href="http://retreatcenter.net/">http://retreatcenter.net/</a><o:p></o:p></span></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="background-color: #990000; border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="background-color: #990000; border-collapse: separate;"><span style="font-size: small;">(Copy written to SEO keywords <i>mostly</i>&nbsp;</span><u style="font-size: medium;">without</u><span style="font-size: small;">&nbsp;talking points provided)</span></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><b><span style="color: #365f91; font-size: 14.0pt;"><a href="http://jcwhelan.com/">http://jcwhelan.com/</a><o:p></o:p></span></b></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span style="font-family: &quot;Arial&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 11.0pt;"><b><i>“I love taking the time to read what you do with what you are given. You amaze me! I don't think I could give higher praise to any vendor we use - and we have 20 to 30 that we use regularly. There are gifts that God gives that cannot be explained by any man or <o:p></o:p></i></b></span></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span style="font-family: &quot;Arial&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 11.0pt;"><b><i>science - they are living examples of a miracle,&nbsp; tangible to even the highest skeptic. This is what I think each time you submit any writing to us. We are blessed to count you <o:p></o:p></i></b></span></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span style="font-family: &quot;Arial&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 11.0pt;"><b><i>as a partner.”&nbsp; — James C. Whelan, Michigan </i></b><o:p></o:p></span></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span style="font-family: &quot;Arial&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;; font-size: 11.0pt;"><b><i><br /></i></b></span></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span style="font-size: small;">(Copy written to SEO keywords <i>mostly</i>&nbsp;</span><u style="font-size: medium;">without</u><span style="font-size: small;">&nbsp;talking points provided)</span></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><b><a href="http://www.4tssi.com/" style="font-size: x-large;">http://www.4tssi.com</a> (I didn’t write the moving banner ads)<span style="font-size: large;"><o:p></o:p></span></b></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large; margin-left: 4.5pt;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><b>I wrote</b> the above websites in their entirety, some via talking points provided by the clients, some by the seat of my pants.</span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large; margin-left: 4.5pt;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large; margin-left: 4.5pt;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large; margin-left: 4.5pt;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div><div style="font-size: x-large;"></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="font-size: x-large; margin-left: 4.5pt;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><br /></span></span></span></div></div><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"></span></span></span></div><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"></span></span></span></div><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate; orphans: 2; widows: 2;"><span class="ecxApple-style-span" style="border-collapse: separate;"></span></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="122997e4da2bf527c60e647bb6d4e70b" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2013/12/one-of-my-favorite-quotes-now-that-i-am.html"><![CDATA[<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-u4UgjGpmWi8/Uqh3caj4h3I/AAAAAAAAA28/DBeYHmoDvbM/s1600/The+Question+Before+Me.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-u4UgjGpmWi8/Uqh3caj4h3I/AAAAAAAAA28/DBeYHmoDvbM/s320/The+Question+Before+Me.jpg" width="235" /></a></div><br /><div style="text-align: center;">In case the above is hard to read, I'm posting it below, too...</div><div style="text-align: center;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;">"The question before me now that I&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;">am old is not how be dead,&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;">which I know from enough practice,&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;">but how to be alive, as these worn&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;">hills still tell, and some paintings&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;">of Paul Cezanne, and this mere&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;">singing wren, who thinks he's alive&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;">forever, and may be."</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><b><i>-- Wendell Berry, Sabbaths 2001</i></b></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">I cut the above photo and quote out of OPRAH magazine probably fifteen years ago and posted it immediately onto a watercolor background. It resonated with me then, while I was still living in California working at Warner Bros.; it resonates more the older I get.&nbsp;</span><span style="font-size: large;">It's a frequent reminder to me that age is more a state of mind than anything else.&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">Recently I've been watching </span><i style="font-size: x-large; font-weight: bold;">The Waltons </i><span style="font-size: large;">again. Doing this has made me want to emulate&nbsp;</span><b style="font-size: x-large;"><i>the manners</i></b><span style="font-size: large;"> they had. I was raised in a far more dysfunctional household than they were! &nbsp;So as I grew I mostly withdrew from the daily whirlwind of dysfunction and entered into my own world--writing--where things were more manageable and often more sensible.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">I don't know if I've mentioned this before in this blog (probably have, but it's been a while, if so) but I distinctly remember brushing my teeth one morning when I was ten or twelve, thinking noble, uplifting thoughts about how I might change the world for the better, when it occurred to me that no one could hear a blasted word I was thinking, although it was coming across as an orchestrated symphony to me, clear as a bell and inspiring as hell (that rhymes, so I'm keeping it!) My young mind was a masterpiece of can-do/will-do energy!&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">But then I considered the words that actually came out of my mouth whenever I spoke. And I was appalled. &nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">What was in my head and heart were golden; what all-too-often came out of my mouth when I opened it was the kind of dysfunctional garbage I was absorbing from many of the people around me! &nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">I suddenly recognized that two disparate people lived inside me: one was compassionate, good-spirited, loving, charming, funny, forward-thinking; the other was angry, &nbsp;mean-spirited, cutting, and stuck, more-or-less, inside one huge sulk because the world wasn't the way it "should" be <b><i>except at school</i></b>, where I was nurtured and encouraged to pursue my writing; <b><i>and on TV</i></b>, where the Leave it to Beaver and Ozzie and Harriet families and the Bonanza boys were living the kind of family life that so resonated with me.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">Now I realize, of course, that the angry me was the wounded me; the angry me was the wall that I had built, brick upon brick over the years, to keep daily hurt from getting to me. I wasn't "stupid" or "lazy" as my father always described me whenever I wasn't performing constant, visible "chores": I was creating worlds on paper, something he considered a huge waste of time because "if you can't build it or grow it, <b><i>what good is it</i></b>?"&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">Later on I resonated immensely to <b>The Waltons</b> because I saw that&nbsp;John Walton understood his oldest son. Certainly, he <b><i>corrected</i></b>&nbsp;(kindly, compassionately) John-Boy when &nbsp;he got lost in his passion for writing and failed to contribute to the family business that kept them from starving during the Great Depression, but he never belittled his passion for stringing words together.<b><i> John Walton is the kind of dad I needed,</i></b> I thought. (That said, I miss my dysfunctional dad like crazy. He was wounded, too--and we patched up all our disagreements and dysfunctions before he died, thank God!)</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">So brick by brick, I built my wall against the injustice of being called lazy and stupid when what I actually was, was dedicated to the trajectory I wanted for my future.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">Most of my frustration came from being misunderstood. I wasn't expressing myself in the world the way I was on paper: I was pushing back against people who wanted me to conform to society's vision of what girls growing into women should be doing.&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">Fat chance of <b><i>that</i></b>, as adamant as I felt about having been "assigned" the wrong gender at birth--or sometime before (by a wise and wonderful God who knew I'd find the a way to understand and handle it) or after (by scared parents and physicians who thought they were doing the best thing for me "under the circumstances" so I wouldn't be "confused or conflicted" when I reached my teen and adult years.) Look up 'intersex' and the customary way of dealing with it during the time I was an infant, if you want to know more. Intersex is as commonly-occurring as natural red hair; people just don't talk about it--it's a taboo topic for most people--<i>but it exists</i>. I suspect a number of "gay" people are actually intersex adults whose choice of gender was denied them in the years before the 1980's when it became less acceptable to alter babies with ambiguous genitalia. (Disclaimer: I don't know for certain that I was "altered" at birth; it would cost tens of thousands of dollars in tests to find out, I've been told. But when I read about intersex operations about 15 years ago everything fell into place for me including the time my dad exclaimed, "That's my boy!" when I did something as a 32 year-old adult that made him immensely proud, throwing <b><i>me</i></b> for a loop--we had no boys in our family--and <b><i>him</i></b> into an apologetic, scrambling kind explanation maneuver that made no sense whatsoever. I assured him it was okay. (I <b><i>didn't</i></b> tell him that it felt <b><i>exactly right</i></b> to me!)</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">Living a lie is counter-productive. I've discovered that being genuine is the only way to live life. When you tell the truth, you don't have to remember anything.&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">As a child, I could no more deny my passion to write than I could fly to the moon on a pogo stick. I did steer clear of dating because I didn't understand until much later why dating and coupling seemed so unsettling to me. I knew I didn't fit the "right" pattern. I wasn't gay, and I wasn't straight. In my mind, I was Roy Rogers, not Dale Evans. So I put dating and marrying completely out of my mind.&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">Lots of people are celibate. I expect many of them are celibate for the same reason. Or they've found ways to celebrate who they are with someone who understands. I expect those are the happiest ones--providing they can ignore the glares and stares of an unenlightened populace. &nbsp;&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">But am I <b><i>unhappy</i></b>? No. I long ago learned to embrace what I've learned in this wonky body. I understand men (most men) and I understand women (most women) in ways "normal" people probably never will. <b>That's a gift.</b>&nbsp;<b>But is it a blessing? </b>&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">If God gave it to me, yes, it is. If surgeons and my parents gave it to me, yes, it <i><b>still</b></i> is. Because I know the decision came from a place of deep love, from a place of wanting to make everything "all better" for me.&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">Love is never wrong. I know my parents loved me. That's all that really matters.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">Boy, <b><i>this</i></b> blog has wandered miles from where I thought it was going when I first put fingers to keyboard this morning! &nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">But not really. Take a look at the Berry quote again:</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;">"The question before me now that I&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;">am old is not how be dead,&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;">which I know from enough practice,&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;">but how to be alive, as these worn&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;">hills still tell, and some paintings&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;">of Paul Cezanne, and this mere&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;">singing wren, who thinks he's alive&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;">forever, and may be."</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><b><i>-- Wendell Berry, Sabbaths 2001</i></b></div><div style="text-align: center;"><b><i><br /></i></b></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">It fits!&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">And as you know, <b><i>if it fits, it ships!</i></b></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1e711eb90ef2da814e2364bb8eaab319" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2013/12/professional-writing-rates.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: large;">Do you ever have one of those days where you think, "If what I do <b><i>best</i></b> in this world appears to be of so little value to the people who need it, <b><i>why am I even sticking around</i></b>?"</span><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;">I'm having one of those days. And I'm having it because I just visited the Elance website (like an idiot on a weekend when I'm supposed to be resting and recovering my spirit) looking for additional writing work.&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;">The <b><i>quickest</i></b> way for me to get depressed these days is to try to find a project at Elance (or any of the other online freelance sites) that pays what it's worth in time, talent and trouble, which is an indication of how utterly lousy the platform has become as a source of income for professional providers in the United States and other western nations. And I say this with utmost sadness, because Elance gave me my start six years ago and I'm listed among its top writing providers now.&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;">If <b><i><u>I</u></i></b> don't even have a chance to make a head-above-water living at Elance anymore, how will a decently-proficient newbie <b><i>ever</i></b> get the chance to achieve what I have as a copywriter there (over $100K in five years) <b><i>unless</i></b> he or she sells himself or herself short to build the reputation needed to make a go of it, thereby entering the bargain basement ghetto, too?&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;">Oh, I get lots of invitations at Elance to submit quotes on projects, but most of the buyers who invite me think I should be deliriously happy to serve them at less-than-minimum wage sweatshop wages. This despite the fact that my profile page reveals my minimum hourly rate, that I have stellar client feedback, that I've passed all the appropriate tests with high scores, that I have a portfolio that shows my proficiency beyond the shadow of a doubt, and that I have achieved results that have my clients jumping up and down like puppy dogs.</span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;">It seems that pathetically few of the potential buyers/clients at Elance have the foggiest notion of the amount of time it takes for a professional writer to earn his or her stripes (decades) nor do many of them seem able to choose a professional writer because their own writing skills (as far as grammar, spelling and punctuation are concerned) aren't up to par.</span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;">How many Elance buyers understand the tedious <b><i>hours</i></b> it takes to rifle through pages of crappy, incomplete project descriptions looking for the very few projects with a budget that makes it worth our total time to submit quotes and then do the work? I spend hours every day looking over the new projects that pop up in the Writing &amp; Translation and Sales and Marketing categories to find the very few buyers who have listed their projects at rates that make any sense at my end! &nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;">How many Elance buyers understand that freelance copywriters cover 100% of their own business costs--health insurance, federally-mandated fees, and all the rest? How may realize that we don't get unemployment compensation when work doesn't materialize, or that we never get paid vacations, sick days or (rarely) bonuses for exemplary work?</span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;">How many understand that we pay membership fees, connect fees and percentage fees to Elance that consume 15%-20% (sometimes more) of the project price, and that Uncle Sam takes another 10-25% and up, leaving the creator of the work with about 60% (if we're lucky!) of the balance?&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;">And why has Elance never told buyers to <b><i>cancel</i></b> their projects if they don't award them to Elancers so providers can get our connect fees back (they cost us approximately $1.50 each) to use them again to submit quotes on other projects? (Why? Because <b><i>this way</i></b> we have to buy more connect fees! Duh! More money in Elance's tills for providing&nbsp;<b><i>dead end leads</i></b> to us!)</span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;">How many Elance buyers even understand the true value of the "evergreen copy" we provide -- copy that will serve them for decades inside brochures, web content, articles and other pieces that don't need tweaking often? When you consider the ROI you get on copy like this, why do they think they can get away with paying peanuts? The mindset just astonishes me!</span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;">This is why I have my own websites (kristinemsmith.biz, copywriter-copywriting.net) and am working on additional websites (wordwhisperer.me and wordwhisperer.net).&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;">The bottom line is that Elance has become a corporate enterprise built on the backs of &nbsp;providers who pay through the nose to get introduced to Scrooges (and uneducated buyers) who think they can pay nothing much for something great. (Buyers pay nothing to list their projects. It is the providers who make the powers-that-be at Elance their gazillions of dollars.)</span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;">The Bottom line is this: you get what you pay for. (With me, you get way <b><i>more</i></b> than you pay for.) So I'm weaning myself off Elance with all deliberate speed. If you're there, and you're a professional western provider like I am, I advise you to do the same. And if you're considering going there as a professional or as a newbie, give it serious thought. Why should you support a platform that encourages sub-standard results by offering third world prices for first class results?</span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;">If you'd like to see a rates sheet for professional writing rates, shoot me an e-mail to kristinemsmithATmsnDOTcom. I'll be happy to send you one. Just know that <b><i>I</i></b> don't charge $1 to $3 per word unless I'm writing for multinational corporations who understand the value of what they're getting from me and can well afford it. I charge just $100/hour and usually write upward of 500 words per hour.* (Editing and copy-enhancement fees are less, depending on the quality of the existing content.) &nbsp;I also advise clients about how to find professional providers in many areas: web design, SEO, writing, editing, and more. I have some great professional contacts that you should get to know. They can serve you well.</span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><b><i><span style="font-size: large;">* (If the Return on Investment that clients get from my copy wasn't well worth it, I couldn't command even these lower-than-average prices.)&nbsp;</span></i></b></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d886890d9e4bc7931fc30d7781a3e895" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2013/12/santa-claus-and-merry-kris-smith.html"><![CDATA[<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-8-ULBP8wZwY/UreFd_n4gpI/AAAAAAAAA3Y/w8QMQOeHgN8/s1600/Santa+and+Kris.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-8-ULBP8wZwY/UreFd_n4gpI/AAAAAAAAA3Y/w8QMQOeHgN8/s320/Santa+and+Kris.jpg" width="320" /></a></div><div style="text-align: center;"><b>Photo by Jina Cieplik</b></div><div style="text-align: center;"><b>Taken at Lutheran Church of Christ the King</b></div><div style="text-align: center;"><b>Tacoma WA&nbsp;</b></div><div style="text-align: center;"><b>December 20 2013</b></div><div style="text-align: center;"><b><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></b></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">Spent 90 minutes at church on Friday evening watching kids decorate Christmas cookies and meet Santa. What a delightful time. After the kids finished meeting Santa, we big kids had our chance. Pastor Peter's photo was hysterical. I hope to spot it somewhere so I can share it here with you but, so far, no such luck. (Pastor Peter is a card. I don't know a pastor who's more fun.)</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">This morning I got to watch about five minutes of the Christmas program in which my grandnieces had parts, but one of the nursery kids got cranky so I had to leave the sanctuary to watch him. (I'm the nursery supervisor at LCCK; have been for three years now.) Usually I have the wee ones come in to watch the play. There were only two kids in the nursery today so I was feeling exceptionally fortunate but, as luck would have it, the above happened. The good news (which I found out later) is that my niece Wendy videotaped the play so I'll be able to watch it later.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">I got one of the delayed projects back (a $1,000 one) so I'll be able to make ends meet this month by the skin of my teeth. Hallelujah!&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">My garage door spring broke this past week and it will cost over $200 to have it replaced on Monday, but I should have enough to cover that, too. I don't have to spend as much for estimated taxes this time (didn't make as much as I usually do this quarter) so I think I'll squeak by even with the additional expense this month.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">Obamacare will be saving me over $300/month in 2014 thanks to the subsidy I'll be getting, so that's a huge monkey off my back. I ought to be able to start putting emergency money away as a result. I'm <i>very</i> happy about that!</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: large;">Guess that's all the news that's fit to print for this time!</span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: left;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: center;"><br /></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c2a891bd170dc8d3cfe4a77665daf125" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2013/12/so-ready-for-2014-i-can-taste-it.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: large;">I just finalized my year-end income/expenses spreadsheet, the one I'll be sending to my accountant soon. I want to get it going fast because I may be eligible for the ACA's Apple Health Plan here in Washington (<b><i>after</i></b>&nbsp;all deductions and business expenses are subtracted from the $32,000 I made as a copywriter in 2013) because of this year's slightly-lower income than last (I would have been just $2,000 in income above the Apple Plan last year after deductions and expenses, had the plan been in existence then) and, if I am, I want to make the change <b><i>before</i></b> the open enrollment period ends on March 15th, which means I have to get the official, accountant-prepared info to the heath exchange people real soon after I get her take on what the bottom line is. It shouldn't take long; I've been <b><i>extremely conscientious</i></b> all year so I have my ducks in a row. &nbsp;&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Today I took in the last payment of the year <b><i>unless</i></b> one of my new clients funds the first milestone of a project I'll be tackling for him in the next few days. It's a 4 to 6-week $7,500 project (20 hours per week) in three milestones, so I may get $1500 of it tonight. That would be fine with me. I can also wait to get it until the new year, just hours from now. Either way works!&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">It's great to have a $7500 project to kick off the new year with, especially one as exciting as this one is: ghostwriting a book! &nbsp;Yes, this means I can't tell you anything more about it unless the client gives me permission or names me on the acknowledgements page but I can tell you that we at least half-expect it to become a bestseller in a niche or two if he places and promotes it properly. So I haven't been this excited about a project since writing my own books! There's just something about writing a book that is enormously exciting whether my name is on the cover or not. Filling blank pages with new insights and revelations is a service and a calling. I feel like a racehorse ready to bolt out the starting gate!</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="17b51354432107e75f1faf0a65c44f9c" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2014/01/best-marketing-book-ive-ever-read.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">I'm reading what I consider the <b><i><u>best marketing book</u></i></b> <u style="font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;">ever</u>&nbsp;-- and I don't make the claim lightly. I've read an abundance of marketing books but this one&nbsp;takes all the guesswork out of the process. It's called <b><i>GET CLIENTS NOW!</i></b> by C.J. Hayden. I'm devouring every word the first time through and will be implementing it starting tomorrow. It's very, very good.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Because of all I've learned from Hayden's book, I anticipate that I'll be able to fill my pipeline (reliably get 20 hours of work per week at $100/hour, which is all I want so I can network and write, on- and off-line, the other 20 hours/week).&nbsp;<u style="font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;">Hooray!</u>&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">I'll be casting my net into new waters with bigger fish and getting away from appealing to bargain-basement shoppers who want stellar copy written for next to nothing price-wise.&nbsp;The folks who want to pay too little can hire newbies, wannabes or offshore providers with UK English-as-a-second-language and suffer the sad consequences. I'm finished appealing to them (even though I would <b><i>love</i></b> to help them!) because it's obvious most of them haven't done their homework and just don't "get it"-- the value of exemplary copy (and other professional services) escapes them entirely! (Or they don't know what to look for when it comes to hiring competent professionals, so they're hiring blind and suffering the consequences.)&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">As I write this, Lisa Twining Taylor is building me a responsive, interactive business website on a WordPress platform with a blog option. She is working her tail off learning the ins and outs of various WordPress templates and gadgets so she can offer an array of options when she officially announces her services.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">I've seen her working with present and potential clients already and all I can say is she is awesome! &nbsp;She puts her nose to the grindstone and piles up additional skills and insights every single day. And the way she treats clients and prospective clients could be a primer on how to do it right. She takes time (hours of it) to truly understand a client's vision and needs before she submits a proposal; and then she charges what I consider anemic prices if she gets the gig, given the amount of time and effort she puts in "on spec" <b><i>before</i></b> the client has given her a dime or even any assurance that she'll get the nod! &nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Lisa's above-mentioned dedication impresses me as much as it concerns me. (I'm a bit of a Mother Hen.) Of course, she is almost 15 years younger than I am and perhaps doesn't understand how </span><b style="font-size: x-large;"><i>valuable</i></b><span style="font-size: large;"> her life and time are. I do! (We don't get any of it back, that's for sure!) &nbsp;But I "get" her because we both love what we do, so it never feels like too great a sacrifice to linger longer when a client or potential client expresses a need...</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">What I've learned from long experience (lots of it <b><i>hard-won experience</i></b>) is this:</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Do business with the individuals you know who have serious, dedicated passion for the ways in which they can serve you.You'll get the best deals at the best prices -- prices that will reliably serve you (without gouging you) for as long as you're in business. Best of all, the costs are often deductible as a part of doing business, so you can write them off when tax time comes around. So t</span><span style="font-size: large;">here's no downside to hiring a professional, as far as I can tell.</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;"><b><i>Cut costs where cutting costs won't hurt your bottom line</i></b>. Doing so will leave you enough to pay for the professional services that &nbsp;<b><i>increase</i></b> your bottom line. Make sense?</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d9cac3182f04a3557230013deb7f17b8" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2014/01/copywriters-for-your-eyes-only.html"><![CDATA[<div align="center" class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: center;"><b><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;">Copywriters: For Your Eyes Only <o:p></o:p></span></span></b></div><div align="center" class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: center;"><b><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;">Evergreen Copywriting Defined and Explained<o:p></o:p></span></span></b></div><div align="center" class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: center;"><b><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></span></b></div><div align="center" class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: center;"><span style="line-height: 115%;">© 2014 Kristine M. Smith<span style="font-size: large;"><o:p></o:p></span></span></div><div align="center" class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: center;"><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: large;"><b><span style="line-height: 115%;"><i>Evergreen copy defined:</i></span></b><span style="line-height: 115%;"><i> any written communication that can stand the test of time — static web pages, brochures, articles, e-books, white papers, radio and TV ads, explainer videos and other written materials that don’t need to be regularly updated, altered or deleted. </i><o:p></o:p></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><b><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;">Evergreen Copy Should Cost More<o:p></o:p></span></span></b></div><div class="MsoNormal"><b><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></span></b></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;">Evergreen copy should be billed at a higher price than temporary copy because it pays for itself hour after hour, day after day, week after week for years at a time. So if clients find themselves reeling when you quote a rate of $100 or more an hour or one dollar to three dollars a word, allow them time to catch their breath as you explain the long-term value and return on investment they’ll be reaping. <o:p></o:p></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><b><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;">Evergreen Copy Takes Longer<o:p></o:p></span></span></b></div><div class="MsoNormal"><b><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></span></b></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;">Evergreen copy isn’t just slapped together. As a professional copywriter, you aren’t a hired hack. You’ve invested years and thousands of dollars learning the trade; you’ve surpassed (or at least closely approached) Malcolm Gladwell’s established “10,000 hours of study, practice and refinement” to get to the place where you can produce engaging, converting evergreen copy. You don’t dither or worry your words to death; you know what you need to do to help business owners and entrepreneurs succeed. The guesswork is gone. You don’t have to wait for your Muse to show up or for inspiration to strike. To a professional copywriter like you, it’s <b><i>always</i></b> show time … <b><i>every time. </i></b>You’re on the clock!<o:p></o:p></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><b><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;">So … Are You a Clueless Copywriter?<o:p></o:p></span></span></b></div><div class="MsoNormal"><b><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></span></b></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;">If you charge the same prices for temporary flyers that you charge for evergreen copy, you’re leaving huge sums of money on the table. And know this: clients who expect to receive evergreen copy for the price of temporary flyers are either misinformed or miserly—and electing to do business with them will be an exercise in frustration and/or futility, so wish them well and get outta Dodge on the next horse.&nbsp; <o:p></o:p></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;">If you have to cajole and coddle clients to get enough financial sustenance to stay in business while ensuring great results, simply move on. Clueless clients who elect to go elsewhere will get the copy they pay for —anemic, substandard copy that may be fit only for lining the bottom of a bird cage. It’s their choice and no skin off your teeth. When they get burned, they’ll figure it out and come to someone better equipped to serve them -- someone like you. (They always do.)<o:p></o:p></span></span></div><div align="center" class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: center;"><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;">#<o:p></o:p></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="line-height: 115%;">Kristine M. Smith is a professional freelance copywriter and the author of seven books. To discover the kinds of projects she tackles and the ones she leaves to other professional writers, please email her at <b>kristinemsmith@msn.com</b>.<span style="font-size: large;"><o:p></o:p></span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></span></div><br /><div class="MsoNormal"><b>Permission is hereby granted to reprint this article as long as the copyright notice and byline are included wherever the reprint appears.<span style="font-size: large;">&nbsp;</span><o:p></o:p></b></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2e15307a875d051e3c6fa73567cd4ec4" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2014/01/day-one-of-get-clients-now.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: large;">Today I fashioned a marketing plan and <b><i>actually picked up the phone and called a warm lead back</i></b>--one I've been putting off for too long. He was delighted to hear from me, so I'm off to a great start!</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Confession Time: I have a phone phobia -- definitely not a good thing when you're in business. I was raised to stay off the phone (period!) because my mom and dad had a home-based business office with one line. (I doubt there were even options for more than one line in the 1950's.) We kids were forbidden to get pick up the phone unless it was an emergency. So I developed what appears to be an eternal phobia about phones. &nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;"><b><i>You can ask anyone I know: I never call them <u>unless</u> I really, really need to communicate something.</i></b> I will email instead. During the entire decade I was interacting on an almost-daily basis with Carolyn and DeForest Kelley, I called them perhaps a dozen times--and usually then it was because they'd called and left me a message to call them back! We exchanged well over a thousand phone calls (I have proof in two and a half <b><i>very full</i></b> &nbsp;three-ring binders) and I'm probably exaggerating <i><b>on the high side</b></i> to say that a dozen of them were initiated by me. <b><i>I just do not feel it's my place to call people. I figure if they need me, they'll call me!</i></b></span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">So imagine my sense of "ACK!!! OMG! OMG!" when I read in <b><i>GET CLIENTS NOW!</i></b> that I should be picking up the phone and doing cold and warm calls, or getting in touch with networking partners on a frequent basis by phone.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">I panicked! &nbsp;"<i>I don't do that.</i>.. <b><i>I just don't do that!</i></b>" &nbsp;The author says not to put on my to-do list any of the steps that I know I won't do, so I wasn't going to put calling on mine at all -- <b><i>except</i></b> that it's documented to be among the top two most effective, one-to-one ways to stay in touch without costing either party additional time or trouble--and email, although personal, seems more impersonal because there's no voice or body language to recognize. Email is disembodied communication. (Spooky, put that way, huh?)</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">So I told myself, "You're going to do this today. You're going to do the thing you most dread doing and see how it turns out."</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">And I did. And it turned out just fine. (I'm grateful for that. Had this first attempt to connect been a bad experience, it might have confirmed to me that I don't have any business calling people--whether it's a cold call, a warm call, or a smokin' hot sales conversation!)</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">The book talks about fear--how unrealistic it is when we're in business. People expect to be called by the people they know, and by people they don't know. It's easy to quickly determine if the call is going to be beneficial to both parties or not; it doesn't take much time at all.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">So today I did something that has always scared me. And I survived. And I may well thrive with this potential client as a direct result.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">He was expecting my call. He just never got it until today. And he apparently forgave me because he'll be calling me back to discuss his newest projects as soon as he gets out of the meeting he's in.</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Goodness! A weight has been lifted! I'm going to call someone else every day until I'm comfortable with calling, and then maybe I'll call two or three a day. Maybe more. ("Maybe more" seems to be pushing it at this early stage but during my first professional copywriting job--for an on-hold script writing and production company--I was calling upward of fifty existing clients every day and having a pretty good time doing it. I had forgotten that until just now! I <b><i>have</i></b> done this before--and it was <b><i>okay</i></b>! I survived!)</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;"><b><i>People do business with people they know, like and trust</i></b>. Sitting here in my office isn't any way to make that happen: I can only do so much with "words on paper". I need to get out and about and really meet business owners and entrepreneurs.</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">I do network -- have been for two years now, with meager results usually -- but that's because up until recently I've always hung back, hoping someone else would ask for a one-to-one.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">As a result of today's phone call, I'm going to start asking more of&nbsp;<i style="font-weight: bold;">my networking partners&nbsp;</i>for one-to-ones. The only way to get a better result than I've been getting is to do something outside my comfort zone. And this is it, for sure.</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">The shy me needs to get a grip, get a clue and put on her big girl panties and deal with it! Wish me luck, then enlist as my accountability partner if you're nearby (or even virtual).&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">I need encouragement. I need <b><u>you,</u></b> who know of my writing abilities, to talk about me to business owners and entrepreneurs you know and send me warm leads. I'll compensate you, believe me! (I'll write a check for 10% of the referred project to whoever FIRST sends me the referral. So for example, send me a qualified, ready-to-roll client who actually does $1000 worth of business with me and you'll get $100. <b><i>You're my agent; you should be paid an agent's fee!</i></b>)</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">I'm not sure I'll <b><i>ever</i></b> be able to make cold calls to complete strangers, but I'm going to contemplate it further. A cold call is a brief intro to business owners and entrepreneurs I'd like to serve combined with an offer to send or email them a brochure about my services so they'll have the information they need to decide if we're a good fit. It's a perfectly legitimate and helpful meeting of the minds, not a dreaded "sales call". I have a quick question I can ask and a follow-on response that lasts less than twenty seconds if they say, "Yes."</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Can you tell I'm on fire to make this happen? Aye, Captain!&nbsp;</span>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="84f57ce53a86814fe30547a1c576c2b9" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2014/01/good-program-worth-watching-for.html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://billmoyers.com/episode/encore-how-do-conservatives-and-liberals-see-the-world/"><span style="font-size: large;">http://billmoyers.com/episode/encore-how-do-conservatives-and-liberals-see-the-world/</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="22796b555fb4a3c547f9238c6178faa" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2014/01/my-ideal-client-is.html"><![CDATA[<div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpFirst" style="mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><span style="font-family: Wingdings; mso-bidi-font-family: Wingdings; mso-fareast-font-family: Wingdings;"><span style="font-family: 'Times New Roman';">&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></span><!--[endif]--><b>Passionate about a <u>benevolent</u> cause (human, animal, the environment, social/class injustice, helpful/healthy products/services)</b></span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpFirst" style="mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><b><br /></b></span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><b>&nbsp;Driven to help others, with the ability to pay what exemplary copywriting is worth based on long-term ROI&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</b></span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><b><br /></b></span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -.25in;"><b style="font-size: x-large; text-indent: -0.25in;">&nbsp;Insecure or unsure about his or her own writing or communications abilities because of unhappy experiences in school English, business communications, and other communications classes or because of ESL difficulties, dyslexia, etc.</b></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><b><br /></b></span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle" style="mso-list: l0 level1 lfo1; text-indent: -.25in;"><span style="font-size: large;"><b>&nbsp;Too busy running a business to be involved in the day-to-day aspects of public outreach via written communications.<o:p></o:p></b></span></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle"><br /></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpLast"><b><span style="font-size: large;">In a nutshell, if I can get “drunk on your cork”—if you can make me as passionate about what you offer as you are, I can write great copy for you.&nbsp;</span></b></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpLast"><b><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></b></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpLast"><b><span style="font-size: large;">If not, I’ll let you know so you can move on. I work well with other copywriters and can usually recommend someone else who works in your niche.<o:p></o:p></span></b></div><div class="MsoListParagraphCxSpLast"><b><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span></b></div><b><span style="font-family: Calibri, sans-serif; line-height: 115%;"><span style="font-size: large;">Please Note: <span style="color: red;">Industries I usually&nbsp;<i style="text-decoration: underline;">leave to other professional copywriters (</i>except when it comes to editing and copy-enhancing<i style="text-decoration: underline;">) </i>include academic, aerospace, banking/ finance, entertainment, fashion/style, human resources, insurance, IT, real estate, securities, and telecommunications</span></span></span></b></div><div><br /></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fe39f5b28758ece1f5689eec6882dde6" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2014/01/settle-for-best-available-in-kindle.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: large;">My latest title is now available on Kindle. It costs less than the tree-book version. If you already own the tree-book version and bought it at Amazon, you can get the Kindle version for just 99 cents.&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">And &nbsp;get this: You don't have to own a Kindle to get the Kindle version. You can download &nbsp;a free desktop Kindle reader from Amazon! So IF you've been waiting for an e-book version, HERE IT IS!&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">You can even loan your copy to a friend. &nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">I would love to get reviews at Amazon after you've read it. &nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Happy New Year!</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;">Here's the link:&nbsp;</span><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Settle-Best-Satisfy-Winner-Were-ebook/dp/B00HMXZWQ0/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1388694148&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=settle+for+best"><span style="font-size: x-small;">http://www.amazon.com/Settle-Best-Satisfy-Winner-Were-ebook/dp/B00HMXZWQ0/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1388694148&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=settle+for+best</span></a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7fb80787b19472bc389204dd7386f6f0" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2014/01/settle-for-best-satisfy-winner-you-were.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: large;">My newest title is on Kindle now. You don't have to own a Kindle to get it; Amazon has a FREE Kindle reader that you can download.&nbsp;</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><a href="http://www.amazon.com/s/ref=nb_sb_noss?url=search-alias%3Ddigital-text&amp;field-keywords=Settle%20For%20Best">http://www.amazon.com/s/ref=nb_sb_noss?url=search-alias%3Ddigital-text&amp;field-keywords=Settle%20For%20Best</a></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: large;">But just a heads up: From Feb 1st to 5th in the U.S. and from Feb 2 to Feb 4th in the UK&lt; you'll be able to get the Kindle version for just .99 the first day, $1.99 the second day, $2.99 the third day, and so on until it reaches its regular price of $5.99, so if you can wait that long, put the dates on your calendar and start your countdown: Just 28 days to go!</span>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="701635ba078c2f1bcca9ccefea3afcfd" url="http://almostfamousbydesfault.blogspot.com/2014/01/shamelessly-swiped-from-heck-of.html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: large;">Robert Louis Stevenson was a magnificent writer. He wrote many treasures, including "The Strange Case of Dr. Jekyll &amp; Mr. Hyde" and "Treasure Island".<br /><br />                        Most people don't know that Stevenson barely survived childhood. He grew up sickly in 19th century Edinburgh. He couldn't go outside to play with his peers.<br /><br />                        Fortunately, his parents had means so young Robert was attended by a nurse. One day, as dusk settled upon Edinburgh, he sat in a chair staring out the window. He wasn't reading or doing anything, just staring as the lamplighters came by to ignite the street lights.<br /><br />                        Finally, his nurse asked him: "Robert, what are you doing?"<br /><br />                        "I'm just watching that fellow punch holes in the darkness."</span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;"><br /><b><i>                        Why do good writers write? Why do good representatives go back into the morass that is Washington D.C. politics?&nbsp;</i></b></span><br /><span style="font-size: large;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: large;"><b><u>For the same reason</u></b>: <b><i>To punch holes in the darkness.</i></b></span>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>