<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="herbscribner.wordpress.com">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="dd93affb939c0078b5f5810e499a9663" url="http://herbscribner.wordpress.com/2012/04/21/the-pen-chapter-1/"><![CDATA[Here&#8217;s the first piece of fiction I&#8217;m going to post to coincide with the new theme of my blog. It&#8217;s the first chapter of &#8220;The Pen,&#8221; a novel I began working on in 2004 during eighth grade. I made a significant dent in the book, which is now around 280 words. The final pieces still [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=herbscribner.wordpress.com&#038;blog=17217063&#038;post=504&#038;subd=herbscribner&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a9568a08d4511a41c87ea16dbca3fb08" url="http://herbscribner.wordpress.com/2012/05/08/jesus-take-the-wheel/"><![CDATA[Well, here we are. It’s the end of the school year, we’re finally done. Junior year has come to a close and I approach my final year of college and, most likely, my final year of education. It all boils down to this. Last time I posted something, I talked about how we beat on [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=herbscribner.wordpress.com&#038;blog=17217063&#038;post=515&#038;subd=herbscribner&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a536384b8fc4ee7b6a97d6a4fc9c029e" url="http://herbscribner.wordpress.com/2012/05/10/end-of-an-era-leaving-baker-129/"><![CDATA[Leaving Baker 129 marks the end of an era in my life. Last year, Baker 129 was the hot spot for the floor, joined with 130 right across the hall. While 130 featured the frat-party like atmosphere, 129 was more chill, but still a spot for people to hang out in and spend the evening. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=herbscribner.wordpress.com&#038;blog=17217063&#038;post=523&#038;subd=herbscribner&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6efe8b5613544e2497042f66f769b072" url="http://herbscribner.wordpress.com/2012/05/16/let-the-summer-of-soccer-begin/"><![CDATA[Here we are again. It’s the middle of May, spring is just beginning to settle into summer and there’s tons of footy being played globally. Teams are being relegated, others promoted, transfer rumors are starting, goals and highlights are being remembered, the Cristiano Ronaldo vs. Lionel Messi debate wages on, and tournaments and qualifiers are [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=herbscribner.wordpress.com&#038;blog=17217063&#038;post=534&#038;subd=herbscribner&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9b934b9fe825e689ec54c9761cca70a6" url="http://herbscribner.wordpress.com/2012/05/18/agudelo-to-chivas-offers-both-something-new/"><![CDATA[Phew, what a day. I’m sure I wasn’t alone yesterday afternoon when I was surprised to see all the Juan Agudelo to Chivas USA Tweets pop-up. And even as rumors swirled for a few hours before the Red Bulls made it official, I still felt the shock that we all feel when two MLS clubs [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=herbscribner.wordpress.com&#038;blog=17217063&#038;post=541&#038;subd=herbscribner&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="412a088934aadcf846b89954c5f10038" url="http://herbscribner.wordpress.com/2012/08/10/10-weeks-older/"><![CDATA[I walked out of the Erie Times-News office today around 5:35 p.m. The first thing I noticed was the sun. It had been raining throughout the entire day and the forecasts called for more. It wasn’t supposed to be so sunny and beautiful out. And as I walked to the bus stop, at the corner [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=herbscribner.wordpress.com&#038;blog=17217063&#038;post=551&#038;subd=herbscribner&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e7352b56d56bf45e7c8ec96cd33121f7" url="http://herbscribner.wordpress.com/2012/10/20/fiction-corner-preface-to-battle-born/"><![CDATA[Jake Manwaring knew monsters were creeping around him, but he stood his ground. It had been dead silent, an oddity for these woods that were flooded with everything evil. From werewolves to vampires, the forests were a walking death trap. Trees were stained with blood, markers of past lives long lost. Jake rarely experienced complete [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=herbscribner.wordpress.com&#038;blog=17217063&#038;post=557&#038;subd=herbscribner&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c536dd0cafe4e8092a925b18ada80660" url="http://herbscribner.wordpress.com/2013/01/02/13-resolutions-for-2013/"><![CDATA[I thought I&#8217;d update my blog with my 13 resolutions for the new year. Some of you probably saw these on Twitter. But for this blog post,  I decided to better explain my resolutions so that there&#8217;s a better understanding. Resolution No. 1: Lose the final 18 lbs of my goal. Those who&#8217;ve known me [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=herbscribner.wordpress.com&#038;blog=17217063&#038;post=564&#038;subd=herbscribner&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4854d2cc938a9e293afdd24a9ab1f43b" url="http://herbscribner.wordpress.com/2013/01/22/one-more-go/"><![CDATA[It’s here. The final semester starts today. It&#8217;s the last first day for me, unless I eventually attend grad school to further my journalism knowledge beyond what actual experience can do. Today is the final time I will debate where to sit for the first class, or what students to befriend and which to avoid. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=herbscribner.wordpress.com&#038;blog=17217063&#038;post=599&#038;subd=herbscribner&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="76db4df9189f0b5a027e60649fe84880" url="http://herbscribner.wordpress.com/2013/05/05/right-back-into-place/"><![CDATA[Note: I originally wrote this piece last May, but thought it&#8217;d be great to post a year later. It was late May, and one of my best friends, who had just returned from studying abroad in Costa Rica, picked me up from outside my house in his white Ford Taurus. Immediately upon entering his car, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=herbscribner.wordpress.com&#038;blog=17217063&#038;post=615&#038;subd=herbscribner&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>