<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="feeds.feedburner.com/DedeWatson">
	<documents count="10">
		<document id="9de316e2e9298c3ea328ef85ae87aee7" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DedeWatson/~3/-gNG14g2qhE/"><![CDATA[Facebook can be very perplexing for a business owner with little advertising budget who wants to grow his  fan page. It takes much more time to build a following on Facebook than Twitter and Pinterest, however there are ways to gain a steady following if you implement a consistent strategy. Here are 5 Tips You [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2bd10dad4bcd620c64af3e5f95ad5d5" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DedeWatson/~3/9lIcJ5yUQdg/"><![CDATA[Here are 5 worth looking at: Evernote &#8211; https://evernote.com/ The ability to save anything from webpages to clips to photos to sounds Evernote syncs each device so you are always updated You can also research and work with friends on projects You can plan for events You can remember important things to do, dates, times [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d8bffc7bd023629261459115f6179b5d" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DedeWatson/~3/cfL1Rz8ZHb0/"><![CDATA[Twitter recently opened up their analytics to everyone, not just ad customers. What this means to you as a Twitter user is that you will now have some free metrics to gauge your performance on Twitter. You can locate the analytics area on the Twitter Ads Dashboard. &#160; There are 2 areas that are available [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9d80af3ff9d7506860178b35fdb333d9" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DedeWatson/~3/GrHOSYayna4/"><![CDATA[This morning Twitter announced a new advertising feature for businesses. It allows advertisers to reach people who have tweeted specific keywords in their recent tweets . What does this mean for you? If you are a business that sells golf equipment, your tweet can reach people that have an interest in golf or have recently [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="fa46b3046b86e84b90b5de573a62ece0" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DedeWatson/~3/SHuPPQSU_5M/"><![CDATA[Here are 5 Blogging tips to get you started for 2013:  1. Make sure you change your copyright to 2013 When you start out this year the first thing to do is to change your copyright to 2013.  This protects you and your work for the year ahead so that nobody can copy your work. [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="440ec267532e01b90f78165769f46583" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DedeWatson/~3/SWzqDbZNdZw/"><![CDATA[You might have seen them all over the world on Twitter and just about every other social media network.  #Hashtags, those words that pop up now and again in tweets and all over Instagram and slowly but surely they are popping up on Facebook. Hashtags are terms used so that if you search for that [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c08269b1160c35816bb57f175c404a8c" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DedeWatson/~3/tOFd_DfVSVU/"><![CDATA[For those of you who do not know much about Slideshare it is a wonderful online and offline tool which you can use for presentations, mini-books, sales pitches, inspiration and so much more. Here are 5 tips for you to use it for your Brand. Join Slideshare and upload your first presentation Visit www.slideshare.net and [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8ec45604599f117b8359b8995ceede1" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DedeWatson/~3/TzAdJq4s_GQ/"><![CDATA[Pinterest might be more important to your brand than you think!  More brands are recognizing the power and importance of a strong social media presence to convert to sales!!  Many major retailers are turning to Pinterest and not simply relying on Facebook. According to Sephora’s head of digital Julie Bornstein, Pinterest members spend 15 times [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="16945d4a7ffe05952ecc2142e2f1bee2" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DedeWatson/~3/vRux1lJfJfs/"><![CDATA[There are many reasons why people might feel a need to protect their Tweets.  What people may not understand about Twitter is that this is not the same as Facebook. You are not necessarily creating a new foundation of  &#8220;friends&#8221; in the same sense as you might on Facebook. Although Twitter is an amazing place [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="11dc0485656b71b17acb17fffedb8bd4" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/DedeWatson/~3/vZ95cKeUdIY/"><![CDATA[So you have read and followed my advice from my first post 4 Steps to Social Media Success BEFORE you start on Social Media: 1) Know what you want to accomplish 2) How much time can you spend on your social media 3) Narrow down the networks you will participate in 4) Plan your content [...]
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>