<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="www.soultsretailview.co.uk">
	<documents count="20">
		<document id="34d2a7752670ac3ebd26f4fbc75cd67f" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/06/28/clicks-bricks-and-stunning-images-retailer-qa-with-the-original-sofa-co/"><![CDATA[If you read the blog accompanying my 2012 Autumn Fair seminar on creating great web content, you&#8217;ll know that one of the things I always look for is a bold, interesting and eyecatching homepage. As I observed then, &#8220;if the impression that your domain name gives is important, making a positive impact with your website’s [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e62606b9c412f85ad48773e45ccfc389" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/07/08/north-east-leads-the-space-change-as-tesco-adds-gyms-to-extra-stores/"><![CDATA[Tesco Extra branches in Stockton-on-Tees and Sunderland are to see surplus space converted into gyms, as the retail giant looks to &#8216;repurpose&#8217; excess square footage within some of its largest stores. Plans to shrink some oversized Extra stores were first mentioned back in October, as constrained consumer spending and a shift to online shopping impact on [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="18e25e4f1da61c2f0987e77381fc2b0b" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/07/08/opened-on-8-july-1933-whats-become-of-the-ex-woolworths-in-morden/"><![CDATA[Regular readers will know that I always enjoy an obscure Woolworths anniversary, and today represents the 80th anniversary of the now-defunct chain opening its 498th store, at Morden in south-west London. Step out of Morden Tube station &#8211; an attractive 1920s frontage bizarrely encased in an ugly &#8217;60s office block &#8211; as I did back in [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8423229535084d76af70d2ef6571c1f7" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/07/11/gatesheads-metrocentre-prepares-for-overnight-intu-fication/"><![CDATA[I understand that Gateshead&#8217;s Metrocentre is to gain its first Intu-branded external signage overnight tonight (11 July), ahead of a weekend of celebrations to mark the &#8216;official launch&#8217; of Intu Metrocentre. Metrocentre owner Capital Shopping Centres plc announced in January that it would be rebranding the company as Intu Properties plc &#8211; styled and, annoyingly from a [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2b1e9e65682f59ae5196c6b4d9bd520e" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/07/11/north-east-stores-invade-london-as-metro-outlet-heads-to-croydons-ex-allders/"><![CDATA[In the same month that Middlesbrough-based furniture institution Barker and Stonehouse has opened its first London store, in Battersea, it&#8217;s been revealed that another firm with a former Boro connection and a current Gateshead one &#8211; the discount department store Metro Outlet &#8211; is to open in the iconic former Allders store in Croydon, which has [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="9d757a81b80960dddbb73b5f80e7ffb8" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/07/17/got-a-question-about-starting-a-retail-business-ask-a-sage-business-expert/"><![CDATA[As you may recall, one of the many hats that I wear is as a Sage Business Expert. Set up by the Newcastle-based software company nearly a year ago, the aim of the group is to support and advise Britain&#8217;s business community via social media, bringing together a raft of handpicked Business Experts who &#8220;share a [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="60e622ca81ee78389b8469d57cf6819a" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/07/19/shrewsbury-the-town-where-independents-are-keeping-the-high-street-buzzing/"><![CDATA[Regular readers will know that I visit a lot of British high streets &#8211; including more than 400 different ones in the last four years &#8211; but it&#8217;s usually on my own, and rarely for very long in any one place (which, in a very few unfortunate cases, is admittedly a blessing). So, it was a [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e85ffa8dfbe893a765b9bc5e75493ac9" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/08/31/celebrating-britains-new-indie-retailers-at-autumn-fair/"><![CDATA[Regular readers will know that one of my favourite things about working in retail is discovering really interesting and successful independent shops &#8211; whether that&#8217;s the &#8220;new breed of web-savvy independents&#8221; who are helping to keep our high streets alive while embracing all the potential of online marketing, to innovative pureplay etailers who are using [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7ab9c7e0498342a5fecea5a8d3aef6e2" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/09/20/tracking-down-darlingtons-original-woolworths-73-years-after-it-relocated/"><![CDATA[Never one to let a good Woolworths anniversary pass me by, today &#8211; 20 September 2013 &#8211; represents 73 years since Darlington&#8217;s Woolworths store relocated from its original premises, opened on 27 September 1913, to what would become its more familiar location at 12-18 Northgate. Following the 1940 move, Woolworths traded from that spot for nearly six [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="94701fa653dc11da031b6eb726e3686b" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/09/30/old-woolies-fascia-exposed-as-byker-wetherspoons-readies-for-october-opening/"><![CDATA[The Newcastle suburb of Byker will gain a welcome addition when its new Wetherspoon pub &#8211; The High Main &#8211; opens at 63 Shields Road on 22 October. In the meantime, however, I&#8217;ve been getting excited about a fragment of the property&#8217;s former life that Wetherspoon&#8217;s work has exposed: the old red-tiled fascia from the building&#8217;s days [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b8206b361b4a4306410140f74079c9e" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/10/18/bm-recruits-for-gateshead-team-valley-store-ahead-of-16-november-opening/"><![CDATA[The thriving discount retailer B&#38;M is recruiting staff for its new Gateshead store, which is scheduled to open at Team Valley Retail World on Saturday 16 November. Various permanent roles, including Customer Service Assistants, are currently being advertised on the B&#38;M site, while Gateshead is listed as one of 14 upcoming locations on the &#8216;new [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c94669fe1039abae3593a4ef5d9eb044" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/10/18/good-news-for-sunderland-as-fashion-store-utopia-takes-over-ex-peacocks/"><![CDATA[Sunderland&#8217;s ex-Peacocks unit in The Bridges is finally to be reoccupied, after more than 18 months of vacancy. The prominent Market Square store was one of ten North East branches that closed following Edinburgh Woollen Mill&#8217;s rescue of 400 Peacocks stores in February last year. Now, after months of posters promising a new retailer &#8216;coming soon&#8217;, I [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7a1204a4dbb11c380264a01515ebd5f5" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/10/21/adidas-and-toys-r-us-move-quickly-to-fill-intu-eldon-square-voids/"><![CDATA[In recent months, the St Andrew&#8217;s Way section of Newcastle&#8217;s Eldon Square has seen its first tenant departures since opening in February 2010, with the loss of Republic and Guess. Both units are set to be quickly refilled, however, as two big names &#8211; Toys R Us and Adidas &#8211; move in to fill the [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ddadf9b548f744bdace43239c169687e" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/10/24/fenwick-newcastles-autumn-window-impresses-but-whsmith-opposite-falls-short/"><![CDATA[Newcastle&#8217;s iconic Fenwick department store is rightly known for its annual Christmas window &#8211; which can&#8217;t, scarily, be very far off making its appearance for 2013. Last year I captured the Christmas window being set up on 30 October (below), so on that basis we can expect to see festive activity kicking off in Northumberland Street [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="8adcddf495a71b55f9e3ba6985b202ae" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/10/25/resurgent-game-reopens-axed-stores-in-newcastle-and-sunderland/"><![CDATA[A year and a half after 21 North East stores closed following Game&#8217;s collapse into administration, two of those shops &#8211; in Grainger Street, Newcastle and High Street West,Sunderland &#8211; are reopening. The Gamestation-branded shop in Grainger Street was one of four Newcastle city centre Game stores at the time of the chain&#8217;s collapse in March [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="5230e6d0b654a21ce2b8ebb1d8f6528a" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/11/12/we-present-a-new-way-of-shopping-retailer-qa-with-the-longest-stay/"><![CDATA[As you&#8217;d expect, running the Home Interiors Directory (part of my CannySites.com business) means that I get to work with a lot of etailers who are operating in - and competing in &#8211; the interiors and home furnishings space. From category-straddling big names like Sainsbury&#8217;s and Dunelm, to smaller specialists in rugs, sofas or glassware, all are [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e322492f809586f52038a2f6e9d0ead6" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/11/15/exclusive-lego-store-set-for-29-november-opening-at-intu-metrocentre/"><![CDATA[The new Lego Store at Gateshead&#8217;s Intu Metrocentre is to open on Friday 29 November, I understand. The imminent opening of the store seems to have prompted much excitement among North East Lego enthusiasts &#8211; many of them somewhat older than the Danish toy brand&#8217;s core market &#8211; since the appearance of job adverts in late September revealed that a [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3fd69d2891950f9033cbaa969171bc7a" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/11/26/five-years-on-from-woolies-collapse-boyes-signs-for-the-coalville-store/"><![CDATA[It&#8217;s hard to believe that it&#8217;s five years ago today &#8211; on 26 November 2008 &#8211; that Woolworths collapsed into administration after trading in the UK for nearly 100 years. At that time, few could have expected that just 40 days later &#8211; on 6 January 2009 &#8211; the entire 807-strong chain would have been [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2e57acc51e3d5bc73a2d439d4a3ed001" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2013/12/02/promoting-the-fair-trade-cause-retailer-qa-with-the-home-decor-company/"><![CDATA[Though navigating the economic downturn continues to challenge many stores, one of the fascinating subtexts has been the growth of new independent retailers, sometimes borne out of individuals who have faced redundancy &#8211; perhaps in the public sector &#8211; and who have sensed the opportunity to take on a new and different challenge in the retail world. Founded [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="588e99b7b197bb6afa90e04b6ef845c7" url="http://www.soultsretailview.co.uk/2014/01/06/five-years-after-closure-newton-aycliffe-woolworths-may-soon-be-occupied/"><![CDATA[If you&#8217;ve managed to miss me hogging the airwaves this morning &#8211; on BBC Radio 5 Live (which you can listen to here), Wales, Scotland, and Coventry &#38; Warwickshire so far &#8211; you may not be aware that today is the fifth anniversary of Woolworths finally closing its doors. On 6 January 2009, the last 207 Woolworths [&#8230;]
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>