<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="abbottanalytics.blogspot.com">
	<documents count="25">
		<document id="a3c6c45058ff812d7ebe119e78989b1e" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/04/another-wisdom-of-crowds-prediction-win.html"><![CDATA[This past week at <a href="http://www.predictiveanalyticsworld.com/toronto/2012/">Predictive Analytics World / Toronto</a> (PAW) has been a great time for connecting with thought leaders and practitioners in the field. Sometimes there are unexpected pleasures as well, which is certainly the case this time.  One of the exhibitors for the eMetrics conference, co-locating with PAW at the venue, was <a href="http://unilytics.com/">Unilytics</a>, a web analytics company. At their booth there was a cylindrical container filled with crumpled dollar bills with a sign soliciting predictions of how many dollar bills were in the container (the winner getting all the dollars). After watching the announcement of the winner, who guessed $352, only $10 off from the actual $362, I thought this would be the perfect opportunity for another <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Wisdom-Crowds-James-Surowiecki/dp/0385721706/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&qid=1335478732&sr=8-1">Wisdom of Crowds</a> test,just like the one conducted 9 months ago and blogged on <a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.ca/2011/07/yet-another-wisdom-of-crowds-success.html">here</a>.  <br> <div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-BZzgyCvOm3Y/T5nLq7Oq_cI/AAAAAAAAAJc/wQwn72r9PK4/s1600/Unilytics%2BGary%2Band%2BKeith%2Bat%2BeMetrics.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear:left; float:left;margin-right:1em; margin-bottom:1em"><img border="0" height="400" width="300" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-BZzgyCvOm3Y/T5nLq7Oq_cI/AAAAAAAAAJc/wQwn72r9PK4/s400/Unilytics%2BGary%2Band%2BKeith%2Bat%2BeMetrics.jpg" /></a></div> Two <a href="http://unilytics.com/">Unilytics</a> employees at the booth, Gary Panchoo and Keith MacDonald, were kind enough to indulge me and my request to compute the average of all the guesses. John Elder was also there, licking his wounds from finished a close second as his guess, $374 was off by $12, a mere $2 away from the winning entry!  The results of the analysis are here (summary statistics created by <a href="http://jmp.com/">JMP Pro 10 </a>for the mac). In summary, the results are as follows:  <h4>Dollar Bill Guess Scores</h4><table border=1 cellpadding=2 cellspacing=1><tr valign=top align=right><th align=left>Method</th><th>Guess Value</th><th>Error</th></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>Actual</td><td>362</td><td></td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>Ensemble/Average (N=61)</td><td>365</td><td>3</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>Winning Guess (person)</td><td>352</td><td>10</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>John Elder</td><td>374</td><td>12</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>Guess without outlier (2000), 3rd place</td><td>338</td><td>24</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>Median, 19th place</td><td>275</td><td>87</td></tr></table><br><br>So once again, the average of the entries (the "Crowds" answer) beat the single best entry. What is fascinating to me about this is not that the average won (though this in of itself isn't terribly surprising), but rather <i>how</i> it won. Summary statistics are below. Note that the Median is 275, far below the mean. Not too how skewed the distribution of guesses are (skew = 3.35). The fact that the guesses are skewed positively for a relatively small answer (362) isn't a surprise, but the amount of skew is a bit surprising to me.   What these statistics tell us is that while the mean value of the guesses would have been the winner, a more robust statistic would not, meaning that the skew was critical in obtaining a good guess. Or put another way, people more often than not under-guessed by quite a bit (the median is off by 87). Or put a third way, the outlier (2000) which one might naturally want to discount because it was a crazy guess was instrumental to the average being correct.   In the prior post on this from July 2011, I trimmed the guesses, removing the "crazy" ones. So when should we remove the wild guesses and when shouldn't we? (If I had removed the 2000, the "average" still would have finished 3rd). I have no answer to when the guesses are not reasonable, but wasn't inclined to remove the 2000 initially here.  Full stats from JMP are below, with the histogram showing the amount of skew that exists in this data.   <h2>Distribution of Dollar Bill Guesses - Built with JMP</h2><h4>Summary Statistics</h4><table border=1 cellpadding=2 cellspacing=1><tr valign=top align=right><th align=left>Statistic</th><th>Guess Value</th></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>Mean</td><td>365</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>Std Dev</td><td>299.80071</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>Std Err Mean</td><td>38.385548</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>Upper 95% Mean</td><td>441.78253</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>Lower 95% Mean</td><td>288.21747</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>N</td><td>61</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>Skewness</td><td>3.3462476</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>Median</td><td>275</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>Mode</td><td>225</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>2% Trimmed Mean</td><td>331.45614</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>Interquartile Range</td><td>185.5</td></tr></table><br>Note: The mode shown is the smallest of 2 modes with a count of 3.<br> <h4>Quantiles</h4><table border=1 cellpadding=2 cellspacing=1><tr valign=top align=right><th align=left>Quantile</th><th></th><th>Guess Value</th></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>100.0%</td><td>maximum</td><td>2000</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>99.5%</td><td></td><td>2000</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>97.5%</td><td></td><td>1546.8</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>90.0%</td><td></td><td>751.6</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>75.0%</td><td>quartile</td><td>406.5</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>50.0%</td><td>median</td><td>275</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>25.0%</td><td>quartile</td><td>221</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>10.0%</td><td></td><td>145.6</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>2.5%</td><td></td><td>98.2</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>0.5%</td><td></td><td>96</td></tr><tr valign=top align=right><td align=left>0.0%</td><td>minimum</td><td>96</td></tr></table><br> <br><br><br><br> <div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-6p31gNE9lCA/T5nMxEuQXBI/AAAAAAAAAJo/EZFg-hCQvEs/s1600/Distribution%2Bof%2Bunilytics%2Bguess.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear:right; float:right; margin-left:1em; margin-bottom:1em"><img border="0" height="400" width="268" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-6p31gNE9lCA/T5nMxEuQXBI/AAAAAAAAAJo/EZFg-hCQvEs/s400/Distribution%2Bof%2Bunilytics%2Bguess.png" /></a></div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f6c913e307b873a7c1c239c13d3ae13a" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/04/dilbert-database-marketing-and-spam.html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/04/what-im-working-on.html">Ruben's comment</a> that referred to spam reminded me of an <a href="http://dilbert.com/strips/comic/2000-11-13/" title="Dilbert.com">old Dilbert comic</a> which conveys the misconception about database marketing (e-marketing) and spam. <br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://dilbert.com/dyn/str_strip/000000000/00000000/0000000/000000/00000/6000/900/6921/6921.strip.gif" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left:1em; margin-right:1em"><img border="0" height="189" width="640" src="http://dilbert.com/dyn/str_strip/000000000/00000000/0000000/000000/00000/6000/900/6921/6921.strip.gif" /></a></div><br />I know Ruben well and know he was poking fun, though I still have to correct folks who after finding out I do "data mining" actually comment that I'm responsible for spam. Answer: "No, I'm the reason you don't get as much spam!"
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4eab00c1a9175a19b76c77ac35bd0fe8" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/05/predictive-analytics-world-had-target.html"><![CDATA[The New York Times Magazine article "<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/02/19/magazine/shopping-habits.html?pagewanted=all">How Companies Learn Your Secrets</a>" by Charles Duhigg with the key descriptions of Target, pregnancy, predictive analytics (blogged on <a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/02/target-pregnancy-and-predictive.html">here</a> and <a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/02/target-pregnancy-and-predictive_21.html">here</a>) certainly generated a lot of buzz; if you are unable to see the NYTimes Magazine article, the <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/kashmirhill/2012/02/16/how-target-figured-out-a-teen-girl-was-pregnant-before-her-father-did/">Forbes summary</a> is a good summary.  However, few know that Eric Siegel booked Andy Pole for the October 2010 <a href="http://www.predictiveanalyticsworld.com/dc/2010/">Predictive Analytics World</a> conference as a keynote speaker. The full video of that talk is <a href="http://rmportal.performedia.com/node/1373">here</a>.  <br><br>In this talk, Mr. Pole discussed how Target was using Predictive Analytics including descriptions of using potential value models, coupon models, and...yes...predicting when a woman is due (if you aren't the patient type, it is at about 34:30 in the video). These models were very profitable at Target, adding an additional 30% to the number of woman suspected or known to be pregnant over those already known to be (via self-disclosure or baby registries). The fact that this went on for over a year after the Predictive Analytics World talk and before the fallout tells me that it didn't cause significant problems for Target prior to the attention brought to the subject related to the NYTimes article.  <br><br>After watching the talk, what struck me most was that Target was applying a true "360 deg" customer view by linking guests through store visits, web, email, and mobile interactions. In addition, close attention was paid to linking the interactions so that coupons made sense: they didn't print coupons to those who had just purchased items they score high for couponing, and they identify which mediums don't generate responses and stop using those channels. <br><br>I suspect what Target is doing is no different than most retailers, but this talk was an interesting glimpse into how much they value the different channels and try to find ways to provide customers with what they are most interested in, and suppress what they are not interested in.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6fd8995898b8aace1cd8fa59546a5bd8" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/06/where-it-began-john-elder-and-dean.html"><![CDATA[I came across this photo today and couldn't resist. <a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/--xplVQzyXVQ/T-PGFm336zI/AAAAAAAAAK8/N3YHJeS7dkk/s1600/Barron%2BAssociates%2Bsummer%2B1988.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left:1em; margin-right:1em"><img border="0" height="266" width="400" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/--xplVQzyXVQ/T-PGFm336zI/AAAAAAAAAK8/N3YHJeS7dkk/s400/Barron%2BAssociates%2Bsummer%2B1988.jpg" /></a> John Elder and I worked at the company <a href="http://www.barron-associates.com/history/" target="_blank">Barron Associates, Inc.</a> (BAI) in Charlottesville, VA in the 80s (John was employee #1). Hopefully you can identify John in the back right and me in the front right, though it will take some good pattern matching to do so!  <br><br>The Founder and President of the company was Roger Barron. Both John and I were introduced to statistical learning methods at BAI and of course went on to careers in the field now known as Data Mining or Predictive Analytics (among other things). I write about my experience with BAI in the forthcoming book <a href="http://www.springer.com/computer/database+management+%26+information+retrieval/book/978-3-642-28046-7">Journeys to Data Mining: Experiences from 15 Renowned Researchers</a>, Ed. by Dr Mohamed Medhat Gaber, published by Springer. Authors in the book include John (thanks to John for recommending my inclusion in the book), Gregory Piatetsky-Shapiro, Mohammed J. Zaki, and of course several others.  <br><br>The photo appeared as I was searching for descriptions of our field back in the 80s and was looking in particular for the Barron and Barron paper "<a href="http://www.stat.yale.edu/~arb4/publications_files/statistical%20learning%20netwooks%20%20a%20unifying%20view.pdf" target="_blank">Statistical Learning Networks: A Unifying View</a>", where "Statistical Learning Networks" was the phrase of interesting, along with "Models", "Classifiers", and "Neural Networks". We used to refer to the field as "Pattern Recognition" and "Artificial Intelligence". It's interesting to note that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pattern_recognition#See_also" target="_blank">pattern recognition on Wikipedia</a> contains a list of "See Also" terms that includes the more modern terms such as data mining and predictive analytics.  <br><br>I will post within a couple days on the pattern recognition terms of the day and how they are changing.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="10bed3b0ea3ea226e6602875cc023958" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/07/predicting-crime.html"><![CDATA[Applying inferential statistics to criminology is not new, but it appears that the market has been maturing.&nbsp; See, for instance, a recent article,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.rawstory.com/rs/2012/07/29/police-using-predictive-analytics-to-prevents-crimes-before-they-happen/">"Police using ‘predictive analytics’ to prevent crimes before they happen"</a>, published by Agence France-Presse on&nbsp;<a href="http://www.rawstory.com/">The Raw Story</a> (Jul-29-2012).<br /><br />Setting aside obvious civil liberties questions, consider the application of this technology.&nbsp; My suspicion is that targeting police efforts by geographic locale and day-of-week/time-of-day using this approach will decrease the overall level of crime, but by how much is not clear. This is typical of problems faced by businesses: It is not enough to predict what we already know, nor is it enough to trot out glowing but artificial technical measures of performance.&nbsp; Knowledge that real improvement has occurred requires more.&nbsp; For instance, at least some effect of police effort on the street does not decrease crime, but merely moves it to new locations.<br /><br />Were I mayor of a small town approached by the vendor of such a solution, I'd want to see some sort of experimental design which made apples-to-apples comparison between our best estimates of what happens with the new tool, and what happens without it.&nbsp; Only once this firm measure of benefit has been obtained could one reasonably weigh it against the financial and political costs.<br /><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="670a828f31bedf983e2d519ad5257b5b" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/08/choose-your-target-carefully.html"><![CDATA[Every so often, an article or survey will appear stressing the importance of data preparation as an early step in the process of data mining.&nbsp; One often-overlooked part of data preparation is to clearly define the problem, and, in particular, the target variable.&nbsp; Often, a nominal definition of the target variable is given.<br /><br />As an example, a common problem in banking is to predict future balances of a loan customer.&nbsp; The current balance is a matter of record and a host of explanatory variables (previous payment history, delinquency history, etc.) are available for model construction.&nbsp; It is easy to move forward with such a project without considering carefully whether the raw target variable is the best choice for the model to approximate.&nbsp; It may be, for instance, that it is easier to predict the logarithm of balance, due to a strongly skewed distribution.&nbsp; Or, it might be that it is easier to predict the ratio of future balances to the current balance.&nbsp; These two alternatives result in models whose output are easily transformed back into the original terms (by exponentiation or multiplication by the current balance, respectively).&nbsp; More sophisticated targets may be designed to stabilize other aspects of the behavior being studied, and certain other loose ends may be cleaned up as well, for instance when the minimum or maximum target values are constrained.<br /><br />When considering various possible targets, it helps to keep in mind that the idea is to stabilize behavior, so that as many observations as possible align in the solution space.&nbsp; If retail sales include a regular variation, such as by day of the week or month of the year, then that might be a good candidate for normalization: Possibly we want to model retail sales divided by the average for that day of the week, or retail sales divided by a trailing average for that day of the week for the past 4 weeks.&nbsp; Some problems lend themselves to decomposition, such as profit being modeled by predicting revenue and cost separately.&nbsp; One challenge to using multiple models in series this way is that their (presumably independent) errors will compound.<br /><br />Experience indicates that it is difficult in practice to tell which technique will work best in any given situation without experimenting, but performance gains are potentially quite high for making this sort of effort.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="699a6697ebbc04d51acf1a54971a484d" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/08/recently-published-research-what-makes.html"><![CDATA[Recently published research, <a href="http://graphics.cs.cmu.edu/projects/whatMakesParis/" target="_blank">What Makes Paris Look like Paris?</a>, attempts to classify images of street scenes according to their city of origin.&nbsp; This is a fairly typical supervised machine learning project, but the source of the data is of interest.&nbsp; The authors obtained a large number of Google Street View images, along with the names of the cities they came from.&nbsp; Increasingly, large volumes of interesting data are being made available via the Internet, free of charge or at little cost.&nbsp; Indeed, I published an article about classifying individual pixels within images as "foliage" or "not foliage", using information I obtained using on-line searches for things like "grass", "leaves", "forest" and so forth.<br /><br />A bewildering array of data have been put on the Internet.&nbsp; Much of this data is what you'd expect: financial quotes, government statistics, weather measurements and the like- large tables of numeric information.&nbsp; However, there is a great deal of other information: 24/7 Web cam feeds which are live for years, news reports, social media spew and so on.&nbsp; Additionally, much of the data for which people once charged serious bucks is now free or rather inexpensive.&nbsp; Already, many firms augment the data they've paid for with free databases on the Web.&nbsp; An enormous opportunity is opening up for creative data miners to consume and profit from large, often non-traditional, non-numeric data which are freely available to all, but (so far) creatively analyzed by few.<br /><br /><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="46e9979656f283b25c40a2ccbf615a66" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/09/budgeting-time-on-modeling-project.html"><![CDATA[Within the time allotted for any empirical modeling project, the analyst must decide how to allocate time for various aspects of the process.&nbsp; As is the case with any finite resource, more time spent on <i>this</i> means less time spent on <i>that</i>.&nbsp; I suspect that many modelers enjoy the actual modeling part of the job most.&nbsp; It is easy to try "one more" algorithm: Already tried logistic regression and a neural network?&nbsp; Try CART next.<br /><br />Of course, more time spent on the modeling part of this means less time spent on other things.&nbsp; An important consideration for optimizing model performance, then, is: Which tasks deserve more time, and which less?<br /><br />Experimenting with modeling algorithms at the end of a project will no doubt produce <i>some</i> improvements, and it is not argued here that such efforts be dropped.&nbsp; However, work done earlier in the project establishes an upper limit on model performance.&nbsp; I suggest emphasizing data clean-up (especially missing value imputation) and creative design of new features (ratios of raw features, etc.) as being much more likely to make the model's job easier and produce better performance.<br /><br />Consider how difficult it is for a simple 2-input model to discern "healthy" versus "unhealthy" when provided the input variables <i>height</i> and <i>weight</i> alone.&nbsp; Such a model must establish a dividing line between healthy and unhealthy weights separately for each height.&nbsp; When the analyst uses instead the ratio of weight to height, this becomes much simpler.&nbsp; Note that the commonly used BMI (body mass index) is slightly more complicated than this, and would likely perform even better.&nbsp; Crossing categorical variables is another way to simplify the problem for the model.&nbsp; Though we deal with a process we call "machine learning", is is a pragmatic matter to make the job as easy as possible for the machine.<br /><br />The same is true for handling missing values.&nbsp; Simple global substitution using the non-missing mean or median is a start, but think about the spike that creates in the variable's distribution.&nbsp; Doing this over multiple variables creates a number of strange artifacts in the multivariate distribution.&nbsp; Spending the time and energy to fill in those missing values in a smarter way (possibly by building a small model) cleans up the data dramatically for the downstream modeling process.<br /><br /><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a44c99d58fa5012441de9e7fee044294" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/09/what-do-we-call-what-we-do.html"><![CDATA[I've called myself a data miner for about 15 years, and the field I was a part of as Data Mining (DM). Before then, I referred to what I did as "Pattern Recognition", "Machine Learning", "Statistical Modeling", or "Statistical Learning". In recent years, I've called what I do Predictive Analytics (PA) more often and even co-titled my blog with both Data Mining and Predictive Analytics. That stated, I don't have a good noun to go along with PA. A "predictive analytist" (as if I myself were a "predictor")? A "predictive analyzer"? I often call someone who does PA a Predictive Analytics Professional.   But the according to google, the trending on data mining is down. Pattern recognition? Down. Machine Learning? Flat or slightly up. Only Predictive Analytics and it's closely-related sibling, Business Analytics, are up.  Even the much-touted Data Science has been relatively flat, though has been spiking Q4 the past few years.    <br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-14MqdWZNF1I/UFAIiOt2j-I/AAAAAAAAALo/4VyKXmBgQCQ/s1600/data%2Bmining%2Btrend%2B11Sep12.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="data mining" border="0" height="179" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-14MqdWZNF1I/UFAIiOt2j-I/AAAAAAAAALo/4VyKXmBgQCQ/s400/data%2Bmining%2Btrend%2B11Sep12.png" title="Google Trends: Data Mining" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Data Mining</td></tr></tbody></table><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-dfy0ZzqEVFw/UFAIiWioupI/AAAAAAAAAL0/CKXpHf1g884/s1600/pattern%2Brecognition%2Btrend%2B11Sep12.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="179" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-dfy0ZzqEVFw/UFAIiWioupI/AAAAAAAAAL0/CKXpHf1g884/s400/pattern%2Brecognition%2Btrend%2B11Sep12.png" title="Google Trends: Pattern Recognition" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Pattern Recognition</td></tr></tbody></table><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-uqMvt4p52cs/UFAIi3GvW6I/AAAAAAAAAMA/q0wZBZbXSxo/s1600/machine%2Blearning%2Btrend%2B11Sep12.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="179" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-uqMvt4p52cs/UFAIi3GvW6I/AAAAAAAAAMA/q0wZBZbXSxo/s400/machine%2Blearning%2Btrend%2B11Sep12.png" title="Google Trends: Machine Learning" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Machine Learning</td></tr></tbody></table><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-2gpPJtnWhRg/UFAIjD3wnBI/AAAAAAAAAMM/Z0vnddoc40M/s1600/predictive%2Banalytics%2Btrend%2B11Sep12.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="179" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-2gpPJtnWhRg/UFAIjD3wnBI/AAAAAAAAAMM/Z0vnddoc40M/s400/predictive%2Banalytics%2Btrend%2B11Sep12.png" title="Google Trends: Predictive Analytics" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Predictive Analytics</td></tr></tbody></table><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-KDtL6J7KFbg/UFAIjciEmnI/AAAAAAAAAMY/A9qRDSBgb1o/s1600/business%2Banalytics%2Btrend%2B11Sep12.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="179" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-KDtL6J7KFbg/UFAIjciEmnI/AAAAAAAAAMY/A9qRDSBgb1o/s400/business%2Banalytics%2Btrend%2B11Sep12.png" title="Google Trends: Business Analytics" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Business Analytics</td></tr></tbody></table>The big winner? Big Data of course! It has exploded this year. Will that trend continue? It's hard to believe it will continue, but this wave has grown and it seems that every conference related to analytics or databases is touting "big data".    <br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-u3-UhBFSPaU/UFAKEzCb2tI/AAAAAAAAAMk/ghGAuKFAKyk/s1600/big%2Bdata%2Btrend%2B11Sep12.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="179" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-u3-UhBFSPaU/UFAKEzCb2tI/AAAAAAAAAMk/ghGAuKFAKyk/s400/big%2Bdata%2Btrend%2B11Sep12.png" title="Google Trends: Big Data" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Big Data</td></tr></tbody></table>&nbsp;   <br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-NGwZY0XOoGI/UFAKFCKWGXI/AAAAAAAAAMw/PPpNuZ805KQ/s1600/data%2Bscience%2Btrend%2B11Sep12.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img alt="" border="0" height="179" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-NGwZY0XOoGI/UFAKFCKWGXI/AAAAAAAAAMw/PPpNuZ805KQ/s400/data%2Bscience%2Btrend%2B11Sep12.png" title="Google Trends: Data Science" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Data Science</td></tr></tbody></table>  <br />I have no plans of calling what I do "big data" or "data science". The former term will pass when data gets bigger than big data. The latter may or may not stick, but seems to resonate more with theoreticians and leading-edge types than with practitioners.   For now, I'll continue to call myself a data miner and what I do predictive analytics or data mining. 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="53274a40360d5d033c8996bd6565ee49" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/10/data-preparation-know-your-records.html"><![CDATA[Data preparation in data mining and predictive analytics (dare I also say Data Science?) rightfully focuses on how the fields in ones data should be represented so that modeling algorithms either will work properly or at least won't be misled by the data. These data preprocessing steps may involve filling missing values, reigning in the effects of outliers, transforming fields so they better comply with algorithm assumptions, binning, and much more. <br><br>In recent weeks I've been reminded how important it is to know your records. I've heard this described in many ways, four of which are:<br><br><LI>the unit of analysis</LI><LI>the level of aggregation</LI><LI>what a record represents</LI><LI>unique description of a record</LI><br><br>For example, does each record represent a customer? If so, over their entire history or over a time period of interest? In web analytics, the time period of interest may be a single session, which if it is true, means that an individual customer may be in the modeling data multiple times as if each visit or session is an independent event. <br><br>Where this especially matters is when disparate data sources are combined. If one is joining a table of customerID/Session data with another table with each record representing a customerID, there's no problem. But if the second table represents customerID/store visit data, there will obviously be a many-to-many join resulting in a big mess. <br><br>This is probably obvious to most readers of this blog. What isn't always obvious is when our assumptions about the data result in unexpected results. What if we expect the unit of analysis to be customerID/Session but there are duplicates in the data? Or what if we had assumed customerID/Session data but it was in actuality customerID/Day data (where ones customers typically have one session per day, but could have a dozen)? <br><br>The answer is just like we need to perform a data audit to identify potential problems with fields in the data, we need to perform record audits to uncover unexpected record-level anomalies. We've all had those data sources where the DBA swears up and down that there are no dups in the data, but when we group by customerID/Session, we find 1000 dups. <br><br>So before the joins and after joins, we need to do those group by operations to find examples with unexpected numbers of matches.  <br><br>In conclusion: know what your records are supposed to represent, and verify verify verify. Otherwise, your models (who have no common sense) will exploit these issues in undesirable ways!     
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="26d14dee77fad4cef668eaef1e5fd5df" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/11/why-predictive-modelers-should-be.html"><![CDATA[Well, the danger is really not the statistical test <i>per se</i>, it the interpretation of the statistical test.  <br><br>Yesterday I tweeted (@deanabb) this fun factoid: "Redskins predict Romney wins POTUS #overfit. if Redskins lose home game before election => challenger wins (17/18) http://www.usatoday.com/story/gameon/2012/11/04/nfl-redskins-rule-romney/1681023/" I frankly had never heard of this "rule" before and found it quite striking. It even has its own Wikipedia page (http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Redskins_Rule). <br><br>For those of us in the predictive analytics or data mining community, and those of us who use statistical tests to help out interpreting small data, 17/18 we know is a hugely significant finding. This can frequently be good: statistical tests will help us gain intuition about value of relationships in data even when they aren't obvious.  <br><br>In this case, an appropriate test is a chi-square test based on the two binary variables (1) did the Redskins win on the Sunday before the general election (call it the input or predictor variable) vs. (2) did the incumbent <i>political party</i> win the general election for President of the United States (POTUS).  <br><br>According to the Redskins Rule, the answer is "yes" in 17 of 18 cases since 1940. Could this be by chance? If we apply the chi-square test to it, it sure does look significant! (chi-square = 14.4, p < 0.001). I like the decision tree representation of this that shows how significant it is (built using the Interactive CHAID tree in IBM Modeler on Redskin Rule data I put together <a href="http://abbottanalytics.com/data/Redskins%20rule%20data.xlsx">here</a>): <div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-nZU3yRRJOHA/UJlSA2_fqdI/AAAAAAAAAN8/l8e6qYI7M6c/s1600/incumbant%2Bresult%2Bchaid%2Bw%2Bchi-square.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left:1em; margin-right:1em"><img border="0" height="400" width="274" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-nZU3yRRJOHA/UJlSA2_fqdI/AAAAAAAAAN8/l8e6qYI7M6c/s400/incumbant%2Bresult%2Bchaid%2Bw%2Bchi-square.png" /></a></div> <br><br>It's great data--9 Redskin wins, 9 Redskin losses, great chi-square statistic!   <br><br>OK, so it's obvious that this is just another spurious correlation in the spirit of all of those fun examples in history, such as the superbowl winning conference predicting if the stock market would go up or down in the next year at a stunning 20 or 22 correct. It even was the <a href="http://www.jstor.org/discover/10.2307/2328679?uid=3739560&uid=2129&uid=2&uid=70&uid=4&uid=3739256&sid=21101254384943">subject of academic papers</a> on the subject! <br><br>The broader question (and concern) for predictive modelers is this: how do we recognize when we have uncovered spurious correlations in the data that are merely spurious? This can happen especially when we don't have deep domain knowledge and therefore wouldn't necessarily identify variables or interactions as spurious. In examples such as the election or stock market predictions, no amount of "hold out" samples, cross-validation or bootstrap sampling would uncover the problem: it is in the data itself. <br><br>We need to think about this because inductive learning techniques search through hundreds, thousands, even millions of variables and combinations of variables. The phenomenon of "over searching" is a real danger with inductive algorithms as they search and search for patterns in the input space. Jensen and Cohen have a very nice and readable paper on this topic (PDF <a href="http://shawndra.pbworks.com/f/Multiple+comparisons+in+induction+algorithms.pdf">here</a>). For trees, they recommend using the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bonferroni_correction">Bonferroni adjustment</a> which does help penalize the combinatorics associated with splits. But our problem here goes far deeper than overfitting due to combinatorics. <br><br>Of course the root problem with all of these spurious correlations is small data. Even if we have lots of data, what I'll call here the "illusion of big data", some algorithms make decisions based on smaller populations, like decision trees, rule induction and nearest neighbor (i.e., algorithms that build bottom-up). Anytime decisions are made from populations of 15, 20, 30 or even 50 examples, there is a danger that our search through hundreds of variables will turn out a spurious relationship.  <br><br>What do we do about this? First, make sure you have enough data so that these small-data effects don't bite you. This is why I strongly recommend doing data audits and looking for categorical variables that contain levels with at most dozens of examples--these are potential overfilling categories. <br><br>Second, don't hold strongly any patterns discovered in your data based on solely on the data, especially if they are based on relatively small sample sizes. These <i>must</i> be validated with domain experts. Decision trees are notorious for allowing splits deep in the trees that are "statistically significant" but dangerous nevertheless because of small data sizes.  <br><br>Third, the gist of your models have to make sense. If they don't, put on your "Freakonomics" hat and dig in to understand why the patterns were detected by the models. In our Redskin Rule, clearly this doesn't make sense causally, but sometimes the pattern picked up by the algorithm is just a surrogate for a real relationship.  Nevertheless, I'm still curious to see if the Redskin Rule will prove to be correct once again. This year it predicts a Romney win because the Redskins lost and therefore the incumbent party (D) by the rule should lose.   UPDATE: by way of comparison...the chances of having 17/18 or 18/18 coin flips turn up heads (or tails--we're assuming a fair coin after all!) is 7 in 100,000 or 1 in 14,000. Put another way, if we examined 14K candidate variables unrelated to POTUS trends, the chances are that one of them would line up 17/18 or 18/18 of the time. Unusual? Yes. Impossible? No!        
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4c5686fa02e11bec0c35840cc61a07ae" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/12/6-reasons-you-hired-wrong-data-miner.html"><![CDATA[As is in any discipline, talent within data mining community varies greatly.&nbsp; Generally, business people and others who hire and manage technical specialists like data miners are not themselves technical experts.&nbsp; This makes it difficult to evaluate the performance of data miners, so this posting is a short list of possible deficiencies in a data miner's performance.&nbsp; Hopefully, this will spare some heartache in the coming year.&nbsp; Merry Christmas!<br /><br /><br /><b>1. The data miner has little or no programming skill.</b><br /><br />Most work environments require someone to extract and prepare the data.&nbsp; The more of this process which the data miner can accomplish, the less her dependence on others.&nbsp; Even in ideal situations with prepared analytical data tables, the data miner who can program can wring more from the data than her counterpart who cannot (think: data transformations, re-coding, etc.).&nbsp; Likewise, when her predictive model is to be deployed in a production system, it helps if the data miner can provide code as near to finished as possible.<br /><br /><br /><b>2. The data miner is unable to communicate effectively with non-data miners.</b><br /><br />Life is not all statistics: Data mining results must be communicated to colleagues with little or no background in math.&nbsp; If other people do not understand the analysis, they will not appreciate its significance and are unlikely to act on it.&nbsp; The data miner who can express himself clearly to a variety of audiences (internal customers, management, regulators, the press, etc.) is of greater value to the organization than his counterpart who cannot.&nbsp; The data miner should should receive questions eagerly.<br /><br /><br /><b>3. The data miner never does anything new.</b><br /><br />If the data miner always approaches new problems with the same solution, something is wrong.&nbsp; She should be, at least occasionally, suggesting new techniques or ways of looking at problems.&nbsp; This does not require that new ideas be fancy: Much useful work can be done with basic summary statistics.&nbsp; It is the way they are applied that matters.<br /><br /><br /><b>4. The data miner cannot explain what they've done.</b><br /><br />Data mining is a subtle craft: there are many pitfalls and important aspects of statistics and probability are counter-intuitive.&nbsp; Nonetheless, the data miner who cannot provide at least a glimpse into the specifics of what they've done and why, is not doing all he might for the organization.&nbsp; Managers want to understand why so many observations are needed for analysis (after all, they pay for those observations), and the data miner should be able to provide some justification for his decisions.<br /><br /><br /><b>5. The data miner does not establish the practical benefit of his work.</b><br /><br />A data miner who cannot connect the numbers to reality is working in a vacuum and is not helping her manager (team, company, etc.) to assess or utilize her work product.&nbsp; Likewise, there's a good chance that she is pursuing technical targets rather than practical ones.&nbsp; Improving p-values, accuracy, AUC, etc. may or may not improve profit (retention, market share, etc.).<br /><br /><br /><b>6. The data miner never challenges you.</b><br /><br />The data miner has a unique view of the organization and its environment.&nbsp; The data miner works on a landscape of data which few of his coworkers ever see, and he is less likely to be blinded by industry prejudices.&nbsp; It is improbable that he will agree with his colleagues 100% of the time.&nbsp; If the data miner never challenges assumptions (business practices, conclusions, etc.), then something is wrong.<br /><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="71bdbee186bf1378697cd8c2c3ffa82f" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2013/01/three-ways-to-get-your-predictive.html"><![CDATA[       <!--[if gte mso 9]><xml> <o:DocumentProperties>  <o:Revision>0</o:Revision>  <o:TotalTime>0</o:TotalTime>  <o:Pages>1</o:Pages>  <o:Words>1195</o:Words>  <o:Characters>6812</o:Characters>  <o:Company>Abbott Analytics</o:Company>  <o:Lines>56</o:Lines>  <o:Paragraphs>15</o:Paragraphs>  <o:CharactersWithSpaces>7992</o:CharactersWithSpaces>  <o:Version>14.0</o:Version> </o:DocumentProperties> <o:OfficeDocumentSettings>  <o:AllowPNG/> </o:OfficeDocumentSettings></xml><![endif]--> <!--[if gte mso 9]><xml> <w:WordDocument>  <w:View>Normal</w:View>  <w:Zoom>0</w:Zoom>  <w:TrackMoves/>  <w:TrackFormatting/>  <w:PunctuationKerning/>  <w:ValidateAgainstSchemas/>  <w:SaveIfXMLInvalid>false</w:SaveIfXMLInvalid>  <w:IgnoreMixedContent>false</w:IgnoreMixedContent>  <w:AlwaysShowPlaceholderText>false</w:AlwaysShowPlaceholderText>  <w:DoNotPromoteQF/>  <w:LidThemeOther>EN-US</w:LidThemeOther>  <w:LidThemeAsian>JA</w:LidThemeAsian>  <w:LidThemeComplexScript>X-NONE</w:LidThemeComplexScript>  <w:Compatibility>   <w:BreakWrappedTables/>   <w:SnapToGridInCell/>   <w:WrapTextWithPunct/>   <w:UseAsianBreakRules/>   <w:DontGrowAutofit/>   <w:SplitPgBreakAndParaMark/>   <w:EnableOpenTypeKerning/>   <w:DontFlipMirrorIndents/>   <w:OverrideTableStyleHps/>   <w:UseFELayout/>  </w:Compatibility>  <m:mathPr>   <m:mathFont m:val="Cambria Math"/>   <m:brkBin m:val="before"/>   <m:brkBinSub m:val="&#45;-"/>   <m:smallFrac m:val="off"/>   <m:dispDef/>   <m:lMargin m:val="0"/>   <m:rMargin m:val="0"/>   <m:defJc m:val="centerGroup"/>   <m:wrapIndent m:val="1440"/>   <m:intLim m:val="subSup"/>   <m:naryLim m:val="undOvr"/>  </m:mathPr></w:WordDocument></xml><![endif]--><!--[if gte mso 9]><xml> <w:LatentStyles DefLockedState="false" DefUnhideWhenUsed="true"   DefSemiHidden="true" DefQFormat="false" DefPriority="99"   LatentStyleCount="276">  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="0" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Normal"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="9" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="heading 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="9" QFormat="true" Name="heading 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="9" QFormat="true" Name="heading 3"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="9" QFormat="true" Name="heading 4"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="9" QFormat="true" Name="heading 5"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="9" QFormat="true" Name="heading 6"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="9" QFormat="true" Name="heading 7"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="9" QFormat="true" Name="heading 8"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="9" QFormat="true" Name="heading 9"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" Name="toc 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" Name="toc 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" Name="toc 3"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" Name="toc 4"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" Name="toc 5"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" Name="toc 6"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" Name="toc 7"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" Name="toc 8"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" Name="toc 9"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="35" QFormat="true" Name="caption"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="10" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Title"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="1" Name="Default Paragraph Font"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="11" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Subtitle"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="22" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Strong"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="20" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Emphasis"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="59" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Table Grid"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Placeholder Text"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="1" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="No Spacing"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="60" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Shading"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="61" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light List"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="62" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Grid"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="63" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="64" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="65" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="66" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="67" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="68" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="69" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 3"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="70" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Dark List"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="71" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Shading"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="72" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful List"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="73" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Grid"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="60" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Shading Accent 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="61" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light List Accent 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="62" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Grid Accent 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="63" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 1 Accent 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="64" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 2 Accent 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="65" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 1 Accent 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Revision"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="34" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="List Paragraph"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="29" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Quote"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="30" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Intense Quote"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="66" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 2 Accent 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="67" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 1 Accent 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="68" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 2 Accent 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="69" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 3 Accent 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="70" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Dark List Accent 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="71" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Shading Accent 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="72" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful List Accent 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="73" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Grid Accent 1"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="60" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Shading Accent 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="61" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light List Accent 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="62" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Grid Accent 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="63" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 1 Accent 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="64" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 2 Accent 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="65" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 1 Accent 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="66" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 2 Accent 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="67" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 1 Accent 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="68" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 2 Accent 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="69" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 3 Accent 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="70" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Dark List Accent 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="71" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Shading Accent 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="72" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful List Accent 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="73" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Grid Accent 2"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="60" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Shading Accent 3"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="61" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light List Accent 3"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="62" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Grid Accent 3"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="63" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 1 Accent 3"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="64" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 2 Accent 3"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="65" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 1 Accent 3"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="66" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 2 Accent 3"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="67" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 1 Accent 3"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="68" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 2 Accent 3"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="69" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 3 Accent 3"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="70" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Dark List Accent 3"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="71" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Shading Accent 3"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="72" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful List Accent 3"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="73" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Grid Accent 3"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="60" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Shading Accent 4"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="61" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light List Accent 4"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="62" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Grid Accent 4"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="63" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 1 Accent 4"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="64" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 2 Accent 4"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="65" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 1 Accent 4"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="66" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 2 Accent 4"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="67" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 1 Accent 4"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="68" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 2 Accent 4"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="69" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 3 Accent 4"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="70" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Dark List Accent 4"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="71" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Shading Accent 4"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="72" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful List Accent 4"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="73" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Grid Accent 4"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="60" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Shading Accent 5"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="61" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light List Accent 5"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="62" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Grid Accent 5"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="63" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 1 Accent 5"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="64" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 2 Accent 5"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="65" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 1 Accent 5"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="66" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 2 Accent 5"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="67" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 1 Accent 5"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="68" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 2 Accent 5"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="69" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 3 Accent 5"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="70" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Dark List Accent 5"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="71" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Shading Accent 5"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="72" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful List Accent 5"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="73" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Grid Accent 5"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="60" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Shading Accent 6"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="61" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light List Accent 6"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="62" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Light Grid Accent 6"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="63" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 1 Accent 6"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="64" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Shading 2 Accent 6"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="65" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 1 Accent 6"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="66" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium List 2 Accent 6"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="67" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 1 Accent 6"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="68" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 2 Accent 6"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="69" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Medium Grid 3 Accent 6"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="70" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Dark List Accent 6"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="71" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Shading Accent 6"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="72" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful List Accent 6"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="73" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" Name="Colorful Grid Accent 6"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="19" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Subtle Emphasis"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="21" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Intense Emphasis"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="31" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Subtle Reference"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="32" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Intense Reference"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="33" SemiHidden="false"    UnhideWhenUsed="false" QFormat="true" Name="Book Title"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="37" Name="Bibliography"/>  <w:LsdException Locked="false" Priority="39" QFormat="true" Name="TOC Heading"/> </w:LatentStyles></xml><![endif]--> <!--[if gte mso 10]><style> /* Style Definitions */ table.MsoNormalTable  {mso-style-name:"Table Normal";  mso-tstyle-rowband-size:0;  mso-tstyle-colband-size:0;  mso-style-noshow:yes;  mso-style-priority:99;  mso-style-parent:"";  mso-padding-alt:0in 5.4pt 0in 5.4pt;  mso-para-margin:0in;  mso-para-margin-bottom:.0001pt;  mso-pagination:widow-orphan;  font-size:10.0pt;  font-family:"Times New Roman";  mso-fareast-language:JA;} </style><![endif]-->   <!--StartFragment--> <br /><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">We all know that given reasonable data, a good predictive modeler can build a model that works well and helps make makes better decisions than what is currently used in your organization (at least in our own minds). Newer data, sophisticated algorithms, and a seasoned analyst are all working in our favor when we build these models, and if success were measured by accuracy (as they are in most data mining competitions), we're in great shape. Yes, there are always gotchas and glitches along the way. But when my deliverable is only slideware, even of the modeling is hard, I'm confident of being able to declare victory at the end.<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">However, the reality is that there is much more to the transition from cool model to actual deployment than a nice slide deck and paper accepted at one's favorite predictive analytics, data mining or big data conference. In these venues, the winning models are those that are "accurate" (more on that later) and have used creative analysis techniques to find the solution; we won't submit a paper when we only had to press the "go" button and have the data mining software give us a great solution!<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">For me, the gold standard is deployment. If the model gets used and improves the decisions an organization makes, I've succeeded. Three ways to increase the likelihood your models are deployed are: <o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><b><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">1) Make sure the model stakeholder designs deployment into the project from the beginning</span></b><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;"><o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">The model stakeholder is the individual, usually a manager, who is the advocate of predictive models to decision-makers. It is possible that a senior-level modeler can do this task, but that person must be able to switch hit: he or she must be able to speak the language of management and be able to talk technical detail to analytics. This may require more than one trusted person: the manager, who is responsible and makes the ultimate decisions about the models, and the lead modeler, who is responsible for the technical aspects of the model. It is more than "talking the talk" and knowing buzz-words in both realms; the person or persons must truly be "one of" both groups. <o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">For those who have followed my blog posts and conference talks, you know I am a big advocate of the CRISP-DM process model (or equivalent methodologies, which seem to be endless). I've referred to CRISP-DM often, including on topics related to </span><a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2011/06/what-do-data-miners-need-to-learn.html"><span style="color: #878787; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA; text-decoration: none; text-underline: none;">what data miners need to learn</span></a><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">and </span><a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/04/why-defining-target-variable-in.html"><span style="color: #878787; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA; text-decoration: none; text-underline: none;">Defining the Target Variable</span></a><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">, just as two examples. <o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">The stakeholder must not only understand the business of objectives of the model (Business Understanding in CRISP-DM), but must be present during discussions take place related to which models will be built. It is essential that reasonable expectations are put into place from the beginning, including what a good model will "look like" (accuracy and interpretability) and how the final model will be deployed. <o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">I've seen far too many projects die or become inconsequential because either the wrong objectives were used in building the models, meaning the models were operationally useless, or because the deployment of the models was not considered, meaning again that the models were operationally useless. As an example, on one project, the model was assumed to be able to be run within a rules engine, but the models that were built were not rules at all, but were complex non-linear models that could not be translated into rules. The problem obviously could have been avoided had this disconnect been verbalized early in the modeling process. <o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><b><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">2) Make sure modelers understand the purpose of the models</span></b><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;"><o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">The modelers must know how the models will be used and what metrics should be used to judge model performance. A good summary of typical error metrics used by modelers is found </span><a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2006/11/error-measures.html%20target="><span style="color: #878787; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA; text-decoration: none; text-underline: none;">here</span></a><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">. However, for most of the models I have deployed in customer acquisition, retention, and risk modeling, the treatment based on the model is never applied to the <i>entire</i> population (we don't mail everyone, just a subset). So the metrics that make the most sense are often ones like "lift after the top decile", maximum cumulative net revenue, top 1000 scores to be investigated, etc. I've actually seen negative correlations between the ranking of models based on global metrics (like classification error or R^2) vs. the ranking based on subset selection ranking, such as top 1000 scores; very different models may be deployed depending on the metric one uses to assess them. If modelers aren't aware of the metric to be used, the wrong model can be selected, even one that does worse than the current approach.<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">Second, if the modelers don't understand how the models will be deployed operationally, they may find a fantastic model, one that maximizes the right metric, but is useless. The Neflix Prize is a </span><a href="http://techblog.netflix.com/2012/04/%20netflix-recommendations-beyond-5-stars.html"><span style="color: #878787; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA; text-decoration: none; text-underline: none;">great example</span></a><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">: the final winning model was accurate but far too complex to be used. Netflix extracted key pieces to the models to operationalize instead. I've had customers stipulate to me that "no more than 10 variables can be included in the final model". If modelers aren't aware of specific timelines or implementation constraints, a great but useless model can be the result.<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><b><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">3) Make sure the model stakeholder understands what the models can and can't do</span></b><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;"><o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">In the effort to get models deployed, I've seen models elevated to a status they don't deserve, most often by exaggerating their accuracy and expected performance once in operation. I understand why modelers may do this: they have a direct stake in what they did. But the manager must be more skeptical and conservative.<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">One of the most successful colleagues I've ever worked with used to assess model performance on held-out data using the metric we had been given (maximum depth one could mail to and still achieve the pre-determined response rate). But then he always backed off what was reported to his managers by about 10% to give some wiggle room. Why? Because even in our best efforts, there is still a danger that the data environment after the model is deployed will differ from that used in building the models, thus reducing the effectiveness of the models.<o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">A second problem for the model stakeholder is communicating an interpretation of the models to decision-makers. I've had to do this exercise several times in the past few months and it is always eye-opening when I try to explain the patterns a model is finding when the model is itself complex. We can describe overall trends ("on average", more of X increases the model score) and we can also describe specific patterns (when observable fields X and Y are both high, the model score is high). Both are needed to communicate what the models do, but have to connect with what a decision-maker understands about the problem. If it doesn't make sense, the model won't be used. If it is too obvious, the model isn't worth being used. <o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">The ideal model for me is one where the decision-maker nods knowingly at the "on average" effects (these should usually be obvious). Then, once you throw in some specific patterns, he or she should scrunch his/her eyes, think a bit, then smile as the implications of the pattern dawns on them as that pattern really does make sense (but was previously not considered). <o:p></o:p></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;">As predictive modelers, we know that absolutes are hard to come by, so even if these three principles are adhered to, other factors can sabotage the deployment of a model. Nevertheless, in general, these steps will increase the likelihood that models are deployed. In all three steps, communication is the key to ensuring the model built addresses the right business objective, the right scoring metric, and can be deployed operationally.</span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: 16.0pt; mso-layout-grid-align: none; mso-pagination: none; text-autospace: none;"><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10.0pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Georgia; mso-fareast-language: JA;"><br /></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10pt; line-height: 16pt;">NOTE: this post was originally posted for the Predictive Analytics Times at&nbsp;</span><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: x-small;"><span style="line-height: 21.328125px;">http://www.predictiveanalyticsworld.com/patimes/january13/</span></span><span style="color: #262626; font-family: Georgia; font-size: 10pt; line-height: 16pt;">&nbsp;</span></div><!--EndFragment-->
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="98c501e77853dce7dc3626cb74f1b722" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2013/01/top-posts-in-2012.html"><![CDATA[For the second consecutive year, a quick look back at posts from the prior year.<br /><br />For posted in 2012, in order of popularity:<br /><ol><li><a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/02/target-pregnancy-and-predictive.html" target="_blank">Target, Pregnancy, and Predictive Analytics, Part I</a></li><li><a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/02/target-pregnancy-and-predictive_21.html" target="_blank">Target, Pregnancy, and Predictive Analytics, Part II</a></li><li><a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/05/predictive-analytics-world-had-target.html" target="_blank">Predictive Analytics World Had the Target Story First</a></li><li><a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/04/why-defining-target-variable-in.html" target="_blank">Why Defining the Target Variable in Predictive Analytics is Critical</a></li><li><a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/04/dilbert-database-marketing-and-spam.html" target="_blank">Dilbert, Database Marketing, and Spam</a></li></ol>I’m also adding #6 because Will post in December did very well, but of course has had only one month to accumulate views.<br /><ol start="6"><li><a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2012/12/6-reasons-you-hired-wrong-data-miner.html" target="_blank">6 Reasons You Hired the Wrong Data Miner</a></li></ol>From posts prior to 2012, in order of popularity for 2012:<br /><ol><li><a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2011/06/what-do-data-miners-need-to-learn.html" target="_blank">What Do Data Miners Need to Learn</a> (June 2011)</li><li><a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2006/11/free-and-inexpensive-data-mining.html" target="_blank">Free and Inexpensive Data Mining Software</a> (November 2006) This post needs to be updated!</li><li><a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2009/04/why-normalization-matters-with-k-means.html" target="_blank">Why Normalization Matters for K Means</a> (April 2009) It always amazes me why this post persists as one of the most popular, but nearly ¼ of the visits used the search term “K Means Noisy Data”</li><li><a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2008/04/data-mining-data-sets.html" target="_blank">Data Mining Data Sets</a> (April 2008) This post also needs to be updated</li><li><a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2009/12/business-analytics-vs-business.html" target="_blank">Business Analytics vs. Business Intelligence</a> (December 2009)</li></ol>One final note: When I look back at visits since the start of this blog, 4 of the top 5 posts are the top 4 “prior to 2012” above. The #5 most popular post over all the years I’ve had the blog is one by Will from 2007, “<a href="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2007/03/missing-values-and-special-values.html" target="_blank">Missing Values and Special Values: The Plague of Data Analyis</a>”, one that I have always liked very much.<br /><br />Best to all of you in 2013! 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b18ff5a710adb658a02b8d805d62e74e" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2013/02/using-geographic-data.html"><![CDATA[Most organizations collect and maintain some type of geographic data, yet many ignore this data during analysis. Any business has some record of customer addresses, for instance, but this data is usually formatted in an awkward, non-numeric form. Geographic data can be very predictive, though, since behaviors being predicted often have some correlation to location.<br /><br />So, how might one use geographic data? Possible answers depend on several factors, most importantly the volume and type of such data. A company serving a national market in the United States, for instance, will have customer shipping and billing addresses (not necessarily the same thing) for each customer (possibly for each transaction). These addresses normally come with a range of spatial granularities: street address, town, state, and associated ZIP Code (a 5-digit postal code).<br /><br />Even at the largest level of aggregation, the state level, there may be over 50 distinct values (besides the 50 states, American addresses may be in Washington D.C. [technically not part of any state], or any of a number of other American territories, the most common of which is probably Puerto Rico). With 50 or so distinct values, significant data volume is needed to amass the observations needed to draw conclusions about each value. Given the best case scenario, in which all states exhibit equal observation counts, 1,000 observations breaks out into 50 categories of merely 20 observations each- not even enough to satisfy the old statistician's 30 observation rule of thumb. In data mining circles, we are accustomed to having much larger observation counts, but consider that the distribution of state values is never uniform in real data.<br /><br />Using individual dummy variables to represent each state <i>may</i> be possible with especially large volumes.&nbsp; Possibly an "other" category covering the least frequent so many states will be needed. Another technique which I have found to work well is to replace the categorical state variable with a numeric variable representing a summary of the target variable, conditioned by state. In other words, all instances of "Virginia" are replaced by the average of the target variable for all Virginia cases, all instances of "New Jersey" are replaced by the average of the target variable for all New Jersey cases, and so on. This solution concentrates information about the target which comes from the state in a single variable, but makes interactions with other predictors more opaque. Ideally, such summaries are calculated on special hold-out set of data, used just for this purpose, so as to avoid over-fitting. Again, it may be necessary to lump the smallest so many states together as "other". While I have used American states in my example, it should not be hard for the reader to extend this idea to Canadian provinces, French départements, etc.<br /><br />Most American states are large enough to provide robust summaries, but as a group they may not provide enough differentiation in the target variable. Changing the spatial scale implies a trade-off: Smaller geographic units exhibit worse summary variance, but improved geographic differentiation. American town names are not necessarily unique within a given state and similar names may be confused (Newtown, Pennsylvania is quite a distance from Newtown Square, Pennsylvania, for instance). In the United States, county names are unambiguous, and present finer spatial detail than states. County names do not, however, normally appear in addresses, but they are easily attached using ZIP Code/County tables easily found on-line. Another possible aggregation is the Section Code Facility, or "SCF", which is the first 3 digits of the ZIP Code.<br /><br />In the American market, other types of spatial definitions which can be used include: Census&nbsp;Bureau definitions, telephone area codes and Metropolitan Statistical Areas ("MSAs") and related groupings defined by the U.S. Office of Management and Budget.  The Census Bureau is a government agency which divides the entire country in to spatial units which vary in scale, down to very small areas (much smaller than ZIP Codes). MSAs are very popular with marketers. There are 366 MSAs at present, and they do not cover the entire land area of the United States, though they do cover about 85% of its population.<br /><br />It is important to note that nearly all geographic entities change in size, shape and character over time. While existing American state and county boundaries almost never change any more, ZIP code boundaries and Census Bureau definitions, for instance, do change. Changing boundaries obviously complicates analysis, even though historic boundary definitions are often available. Even among entities whose boundaries do not change, radical changes in behavior may happen in geographically distinct ways. Consider that a model built before hurricane Katrina may no longer perform well in areas affected by the storm.<br /><br />Also note that some geographic units, by definition, "respect" other definitions. American counties, for instance, only contain land from a single state. Others don't: the third-most populous MSA, Chicago-Joliet-Naperville, IL-IN-WI, for example, overlaps three different states.<br /><br />Being creative when defining model inputs can be as helpful with geographic data as it is with more conventional data. In addition to the billing address itself, consider transformations such as: Has the billing address ever changed (1) or not (0)? How many times has the billing address changed? How often has the billing address changed (number of times changed divided by number of months the account has been open)? How far is the shipping address from the billing address? And so on...<br /><br />Much more sophisticated use may be made of geographic data than has been described in this short posting. Software is available commerically which will determine drive time contours about locations, which would be useful, for instance when modeling retail store location revenue models. Additionally, there is an entire of statistics, called <i>spatial statistics</i>, which defines an entire class of analysis procedures specific to this sort of thing.<br /><br />I encourage readers who have avoided geographic data to consider even simple mechanisms to include it in model construction. Opening up a new dimension in your analysis may provide significant returns.<br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b6d4d1e268a49071e6d2666370683652" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2013/02/what-to-take-home-from-your-next.html"><![CDATA[Why should one go to a predictive analytics conference? What should one take home from a conference like <a href="http://www.predictiveanalyticsworld.com" target="_blank">Predictive Analytics World</a> (PAW)? There are many reasons conferences are valuable including interacting with thought leaders and practitioners, seeing software and hardware tools (the exhibit hall), and learning principles of predictive analytics from talks and workshops. This post focuses on the talks, and in particular, case studies. <br><br> There is no quicker way to upgrade our capabilities than having someone else who has "been there" tell us how they succeeded in their development and implementation of predictive models. When I go to conferences, this is at the top of my list. In the best case studies I am able to see different way of looking at a problem than I had considered before, how the practitioner overcame obstacles, how their target variable was defined, what data was used in building the models, how the data was prepared, what figure of merit they used to judge a model's effectiveness, and much more. <br><br> Almost all case studies we see at conferences are success stories; we all love winners. Yes, we all know that we learn from mistakes and many case studies actually enumerate mistakes. But success sells and given time limitations in a 20-50 minute talk, few mistakes and dead-ends are usually described in the talks. And, as we used to say in when I was doing government contracting, one works like crazy on the research and then when the money runs out, one declares victory. Putting a more positive spin on the process, we do as well as we can with the resources we have, and if the final solution improves the current system, we are indeed successful. <br><br> But once we observe the successful approach, what can we really take home with us? There are three reasons we should be skeptical taking case studies and applying them directly to our own problems.<br><br> The first two reasons are straightforward. First, our data is different from the data used in the talk. Obviously. But it is likely to be different enough that one cannot not take the exact same approach to data preparation or target variable creation that one sees at a conference.<br><br> Second, our business is different. The way the question was framed and the way predictions can be used are likely to differ in our organization. If we are building models to predict Medicare fraud, they way the “suspicious” claim is processed and which data elements are available vary significantly for each provider (codes being just one example).<br><br> The third reason is more subtle and more difficult to overcome. In a fascinating New Yorker article entitled, <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2010/12/13/101213fa_fact_lehrer" target="_blank">"The Truth Wears Off: Is there something wrong with the scientific method?"</a>, author Jonah Lehrer describes an effect seen by many researchers over the past few decades. Findings in major studies, published in reputable journals, and showing statistically significant results have been difficult to replicate by the original researcher and by others. This is a huge problem because replicating results is what we do as predictive modeler: we assume that behavior in the past can and will be replicated in the future.<br><br> In one example, researcher Jonathan Schooler (who was originally at the University of Washington as a graduate student) “demonstrated that subjects shown a face and asked to describe it were much less likely to recognize the face when shown it later than those who had simply looked at it. Schooler called the phenomenon ‘verbal overshadowing’. The study turned him into an academic star."<br><br> A few years later, he tried to replicate the study didn’t succeed. In fact, he tried many times over the years and never succeeded. The effect he found at first waned each time he tried to replicate the study with additional data.  "This was profoundly frustrating. It was as if nature gave me this great result and then tried to take it back.”  There have been a variety of potential explanations for the effect, including “regression to the mean”. This might very well be the case because even when we show statistically significant results defined by having a p value less than 0.05, there is still a chance that the effect found was not really there at all. Over thousands of studies, dozens find effects therefore that aren't really there. <br><br> Let's assume we are building models and there is actually no significant difference between responders and non-responders (but we don't know that). However, we work very hard to identify an effect, and eventually we find the effect on training and testing data. We publish. But the effect isn't there; we happened upon the effect just had good luck (which in the long run is actually bad luck!). Even if the chance of finding the effect by chance is 1 in 100, or 1 in 1000, if we experiment enough and search through enough variables, we may happen upon a seemingly good effect eventually. This process, called "over searching" by Jensen and Cohen (see "<a href="http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/summary?doi=10.1.1.32.7008" target="_blank">Multiple Comparisons in Induction Algorithms</a>"), is a real danger.<br><br> So what do we do at conferences? We should take home ideas, principles, and approaches rather than recipes. It should spur us to try ideas we either hadn't yet tried or even thought about before. <br><br> (An earlier version of this post was first published in the <a href="http://www.predictiveanalyticsworld.com/patimes/february13/" target="_blank">Predictive Analytics Times February 2013</a> issue)
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c9a4a2cb14786c2704674b4c444ee152" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2013/02/when-analysis-isnt-answer.html"><![CDATA[Data mining is an important tool whose benefits have been demonstrated in diverse fields, among business, government and non-profit organizations. Its application areas continue to grow, especially given the ever-shrinking cost of gathering and organizing data. Yet, there are problems for which data mining is wholly unsuited as a solution.<br /><br />To understand when data mining is not applicable, it will be helpful to define precisely when it <b>is</b> applicable. Data mining (inferential statistics, predictive analytics, etc.) requires data stored in a machine format of sufficient volume, quality and relevance so as to permit the construction of predictive models which assist in real-world decision making.<br /><br />Most of our time as data miners is spent worrying over the quality of the data and the process of turning data into models, however it is important to realize the usual context of data mining. Most organizations can perform basic decision making competently, and they have done so for thousands of years. Whether the base decision process is human judgment, a simple set of rules or a spreadsheet, much performance potential is already realized before data mining is applied. Consultants' marketing notwithstanding, data mining typically inhabits the margin of performance, where it tries to bring an extra "edge".<br /><br />So, if the above two paragraphs describe conditions conducive to data mining success, what sorts of real-world situations defy data mining? The most obvious would be problems featuring data that is too small, too narrow, too noisy or of too little relevance to allow effective modeling. Organizations which have not maintained good records, which still rely on non-computer procedures and those with too little history are good examples. Even within very large organizations which collect and store enormous databases, there may be no relevant data for the problem at hand (for instance, when a new line of business is being opened, or new products introduced). It is surprising how often business people expect to extract value from a situation when they have failed to invest in appropriate data gathering.<br /><br />Another large area with minimal data mining potential is organizations whose basic business process is so fundamentally broken that the usual decision making procedures have failed to do the usual "heavy lifting". Any of us can easily recall experiences in retail establishments whose operation was so flawed that it was obvious that the profit potential was not nearly being exploited. Data mining cannot fine tune a process which is so far gone. No amount of quantitative analysis will fix unkept shelves, weak product offering or poor employee behavior.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="b3a6c74152d88ac4bce0577524ac0365" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2013/04/do-predictive-modelers-need-to-know-math.html"><![CDATA[(Note: this post was first published in the <a href="http://www.predictiveanalyticsworld.com/patimes/march13/" target="_blank">March 2013 Edition of the Predictive Analytics Times</a>)<br> Predictive analytics is just a bunch of math, isn’t it? After all, algorithms in the form of matrix algebra, summations, integrals, multiplies and adds are the core of what predictive modeling algorithms do. Even rule-based approaches need math to compute how good the if-then-else rules are. <br><br>I was participating in a predictive analytics course recently and the question a participant asked at the end of two days of instruction was this: “it’s been a long time since I’ve had to do this kind of math and I’m a bit rusty. Is there a book that would help me learn the techniques without the math?” <br><br>The question about math was interesting. But do we need to know the math to build models well? Anyone can build a bad model, but to build a good model, don’t we need to know what the algorithms are doing? The answer, of course, depends on the role of the analyst. I contend, however, that for most predictive analytics projects, the answer is “no”.   <br><br>Let’s consider building decision tree models. What options does one need to set to build good trees? Here is a short list of common knobs that can be set by most predictive analytics software packages: 1. Splitting metric (CART style trees, C5 style trees, CHAID style trees, etc.) 2. Terminal node minimum size 3. Parent node minimum size 4. Maximum tree depth 5. Pruning options (standard error, Chi-square test p-value threshold, etc.) <br><br>The most mathematical of these knobs is the splitting metric. CART-styled trees use the Gini Index, C5 trees use Entropy (information gain), and CHAID style trees use the chi-square test as the splitting criterion. A book I consider the best technical book on data mining and statistical learning methods, “The Elements of Statistical Learning”, has this description of the splitting criteria for decision trees, including the Gini Index and Entropy: <br><br><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Fd3pF9d51mI/UVWxcnn7mLI/AAAAAAAAAPw/nSOjGqwEwWo/s1600/gini+entropy+and+misclassification+formulas.png" imageanchor="1"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Fd3pF9d51mI/UVWxcnn7mLI/AAAAAAAAAPw/nSOjGqwEwWo/s320/gini+entropy+and+misclassification+formulas.png" /></a> <br><br>To a mathematician, these make sense. But without a mathematics background, these equations will be at best opaque and at worst incomprehensible. (And these are not very complicated. Technical textbooks and papers describing machine learning algorithms can be quite difficult even for more seasoned, but out-of-practice mathematicians to understand).  <br><br>As someone with a mathematics background and a predictive modeler, I must say that the actual splitting equations almost never matter to me. Gini and Entropy often produce the same splits or at least similar splits. CHAID differs more, especially in how it creates multi-way splits. But even here, the biggest difference for me is not the math, but just that they use different tests for determining "good" splits <br><br>There are, however, very important reasons for someone on the team to understand the mathematics or at least the way these algorithms work qualitatively. First and foremost, understanding the algorithms helps us uncover why models go wrong. Models can be biased toward splitting on particular variables or even particular records. In some cases, it may appear that the models are performing well but in actuality they are brittle. Understanding the math can help remind us that this may happen and why. <br><br>The fact that linear regression uses a quadratic cost function tells us that outliers affect overall error disproportionately. Understanding how decision trees measure differences between the parent population and sub-populations informs us why a high-cardinality variable may be showing up at the top of our tree, and why additional penalties may be in order to reduce this bias. Seeing the computation of information gain (derived from Entropy) tells us that binary classification with a small target value proportion (such as having 5% 1s) often won't generate any splits at all. <br><br>The answer to the question if predictive modelers need to know math is this: no they don’t need to understand the mathematical notation, but neither should they ignore the mathematics. Instead, we all need to understand the effects of the mathematics on the algorithms we use. “Those who ignore statistics are condemned to reinvent it,” warns Bradley Efron of Stanford University. The same applies to mathematics.  <br><br>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c0920b05f20d572fdf650e954c69c1e" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2013/04/math-and-predictive-analytics-personal.html"><![CDATA[Last week I taught a workshop at Predictive Analytics World entitled <a href="http://www.predictiveanalyticsworld.com/sanfrancisco/2013/ensembles_handson.php" target="_blank">Supercharging Prediction: Hands-On with Ensemble Models</a>. The workshop was intended to introduce predictive modelers to the concept of ensembles through a combination of lecture to provide an overview of model ensembles and hands-on to gain experience building ensembles using <a href="http://www.salford-systems.com/">Salford Systems SPM v7.0</a> (Salford Systems sponsored the workshop).   <br /><br />This morning, Heather Hinman, a Marketing Communications Manager at Salford Systems, <a href="http://1.salford-systems.com/blog/bid/285726/Supercharging-Predictive-Modeling-A-Beginners-Perspective" target="_blank">posted comments on attending that workshop at the Salford Systems blog</a>. Two comments were particularly interesting, especially their implications vis a vis my last blog post on math and predictive analytics:<br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-family: Arial, ?Helvetica, ?sans-serif; font-size: 13px; line-height: 18px;">I will admit I was intimidated at first to be participating in a predictive modeling workshop as I do not have a background in statistics, and only have basic training on decision tree tools by Salford Systems' team of in-house experts. Despite my basic knowledge of decision trees, I was thrilled that I was able to follow along with ease and understanding when learning about tree ensembles and modern hybrid modeling approaches. Marketing folk building predictive models? Yes, we can!</span></blockquote>and<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">Now back at the office in San Diego, along with my usual responsibilities, I feel confident in my ability to build predictive models and gain insights into the data at hand to achieve the email marketing and online campaign goals for our communication efforts!&nbsp;&nbsp;</blockquote>In the post, Heather also outlines some of the principles she learned and how she used them to build the predictive models in the workshop.<br /><br />The point is this: if one uses good software that uses solid principles for building predictive models, and one understands key principles of building predictive models, someone without a mathematics background can build good, profitable models.<br /><br /><br /><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="706948d492783f52ed7d74ffe551d0ea" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2013/06/big-data-is-not-enough.html"><![CDATA[Big data is the big buzz word in the world of analytics today. According to google trends, shown in the figure, searches for "big data" have been growing exponentially since 2010 though perhaps is beginning to level off. Or take a look on amazon.com for books with Big Data in the title sometime: the publication dates, for the most part, are in 2012 or 2013. <br /><script src="//www.google.com/trends/embed.js?hl=en-US&amp;q=big+data&amp;cmpt=q&amp;content=1&amp;cid=TIMESERIES_GRAPH_0&amp;export=5&amp;w=400&amp;h=330" type="text/javascript"></script>    <br /><br />But what's the key to unlock the big data door? In his interview with Eric Siegel on April 12, Ned Smith of Business News Daily (http://www.businessnewsdaily.com/4326-predictive-analytics-unlocks-big-data.html) starts with this apt insight: "Predictive Analytics is the 'Open Sesame' for the world of Big Data." Big data is what we have; predictive analytics (PA) is what we do with it.  <br /><br />Why is the data so big? Where does it come from? We who do PA usually think of doing predictive modeling on structured data pulled from a database, probably flattened into a single modeling table by a query so that the data is loadable into a software tool. We then clean the data, create features, and away we go with predictive modeling. <br /><br />But according to a 2012 IBM study, <a href="http://www.ibmbigdatahub.com/infographic/where-does-big-data-come">"Analytics: The real-world use of big data"</a>, 88% of big data comes from transactions, 73% from log data, and significant proportions of data come from audio and video (still and motion). These are not structured data. Log files are often unstructured data containing nothing more than notes, sometimes freehand, sometimes machine-created, and therefore cannot be used without first preprocessing the data using text mining techniques. For all of us who have built models augmented with log files or other text data, we know how much work is involved in transforming text into useful attributes that can then be used in predictive models <br /><br />Even the most structured of the big data sources, transactional data, often are nothing more than dates, IDs and very simple information about the nature of the transaction (an amount, time period, and perhaps a label about the nature of the transaction).  <br /><br />Transactional data is rarely used directly; it is usually transformed into a form more useful for predictive modeling. For example, rather than building models where each row is a web page transaction, we transform the data so that each row is a person (the ID) and the fields are aggregations of that person’s history for as long as their cookie has persisted; the individual transactions have to be linked together and aggregated to be useful. <br /><br />The big data wave we are experiencing is therefore not helpful directly for improving predictive models, we need to first determine the level of analysis needed to build useful models, i.e., what a record in the model represents. The unit of analysis is determined by the question the model is intended to answer, or put another way, the decision the model is intended to improve within the organization. This is determined by defining the business objectives of the models, normally by a program manager or other domain expert in the organization, and not by the modeler.  <br /><br />The second step in building data for predictive modeling is creating the features to include as predictors for the models. How do we determine the features? I see three ways: <br /><ol><li>the analyst can define the features based on his / her experience in the field, or do research to find what others have done in the field through google searching and academic articles. This assumes the analyst is, to some degree, a domain expert.</li><li>the key features can be determined by other domain experts either handed down to the analyst or through interviews of domain experts by the analyst. This is better than a google search because the answers are focused on the organization’s perspective on solving the problem.</li><li>the analyst can rely on algorithm-based features creation. In this approach, the analyst merely provides the raw input fields and allows the algorithms to find the appropriate transformations of individual fields (easy) or multivariate combinations (more complex). Some algorithms and implementations of algorithms in software can do this quite effectively. This third approach I see advocated implicitly by data scientists in particular.</li></ol>In reality, a combination of all three is usually used and I recommend all three. But features based on domain expertise almost always provides the largest gains in model performance compared with algorithm-based (automatic) feature creation.  <br /><br />This is the new thee-legged stool of predictive modeling: big data provides the information, augmenting what we have used in the past, domain experts provide the structure for how to set up the data for modeling, including what a record means and the key attributes that reflect information expected to be helpful to solve the problem, and predictive analytics provides the muscle to open the doors to what is hidden in the data. Those who take advantage of all three will be the winners in operationalizing analytics. <br /><br />First posted at <a href="http://www.predictiveanalyticsworld.com/patimes/">The Predictive Analytics Times</a>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="937a0eaf265ac355b079616ca310d9e5" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2013/06/dean-abbott-featured-in-popular.html"><![CDATA[Our own Dean Abbott has been consulted for an on-line <i>Popular Mechanics</i> article, <a href="http://www.popularmechanics.com/technology/military/news/why-the-nsa-wants-all-that-verizon-metadata-15562288" target="_blank">"Why the NSA Wants All That Verizon Metadata"</a> (Jun-06-2013), by Glenn Derene. Since the initial report connecting the NSA with Verizon, details have emerged suggesting similar large-scale information-gathering by the American government from other telecommunication and Internet companies.<br /><br />Some applications of data mining to law enforcement and anti-terrorism problems have clearly been fruitful (for detection of money laundering, for instance, which is one source of funding for criminal and terrorist organizations). On the other hand, direct application of these techniques to plucking out the bad guys from large numbers of innocents strikes this author as dubious, and has long been criticized by experts, such as Bruce Schneier. What's plain is that people in democratic societies must remain vigilant of the balance of information and power granted to their governments, lest the medicine become worse than the disease.<br /><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ebd5287e1eb1fe6f242a8da892501a15" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2013/07/the-nsa-link-analysis-and-fraud.html"><![CDATA[<div style="border: 0px; color: #444444; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', HelveticaNeue-Light, Arial, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22px !important; margin-bottom: 20px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">The recent leaks about the NSA’s use data mining and predictive analytics has certainly raised awareness of our field and has resulted in hours of discussions with family, relatives, friends and reporters about what predictive analytics can (and can’t) do with phone records, emails, chat messages, and other structured and unstructured data. Eric Siegel and I have been interviewed on multiple occasions to address this issue from a Predictive Analytics perspective, and in case, in the same article: “<a href="http://fcw.com/articles/2013/06/12/nsa-risk-assessment.aspx" target="_blank">What the NSA can’t do with your data (probably)</a>”.&nbsp;Part of my goal in these conversations has been to bring back to reality many of the inflated expectations of what can be done with predictive analytics: predictive analytics is a powerful approach to finding patterns in data, but it isn’t magic, nor is it fool-proof.</div><div style="border: 0px; color: #444444; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', HelveticaNeue-Light, Arial, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22px !important; margin-bottom: 20px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">First, let me be clear: I have no direct knowledge of the analytics the NSA is doing. I have worked on many fraud detection projects for the U.S. Government and private sector, some including what I would describe as a “social networking” component to them where the connections between parties is an important part of the risk factors.</div><div style="border: 0px; color: #444444; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', HelveticaNeue-Light, Arial, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22px !important; margin-bottom: 20px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">The phone call meta data shows simple information about each phone call: origination, destination, date of the call, duration, and perhaps some geographic information about the origination and destination. One of the valuable aspects of the data is that connections can be made between origination and destination numbers, and as a results, one can build social networks of every origination phone number in the data. The U.S. has more than 326.4 millions cell phones subscriptions as of December 2012 according to CTIA. The Pew Research survey found that individual cell phone users had on average 664 social connections (not all of which are cell connections). The number of links needed to build a U.S.-wide social map of phone call connections easily outstrips any possible visualization method, and therefore, without filtering connections and networks, these social maps would be useless. One of the factors working in our favor, if we are concerned with privacy issues related to this meta data, is therefore the sheer size of the network.</div><div style="border: 0px; color: #444444; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', HelveticaNeue-Light, Arial, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22px !important; margin-bottom: 20px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">The networks of phone calls, I believe, are particularly useful in connecting high-risk individuals with others whom the NSA may not know beforehand are connected to the person of interest. In other words, a starting point is needed first and the social network is built from this starting point. If one has multiple starting points, one can also find linkages between networks even if the networks themselves don’t overlap significantly.</div><div style="border: 0px; color: #444444; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', HelveticaNeue-Light, Arial, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22px !important; margin-bottom: 20px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">The strength of a link can include information such as number of calls, duration of calls, regularity of calls, most recent call, oldest call, and more. Think of these as a cell-phone version of RFM analysis. The networks can be pruned easily based on thresholds for these key features, simplifying the networks considerably.</div><div style="border: 0px; color: #444444; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', HelveticaNeue-Light, Arial, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22px !important; margin-bottom: 20px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">But even if the connections are made, this data is woefully incomplete on its own. First, there is no connection to the person who actually made the call, only the phone number and who it is registered to. Finding who made the calls requires more investigation. Second, it doesn’t necessarily connect all the phones an individual might use. If a person uses 5 or 6 cell phones, one doesn’t know that the same person is behind these phone numbers. Third, one certainly doesn’t know the intent or content of the call.</div><div style="border: 0px; color: #444444; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', HelveticaNeue-Light, Arial, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22px !important; margin-bottom: 20px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Given these limitations, what value is there to the network of calls? These networks are usually best used as lead-generation engines. Which other phone numbers in a network are connected to multiple high-risk individuals (but weren’t here-to-fore considered high risk)? Is the timeline of calls temporally correlated with other known events?</div><div style="border: 0px; color: #444444; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', HelveticaNeue-Light, Arial, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22px !important; margin-bottom: 20px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Analytics, and link analysis in particular, provide tremendously powerful techniques to identify new leads and remove unfruitful leads by finding connections unlikely to occur randomly.</div><div style="border: 0px; color: #444444; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', HelveticaNeue-Light, Arial, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22px !important; margin-bottom: 20px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">NOTE: this article first appeared as an article in the PATimes: http://www.predictiveanalyticsworld.com/patimes/the-nsa-link-analysis-and-fraud-detection/</div>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4a9c8d52bbc935bf1f7be546f0aecdbc" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2013/08/beware-phantom-data.html"><![CDATA[One of the perennial challenges facing the data analyst is missing values. A great deal has been written about the importance of identifying the source of missing values, the danger of overly simplistic solutions and, of course, the many and varied mechanisms for "filling them in" with synthetic data ("imputation").<br /><br />Of the tremendous volume of material written on this subject, nearly all assumes that the analyst knows precisely which items are missing from the data. In reality, this is sometimes not the case. Relational databases and statistical software files, as a rule, have a special value to indicate "missing", though that does not mean that it is always used. Some file formats offer only indirect provision for missings, if any at all, and how software reacts to such missings varies.<br /><br />Consider, too, the popular practice of using special values (such as -9999) to represent missing values. What could possibly go wrong? For one thing, the person writing the data may not consider whether the flag value might represent a legitimate value. Is it possible, for instance, to have an account balance of -9999 dollars (euros, etc.)? In my career, I have seen databases which used different flag values for each field (-99, -9999, -99999, etc.), making the writing of code against such data extremely tedious (and error-prone). I have also seen -9999 used to indicate one type of missing value, and -9998 to indicate another type of missing. When the hand-off of information from one person (system, process, etc.) to another is confused or incomplete, interpretation of the data becomes incorrect.<br /><br />Another aspect of this problem is the precise definition given to fields, and their possible misinterpretation by data consumers (such as data miners). Imagine that a particular integer field is being used to record the number of times each customer has made a payment on their loan, within the past 6 months. As customers begin their tenure, this variable starts with a value of zero. Suppose our model included this field as an independent variable. Presumably low risk customers have higher values, while higher risk customers have lower values. Without missing any payments, early lifecycle customer are penalized arbitrarily by the model. One could make the argument that this variable should be undefined (recorded as a database missing value flag) until a customer has a full 6-month track record, but this is exactly the sort of conversation which very often fails to materialize in real organizations.<br /><br />These are all instances of "phantom data": Items in the database which are missing values, but mistaken for real data. It shouldn't take much imagination on the reader's part to conjure similar problematic situations in his or her own field. The lesson is to look beyond the known missings for more subtle gaps in the data. Time spent investigating the nature of database systems, company procedures and so forth which generate data is insurance against being burned by serious misunderstanding of the data.<br /><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c17244ec7b36287d16019c489159422f" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2013/09/on-data-mining-contests.html"><![CDATA[Data mining contests have grown in popularity over the years, from the annual competitions at technical conferences to the continuous stream of events at sites like Kaggle. This has yielded several benefits, allowing many experts to work on difficult problems, giving novices a chance to work on real data and showcasing successful solutions. These competitions have even garnered the attention of the mainstream press. While believing that the spread of these technical contests has been largely positive, this author feels that it's worth noting the limitations of these contests.<br /><br />Despite using real data, the problems, as formulated, are somewhat artificial. Questions of sampling and initial variable selection have already been decided, as have the evaluation function and the model's part in the ultimate solution. To some extent, these are necessary constraints, but they are constraints nonetheless. In real world data mining, all of these questions are the responsibility of the data miner and his or her clients, and they are not trivial considerations. In most larger organizations, the data is large enough that there is always "one more" table in the database which could be tapped for candidate predictors. Likewise, how the model might best be positioned as part of the total solution is not always obvious, especially in more complex problems. A minority of contests permit the use of outside data, but even this is somewhat unrealistic since real organizations have budgets for the purchase of outside data, such as demographic data to be appended to a customer population. I've yet to learn of anyone paying for outside variables to append to competition data, though.<br /><br />Another issue is the large number of competitors which these contests attract. Though it is good to have many analysts take a crack at a problem, one must wonder about the statistical significance of having hundreds of statisticians test God-only-knows how many hypotheses against the same data. Further, the number of competitors and the similarity of top contestants' performance figures make selection of a single "winner" a dubious proposition.<br /><br />Finally, it has become rather common for winners of the contests to construct solutions of vast proportions- typically ensembles of gigantic number of base models. While such models may be feasible to deploy in some circumstances, they far too computationally demanding to execute on many real databases quickly enough to be practical.<br /><br />Some of these criticisms are probably unavoidable, especially the ones regarding the pre-selected, pre-digested contest data. Still, it'd be interesting to see future data mining competitions address at least some of these issues. For one thing, it might be interesting to see solution sizes (lines of SQL or C++ or something similar) limited to something which ordinary IT departments would be capable of executing during a typical overnight run. Averaging across an increased number of tasks might begin to improve the significance of differences among contestants' performances.<br /><br />
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="efa3f6548ae93a1116c606d4db098a12" url="http://abbottanalytics.blogspot.com/2013/11/a-good-business-objective-beats-good.html"><![CDATA[<div style="border: 0px; color: #444444; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', HelveticaNeue-Light, Arial, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22px !important; margin-bottom: 20px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Predictive Modeling competitions, once the arena for a few data mining conferences, has now become big business. Kaggle (<a href="http://www.kaggle.com/" style="border: 0px; color: #3b44a1; font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-weight: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;" target="_blank">kaggle.com</a>) is perhaps the most well-known forum for modeling competitions, using a crowd-sourcing mentality: if more people try to solve a problem, the likelihood that someone will create an excellent solution to that problem increases.</div><div style="border: 0px; color: #444444; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', HelveticaNeue-Light, Arial, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22px !important; margin-bottom: 20px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">The participants, and there have been 10s of thousands of participants since their 2011 beginning, sometimes have no predictive modeling background and sometimes an extensive data science background. Some very clever algorithms and solutions have been developed with, on some occasions, ground-breaking results</div><div style="border: 0px; color: #444444; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', HelveticaNeue-Light, Arial, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22px !important; margin-bottom: 20px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">One conclusion to draw from these competitions is that what we need in the predictive analytics space is more data scientists with different, innovative ideas for solving problems, and perhaps more in-depth training of data scientists so they can create these innovative solutions. After all, the Netflix prize winner created a solution that was an ensemble of model ensembles, comprised of hundreds of models (not a Kaggle competition, but one created by and for&nbsp;<a href="http://techblog.netflix.com/2012/04/netflix-recommendations-beyond-5-stars.html" style="border: 0px; color: #3b44a1; font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-weight: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;" target="_blank">Netflix</a>).</div><div style="border: 0px; color: #444444; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', HelveticaNeue-Light, Arial, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22px !important; margin-bottom: 20px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">This idea of the importance of machine learning expertise was the topic of a Strata conference debate in 2012, tackling the question, “which is more important, domain expertise or machine learning expertise”, or the way it was phrased for the debate, “who should your first hire be: a domain expert or data scientist?”</div><div style="border: 0px; color: #444444; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', HelveticaNeue-Light, Arial, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22px !important; margin-bottom: 20px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">The conclusion of the majority at the Strata conference was the machine learning is more important, but even the moderator, Mark Driscoll, concluded the following,<br style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;" />“Could you currently prepare your data for a Kaggle competition?&nbsp; If so, then hire a machine learner.&nbsp; If not, hire a data scientist who has the domain expertise and the data hacking skills to get you there.” (<a href="http://medriscoll.com/post/18784448854/the-data-science-debate-domain-expertise-or-machine" style="border: 0px; color: #3b44a1; font-family: inherit; font-size: inherit; font-style: inherit; font-variant: inherit; font-weight: inherit; line-height: inherit; margin: 0px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;" target="_blank">http://medriscoll.com/post/18784448854/the-data-science-debate-domain-expertise-or-machine</a>)</div><div style="border: 0px; color: #444444; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', HelveticaNeue-Light, Arial, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22px !important; margin-bottom: 20px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">The point is that defining the competition objectives and the data needed to solve the problem is critically important. Non-domain experts, the data scientists, can not ever hope to understand the domain well enough to determine what the most effective question to answer would be, where to find the data to build a modeling data set, what the target variable should be, and how one should assess which model is best. These are business domain specific.</div><div style="border: 0px; color: #444444; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', HelveticaNeue-Light, Arial, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22px !important; margin-bottom: 20px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">Even companies building the same kinds of models, let’s say customer retention or churn, will approach them differently depending on the kind of business, the lead time needed to act on potential churners, and the metrics for churn that relate to ROI for that company. I’ve build models for companies in the same domain area that took very different approaches; even though I had some domain experience from customer 1, that didn’t translate into developing business objectives well for company 2.</div><div style="border: 0px; color: #444444; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', HelveticaNeue-Light, Arial, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22px !important; margin-bottom: 20px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">It’s the partnership that matters. I often think of these partnerships within an organization as the three-legged stool, all of which are needed for the modeling project to succeed: a business stakeholder who understands what business objectives matter to the company and how to articulate them, IT staff who know where the data is, what it means, and how to access it, and the analysts who know how to take the data and the business objectives and translate them into modeling objectives that address the business problem. Without all three, projects fail. We modelers could build the best models in the world that solve the wrong problem exceedingly well!</div><div style="border: 0px; color: #444444; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', HelveticaNeue-Light, Arial, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 16px; line-height: 22px !important; margin-bottom: 20px; outline: 0px; padding: 0px; vertical-align: baseline;">(first posted at http://www.predictiveanalyticsworld.com/patimes/a-good-business-objective-beats-a-good-algorithm/)</div>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>