<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="www.lisasellsstroudsburg.com">
	<documents count="5">
		<document id="c811703f49cad0e84e1a7aeea229fd19" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/PoconosRealEstateBlog/~3/9amarx7IS8s/stroud-landlords-register-your-tenants.html"><![CDATA[All landlords with residential rental properties in Stroud Township are required to register tenants with the Township every year by May 31. You must also report any tenant changes or vacancies within 30 days. There is no fee for this....
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="163ba2ae50c60d108418050cfad5e524" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/PoconosRealEstateBlog/~3/a2JAk4l7MOc/summer-2013-in-the-pokies-carnivals-fairs-fireworks-music-trivia.html"><![CDATA[Not on the list: Every Thursday evening, starting around 7pm, join me as I host World Tavern Trivia on the Patio/Tiki Bar outdoors at Petrizzo's Italian Restaurant in Bushkill. It's always a great time!

Petrizzo's also offers live music every weekend, and Johnny P. also puts on a fantastic fireworks extravaganza on the 4th of July!
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c5f130ff1b334ccee48d3c42b1f502a8" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/PoconosRealEstateBlog/~3/DPUakPkxVOg/looking-for-a-house-with-a-view-consider-saw-creek-estates.html"><![CDATA[Whether you are looking for wide open vistas or prefer a wooded creekside setting, you may be able to find your perfect home or weekend getaway in Saw Creek.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="44e96d06f54546cc767538bf8501e998" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/PoconosRealEstateBlog/~3/ohhWAzwF8Rc/sales-data-home-availability-in-saw-creek-estates.html"><![CDATA[Saw Creek Estates is made up of single family homes but it should be noted that there are two separate townhome Associations inside of Saw Creek, Mill Pond and The Falls, that share some of the amenities of SCE but have their own rules and fees. There really is something for everyone here in this gated, amenity-rich community in the Eastern Poconos. 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4146acc273fefbbb4d9340a1845efa7f" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/PoconosRealEstateBlog/~3/tVZKCQqdP7I/concerned-about-your-school-property-tax-bill-vote-in-the-pa-primary.html"><![CDATA[Members of your school board determine where your property tax dollars are spent, the quality of the education provided to children, AND how much your school district collects from you in taxes!
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>