<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="lizolivier.com/blog">
	<documents count="6">
		<document id="9a20e93e49528beaa79cadb4e3af8e03" url="http://lizolivier.com/blog/advertising/dirk-bikkembergs-ad-campaign-behind-the-scenes/"><![CDATA[Here is a small video of what went on behind the scenes of the Dirk Bikkembergs Ad Campaign. The Ad campaign was shot in one of the most beautiful locations in Africa, The Karoo Desset.  The vast salt pans were amazing, but it was winter (zero degrees at night) and we were camping for 10 [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="53a1eaef4fff7113bc24d3a65b45ef5" url="http://lizolivier.com/blog/advertising/fight-aging-the-right-way/"><![CDATA[Anti-aging creams are part of a multi-billion dollar market, so why is it so hard to choose the right product? You can never be too sure – should you wear anti-wrinkle creams, eye creams, firming creams or all of the above? Knowing what suits your skin at your age will lead you to that fountain [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c50eafd1ae21c787b30bcd1f8c6c05cc" url="http://lizolivier.com/blog/beauty/jennifer-lawrence/"><![CDATA[Jennifer Lawrence had one of the most talked about  makeup and hair looks on the Golden Globes red carpet. Now you can achieve the makeup in 4 easy steps. Step 1 Foundation &#38; Highlight After applying foundation and concealer, set it with powder. Apply a highlighter on top of your cheekbones and along the top [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3837b970e1efa4aa94b77b637f74892" url="http://lizolivier.com/blog/beauty/julianne-hough/"><![CDATA[Recreating Julianne Hough straight off the Golden Globe Red Carpet. Julianne Hough looked amazing with her bronze smoky eyes and nude lip. It was a perfect match with her Monique Lhuillier gown on the red carpet. You can achieve the same in just 4 easy steps. &#160; Step 1 Prep &#38; Prime Moisturize &#38; prime [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2b5e38b4ec526c1b38135d7e94c2492d" url="http://lizolivier.com/blog/beauty/salma-hayek-oscar-2013-transformation-celeb-to-reality-by-jennifer-macdougall-and-liz-olivier/"><![CDATA[L&#8217;oreal Professional and American Salon magazine joined us at our Oscar twitter party this year.  Together with Jennifer MacDougall we recreated hair and makeup looks live during the Oscars  show. Jolene Turner  from American Salon Magazine volunteered herself to Jennifer MacDougall and I for  the red carpet transformation. BEFORE &#160; AFTER &#160; Here is how [...]
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a75a5be1f892db1e418a6fd22fdf804c" url="http://lizolivier.com/blog/beauty/the-basics-to-a-flawless-complextion/"><![CDATA[The Basics to a Flawless Complexion A Flawless Glam Look in 5 Easy Steps From Frieda Pinto (Left) to Isabel Lucas (Right), one of the most sought after qualities of Tinsel Town’s leading ladies is their flawless skin. Whether gracing the red carpet or appearing on the big screen, their complexion always seems to be [...]
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>