<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="65-XX" url="anneisaman.blogspot.com">
	<documents count="24">
		<document id="484ba24c13d083a6a7e27a86e34aab4" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/8lsuuA-PXhU/india-and-mahabharata.html"><![CDATA[<div>Professor Vinay Lal (UCLA) can be heard again on podcast with his <a href="http://www.oid.ucla.edu/webcasts/courses/2011-2012/2012winter/hist9a-1">History of India</a> (UCLA - History 9A) (<a href="http://podcast.oid.ucla.edu/courses/2011-2012/2012winter/hist9a-1/podcast.xml">feed</a>), about which I have written before in 2009 when it was also podcast. As then, also this time, there is a considerable difference in the characteristics of the material delivered between the first lectures and that those towards the end of the course. Whereas the history is more recognizably history, that is political history, economic history, as we approach the present, the very early history of the Indian subcontinent is presented by Lal with very little political and economic data. Much of the first 10 lectures are spent on discussing culture, religion (as much as the term can be applied, which is doubtful according to Lal) a bit of archeology and the literary traces of old India the Vedas, the Upanishads, the Ramayana and the Mahabharata.<br /><br /><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_N56aAeTnoT8/SeBYubSGkmI/AAAAAAAAB4U/U5ujYmAFEMw/s1600-h/ucla.gif" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_N56aAeTnoT8/SeBYubSGkmI/AAAAAAAAB4U/U5ujYmAFEMw/s320/ucla.gif" /></a>Two years ago, the series of lectures that discussed hardly any data, but delved into those texts were very hard for me to follow and I am happy to report it is different this time around. The kudos in this respect go entirely to another podcast: <a href="http://mahabharatapodcast.blogspot.com/">The Mahabharata Podcast</a> (<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/MahabharataPodcast">feed</a>). Lawrence Manzo's retelling of the Mahabharata, which has progressed to the 90th episode (Bhisma's <a href="http://mahabharatapodcast.blogspot.com/2012/02/episode-90-final-teachings-part-2.html">Final Teachings part 2</a>), has made the story as well as the cultural scope of the epic much more familiar to me. As a consequence, whenever Lal is referring to the Mahabharata's characters and anecdotes, they are familiar, easy to place and his point is coming through.<br /><br /><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_N56aAeTnoT8/TEUm2xpaMkI/AAAAAAAACrY/pQuPfvmvbhQ/s1600/mahabharata+podcast.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_N56aAeTnoT8/TEUm2xpaMkI/AAAAAAAACrY/pQuPfvmvbhQ/s1600/mahabharata+podcast.jpg" /></a>I want to recommend Manzo's podcast to anyone, regardless whether you are thinking of latching on to History 9A. The Mahabharata is a most fascinating, entertaining and at times mind boggling tale to engage with. Should you seek some shorter preparation, you can also turn to Rick ALbright's series on World Literature (<a href="http://deimos3.apple.com/WebObjects/Core.woa/Feed/hacc.edu.3112468726.03112468728">feed</a>) which has a two part issue addressing the Ramayana.<br /><br />Next on Lal's schedule is the Kama Sutra, which, incidentally was also discussed on the last program of BBC's <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b01bb9c9">In Our Time</a>. (<a href="http://downloads.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/radio4/iot/rss.xml">feed</a>)<br /><br />More History of India:<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/01/history-of-india-search-goes-on.html">History of India - the search goes on</a><br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2009/12/8-podcasts-i-listened-to.html">8 podcasts I listened to</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2009/12/history-of-india-or-europe.html">History of India or Europe?</a><br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2009/10/history-of-india-ucla-lecture-podcast.html">History of India</a>.<br /><br />More Mahabharata:<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/05/temptation-of-karna-twist-in-dharma.html">The Temptation of Karna</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/12/flood-tales-noah-gilgamesh-and-manu.html">Flood tales; Noah, Gilgamesh and Manu</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/11/indian-roots-of-unicorn.html">Indian roots of the Unicorn</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/08/endless-cloth-mahabharata-podcast.html">Endless cloth</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/07/mahabharata-podcast.html">The Mahabharata Podcast</a>.<br /><br />More Rick Albright's English 205:<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/03/world-literature-hacc.html">World Literature</a>.<br /><br />More In Our Time:<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2012/01/in-our-time-archive.html">In Our Time Archive</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/03/reminder-of-great-bbc-podcasts.html">A reminder of the great BBC podcasts</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/11/diarmaid-macculloch-in-podcast.html">Diarmaid MacCulloch in podcast</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/02/indian-rebellion-1857-bbc-berkeley-ucla.html">The Indian Rebellion of 1857</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/01/frankfurt-school-iot.html">Frankfurt School</a>.</div><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=8lsuuA-PXhU:PNXxfmYyEOQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=8lsuuA-PXhU:PNXxfmYyEOQ:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=8lsuuA-PXhU:PNXxfmYyEOQ:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/8lsuuA-PXhU" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e1259eb9d8d452bc7639ebc143358036" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/8WgGNMZn708/neither-orderly-nor-humane-nbih.html"><![CDATA[Population transfers are of all ages and although they are considered a crime against humanity these days, or at least bordering on it, there is a rich history of transfers and they were mostly regarded as legitimate at the time. I was aware of big transfers between Turkey and Greece in the 1920s and between India and Pakistan in 1947. I knew of the transfers in Europe after the Second World War, but had no idea that the transfer of Germans that took place was the largest in history. This is what we are told in a recent issue of <a href="http://newbooksinhistory.com/">New Books in History</a>, when Marshal Poe interviewed Ray Douglas about his 10 year research project into this transfer, resulting in the book <a href="http://newbooksinhistory.com/2013/02/14/r-m-douglas-orderly-and-humane-the-expulsion-of-the-germans-after-the-second-world-war-yale-up-2012/">Orderly and Humane: The Expulsion of the Germans after the Second World War</a> (Yale University Press, 2012). (<a href=" http://newbooksinhistory.com/?feed=rss2">feed</a>)<br /><br /><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-huDmVMw6wNI/TiVB64A_FOI/AAAAAAAACz4/0FJf79agpzE/s1600/NBNHistLogo1.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-huDmVMw6wNI/TiVB64A_FOI/AAAAAAAACz4/0FJf79agpzE/s1600/NBNHistLogo1.jpg" /></a>Vae Victis, woe to the vanquished, could have been another title for the book. Nazi Germany lost the war, and after all its own demographic scheming to benefit the ethnic Germans, the ethnic Germans got to taste the reverse. What Ray Douglas adds to what we'd already know about this history is the sheer size of the transfer: up to 14 million Germans were transferred from Poland, Czechoslovakia and other places in Eastern Europe. The transfer was premeditated and sanctioned way in advance by the Allies. The swiftness of the transfer necessarily implied that the transfer was carried out neither orderly nor humanely as was originally the goal. And the Germans underwent it without resistance.<br /><br />The operation added such a huge number of Germans to the other displaced multitude that was roaming about Europe at the time, that relief aid became a political hot potato - aiding the displaced persons, would imply aiding, mainly, the Germans, the vanquished. It would be a follow-up question whether this finding of Douglas's implied that for example this is another reason why the displaced Jews, were not helped at all?<br /><br />I also assumed that these displaced Germans were integrated pretty well, but as Poe brings this issue up, Douglas suggest otherwise, however without much detail. More than the measure to which integration was successful, I was more surprised again by the numbers: Douglas claimed that about 20% of Germans today are transferred Germans or their offspring.<br /><br />Many more surprising issues arise during this riveting interview.<br /><br />More New Books in History:<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.co.il/2011/05/big-history-big-lands-and-big-men.html">Big History, Big Lands and Big Men</a><br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/03/hans-kundnani-about-germanys-left-after.html">Hans Kundnani about Germany's left after the war</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/03/ottoman-age-of-exploration.html">Ottoman Age of Exploration</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/01/new-books-in-history-is-my-weekly-stop.html">The mysteries of whites and of mass</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/11/soviet-memoir-new-books-in-history.html">A Soviet Memoir</a>.<br /><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=8WgGNMZn708:u9xEu8AcAxw:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=8WgGNMZn708:u9xEu8AcAxw:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=8WgGNMZn708:u9xEu8AcAxw:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/8WgGNMZn708" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f14e5819e403cf7c7b94d3dbf73b0a5d" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/8zlCwcuBZoM/while-i-have-virtually-stopped-blogging.html"><![CDATA[While I have virtually stopped blogging about podcasts, I am still listening. There are a couple of podcasts I keep following and here is a list.<br /><br /><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-zXGQdmENaNA/TjAoJ-u5SvI/AAAAAAAAC0M/FEr4PnSxt_M/s1600/tns.qonhmzuh.170x170-75.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-zXGQdmENaNA/TjAoJ-u5SvI/AAAAAAAAC0M/FEr4PnSxt_M/s1600/tns.qonhmzuh.170x170-75.jpg" /></a><a href="http://oyc.yale.edu/history/hist-210" target="_blank">The Early Middle Ages</a> - Yale course. (<a href="http://deimos3.apple.com/WebObjects/Core.woa/Feed/yale.edu-dz.14523394129.014523394131" target="_blank">iTunesU</a>)<br />I have done this course <a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.co.il/2012/05/early-middle-ages-yale.html" target="_blank">before</a>, but I was caught by it again. The reason I pick up certain history podcasts is because I want to wrap my mind around something. The point that was brought to my attention first by <a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/01/european-unity-europe-from-its-origins.html" target="_blank">Europe from its origins</a> is that the Roman Empire did not 'fall' in 476. Even if that was clear to anyone who was aware that it proceeded as the Byzantine Empire, which finally fell in 1453, an additional point is how Western Europe kept on developing at the hand of the Church, not being the Roman Empire, but also, in many ways as a continuation of it in its own way. The overall question being, how much western society can be coherently taken as one culture and as such be regarded as Roman.<br /><br />A new podcast I have taken up is <a href="http://worldwariipodcast.net/wordpress/" target="_blank">The History of World War II</a> by Ray Harris. This is an amateur podcast which takes on the vast and unwieldy task of telling the entire history of WW2, which professionals do not begin to tackle. The result is very interesting shedding light on some less familiar parts such as Mussolini's rise in Italy. It pays ample attention to the nuts and bolts of the military campaigns in the war, which have to be to your liking of course. (<a href="http://worldwariipodcast.net/wordpress/feed/" target="_blank">feed</a>)<br /><br />Other podcasts I stick with are <a href="http://chinahistorypodcast.com/" target="_blank">The China History podcast</a> - which just finished a series about the history of Hong Kong (<a href="http://chinahistorypodcast.com/feed/podcast/" target="_blank">feed</a>) - and David Crowther's <a href="http://historyofengland.typepad.com/" target="_blank">History of England</a> (<a href="http://historyofengland.typepad.com/blog/rss.xml" target="_blank">feed</a>). Needless to say, I also persist in listening to each week's issue of BBC's <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b006qykl" target="_blank">In Our Time</a> (<a href="http://downloads.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/radio4/iot/rss.xml" target="_blank">feed</a>).<br /><br />Apart from having a writer's block (I feel I am repeating myself on the blog and cannot bring myself to continue repeating), I also find that with the latest upgrade of iTunes, a crucial feature has been removed: the advanced subscribing to podcasts. That seems like a minor change, but I find it has great meaning and implication and first of all renders irrelevant almost all of the feed links I have been posting over the past years - 2000+ posts hurt, ouch!<br /><br />I would like to revive this blog. I love to write about audio on the web, but I have to find a new way of doing it. Feel free to drop suggestions. In the mean time, I'll be silent, but there will be another guest post by <a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.co.il/search/label/Saeed" target="_blank">Saeed</a> coming up and maybe I'll give in to a rant about iTunes.<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/8zlCwcuBZoM" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2bdb5a98af27b64ce92d70ac4b8a5900" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/aeAc8Bc28us/moral-and-political-thought-of-gandhi.html"><![CDATA[Unfortunately, the audio is incomplete, but Vinay Lal's course at UCLA -<a href="http://www.oid.ucla.edu/webcasts/courses/2011-2012/2012spring/hist175c-1">History 175c</a>- still gives a compelling series of lectures digging into the biography of Gandhi, his thought and his critics. (<a href="http://podcast.oid.ucla.edu/courses/2011-2012/2012spring/hist175c-1/podcast.xml">feed</a>)<br /><br /><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_N56aAeTnoT8/SeBYubSGkmI/AAAAAAAAB4U/U5ujYmAFEMw/s1600-h/ucla.gif" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_N56aAeTnoT8/SeBYubSGkmI/AAAAAAAAB4U/U5ujYmAFEMw/s320/ucla.gif" /></a>Even if the life of Gandhi and his thought are well-known, there are many surprises when you start digging into it. As a concept, nonviolence is not so difficult to understand, but a theory how this might work in a political theory and in a spiritual philosophy is far from self-explanatory. Vinay Lal's lectures are a good way to get acquainted. Although Lal certainly reveres Gandhi there is ample distance to let you feel you are getting a fair introduction.<br /><br />In comparison, the old Berkeley courses on nonviolence are much more engaged. These two, <a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2008/05/non-violence-readers.html">PACS 164A&B</a> are among those podcast lectures that are no longer available through Berkeley, not even among the classical courses on iTunesU. The <a href="http://www.mettacenter.org/nonviolence-courses">Metta Center for nonviolence</a> however still points at them, including video recordings of those lectures. Should you want to take on these, start with Lal's course.<br /><br /><iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/H4F8kJchX4I" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe><br /><br />Lal's course is a great complement to other podcasts about Gandhi. When Joseph Lelyveld published his controversial biography of Gandhi, <a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/04/more-gandhi-lelyveld-at-kqed.html">I reviewed a couple of podcasts</a> that paid attention to this book.<br /><br />Also among other Indian History courses Lal teaches at UCLA this one stands out. It clearly is the subject that is most closely to Lal's areas of interest. The other courses are <a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/01/history-of-india-search-goes-on.html">History of India</a> and the <a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/05/gandhi-history-174c-ucla.html">History of British India</a>.<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=aeAc8Bc28us:GsudGFeTUN4:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=aeAc8Bc28us:GsudGFeTUN4:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=aeAc8Bc28us:GsudGFeTUN4:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/aeAc8Bc28us" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d134f2a80337d2385e6bdff5c1621e1" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/AflEJxpSCqA/only-slightly-different-perspective.html"><![CDATA[We have gone through this history in quite a number of podcasts: Sarajevo 1914, Pearl Harbor 1941 and even the fall of Mossadegh 1953, haven't we? How is it that I was glued to my iPod with these narratives all over again? I was listening to <a href="http://historyofoil.typepad.com/">A History of Oil</a> an amateur podcast by Peter Doran. (<a href="http://historyofoil.libsyn.com/rss">feed</a>)<br /><br />Any new history podcast should reveal a fact about history that was not that clear until now. A History of Oil does that even where you hardly expect to be surprised. Take for instance Operation Barbarossa, the Nazi Invasion of the Soviet Union in 1941. We already knew the Germans over-stretched themselves. We knew they had fuel shortages. We knew they had to capture the oil fields on the Caspian Sea around Baku and failed to do so. We knew that no matter how long they could hold out in Soviet territory, this was a turning point in the Second World War, but still A History of Oil's perspective gives something new. <br /><br /><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-HBs0llBsYE8/Ul0eR3Ilj-I/AAAAAAAAGTM/96o4UXEHM-c/s1600/ahistoryofoil.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-HBs0llBsYE8/Ul0eR3Ilj-I/AAAAAAAAGTM/96o4UXEHM-c/s320/ahistoryofoil.jpg" width="320" /></a>A History of Oil effectively starts in the middle of the nineteenth century when crude oil began to enter the markets as a commodity and before long we approach the First World War. The British are the first to let their navy switch from coal to oil, but others are soon to follow, so that we are more than normally aware how oil has become a vital strategic resource by the time the Second World War comes around. Then, in 1941, as the Nazis invade the Soviet Union and have one success after another, oil became a problem. The Germans had used many times more fuel than planned. In fact operation Barbarossa rapidly depleted the oil reserves and no source was at hand that could meet the increased demand. So, if we thought that the defeat at Stalingrad was the turning point, A History of Oil, makes it clear that the defeat was inherent. Not a radically new point, but still a new support for the thesis that Barbarossa was a decisive Nazi mistake from the get go.<br /><br />This is only one example of what the slightly altered perspective of A History of Oil brings to familiar data. Another refreshing experience is to go through the era not by means of national histories, but by means of the history of corporations; Standard Oil, Royal Dutch, Shell, British Petroleum and so on. It makes John D. Rockefeller more prominent than Theodore Roosevelt. It makes the Japanese invasion of Borneo more prominent than their attack on Pearl Harbor. It places Mexico, Venezuela and Indonesia in the center of attention what rarely happens and so on. <br /><br />In short, A History of Oil is a remarkable enrichment to the library of history podcasts and highly recommended listening.<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=AflEJxpSCqA:qSOstl1GFy0:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=AflEJxpSCqA:qSOstl1GFy0:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=AflEJxpSCqA:qSOstl1GFy0:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/AflEJxpSCqA" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e8380d91e3501cbaa756ccebf788ed02" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/cuDI77ICdTQ/de-duif-van-de-directrice.html"><![CDATA[Dit is voor mij de ultieme nostalgie <br /><br /><object height="94" width="422"><param value="http://www.divshare.com/flash/audio_embed?data=YTo2OntzOjU6ImFwaUlkIjtzOjE6IjQiO3M6NjoiZmlsZUlkIjtzOjg6IjI0NTEzNjQzIjtzOjQ6ImNvZGUiO3M6MTI6IjI0NTEzNjQzLTgwNSI7czo2OiJ1c2VySWQiO3M6NjoiMzM0NDU0IjtzOjEyOiJleHRlcm5hbENhbGwiO2k6MTtzOjQ6InRpbWUiO2k6MTM3OTMwMjMzMjt9&autoplay=default" name="movie"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><param name="wmode" value="transparent"></param><embed wmode="transparent" height="94" width="422" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" src="http://www.divshare.com/flash/audio_embed?data=YTo2OntzOjU6ImFwaUlkIjtzOjE6IjQiO3M6NjoiZmlsZUlkIjtzOjg6IjI0NTEzNjQzIjtzOjQ6ImNvZGUiO3M6MTI6IjI0NTEzNjQzLTgwNSI7czo2OiJ1c2VySWQiO3M6NjoiMzM0NDU0IjtzOjEyOiJleHRlcm5hbENhbGwiO2k6MTtzOjQ6InRpbWUiO2k6MTM3OTMwMjMzMjt9&autoplay=default"></embed></object><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=cuDI77ICdTQ:yzFDz4-8mo4:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=cuDI77ICdTQ:yzFDz4-8mo4:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=cuDI77ICdTQ:yzFDz4-8mo4:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/cuDI77ICdTQ" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="653eb6cd8342155b605b7acf87ef9a1a" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/f8zD2nmVtdw/reith-lectures-2012-bbc-podcast.html"><![CDATA[Here is a quick heads up to announce that the <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/series/reith">Reith lectures Podcast</a> has begun publishing the lecture series that was held about a month ago. Speaker is historian Niall Ferguson and the series title is <i>The Rule of Law and Its Enemies</i>. (<a href="http://downloads.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/radio4/reith/rss.xml">feed</a>)<br /><br /><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-A4R6O5PsRmg/T-BQTy7KKJI/AAAAAAAADnA/JMOvUehyofw/s1600/reith_2012.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-A4R6O5PsRmg/T-BQTy7KKJI/AAAAAAAADnA/JMOvUehyofw/s1600/reith_2012.jpg" /></a>This title is rather reminiscent of Karl Popper's <i>The Open Society and Its Enemies</i> (1945) in which he pointed at Fascism and Communism as the ideologies that held the greatest threat to society. Underlying these ideologies were theories that, in Popper's view, had the kind of tendency towards totalitarianism that brought these ideologies about and what similar dangerous ideologies could emerge.<br /><br />In 2012 such discourse is not taken to ideologies, as is to be expected. Ferguson takes a look at the institutions and their role in society. But the question is still the same: what helps and what threatens the kind of nation we would like to live in?<br /><br />Reith Lectures 2011:<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.co.il/2011/06/reith-lectures-2011.html">Reith Lectures 2011</a>.<br /><br />Reith Lectures 2010:<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/06/reith-lectures-2010-2.html">Reith Lectures 2010 (2)</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/05/reith-lectures-2010.html">Reith Lectures 2010</a>.<br /><br />Reith Lectures in 2009:<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2009/07/new-politics-of-common-good-reith.html">A new politics of the common good</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2009/06/bioethics-concern-third-reith-lecture.html">The bioethics concern</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2009/06/morality-in-politics-bbc-reith-lectures.html">Morality in Politics</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2009/06/reith-lectures-2009-michael-sandel-on.html">Morality and the Market</a>.<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=f8zD2nmVtdw:W3GqYt75XHE:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=f8zD2nmVtdw:W3GqYt75XHE:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=f8zD2nmVtdw:W3GqYt75XHE:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/f8zD2nmVtdw" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="16ac601375c18151666bcde42a378990" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/f93csehfOhU/in-our-time-archive.html"><![CDATA[How long has this been going on? I do not know since when, but this morning I suddenly noticed that the BBC has opened up the entire In Our Time archive for podcast.<br /><br />I used to write that one should always download the In Our Time podcasts and keep for ever. The BBC used to keep only the last episode in the feed. In case one had not kept the episode, the only option to listen was to go to the on-line archive and listen while streaming. While that has become less and less of a bother with WiFi all around and capable smartphones, it still was a pity you had no option. All of this now belongs to the past; the archive is also available for download and one can lay ones hands on any chapter ever.<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-TT1g-U8igTY/Tw7YYvwEfYI/AAAAAAAAC1k/WeXVicBAlPE/s1600/In+Our+Time+Archive_+History.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-TT1g-U8igTY/Tw7YYvwEfYI/AAAAAAAAC1k/WeXVicBAlPE/s1600/In+Our+Time+Archive_+History.jpg" /></a></div>The archive has been broken down in five subject feeds:<br /><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/series/iotc" target="_blank">In Our Time Archive - Culture</a>, (<a href="http://downloads.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/radio4/iotc/rss.xml">IOT Culture feed</a>)<br /><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/series/ioth" target="_blank">In Our Time Archive - History</a>, (<a href="http://downloads.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/radio4/ioth/rss.xml">IOT History feed</a>)<br /><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/series/iotp" target="_blank">In Our Time Archive - Philosophy</a>, (<a href="http://downloads.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/radio4/iotp/rss.xml">IOT Philosophy feed</a>)<br /><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/series/iotr" target="_blank">In Our Time Archive - Religion</a>, (<a href="http://downloads.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/radio4/iotr/rss.xml">IOT Religion feed</a>)<br /><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/series/iots" target="_blank">In Our Time Archive - Science</a>, (<a href="http://downloads.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/radio4/iots/rss.xml">IOT Science feed</a>)<br /><br />I immediately tried the history archive in order to find an issue from 2006, that I remembered as especially informative and the copy of which I had long lost: <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p0038x8z" target="_blank">The Diet of Worms</a> - which has nothing to do with food, in case you wondered. The Diet was an imperial assembly held in the German city of Worms and this program was about the one in 1522, during which Martin Luther had to defend his theology in public. If you ever needed 40 minutes to get a handle on Luther, the man and his ideas, this is the place to go.<br /><br />Not only the Diet of Worms can be found in the feed, I saw the archive goes back as far as 1998 with promising titles such as <i>Money</i>, <i>Byzantium</i>, the <i>Celts</i>, the <i>Aztecs</i>, the <i>East India Company</i>, the <i>Mughal Empire</i> and on and on. A veritable treasure trove. <br /><br /><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=f93csehfOhU:jQmNSR2U-zo:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=f93csehfOhU:jQmNSR2U-zo:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=f93csehfOhU:jQmNSR2U-zo:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/f93csehfOhU" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="611a34dcc63f6a2612b4d0850e0edb4e" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/gjC8wDiJLqY/early-middle-ages-yale.html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://oyc.yale.edu/">Open Yale</a> is a great source for academic podcasts. Thanks to a tip from my reader <a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2008/09/professor-charles-lipson-university-of.html">Charles Lipson</a>, I learned about a set of new courses that have become available at Yale, among others Paul Freedman's series about <a href="http://oyc.yale.edu/history/hist-210">the Early Middle Ages</a> (284-1000 CE) - (<a href="http://deimos3.apple.com/WebObjects/Core.woa/Feed/yale.edu-dz.14523394129.014523394131">feed</a>). After having heard the first four lectures (out of 22), I warmly recommend this series.<br /><br /><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-zXGQdmENaNA/TjAoJ-u5SvI/AAAAAAAAC0M/FEr4PnSxt_M/s1600/tns.qonhmzuh.170x170-75.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-zXGQdmENaNA/TjAoJ-u5SvI/AAAAAAAAC0M/FEr4PnSxt_M/s1600/tns.qonhmzuh.170x170-75.jpg" /></a>In the world of history podcasts there are a couple of other options to get information about the early Middle Ages; UCSD has an <a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2009/05/mmw-3-by-matthew-herbst-ucsd-history.html">MMW</a> part dedicated to this era and there is also a series about the <a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/01/byzantine-empire-ucsd-lecture-podcast.html">Byzantine Empire</a> that should be had when you are interested in these centuries and there is the multimedia experience of <a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/01/european-unity-europe-from-its-origins.html">Europe From Its Origins</a>. All of these tend to start with the Roman emperors Diocletian and Constantine to mark the beginning of the Early Middle Ages and then move on to cover the fall of Rome in the West and the consecutive developments in Western Europe.<br /><br />Yale's Paul Freedman does the same, but with his lectures I was made to realize for the first time, how radical the change is, especially under Constantine and how this truly is the beginning of the Middle Ages, that era in the history of Western Europe that is dominated by Christianity and the Church power. It has been said before, but as Freedman emphasizes how odd it is that an insignificant minority sect such as the Christians, that is known for its pacifism, within a hundred years becomes the dominant creed and political power in this mighty and militaristic empire, I have come to understand more profoundly how remarkable the development is. Really the start of a new age. Neither religion nor the state were the same as before.<br /><br />More <a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/search/label/Yale">Yale</a>:<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/07/moral-foundations-of-politics-yale.html">The Moral Foundations of Politics</a><br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/06/ehec-and-history-of-emerging-diseases.html">History of epidemics</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/05/early-modern-england-yale.html">Early Modern England</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/03/great-war-ww1-in-podcasts.html">European Civilization 1648-1945</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/01/france-since-1871-yale-lecture-podcast.html">France since 1871</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2009/12/pasts-and-futures-of-christianity-lse.html">New Testament, history and literature</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2009/01/hebrew-bible-open-yale-course-review.html">The Hebrew Bible</a>.<br /><br />More <a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/search/label/medieval%20history">Medieval History</a>:<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/01/european-unity-europe-from-its-origins.html">Europe From Its Origins</a><br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/08/summertime-tip-across-podcast-listening.html">Norman Centuries</a><br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2008/02/byzantine-sources.html">12 Byzantine Rulers</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2009/04/medieval-heroes-in-short-hum-4104.html">Byzantine Empire</a> (UCSD),<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2008/04/world-history-guided-by-religions.html">Medieval Heritage</a> (UCSD - Chamberlain),<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2008/04/world-history-outside-european-box.html">Medieval Heritage</a> (UCSD - Herbst).<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=gjC8wDiJLqY:R_D8ml4Kwjg:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=gjC8wDiJLqY:R_D8ml4Kwjg:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=gjC8wDiJLqY:R_D8ml4Kwjg:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/gjC8wDiJLqY" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="d336b243f7b10e9a5ec6778d851de30d" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/gw_ue_w6y8g/how-to-delete-itunes-u-files-from-ipod.html"><![CDATA[The most read post on this blog is the one (actually there are several) about <a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.co.il/2010/08/problem-with-ipod-remove-itunesu-files.html">how to remove iTunesU files from your iPod</a>. Until the recent upgrade to iTunes 11 that was a major problem. The great news is that with iTunes 11, this problem is finally taken care of.<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-B5tu1KAg14k/US9Eff8oycI/AAAAAAAADog/lpME_aOQU34/s1600/itunes11itunesuipod.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" height="150" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-B5tu1KAg14k/US9Eff8oycI/AAAAAAAADog/lpME_aOQU34/s320/itunes11itunesuipod.png" width="320" /></a></div>Until now, iTunesU files would simply not show on the iPod, within iTunes and consequently they could not be deleted. Now, iTunesU has received its own -long in coming- folder as shown to the right. In there the files can be found and, provided you manually manage your iPod, can be at will deleted. In case you do not manually manage the pod, naturally the synchronization with iTunes will take care of that - as was one of the previously suggested solutions.<br /><br /><b>One more thing (or two)...</b><br /><br />Of the five previously suggested solutions the two last methods were full-proof and both entailed a certain way of dealing with the iPod and with the subscription. I would like to point out that these approaches are still valid within iTunes 11.<br /><br /><i>1- Synchronize your iPod to iTunes. </i><br />I used to prefer to manually manage the pod, but in order to evade the iTunesU problem I have gotten used to letting iTunes synch my pod. It is still a valid way of dealing with the pod. You have to carefully select as what to synchronize. Generally I would not sync ALL music and not even ALL podcasts and iTunesU, but rather a selection, or a couple of specific playlists I manage centrally on iTunes.<br /><br /><i>2- Subscribe to iTunesU feeds as podcast</i><br />Copy the URL from the iTunesU section and then use the subscribe to podcast by URL method to subscribe. In my humble opinion, iTunesU series are not different from podcasts, so why not have them in that category and organize all of them together? This used to make sense, regardless of the deletion problem and therefore continues to be so. Do you have a problem finding the 'subscribe to podcast by URL' method in iTunes 11? So did I - I'll write about it in my next post.<br /><br /><b>As a last remark...</b><br /><br />I have had an iPod nano since 2006 and have been using iTunes to manage the audio on my pod since. Once upon a time, iTunesU feeds were simply podcast feeds and the management was no different from podcast files. Somewhere around the release of iTunes 8 or 9, iTunesU got its strange state, since when the files are neither completely like podcast files nor completely like music files or audiobook files, for that matter. I first ran into the problem with the removal of those files from the pod early in 2010 and the endlessly requested post I wrote about it dates from August that year. So it has taken Apple two and a half years to solve this issue, which seems way too simple and way too critical to have had to take this amount of time.<br /><br />This issue is only one of the examples of my frustration with iTunes and I am sure I am not the only one who is a disgruntled iTunes user. Before I go write about what I find wrong with iTunes, I'll have to write about the podcast subscription. Stand by.<br /><br /><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=gw_ue_w6y8g:v0IAGT427Ss:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=gw_ue_w6y8g:v0IAGT427Ss:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=gw_ue_w6y8g:v0IAGT427Ss:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/gw_ue_w6y8g" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="c69bf3bd48e7401a8f3b8bf1c0ffef43" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/I9NC_MXWsBI/stephen-fry-reads-eugene-onegin-pushkin.html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-yz5O-1LtUB8/UbVogmFsoRI/AAAAAAAADrc/LvW8qOIFWoc/s1600/Eugene+Onegin+1.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-yz5O-1LtUB8/UbVogmFsoRI/AAAAAAAADrc/LvW8qOIFWoc/s320/Eugene+Onegin+1.png" width="320" /></a>Russian literature translated into rhyming English - that could go wrong a million ways. In 1832 Alexander Pushkin published the final version of his novel about the eternal bachelor Eugene Onegin. The novel is comprised of eight chapters written in stanzas of iambic tetrameter with a unique rhyming scheme. The book has been translated many times and the James Falen translation is now available as an audio book, greatly performed by <a href="http://fryreadsonegin.com/">Stephen Fry</a>. The files can be downloaded in two ways Fry <a href="http://fryreadsonegin.com/download/Onegin.zip">Reads Onegin Zip</a> and <a href="http://fryreadsonegin.com/download/Onegin.m4a">Fry Reads Onegin from iTunes</a>. Delightful and exquisite. I wish I could compare it to the original.<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=I9NC_MXWsBI:7SycO8ioTI8:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=I9NC_MXWsBI:7SycO8ioTI8:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=I9NC_MXWsBI:7SycO8ioTI8:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/I9NC_MXWsBI" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6e20f9fdf9560e2824d5975370e03afc" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/j4MC57ew2TM/subscribe-to-podcast-by-url-itunes-11.html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xcdy5Q5CqsY/US9N6frONmI/AAAAAAAADow/m3kzuTst5aE/s1600/itunes11subscribe.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xcdy5Q5CqsY/US9N6frONmI/AAAAAAAADow/m3kzuTst5aE/s320/itunes11subscribe.png" width="191" /></a>I was about to go off about a new problem that I thought had arisen with iTunes 11 - see a previous post - but I just found out that on this particular issue I am mistaken. I thought the possibility to directly subscribe to a podcast had vanished with iTunes 11, but that is not the case. The option has moved on the menu from 'Advanced' to 'File'. For my blog this feature is absolutely critical as this allows me to continue posting feed URLs as I used to.<br /><br />Copy the URL to a podcast feed anywhere you find it, for example on any post on this blog that reviews a podcast. Go to iTunes 11 and click the menu item 'File'. Under File you will find the option "Subscribe to Podcast..." - select this. A tiny window will open in which you can paste the URL you had copied to begin with. After pasting the URL, click OK and iTunes will be subscribed to the chosen podcast. Thus you will not have to look the same podcast up in the iTunes store and subscribe from there.<br /><br />&nbsp;If you have a previous version of iTunes, you find the same possibility under 'Advanced' as explained in the old post about <a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.co.il/2008/06/podcast-listening-for-beginners-4.html">subscribing to podcasts in iTunes</a>.<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-5hyxAk6tynM/US9ObbxNm9I/AAAAAAAADo4/U82VYcfgREs/s1600/itunes11subscribeFeed.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="163" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-5hyxAk6tynM/US9ObbxNm9I/AAAAAAAADo4/U82VYcfgREs/s320/itunes11subscribeFeed.png" width="320" /></a></div><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=j4MC57ew2TM:_oJE_Ch-F0w:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=j4MC57ew2TM:_oJE_Ch-F0w:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=j4MC57ew2TM:_oJE_Ch-F0w:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/j4MC57ew2TM" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e5e6114f77466c8a2d8a2d80b2774052" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/LasS1MjcYc4/agatha-christie-oxford-biographies.html"><![CDATA[Oxford University Press has a <a href="http://oxforddnb.com/">Dictionary of National Biographies</a> which probably is also available in print, but can be accessed on-line at a premium. It contains biographies of some sixty thousand people in British history, from 400 BC to today. For promotion they have a podcast every fortnight <a href="http://www.oup.com/oxforddnb/info/freeodnb/pod/">Oxford Biographies</a> that delivers spoken biographies in seven to fifteen minutes. (<a href="http://www.oxforddnb.com/public/podcast.xml">feed</a>)<br /><br /><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_N56aAeTnoT8/SjYld-NUTsI/AAAAAAAAB8g/4o8juQNboY8/s1600-h/oxford+dnb.PNG" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_N56aAeTnoT8/SjYld-NUTsI/AAAAAAAAB8g/4o8juQNboY8/s320/oxford+dnb.PNG" /></a>Each free issue is maintained for a limited amount of time in the feed. Names I have commented on in the past such as Roald Dahl and George Best, can no longer be had, but if you are quick <a href="http://www.oxforddnb.com/public/audio/Oxford_Biography_PG_Wodehouse_2012_02_15.mp3">PG Wodehouse</a> can still be had, along with <a href="http://www.oxforddnb.com/public/audio/Oxford_Biography_William_Morris_2012_03_28.mp3">William Morris</a> (of the Morris cars) and <a href="http://www.oxforddnb.com/public/audio/Oxford_Biography_Hannah_Snell_2012_04_11.mp3">Hannah Snell</a> an 18th century female soldier.<br /><br />The latest issue, <a href="http://www.oxforddnb.com/public/audio/Oxford_Biography_Agatha_Christie_2012_05_09.mp3">Agatha Christie</a>, is also one not to miss out on. In nineteen minutes you will get every thing you need to know. How she was shy as a youngster, still loathed being a celebrity as an elderly woman, still such a prolific and successful writer and made a Dame by the end of her life. What I particularly liked was the attention given to her writing methods and the technique she applied to giving the clues, yet manipulating their ambiguity such that it would confuse the reader towards the wrong conclusion until the truth was revealed and the right solution to the whodunnit would be perfectly correct.<br /><br />More Oxford Biographies:<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2009/08/george-best-oxford-biographies.html">George Best</a><br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2009/06/roald-dahl-oxford-biographies.html">Roald Dahl</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2008/10/biography-podcasts.html">Biography Podcasts</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2008/07/oxford-biographies-podcast-review.html">Oxford Biographies podcast review</a>.<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=LasS1MjcYc4:7Gezb69WsEY:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=LasS1MjcYc4:7Gezb69WsEY:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=LasS1MjcYc4:7Gezb69WsEY:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/LasS1MjcYc4" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a30a6bddec2aa73e2c7ff271ea99dd44" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/Le81JdY3jSs/our-brain-dichotomies-saeed-ahmed.html"><![CDATA[Here is another guest-post written by <b><i>Saeed Ahmed</i></b>: <br /><br />Have you ever thought about the question “Who am I?” or the question “Why do I do the things I do?”<br /><br />On the surface, perhaps these seem trivial questions, and yet they have been discussed by philosophers for thousands of years, with no firm answers, and the dialog continues.<br /><br />Modern neuroscience has reached a point that it can in some ways inform this dialog.  Three recent podcast interviews, based on books written for lay audiences, illuminate slightly different aspects of the debate, provide some answers, and raise many more questions. <br /><br />Two dichotomies are emphasized in these podcasts; conscious and unconscious mental processing, and the functions of the left and right hemispheres. <br /><br />Each author has been interviewed several times, and I have posted below links for sessions with three very experienced interviewers. <br /><br /><a href="http://www.npr.org/2012/08/24/159922899/incognito-whats-hiding-in-the-unconscious-mind" target="_blank">David Eagleman, interviewed by Terry Gross</a>, is a neuroscientist and talks about a competition for attention among the myriad of neural processes (central, peripheral, sympathetic, parasympathetic) that we all possess.   Volition and action occur on the basis of which processes “win.”  Virtually all of the competition occurs unconsciously.   In a way, Eagleman provides an organic basis for what an aspect of “unconscious: may be.   In the latter part of the book, he discusses implications of this, including those for our legal systems. <a href="http://www.npr.org/programs/fresh-air/" target="_blank">Fresh Air</a> - (<a href="http://www.npr.org/rss/podcast.php?id=13" target="_blank">feed</a>)<br /><br /><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-XL2ri3VHrBE/TZ6ao-FdA-I/AAAAAAAACxA/FE98h-7akfI/s1600/WNYC%2527s+Leonard+Lopate+Show.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-XL2ri3VHrBE/TZ6ao-FdA-I/AAAAAAAACxA/FE98h-7akfI/s1600/WNYC%2527s+Leonard+Lopate+Show.jpg" /></a><br /><a href="http://www.wnyc.org/shows/lopate/2011/nov/21/daniel-kahneman-thinking-fast-and-slow/" target="_blank">Daniel Kahneman, interviewed by Leonard Lopate</a>, is a nobel-prize winner in economics.  While this may seem a bit odd (why economics; isn’t that about supply and demand curves, utility functions and mathematical models?), it isn’t really, because aspects of behavior, particularly “non-rational” behavior, are becoming very important in economics research, as it has become more and more apparent that participants in markets often do not act as rationally as traditional models have assumed.  Kahneman describes two neural systems: one that operates quickly with virtually no sense of voluntary control and a second that allocates attention to effortful activities.  He too speculates about legal implications, e.g. the effect of judicial decisions on whether judges are hungry or have just eaten. <a href="http://www.wnyc.org/shows/lopate/" target="_blank">Leonard Lopate Show</a> - <a href="http://feeds.wnyc.org/wnyc_lopate" target="_blank">Feed</a><br /><br />Kahneman also wrote an article on the same subject matter as his book for Scientific American, which can be accessed <a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm?id=kahneman-excerpt-thinking-fast-and-slow" target="_blank">here</a>.<br /><br />My favorite interview of the three, was of Iain McGilchrist a British psychiatrist, who sat with Phillip Adams of Australia’s Radio National, who discusses the implications of the left-brain/right-brain dichotomy.  The left-right dichotomy is just as fundamental as the conscious-unconscious one (although both ultimately are reductionist).  Briefly summarized, just as one may hypothesize that the phenomena of perception/conception/volition/action are determined in some way by a competition between multiple unconscious processes, so too may one say that these phenomena occur due to states generated by the cooperative/competitive “discussion” between the two “persons” who exist inside us, and very different persons they are, apparently.  McGilchrist goes beyond mechanistic explanations, and it is his foray into the implications of this dichotomy that I found quite compelling, speculative though they might be.  The basic hypothesis he puts forth is that due to a predominance of left-dominant thinking, certain tendencies of western civilization have become damaging.  In <a href="http://www.abc.net.au/radionational/programs/latenightlive/the-divided-brain-26-the-western-world/4392698" target="_blank">his own words</a> (from his book’s introduction):<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq">“Here I suggest that it is as if the left hemisphere, which creates a sort of self-reflexive virtual world, has blocked off the available exits, the ways out of the hall of mirrors, into a reality which the right hemisphere could enable us to understand. In the past, this tendency was counterbalanced by forces from outside the enclosed system of the self-conscious mind; apart from the history incarnated in our culture, and the natural world itself, from both of which we are increasingly alienated, these were principally the embodied nature of our existence, the arts and religion. In our time each of these has been subverted and the routes of escape from the virtual world have been closed off. An increasingly mechanistic, fragmented, decontextualised world, marked by unwarranted optimism mixed with paranoia and a feeling of emptiness, has come about, reflecting, I believe, the unopposed action of a dysfunctional left hemisphere.”</blockquote>Right/Left brain speculations, in books and blog posts on the hidden power of the right brain, are becoming quite fashionable, but they sometimes overstate the implications of the evidence they put forth to support their claims.  Gilchrist advocates balance between the left and the right hemispheres.  It is always hard to judge how far one may speculate, given any line of evidence, and I don’t think Gilchrist went too far, but not everyone may see his suppositions about social and humanistic issues well-grounded in research in this area.  But few will fault his effort to reach this far.<br /><br />More about the three books can be found at <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Incognito-Secret-Lives-David-Eagleman/dp/0307389928" target="_blank">Amazon</a>, Wikipedia (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thinking,_Fast_and_Slow" target="_blank">thinking fast and slow</a>) (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Master_and_His_Emissary" target="_blank">the master and his emissary</a>).<br /><br /><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=Le81JdY3jSs:qC20x5UcJ9w:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=Le81JdY3jSs:qC20x5UcJ9w:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=Le81JdY3jSs:qC20x5UcJ9w:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/Le81JdY3jSs" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4acfcc5058e293ac8825a1fa7f757636" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/N-dA_NaCUpc/shakespeares-restless-world.html"><![CDATA[When the excellent BBC history podcast <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b00nrtd2">History of the World in 100 Objects</a> arrived at its 100th episode and discussed the 100th object, sadly, this series had to end. (<a href="http://downloads.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/radio4/ahow/rss.xml">feed</a>) Sadly, because with Neil MacGregor discussing history by analyzing an object from the British Museum or any other museum, the BBC had found a formula for radio and podcast that could be applied to much more than just a 100 pieces. A new subject had to be found for Neil MacGregor to tackle with the help of Museum collections, and fortunately a new subject has been found and a very promising new series has started.<br /><br /><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/series/r4shakespeare">Shakespeare's Restless World</a> has Neil MacGregor discuss the history of Shakespeare's time, by looking at objects from its period and, as with the previous series, calling in various specialists to add their knowledge to the podcast (<a href="http://downloads.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/radio4/r4shakespeare/rss.xml">feed</a>). Just as the previous series, these programs are carefully edited and delivered in comprehensive 14 minute episodes. An additional feature is that the series not only looks at an object, but also has quotations from Shakespeare's work to illustrate the subject at hand. Also, as an improvement on the previous series, the object is pictured in the podcast logo of the episode, so if you have a player that displays the logo while you listen, you can even take a glance at the prop that is being discussed. The podcast is published every workday. Considering that it is not called, Shakespeare in 54 objects or some such numbered title, the makers have not limited themselves from the start to a particular length.<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-bJ83pahHmhU/T5OMknpo9dI/AAAAAAAADlE/o8SkxD3aihs/s1600/Shakespeare_s+Restless+World.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" height="200" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-bJ83pahHmhU/T5OMknpo9dI/AAAAAAAADlE/o8SkxD3aihs/s200/Shakespeare_s+Restless+World.jpg" width="200" /></a></div>So far, we have had five issues published, four of which I have already heard. I especially liked '<a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/radio4/features/shakespeares-restless-world/programmes/snackingthroughshakespeare/">Snacking through Shakespeare</a>' that taught me what were the 16th centuries equivalent of a box of popcorn and a can of soda. In other words: what did people eat while they attended the theater in Shakespeare's time. I was surprised by how accurate this question could be answered and how varied the menu was. Next time you try to silently open your can in the theater and dread the fizzy noise, know that in the 16th century, you'd be in the same spot, but in stead of a can with a fizzy soft drink, you'd pop a bottle of fizzy ale.<br /><br />More:<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/03/reminder-of-great-bbc-podcasts.html">A reminder of the great BBC podcasts</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/09/ahow-is-back-again.html">AHOW is back again</a>,<br /><div style="margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;"><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/05/returned-from-hiatus-history-of-world.html">Returned from hiatus: A History of the World in 100 Objects</a>,</div><div style="margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;"><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/02/indus-seal-world-history-in-objects.html">Indus Seal</a>,</div><div style="margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;"><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/01/history-of-world-in-100-objects-bbc.html">First AHOW Review</a>.</div><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=N-dA_NaCUpc:KPCGF2FggOg:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=N-dA_NaCUpc:KPCGF2FggOg:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=N-dA_NaCUpc:KPCGF2FggOg:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/N-dA_NaCUpc" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ecdda2c9cd19e8c67ac345e882c36cda" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/OfPkvG6wS94/taking-courses-with-saeed-ahmed.html"><![CDATA[<div class="im" style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #500050; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;">Here is a guest-post written by Saeed Ahmed: </span><br /><br /><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;">Jean Jacques Rousseau “was a charlatan,” a “moral leach,” who “consciously set out to tickle the fancy of the cultural elite in France.”&nbsp; Hegel “used technical terminology but wasn’t sure what he meant”; “he thought that the way to greatness was through obfuscation.”&nbsp;&nbsp; “Nobody invented jargon with the viciousness and vengeance of Kant.”&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;">Containing such declarations, it is not surprising that Ronald Nash’s course on Modern Philosophy gets mixed reviews on itunes.&nbsp;</span><br /><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-RSQAmGTgugY/URnOLbXil9I/AAAAAAAADoM/8xndXstQqQE/s1600/nashmodernphil.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-RSQAmGTgugY/URnOLbXil9I/AAAAAAAADoM/8xndXstQqQE/s1600/nashmodernphil.jpg" /></a><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;"><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/itunes-u/modern-philosophy/id412910038" style="color: #1155cc;" target="_blank">https://itunes.apple.com/us/<wbr></wbr>itunes-u/modern-philosophy/<wbr></wbr>id412910038</a></span><br /><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;">Nash (who died in 2006) was an unapologetic Christian apologetic.&nbsp; His lectures are full of attacks on moral relativism, modernism, post-modernism, enlightenment thinking, and just about anything that does not conform to his absolute, foundational belief in the Christian God.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><br /><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;">When it comes to worldview, there is virtually nothing that I find appealing in Dr. Nash’s ideas.&nbsp; Nevertheless I found his course compelling at 3 levels.&nbsp;</span></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;">First, he has a surprisingly engaging style; he is not bashful, neutral or balanced.&nbsp; &nbsp;You know exactly where he is coming from.&nbsp; His is a full frontal assault on virtual all liberal ideas.&nbsp; This is strangely refreshing and a change from the nuanced and “balanced” presentations in many lecture courses.&nbsp; Agree with him or not, he will capture your attention.&nbsp; His view is a full, undiluted measure of unabashed fundamentalist thought. There are no hidden levers; it’s all visible. &nbsp;</span></div><div class="im" style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #500050; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;">Second, his summaries of philosophers, while reductionist, are quite pithy and at least to my non-professional view, accurate enough to be good introductions. &nbsp;&nbsp;His basic approach is often something like “this guy was an idiot, but here are the three points he made” and then he lists them very systematically. &nbsp;For Kant he summarizes: “Concepts without percepts are empty; Percepts without concepts are blind.”&nbsp; Further, “Kant integrated rationalism and empiricism…rationalism entered Kant’s system because it encompassed the apriori set of categories with which experience was worked upon “; “With the categories, our minds organize percepts in ways that produce knowledge.”&nbsp; Kant put “human mind at the center”.&nbsp; “The reason we are conscious of space and time is not just because we apprehend something out there, but because our minds contribute notions of space and time to what we see.”&nbsp; “There are 12 apriori categories (such as unity, equality, and causation) that allow the mind to organize and relate ideas.” “Laws of nature are in a way a product of the knowing mind.” “We believe x causes y because our minds force us think in this way.” &nbsp;“We are never conscious of raw percepts; the moment we become conscious, of a raw percept, it has already been acted upon by the knowing mind; it has been given a structure, organization and a set of relationships.” “We cannot have knowledge of what we cannot perceive, thus we cannot know knowledge of our self” (the unifying transcendental self).</span><br /><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;">Category (apriori) -&gt; Concept (direct object of human awareness) -&gt; unified coherent field (transcendental unity of apperception).&nbsp;</span></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;">Not bad.&nbsp; I am not a professional philosopher, and I would be very curious to know what people who really know the subject well think of Nash’s summaries.</span></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;">Third, it is kind of fun to listen to someone who is confident enough to unabashedly bash some of the greatest minds of the last few thousand years.&nbsp; &nbsp;Wrong or right (and usually wrong, I would submit), this is just plain fun to listen to at times.</span></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;">If Nash leaves a bad taste in your mouth, and a ringing in your ears, I recommend four &nbsp;antidotes: &nbsp;1) Peter Milican’s general philosophy introduction (available in audio and video from Oxford), 2) Mythology by Gail Lavender, 3) episode 328 of Shrink Rap radio featuring an interview with the extremely erudite Dutch Jungian Analyst Robert Bosnak and 4) &nbsp;and Buddhist Psychology by Eleanor Rosch.</span></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;">Unlike Nash’s survey course, Dr. Milican’s is much more balanced and accurate.</span></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;"><a href="http://www.philosophy.ox.ac.uk/podcasts/general_philosophy" style="color: #1155cc;" target="_blank">http://www.philosophy.ox.ac.<wbr></wbr>uk/podcasts/general_philosophy</a></span></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><br /></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;">In Lavender’s course, I particularly direct you to the lecture on psychological theories of mythology, in which she mentions the dictum “dreams are the myths of the individual; myths are the dreams of the race”, then goes on to explain this using concepts developed by Freud and Jung.&nbsp;</span></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;"><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/itunes-u/mythology/id497995501" style="color: #1155cc;" target="_blank">https://itunes.apple.com/us/<wbr></wbr>itunes-u/mythology/id497995501</a></span></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><br /></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;">In the Shrink Rap podcast (#328), Bosnak discusses the astonishing Red Book of Carl Jung (that was published in 2009 for the first time) and in a very short time.&nbsp;&nbsp; He mentions a plausible hypothesis about why religious fundamentalism is so prevalent these days.</span></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;"><a href="http://www.shrinkrapradio.com/2012/11/29/328-the-red-book-and-cycles-of-change-with-jungian-analyst-robert-bosnak/" style="color: #1155cc;" target="_blank">http://www.shrinkrapradio.com/<wbr></wbr>2012/11/29/328-the-red-book-<wbr></wbr>and-cycles-of-change-with-<wbr></wbr>jungian-analyst-robert-bosnak/</a></span></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><br /></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;">In the Buddhist Psychology course, Rosch demonstrates how in many ways, she is the polar opposite of Nash.&nbsp; Her style is generous, open, non-judgmental, liberal, and compassionate.&nbsp; She has a very deep knowledge of Buddhist philosophy and modern psychology, so is able to discuss the former, and place the latter in its context, and vice versa.&nbsp;&nbsp; I would recommend starting this course from the beginning, but if time is limited, then skip ahead and listen first to the third lecture, where a specific form of meditation is introduced.&nbsp; I have been doing this, and have noticed changes in me after only a few days.&nbsp;</span></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;"><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/itunes-u/psychology-107-001-fall-2010/id391538994" style="color: #1155cc;" target="_blank">https://itunes.apple.com/us/<wbr></wbr>itunes-u/psychology-107-001-<wbr></wbr>fall-2010/id391538994</a></span></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><br /></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;">These courses complement each other.&nbsp; Listening to lectures from all contemporaneously really blows one’s mind due to the sheer breadth of material that creates conflicts and tensions in one’s understanding and perspectives.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;"><br /></span></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;"><i><b>Saeed Ahmed</b></i></span></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 10pt;"><br /></span></div><div style="-webkit-text-size-adjust: auto; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: white; color: #222222; font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: normal; letter-spacing: normal; line-height: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px;"><br /></div>More Saeed Ahmed:<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.co.il/2011/08/optimizing-brain-fitness-saeed-ahmed.html" target="_blank">Optimizing Brain Fitness</a>, <br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/07/wittgenstein-saeed-ahmed-guest-post.html">Wittgenstein</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/07/political-and-current-affairs-podcasts.html">Political and current affairs podcasts</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/07/international-political-economy-saeed.html">International Political Economy</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/05/podcast-on-climate-energy-and-food.html">A podcast on climate, energy and food</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/03/two-podcasts-on-brain-saeed-ahmed-guest.html">Two podcasts on the brain</a>.<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=OfPkvG6wS94:JVj0y6Baijs:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=OfPkvG6wS94:JVj0y6Baijs:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=OfPkvG6wS94:JVj0y6Baijs:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/OfPkvG6wS94" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4bcc89d9c006056f5bc7f6d4f631f928" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/rNbPuwQtxcs/monocle-saeed-ahmed.html"><![CDATA[Here is another guest-post written by <i><b>Saeed Ahmed</b></i>: <br /><br /><i>Monocle </i>is a relatively new magazine (launched 2007) that takes great pride in it's real-paper format, putting tremendous thought into the look, feel and emotional appeal of the visual and tactile aspects of its product.  However, don't let this retro-focus fool you.  Since 2008, Monocle has been "airing" a around the clock radio schedule.  I recently discovered this and after sampling a couple of its program offerings, decided to immerse myself in the Monocle experience for a week, which included listening its podcasts and watching videos posted on <a href="http://monocle.com/radio/shows/" target="_blank">the Monocle website</a>. <br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-90EsLSnsWdc/UhsTipPUfxI/AAAAAAAADtA/VcI5u8AOsyE/s1600/monocle.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="200" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-90EsLSnsWdc/UhsTipPUfxI/AAAAAAAADtA/VcI5u8AOsyE/s200/monocle.jpg" width="200" /></a></div>On weekdays, Monocle has five daily hour long news shows which start at 6am (UK time) and end at around midnight.  The Monocle staff are prompt in posting the podcasts (much faster than news podcasts from the BBC it seemed to me).  Each of these has news headlines at the start and in the middle of the show.  In between, there are pre-recorded reports from correspondents, live interviews, and a review of newspapers from different regions of the world, usually with a studio guest. Each of the five shows (Globalist, Midori House, Briefing, Globalist Asia, and Monocle Daily) has its own flavor, and what I found remarkable was the very small amount of redundancy.  I didn't listen to every show every day, but when I did listen to two or three of these in a row, generally only one or two stories were repeated at the most. <br /><br />In addition to the weekday news shows, Monocle has weekly shows on that cover design, urban living, food, movies, books and magazines (yes, magazines, in a show called the "Stack" in which they discuss developments in in-print magazines because this is something they consider important and enduring).  <br /><br />Monocle is also somehow able to maintain a correspondents in several countries (all of whom are good on air), to find interesting studio guests, and to maintain good relationships with other news outlets whose representatives call in regularly and provide reports.  Perhaps my favorite thing is the Monocle radio personalities, who come from many different places including the UK, US, Canada, Australia and Finland.  Unlike the dry presentation of Al Jazeera, BBC or the US networks, the Monocle broadcasters inject a quite healthy dose of humor in between the news headlines, features and interviews.   <br /><br />I don’t know how Monocle does maintains this prolific output and very high standard in print and broadcast media with what must be a small staff and budget (compared to BBC, CBC, ABC RadioNational, RTE and US networks).   It is amazing!  I hope they can keep it up. <br /><br />After my week long immersion, I felt like I had been on a vicarious vacation of sorts, and made new friends.   Give it a try, and perhaps you will feel the same way about <a href="http://monocle.com/contributors/" target="_blank">Tyler Brule, Andrew Tuck, Emma Nelson, Barney Burnham, Markus Hippi, Aisha Speirs, Fiona Wilson and the rest</a>.<br /><br />You can check out <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monocle_(lifestyle_magazine)" target="_blank">Monocle’s Wikipedia page</a> or read an article about it (<a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/news/media/press/monocle-its-the-media-project-that-ive-always-wanted-to-do-2040516.html" target="_blank">The Independent - Monocle, the media project I have always wanted to do</a>). Brule also has his <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tyler_Br%C3%BBl%C3%A9" target="_blank">own page</a>, and enough of an internet presence that someone generated a somewhat tongue and cheek <a href="http://www.beingtylerbrule.com/" target="_blank">fan site</a>.<br /><br />If I could give feedback to Monocle, I would suggest four things:<br />1) include some information about it’s radio personalities on its website,<br />2) provide some links to features that come up in it’s shows,<br />3) during the news shows perhaps mention some of the videos that are posted on it’s website so that people know to look at these and enrich their experience, and<br />4) provide the podcast RSS feeds (rather than just i-tune links).  This last mentioned one can be a bit irritating to those who don’t use i-tunes.  However, there is a technical way to retrieve the RSS feed from the i-tunes site, which can be accessed <a href="http://itunes.so-nik.com/" target="_blank">here </a>(after you go to each of the Monocle show pages and click on “subscribe in iTunes”):<br /><br />More Saeed Ahmed:<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.co.il/2013/02/our-brain-dichotomies-saeed-ahmed.html" target="_blank">Brain Dichotomies</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.co.il/2013/02/taking-courses-with-saeed-ahmed.html" target="_blank">Taking courses with Saeed Ahmed</a>, <br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.co.il/2011/08/optimizing-brain-fitness-saeed-ahmed.html" target="_blank">Optimizing Brain Fitness</a>, <br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/07/wittgenstein-saeed-ahmed-guest-post.html">Wittgenstein</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/07/political-and-current-affairs-podcasts.html">Political and current affairs podcasts</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/07/international-political-economy-saeed.html">International Political Economy</a>.<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=rNbPuwQtxcs:kO8boLUA3ho:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=rNbPuwQtxcs:kO8boLUA3ho:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=rNbPuwQtxcs:kO8boLUA3ho:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/rNbPuwQtxcs" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="18df61556eb879950255c11b64a32345" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/uPynT4sqBww/otzi-in-podcast.html"><![CDATA[I used to feel that prehistory were not that interesting. Too little data to go on, too few narratives that can be reconstructed. But with a find such as Ötzi the Iceman, human history of 5000 years ago suddenly bursts to life. In the twenty years that have passed since the find, Ötzi has not stopped telling us new stuff about his life in the Copper Age.<br /><br /><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eFb36DxBFwY/UDsEc4LrL_I/AAAAAAAADnM/ZFZ7BHCkw5I/s1600/The+History+of+Europe+Podcast.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eFb36DxBFwY/UDsEc4LrL_I/AAAAAAAADnM/ZFZ7BHCkw5I/s1600/The+History+of+Europe+Podcast.jpg" /></a>I was reminded to Ötzi by an original amateur podcast <a href="http://thehistoryofeuropepodcast.blogspot.co.il/">The History of Europe Podcast</a> (<a href="http://thehistoryofeuropepodcast.podomatic.com/rss2.xml">feed</a>) Christopher Linehan tells the history of Europe, as so many other podcasters do, but his starting point is the earliest of histories. Since the first episodes he has worked his way from the Paleolithic to the Chalcolithic period in the 7th issue. And it is there that Ötzi pops up. With his copper age axe and his whole body and garments preserved in the Alpine ice, he allows Linehan to tell a much more specific story in his podcast.<br /><br />But if you are new to Ötzi, before listening to Linehan's History of Europe, listen first to <a href="http://www.howstuffworks.com/stuff-you-missed-in-history-class-podcast.htm">Stuff You missed in History Class</a> (<a href="http://www.howstuffworks.com/podcasts/stuff-you-missed-in-history-class.rss"> feed</a>) where the basics are told of how Ötzi was found in the Alps between Austria and Italy, however they first thought it was the body of a recently disappeared hiker. Only when the forensic experts had extracted the body fully from the ice it began to dawn this might be a much older individual. <br /><br /><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-7VSE1g8JTtY/UDsFYBWreCI/AAAAAAAADnU/6oEd_Ng-19w/s1600/Engines+Of+Our+Ingenuity.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-7VSE1g8JTtY/UDsFYBWreCI/AAAAAAAADnU/6oEd_Ng-19w/s1600/Engines+Of+Our+Ingenuity.jpg" /></a>Modern technology has allowed so many ways of analyzing the remains, so that each part of it can be the subject of an entire podcast. Ötzi's shoes for example. The shoes are discussed by Linehan's History of Europe as well as the charming, but short episode of <a href="http://www.uh.edu/engines/">Engines of our ingenuity</a> (<a href="http://www.npr.org/rss/podcast.php?id=510030">feed</a>). The shoes are made of multiple materials and considered extremely fit for the iceman's trek through the mountains. The podcast even goes as far as to claim Ötzi's shoes are even better than many shoes modern people wear. Think about that when you barge around on your crocs.<br /><br />A huge subject is also Ötzi's medical record: his genetic makeup, his diseases, fractures and wounds as well as the contents of his intestines. Learn more at <a href="http://www.medicaldiscoverynews.com/podcast/podcast.html">Medical Discovery News</a> (<a href="http://www.medicaldiscoverynews.com/shows/audio/mdnews.xml">feed</a>) and <a href="http://www.blogtalkradio.com/lifetechnologies">Life Technologies</a> (BTR) (<a href="http://www.blogtalkradio.com/lifetechnologies.rss">feed</a>) Ötzi, for example, was found to have Lime's disease, how that is not what has taken him in. <br /><br />What actually caused his death, has proven to be one of the conundrums about Ötzi. Did he die of the arrow wound that was inflicted upon him shortly be fore his death (with the arrow head still stuck in his back), or did he die of the frost in the ice  that preserved him for 53 centuries? What is certain is that he had been in a fight. It also has become clear he had two good meals with meat and vegetables on the day of his death. He was 46 years old, had brown hair and brown eyes - just like your bloghost...<br /><br /><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=uPynT4sqBww:Tvl5AEG2vUo:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=uPynT4sqBww:Tvl5AEG2vUo:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=uPynT4sqBww:Tvl5AEG2vUo:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/uPynT4sqBww" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="93ddb77adb58d7c9b295d2cff48927e5" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/vbGW8Cnhkhw/along-ancient-road-to-kaifeng-chp.html"><![CDATA[Whenever the Yangtze would rise and flood the city of Kaifeng, the residents would salvage their property, if possible in advance, and return after the river had fallen again. Then they would rebuild their structures until the next time. Thus also did the Jewish community of Kaifeng and in that way they lost and rebuilt their synagogue for some seven centuries. All the while they maintained their traditions, in spite of being (nearly) completely isolated from Jewry on the whole. By 1810, the last Chinese Rabbi died and in 1866 the synagogue was destroyed for the last time. <br /><br /><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jgVC_k4cbfY/TwQdI1e37HI/AAAAAAAAC1U/UN5d-sMfmjo/s1600/The-China-History-Podcast.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="144" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jgVC_k4cbfY/TwQdI1e37HI/AAAAAAAAC1U/UN5d-sMfmjo/s200/The-China-History-Podcast.png" width="144" /></a>The <a href="http://chinahistorypodcast.com/">China History Podcast</a> in it's 112th episode gives us a riveting 38 minutes about the <a href="http://chinahistorypodcast.com/chp-112-the-kaifeng-jews">Kaifeng Jews</a>. This is yet another unmissable edition in this magnificent series, by Laszlo Montgomery. (<a href="http://chinahistorypodcast.com/feed/podcast/">feed</a>)<br /><br />In 1163 CE the Jews of Kaifeng got official permission from the Chinese emperor to build a synagogue. From here on they have a well traceable history and Laszlo tells a couple of fascinating stories about it. For example how the Jesuits found them and there was a mutual attempt to co-opt the other. Or how when decline set it and the Jews lost their Hebrew, they'd display the Torah Scrolls in the market, hoping to run into someone who could read them. But he does not simply begin in 1163 and end in 1866. This podcast spans nearly a thousand years.<br /><br />How did the Jews get there in the first place? And what was done and is done until this day to rekindle Judaism in Kaifeng? Such questions take us from the ancient Silk Road (one of my favorite history subjects) to the effects of the Boxer rebellion and the Second World War. All is told in the relaxed, yet thoroughly engaging Laszlo Montgomery style.<br /><br />More China History Podcast:<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.co.il/2012/02/getting-silk-road.html">Getting the Silk Road</a><br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2012/01/break-update-for-2012.html">Deng Xiaoping</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/09/chronology-of-dynasties-china-history.html">Chronology of Dynasties</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/09/china-history-podcast-laszlo-montgomery.html">China History Podcast</a>.<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=vbGW8Cnhkhw:Xv2RAxAm1Qo:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=vbGW8Cnhkhw:Xv2RAxAm1Qo:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=vbGW8Cnhkhw:Xv2RAxAm1Qo:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/vbGW8Cnhkhw" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7546ae226f84d52a45b0388035aeb365" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/vFY_9kAaSs0/the-meaning-of-everything-big-ideas.html"><![CDATA[An exceptionally witty and entertaining lecture by Simon Winchester can be heard at the TVO podcast <a href="http://www.tvo.org/TVOsites/WebObjects/TvoMicrosite.woa?bigideas">Big Ideas</a>. (<a href="http://www.tvo.org/TVOspecial3/WebObjects/TVOMedia.woa?bigideasfeed">feed</a>)<br /><br /><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_N56aAeTnoT8/S_T-hVrbUfI/AAAAAAAACnE/kRVQCH_9UBE/s1600/bigideas2.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_N56aAeTnoT8/S_T-hVrbUfI/AAAAAAAACnE/kRVQCH_9UBE/s1600/bigideas2.png" /></a>Winchester relates the history of the Oxford English Dictionary. How it came into being and how it attempts to be complete and impartial other than Webster's or Samuel Johnson's dictionaries. Or similar dictionaries of other languages. <br /><br />A history with many maniacs, slips of paper and a huge crowd of anonymous contributors. Sounds familiarly modern?<br /><br />More Big Ideas:<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.co.il/2011/03/meaning-systems-big-ideas.html">Meaning Systems</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/03/elegance-of-hedgehog.html">The Elegance of the Hedgehog</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/03/age-of-unequals-big-ideas.html">Age of Unequals</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/03/dan-dennett-what-should-replace.html">Dan Dennett: what should replace religion?</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/02/chris-hedges-big-ideas.html">Chris Hedges</a>.<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=vFY_9kAaSs0:PJ71WTIR1G8:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=vFY_9kAaSs0:PJ71WTIR1G8:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=vFY_9kAaSs0:PJ71WTIR1G8:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/vFY_9kAaSs0" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="433e50ebc6d2a7917d11321c4b2e61ba" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/vuK_d18mvSE/the-history-of-english-and-history-of.html"><![CDATA[Recently I have been dedicating all my listening time to one podcaster, Kevin Stroud, who offers two series on the web. The first is <a href="http://historyofenglishpodcast.com/" target="_blank">The History of English Podcast</a> which has by now reached its 30th episode, 20 of which I have managed to cover since I made the discovery. The other is <a href="http://historyofenglishpodcast.com/alphabet-history/" target="_blank">The History of the Alphabet</a> which I learned about through the aforementioned and which I listened through from beginning to end in one fell swoop.<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-F29188BccOI/UjVcvvH_tXI/AAAAAAAADvw/YiEXC2W4uvA/s1600/The+History+of+English+Podcast+1.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-F29188BccOI/UjVcvvH_tXI/AAAAAAAADvw/YiEXC2W4uvA/s320/The+History+of+English+Podcast+1.jpg" /></a></div>Kevin Stroud is an American lawyer with a love for language, who has taken up the unique challenge among history podcasts to relate the history of a language, any language. His history of the English language goes back to the earliest of beginnings, the Indo-European language and slowly takes it from there. He delivers a lot of linguistic samples but by following a historic narrative which is in many ways a retelling of the main stream history from the dawn of civilization up to modern times. This means he delivers material that is touched upon by many other podcasters. I am not sure whether he is familiar with them all, but I find his history to be closely in synch with what is known through other sources. What makes the podcast unique, original and highly interesting is the linguistic perspective. In addition, Stroud has a good voice and delivers his text in a way that is highly effective in audio, that is, his sentences are straightforward and he does not shy away from repetition so that you cannot get lost and his point passes really well. (<a href="http://historyofengland.typepad.com/blog/rss.xml">feed</a>)<br /><br />During this podcast, Stroud naturally gives a lot of attention to the development of script in general and the alphabet in particular. For example he dedicated a whole episode to the letter C. However, for a more extensive and systematic discussion of the alphabet and this different letters, he decided to make another series: The history of the alphabet. This is more of an audio-book and it can be purchased from several vendors at a price around $9, but I bought it for $6 directly at the podcast's website. It is the first time I have actually paid money for audio and I have not regretted it for a single moment. This series has shown me how the Hebrew alphabet that I had to learn at a later age is much more closely related and traceable in the Latin alphabet with which I grew up than I thought. It clarifies some of the strange spellings you encounter, especially in English and French, but not much less in Dutch. I also never knew that the letters J and V are actually so new in our language that the first dictionaries that were made, like for example Samuel Johnson's (1755), did not even treat them separately from I and U.<br /><br />I'll continue to catch up with Stroud's podcast and in the mean time I should be updating you on many other new podcasts I have been picking up on of late. Many of these also dive into ancient history, so it seems I am really going through a '<i>back to the roots</i>' phase as it were. My playlist contains The Ancient World, Myths and  History of Ancient Greece and the Podcast History of our World to name a few along this line.<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=vuK_d18mvSE:zeacCUem8z0:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=vuK_d18mvSE:zeacCUem8z0:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=vuK_d18mvSE:zeacCUem8z0:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/vuK_d18mvSE" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="62c7cd2535a5f9d496679ae020c904ed" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/wxzvaXS5W3Y/football-weekly-euro-2012-daily.html"><![CDATA[Occasionally I listen to The Guardian's podcast <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/series/footballweekly">Football Weekly</a>, but when major tournaments come around, this podcast changes to a daily one and is permanently on my playlist. So now we have the <b>Euro 2012 Daily</b> and it is a great listen (<a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/football/series/footballweekly/podcast.xml">feed</a>). In fact it is so good, I did not even bother with other podcasts.<br /><br /><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-4ETAW7szUIY/T97rUmLE3TI/AAAAAAAADm4/po0G6VgfkXQ/s1600/Euro+2012+Football+daily.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-4ETAW7szUIY/T97rUmLE3TI/AAAAAAAADm4/po0G6VgfkXQ/s1600/Euro+2012+Football+daily.jpg" /></a>James Richardson, is as always the witty host to a panel of guests who comment on the games and make haphazard predictions of the upcoming venues. In 30 minutes you are informed and entertained.<br /><br />The podcast comes out immediately after every games night and accompanies me the morning after. And since my team has been met with defeat it was not met with much happiness, but the podcast invariably managed to cheer me up.<br /><br />More:<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.co.il/2010/07/world-cup-podcasts.html">World Cup Daily</a>.<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=wxzvaXS5W3Y:wbz0EbyQ-BA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=wxzvaXS5W3Y:wbz0EbyQ-BA:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=wxzvaXS5W3Y:wbz0EbyQ-BA:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/wxzvaXS5W3Y" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="27cc6b5a77d35a55120d24bfb7e38094" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/XO-y4fV6UAY/passover-joke.html"><![CDATA[Rabbi Jack receives a letter from the Royal Court that he going to be knighted. All his friends and relatives are so proud of him, but the rabbi is concerned. "How can I be a knight? A rabbi knight, who can conceive of such a thing? And besides, I'll have to go through the whole knighting ceremony. I'll probably do it all wrong. What do I do?"<br />His friends try to rest him assured. "It is really simple, you kneel before the Queen, she will announce you to be Sir Jack from now on and that's it. It's easy - don't worry. And you will continue to be the same old Jack."<br />That sort of calms the Rabbi down, but then he finds out that every knight has to choose a motto. Some line in Latin that he has to utter when the Queen knights him. This upsets him even more. "Latin! I do not know the simplest thing in Latin. Why must it be Latin? Couldn't it be Hebrew." In order to get rid of the whining his friends agree: "Yes, choose a line in Hebrew, that will be fine." <br />"Good," the rabbi acclaims, "I will think of something."<br /><br />And so the evening comes round that together with a whole lot of other people, Rabbi Jack is going to be knighted. Each man kneels in front of the Queen, she announces their knighthood, they say their line in Latin and the affair is done. <br />Rabbi Jack is  the last in line. He approaches the Queen and she proclaims: "Henceforth, you will be Sir Jack." And Jack says: "Ma Nishtana."<br />The Queen frowns, failing to recognize his motto, leans over to her adviser and whispers: <br /><br />"Why is this knight different from others??"<br /><br /><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=XO-y4fV6UAY:j-7M3bAauLI:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=XO-y4fV6UAY:j-7M3bAauLI:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=XO-y4fV6UAY:j-7M3bAauLI:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/XO-y4fV6UAY" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="345b12bc902bb4e39d592a99e531334f" url="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~3/ZUr5YRh4FfY/getting-silk-road.html"><![CDATA[I am fascinated by the Silk Road and if you, like me, would like to learn more about it, here are some good tips. First of all, Laszlo Montgomery's great <a href="http://chinahistorypodcast.com/">China History Podcast</a> (<a href="http://chinahistorypodcast.com/feed/podcast/">feed</a>) has begun a <a href="http://chinahistorypodcast.com/2012/02/chp-073-the-early-years-of-the-silk-road/">series about the Silk Road</a> just now. There was also an <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b00p315t">In Our Time issue about the Silk Road</a> in 2009 which can now be had from the <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/series/ioth">In Our Time History Archive</a> (<a href="http://downloads.bbc.co.uk/podcasts/radio4/ioth/rss.xml">feed</a>). Other podcast tips I have come up with in the past are: <br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2011/06/today-in-podcast-22-june-2011.html">Zhang Qian</a>, <br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/09/history-of-parthians-edward-dabrowa.html">The Parthians</a>, <br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/01/9-podcasts-i-enjoyed-and-cannot-all.html">Turfan</a>, <br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/09/heads-up-for-16-september-2010.html">Jade artifact</a>&nbsp; <br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/01/trade-story-of-india-3.html">The Kushan</a>.<br /><br />The basics of the Silk Road are not difficult to understand: it was -already by 200 BC and still is today- a network of land routs that connected China with the rest of Asia and Europe and which allowed for trade between distant cultures such as the Roman Empire, the Han Chinese, India and more. Notably Silk and Jade were traded along the routes and if you stop here, you are just fine. I try to imagine how this actually worked and then the idea of a Silk Road becomes very complicated to understand. If you begin considering the sheer distances, the difficulty of the terrain, the problems of logistics and so on, I fail to see how it could actually work. How could a trader from China transport something extremely valuable like silk over such a distance alone? He'd be away for at least a year, he'd take enormous risks along the road and assuming he'd manage to sell his goods in Rome, he'd have to get home safely. On the other hand, if the trader wasn't to sell the silk in Rome himself, but rather rely on a chain of middle men, I would expect that the silk, by the time it reached Rome, had become so expensive, nobody would be willing to pay the price.<br /><br /><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jgVC_k4cbfY/TwQdI1e37HI/AAAAAAAAC1U/UN5d-sMfmjo/s1600/The-China-History-Podcast.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" height="144" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jgVC_k4cbfY/TwQdI1e37HI/AAAAAAAAC1U/UN5d-sMfmjo/s200/The-China-History-Podcast.png" width="144" /></a>I am still to get an answer to this basic question, but from Laszlo Montgomery's opening episode, I learned of a solution that addressed one of the logistic problems that would have made the journey impossible: the problem of fresh water. If traders had had to carry the water they needed for the journey, along with the goods they wanted to trade with, the amount of luggage would have become simply too large. Yet, most of the roads pass arid terrain, if not outright desert. The way this was addressed was by local populace that had dug canals from the snowy mountain tops, until numerous wells along the route. This allowed the traders to journey with just their goods. I also understand that this brought the routes down to a very limited amount of possibilities: only those places where the mountains were sufficiently close by and wells had been established. <br /><br />I still have to get an answer to the practical questions of how the trade was actually pulled off, because it continues to escape me how anyone would have taken the risk of the whole journey or how it could deliver affordable goods within an endless chain of middle men. Exposes about the Silk Road, whether podcast or not, rapidly leave the subject of trade and move on to emphasize what else began to travel along the Silk Road: ideas and technologies. The Silk Road allowed Buddhism to spread from India to the rest of Asia. Along the road also spread Manicheanism and early forms of Christianity. Eventually Islam took the road. Chinese inventions such as paper made it to the west over the road and of course Marco Polo traveled the Silk Road back and forth.<br /><br />Another point that is not always made, but needs to be held in mind is an inequality that also played a part in the age of exploration when the sea routes also connected China with the rest: China had all the splendid stuff, but what did the rest of the world, especially the Europeans have to offer China? In the later years it was silver from South America, but what traveled on the Silk Road from west to east? How did the Romans pay for their much craved silk? Montgomery mention that spices, ivory and horses were wanted by the Chinese, but this is stuff from other parts of Asia and possibly Africa. What came from Europe? One thing that could not possibly be all, comes as a surprise: chairs. I hope the China History podcast will have more answers in the coming chapters.<br /><br />More China History Podcast:<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2012/01/break-update-for-2012.html">Deng Xiaoping</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/09/chronology-of-dynasties-china-history.html">Chronology of Dynasties</a>,<br /><a href="http://anneisaman.blogspot.com/2010/09/china-history-podcast-laszlo-montgomery.html">China History Podcast</a>.<br /><br /><br /><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=ZUr5YRh4FfY:QmSiYq9-y98:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=ZUr5YRh4FfY:QmSiYq9-y98:cTv1dNCI_Tc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=cTv1dNCI_Tc" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?a=ZUr5YRh4FfY:QmSiYq9-y98:63t7Ie-LG7Y"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Anne_Is_A_Man?d=63t7Ie-LG7Y" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Anne_Is_A_Man/~4/ZUr5YRh4FfY" height="1" width="1"/>
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>