<author type="blog" lang="EN" gender="xx" age_group="xx" url="leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com">
	<documents count="25">
		<document id="727c588bdfa4e5631c4ee495b0fe21f6" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2012/02/to-succeed-in-life-and-work.html"><![CDATA[
Before the holidays, Lisa Gates of She Negotiates started a discussion  on ForbesWoman with this "burning question:" "What are the top 10 things  you think all women need to learn to master to succeed in life and  work?"She sparked a pretty  active discussion and here's what I observed about the replies. 
As you might expect the  VAST majority of the answers had to do with enhancing personal 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="e408c74433b2d6ff32ef19e2d890f7e1" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2012/02/whats-love-got-to-do-with-it.html"><![CDATA[
About every other year I use February to talk about love in the  organizational context. This year I'm inspired by a presentation I saw  Brendon Burchard make in which he said that at the end of our lives,  each of us wants to be able to give positive answers to 3 questions:                                                 Did I live?
Did I love?
Did I matter?

]]>
		</document>
		<document id="7dbdba0ce9c9efe33ed7fc5a4ee29400" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2012/02/why-women-mbas-do-less-well-than-men.html"><![CDATA[
A while ago I sent a colleague who is a strong critical thinker our new research on gender dynamics that constrict talent pipelines. The findings motivated him to rethink some of their talent development strategies. In addition, he sent along this question."I’m curious why female business and MBA grads don’t fare as well as male business and MBA grads.  Both graduate with similar education and 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f4c383c6e8a496177f8c2dd39b3ce181" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2012/04/business-savvy-barrier.html"><![CDATA[             
<!--
 /* Font Definitions */
@font-face
 {font-family:"?? ??";
 panose-1:0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0;
 mso-font-charset:128;
 mso-generic-font-family:roman;
 mso-font-format:other;
 mso-font-pitch:fixed;
 mso-font-signature:1 134676480 16 0 131072 0;}
@font-face
 {font-family:"?? ??";
 panose-1:0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0;
 mso-font-charset:128;
 mso-generic-font-family:roman;
 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f56dbd107323209f0d64e1d00247bb05" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2012/04/dont-grow-complacent-hbr-report-is-not.html"><![CDATA[While I was in Guatemala for our Leadership in Action program many of you sent me links to the Harvard Business Review blog asking: Are Women Better Leaders than Men? The authors' assertions are that in an analysis of their 360 feedback reports of over 7000 managers, women were rated as outperforming men in nearly all of them - actually 12 out of 16. BUT hold on a minute! There are 2 major 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="42781dc23ef0732911293286ce5b0747" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2012/08/curiosity-mars-and-final-frontier-for.html"><![CDATA[

Curiosity Exploring Mars
In the past 40 years, corporations have tackled the challenge of women's advancement by working diligently on two fronts.They have worked on the women. They help women set career goals and tell them what skills they need to enhance in order to get ahead - leadership, self-promotion, negotiation and more. 
They have worked on corporate practices and policies. Instituting
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="902542a8ba175493854020669874192a" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2012/08/legitimate-rape-my-ass.html"><![CDATA[I try to stay out of politics in this blog, but yesterday's comments by Senate candidate Rep. Todd Akin have me incensed. He's a republican. I would be equally incensed if I heard such disdain for women from the mouth of a democrat.

His original statement was this piece of inanity that has no basis in medical fact, "First of all, from what I understand from doctors, [pregnancy from  rape] is 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="edf5217e0939a20ee0573c223cd45a78" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2012/08/new-zealand-aheadand-yet-so-far-to-go.html"><![CDATA[            
<!--
 /* Font Definitions */
@font-face
 {font-family:"?? ??";
 panose-1:0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0;
 mso-font-charset:128;
 mso-generic-font-family:roman;
 mso-font-format:other;
 mso-font-pitch:fixed;
 mso-font-signature:1 134676480 16 0 131072 0;}
@font-face
 {font-family:"?? ??";
 panose-1:0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0;
 mso-font-charset:128;
 mso-generic-font-family:roman;
 mso-font-format:other
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4376075f7d73c2492cc9a03c6030a5b6" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2012/09/develop-top-talent-challenge-managers.html"><![CDATA[Following up on our blog about the Final Frontier for Women's Advancement check out our new video.



Managers have mindsets about women and men, about leadership and    careers. Many of these mindsets create barriers for women and get in the    way of developing top talent. Helping managers take action to  minimize   gender barriers is the new frontier in women's advancement --  and one   that 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="3d745e14c9034fe01ee8ab4abf32e6be" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2012/09/if-president-can-so-can-you-dinner-with.html"><![CDATA[Whether or not you support President Obama, if you're a mother you'll want to listen to the first 40 second or so of this interview.

  We encourage women to be proactive with internal and external networking, but that doesn't mean that you have to overdo it. If the President of the United States can make sure that when he's in town he's having dinner with his children, so can you!   Of course, 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6bf0f6f8de511919aad5a1875e206737" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2012/09/the-power-of-womens-leadership.html"><![CDATA[Guest blog by Renee' Aloisio and Kate Kennedy. As one of the state delegates to Vision 2020, I have enjoyed working with them and the other amazing women who are part of this effort. Thanks to GoLocal for the original.

As the Rhode Island economy plods along its slow recovery, our state's  businesses continue to seek out any kind of competitive advantages to  get ahead. One such advantage that 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="be5a680a1bf2953fe69d47eb6e6695a3" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2012/10/lessons-from-13th-most-wealthy-woman.html"><![CDATA[Forbes just released its list of the 400 richest Americans
 and it took until number 92 on the list to find a woman who is known 
primarily as an executive not an heiress. Meet Marilyn Carlson Nelson.

Marilyn Carlson Nelson was the CEO and now chairs the board of hotel,
 travel and restaurant company Carlson Inc. Her father, Curt  founded 
the company in the 1930s. Marilyn served as CEO until 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="78f838154e6221db026cf330699b470e" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2012/11/i-did-it-my-way-regrets-ive-had-few-but.html"><![CDATA[



"Regrets, I've had a few
But then again, too few to mention
I did what I had to do and saw it through without exemption
I planned each charted course, each careful step along the byway
And more, much more than this, I did it my way"
Who knew that Frank Sinatra's signature song concealed important career advice? Certainly not the woman I was sitting with at lunch the other day. She was chosen 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="ca410e23aed995fecc5b5950dda9363e" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2013/01/new-year-new-insights-on-womens.html"><![CDATA[Much of the effort that organizations invest in women's advancement isn't solving the talent development challenges executives care most about. Sure
 all the advice today’s diversity and learning functions
are giving women is helpful, but it falls short in fueling the pipeline for women into senior and executive positions. 

For example, in December, Catalyst’s published its latest census of 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="f0d8321fe1aa5c4563c152d344b92dbc" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2013/02/an-abundance-of-news.html"><![CDATA[Why is it that just ahead of Black History Month so much news comes out about women in general?

Gender Dynamics
At Davos, Sheryl Sandberg spoke out about the impact of gender dynamics on women's advancement.

"She blasted managers who unconsciously reflect stereotypes when they 
judge women's performance, saying: 'She's great at her job but she's 
just not as well liked by her peers,' or: 'She's
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2d63c30c92d50505a4e1008a7b43a886" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2013/02/leaning-in-only-partial-solution.html"><![CDATA[



I've been delighted as Sheryl Sandberg, COO of Facebook has taken public stances on the issue of women's advancement. I look forward to the release of her book Lean In. Her advice to women to "lean in" is important - especially for women who aren't already acting on their ambitions. But research tells us that this isn't advice for all women! It's generally advice for women who are on their 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="87f4529f42e53e7cdc4de0fc6d96d3ac" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2013/03/lean-in-must-read.html"><![CDATA[



I just finished reading Lean In and I love it.

Is it a guidebook for women in leadership? Not exactly. But that is not what Sheryl Sandberg set out to write. For me it is several important things and for any one of them should be read. In no particular order, Lean In is:



A summary for younger women of what has happened in the last 40 years to make possible today's opportunities for women.
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="4e7c520219ea3a0fd7e781e50aa11bec" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2013/04/equal-paywhats-up-in-your-company.html"><![CDATA[



April 9, 2013 is Equal Pay Day so we thought we'd share information that might spark a conversation in your company.

Last year, through the work of an amazing group of women and the participation of key HR professionals, Vision 2020 RI surveyed many of Rhode Island's largest employers about their gender equity practices.  Here's what we discovered about equal pay.


What Vision 2020 Asked

1
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="a9be5c6836aba6718d8b0c5cd731ba02" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2013/04/find-courage-to-take-your-next-step.html"><![CDATA[













<!--
 /* Font Definitions */
@font-face
 {font-family:Times;
 panose-1:2 0 5 0 0 0 0 0 0 0;
 mso-font-charset:0;
 mso-generic-font-family:auto;
 mso-font-pitch:variable;
 mso-font-signature:3 0 0 0 1 0;}
@font-face
 {font-family:"?? ??";
 mso-font-charset:78;
 mso-generic-font-family:auto;
 mso-font-pitch:variable;
 mso-font-signature:-536870145 1791491579 18 0 131231 0;}
@font-face
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="24e82f9baa4e6633032cb4fc78a76f3c" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2013/04/learning-from-boston.html"><![CDATA[



I was often in my hometown outside of Boston during the weeks during and following the Boston Marathon bombings. As I listened to President Obama, Governor Deval Patrick and Mayor Menino in public statements and news conferences,  I was struck by their leadership - especially during their addresses in the Cathedral of the Holy Cross.

What I noticed was the skill with which they reached out 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="884caad67b11710ad8c338a18bde85da" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2013/04/surely-things-have-changed.html"><![CDATA[



When I talk about The Missing 33%™, the first research I cite is from a BusinessWeek cover story published in 2000. In short, the findings were that women "outshine their male counterparts on almost every measure."

This led me to research what the almost was all about. After all, if we're so good, why were there so few of us at the top? The finding is what we call The Missing 33% and 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="6bc7e13eb2416f110f17e5e564d2b706" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2013/06/self-promote-with-grace-and-authenticity.html"><![CDATA[



In our workshop and online module on how to self-promote with grace and authenticity, one of the foundation concepts is this - when you highlight your contributions to moving the business forward it is always graceful.

I was reminded of this a while ago when I heard a feature on NPR's Talk of the Nation on The Quiet Power of Introverts. 

During the segment a hotel manager called in with a 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="2582d3997f91a3d702f561b5d8022ee6" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2013/06/what-gets-you-to-middle-wont-take-you.html"><![CDATA[




I'm redesigning my office...and that means cleaning up and throwing out. In the cleaning I came across a list of inquiries that a recent Leadership Mastery group of participants had. These are women poised to move into senior and executive positions.

There were two significant learning goals shared across nearly all of the women:

What will it take to unstick from where I am and to move to 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="1c0c947e769a26f13f05acffef86c706" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2013/07/be-for-business-and-other-essential.html"><![CDATA[When we asked women to tell us the best career advice they received and applied our definition of leadership to analyze what we heard, we discovered that:

Nearly 75% of the advice had to do with the personal greatness component "Use the greatness in you..."
Nearly 24% was advice about "...engaging the greatness in others."
Only about 2% was advice about how to "...achieve and sustain 
]]>
		</document>
		<document id="362581e382fa87961ce4aec72b7a43c5" url="http://leadingwomenblog.blogspot.com/2013/12/visit-us-at-our-new-blog.html"><![CDATA[


We have a new blog for you! 
As of 12/16/13, you will find Leading Women's news, information and insights for your career success and about closing the gender gap at the top of organizations here:

http://www.LeadingWomen.biz/blog

Hope you'll join us there. 

Lead ON!
Susan
Susan Colantuono, CEO and Founder Leading Women
]]>
		</document>
	</documents>
</author>